<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:prism="http://prismstandard.org/namespaces/basic/2.0/"><channel><title> Wiley：水资源研究：目录</title><link/>https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R<description>水资源研究目录。最新和 EarlyView 问题的文章列表。</description><language>英文</language><copyright></copyright><managingeditor>wileyonlinelibrary@wiley.com（AGU 出版物）</managingeditor><pubDate> Sat, 15 Apr 2023 07:58:52 +0000</pubDate><lastbuilddate> 2023 年 4 月 15 日星期六 07:58:52 +0000</lastbuilddate><generator> Atypon®文学™</generator><docs> https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs><ttl> 10080</ttl><dc:title> Wiley：水资源研究：目录</dc:title><dc:publisher>威利</dc:publisher><prism:publicationname>水资源研究</prism:publicationname><atom:link href="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"></atom:link><image/><title> Wiley：水资源研究：目录</title><url>https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/pb-assets/journal-banners/19447973.jpg</url><link/> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R<item><link/> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033714?af=R<pubDate> Fri, 14 Apr 2023 14:25:27 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-04-14T02:25:27-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley：水资源研究：目录<prism:coverdate>2023 年 4 月 1 日星期六 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate> 2023 年 4 月 1 日星期六 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR033714</guid><title>洪泛区连接渠道作为三角洲河网水文连通性的关键路径</title><description>水资源研究，第 59 卷，第 4 期，2023 年 4 月。</description><dc:description>摘要 河流分叉对于将水、沉积物和养分分配到三角洲河网的下游支流至关重要。然而，分叉的下游分支可以通过穿过三角洲漫滩的连接通道连接起来。作为下游控制的洪泛区连接通道可以影响河流分叉处的水分配，从而影响河网的水文连通性。然而，它的影响在很大程度上仍然难以捉摸。在这项研究中，我们探讨了连接下游支流的连接渠道如何影响上游分叉处的水分配和两个支流的水分配。调查是通过使用 Delft3D 的理想化数值模拟进行的，然后使用图论分析了对河网水文连通性的级联效应。结果表明，连接通道可以减轻上游分叉处的不对称水分配。然而，这是以在下游出口引起更多不均匀流动为代价的。流量调整是由于两个分支中空间水面坡度的改变与通过连接通道从一个通道到另一个通道的流量交换相关联。对水文连通性的进一步分析表明，连接渠道通常可以通过增强两个分支之间的流量交换来降低渠道网络对水文变化的脆弱性，尤其是入流变化。我们的结果表明，连接渠道是水文连通性的关键路径，这对三角洲河网及其漫滩的管理具有重要意义。</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;摘要&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;河流分叉对于将水、沉积物和养分分配到三角洲河网的下游支流至关重要。然而，分叉的下游分支可以通过穿过三角洲漫滩的连接通道连接起来。作为下游控制的洪泛区连接通道可以影响河流分叉处的水分配，从而影响河网的水文连通性。然而，它的影响在很大程度上仍然难以捉摸。在这项研究中，我们探讨了连接下游支流的连接渠道如何影响上游分叉处的水分配和两个支流的水分配。调查是通过使用 Delft3D 的理想化数值模拟进行的，然后使用图论分析了对河网水文连通性的级联效应。结果表明，连接通道可以减轻上游分叉处的不对称水分配。然而，这是以在下游出口引起更多不均匀流动为代价的。流量调整是由于两个分支中空间水面坡度的改变与通过连接通道从一个通道到另一个通道的流量交换相关联。对水文连通性的进一步分析表明，连接渠道通常可以通过增强两个分支之间的流量交换来降低渠道网络对水文变化的脆弱性，尤其是入流变化。我们的结果表明，连接渠道是水文连通性的关键路径，这对三角洲河网及其漫滩的管理具有重要意义。&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> Weilun Gao, Zheng Bing Wang, Maarten G. Kleinhans, Chiyuan Miao, Baoshan Cui, 邵东东</dc:creator><category>研究文章</category><dc:title>洪泛区连接渠道作为三角洲河网水文连通性的关键路径</dc:title><dc:identifier>10.1029/2022WR033714</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname>水资源研究</prism:publicationname><prism:doi>10.1029/2022WR033714</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033714?af=R</prism:url><prism:section>研究文章</prism:section><prism:volume>59</prism:volume><prism:number> 4个</prism:number></item><item><link/>https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033151?af=R<pubDate> Fri, 14 Apr 2023 14:19:47 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-04-14T02:19:47-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley：水资源研究：目录<prism:coverdate>2023 年 4 月 1 日星期六 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate> 2023 年 4 月 1 日星期六 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR033151</guid><title>了解低洼沿海地下水系统中当今地下水盐度的古水文地质模型（德国西北部）</title><description>水资源研究，第 59 卷，第 4 期，2023 年 4 月。</description><dc:description>摘要 地下水的抽取和排水被认为是低洼沿海地下水系统盐碱化的主要驱动因素，而过去边界条件的作用尚不清楚。在这项研究中，应用 3-D 古水文地质变密度地下水流和盐分运移模型（“古模型”）来重建全新世期间地下水盐度的演变，即最近 9,000 年，在德国西北部.这项研究的新颖之处包括在 3-D 古建模框架中考虑高度分辨的时变边界条件，例如海平面上升、地表高程和海岸线变化、排水网络的发展和地下水抽取，以及作为影响盐渍化的孤立过程的量化。结果表明，从公元前 9000 年到公元 1300 年，盐渍化是海平面上升的函数。公元 1300 年堤防线的创建为加强水文（地质）系统的人为控制设定了起点：地表高程的变化和低洼沼泽地的排水系统已成为公元 1600 年以后泥炭被人为开采后盐碱化的主要驱动因素退化。此外，风暴洪水引起的堤防线变化影响了盐度。 2020 CE 的模型结果与当前的盐度观测结果非常吻合。然而，由于水（地质）系统尚未达到平衡，未来盐碱化仍将继续。所提出的古建模框架可以被视为受海侵和人类发展影响的类似低洼沿海地下水系统的蓝图。因此，它能够重建有意义的当今盐度分布，作为模拟气候变化中未来地下水系统的重要基础。</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;摘要&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;地下水的抽取和排水被认为是低洼沿海地下水系统盐化的主要驱动因素，而过去边界条件的作用尚不清楚。在这项研究中，应用 3-D 古水文地质变密度地下水流和盐分运移模型（“古模型”）来重建全新世期间地下水盐度的演变，即德国西北部的最后 9,000 年.这项研究的新颖之处包括在 3-D 古建模框架中考虑高度分辨的时变边界条件，例如海平面上升、地表高程和海岸线变化、排水网络的发展和地下水抽取，以及作为影响盐渍化的孤立过程的量化。结果表明，从公元前 9000 年到公元 1300 年，盐渍化是海平面上升的函数。公元 1300 年堤坝线的创建为加强水文（地质）系统的人为控制设定了起点：地表高程的变化和低洼沼泽地的排水已成为公元 1600 年以后人工泥炭盐化的主要驱动因素退化。此外，风暴洪水引起的堤防线变化影响了盐度。 2020 CE 的模型结果与当前的盐度观测结果非常吻合。然而，由于水（地质）系统尚未达到平衡，未来盐碱化仍将继续。所提出的古建模框架可以被视为受海侵和人类发展影响的类似低洼沿海地下水系统的蓝图。因此，它能够重建有意义的当今盐度分布，作为模拟气候变化中未来地下水系统的重要基础。&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> Stephan L. Seibert、Janek Greskowiak、Friederike Bungenstock、Holger Freund、Martina Karle、Rena Meyer、Gualbert HP Oude Essink、Joeri Engelen、Gudrun Massmann</dc:creator><category>研究文章</category><dc:title>了解低洼沿海地下水系统中当今地下水盐度的古水文地质模型（德国西北部）</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2022WR033151</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname>水资源研究</prism:publicationname><prism:doi>10.1029/2022WR033151</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033151?af=R</prism:url><prism:section>研究文章</prism:section><prism:volume>59</prism:volume><prism:number> 4个</prism:number></item><item><link/>https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR034151?af=R<pubDate> Fri, 14 Apr 2023 12:50:46 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-04-14T12:50:46-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley：水资源研究：目录<prism:coverdate></prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate></prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR034151</guid><title>床粗糙度对部分埋藏的孤立淡水贻贝周围流动和湍流结构的影响</title><description>水资源研究，接受的文章。</description><dc:description>摘要 本研究使用涡分辨数值模拟来研究床粗糙度如何影响孤立的、部分埋藏的贻贝 (Unio elongatulus) 周围的流动和湍流结构，该贻贝与入流对齐。粗糙床模拟解决了流过砾石床裸露部分的问题，其表面是从实验室实验中获得的，该实验还为数值模型的验证提供了一些额外的数据。还讨论了水平光滑床的极限情况的结果。此外，通过一组模拟研究了改变贻贝在基质内的埋藏水平和通过两个贻贝虹吸管排放的影响，其中形成粗糙床的（砾石）颗粒的中值直径之间的比率， d50 和贻贝暴露部分的高度 h 在 0.10 和 0.22 之间变化。床层粗糙度的增加与近尾流区湍流动能的强烈放大有关。增加床粗糙度和/或降低 h 会加强床颗粒产生的涡流与分别由主动过滤和贻贝壳引起的底部和尖端涡流的相互作用，这反过来又会导致更快速的消散这些漩涡。增加床层粗糙度也会降低尾流中形成的主要下降流区域的强度。对称平面附近的强下降流是对称尾流脱落模式在光滑床模拟中占主导地位的主要原因，主动过滤可忽略不计。相比之下，反对称尾流脱落模式在以高床粗糙度值进行的模拟中占主导地位。壳出现部分的平均流向阻力系数和流出虹吸射流的稀释度随着床层粗糙度的增加而增加。本文受版权保护。版权所有。</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;摘要&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;本研究使用涡分辨数值模拟来研究床粗糙度如何影响孤立的、部分埋藏的贻贝 (&lt;i>;Unio elongatulus&lt;/i>;) 周围的流动和湍流结构与传入流。粗糙床模拟解决了流过砾石床裸露部分的问题，其表面是从实验室实验中获得的，该实验还为验证数值模型提供了一些额外的数据。还讨论了水平光滑床的极限情况的结果。此外，通过一组模拟研究了改变贻贝在基质内的埋藏水平和通过两个贻贝虹吸管排放的影响，其中形成粗糙床的（砾石）颗粒的中值直径之间的比率， &lt;i>;d&lt;/i>; &lt;sub>;50&lt;/sub>;，贻贝暴露部分的高度&lt;i>;h&lt;/i>;在0.10和0.22之间变化。床层粗糙度的增加与近尾流区湍流动能的强烈放大有关。增加床粗糙度和/或减少 &lt;i>;h&lt;/i>; 加强了床颗粒产生的涡流与分别由主动过滤和贻贝壳引起的底部和尖端涡流的相互作用，这反过来又，导致这些涡流更快消散。增加床层粗糙度也会降低尾流中形成的主要下降流区域的强度。对称平面附近的强下降流是对称尾流脱落模式在光滑床模拟中占主导地位的主要原因，主动过滤可忽略不计。相比之下，反对称尾流脱落模式在以高床粗糙度值进行的模拟中占主导地位。壳层露出部分的平均流向阻力系数和流出虹吸射流的稀释度随床层粗糙度的增加而增加。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;本文受版权保护。保留所有权利。&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> T. Lazzarin、G. Constantinescu、L. Di Micco、H. Wu、F. Lavignani、M. Lo Brutto、D. Termini、DP Viero</dc:creator><category>研究文章</category><dc:title>床粗糙度对部分埋藏的孤立淡水贻贝周围流动和湍流结构的影响</dc:title><dc:identifier>10.1029/2022WR034151</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname>水资源研究</prism:publicationname><prism:doi>10.1029/2022WR034151</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR034151?af=R</prism:url><prism:section>研究文章</prism:section></item><item><link/>https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033673?af=R<pubDate> Fri, 14 Apr 2023 12:50:10 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-04-14T12:50:10-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley：水资源研究：目录<prism:coverdate></prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate></prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR033673</guid><title>在流域水质建模中吸收低成本高频传感器数据：贝叶斯方法</title><description>水资源研究，接受的文章。</description><dc:description>摘要 减少流域水质 (WWQ) 建模的不确定性仍然是一个主要挑战。一个重要的原因是缺乏足够的水质观测资料，因为传统的实验室水样分析具有很高的人力、财力和时间成本。来自原位传感器的低成本高频水质数据为解决这一问题提供了机会。然而，在复杂的自然环境中进行长期传感通常会出现更大的误差。本研究旨在开发一种在 WWQ 建模中利用原位传感器数据的新方法，即使用多源观测的贝叶斯校准 (BCMSO)，它可以同时吸收基于实验室的观测和原位传感器数据。硝酸盐模拟的合成案例和真实案例都被用来证明该方法，土壤和水评估工具 (SWAT) 被用作 WWQ 模型。结果表明，传统贝叶斯定标直接同化传感器数据在参数推断和模型模拟中会产生明显的偏差，从而导致对未来预测的偏差，影响管理决策的正确性。然而，在对传感器数据中的错误进行适当处理后，BCMSO 方法可以从传感器数据中提取有意义的信息并防止错误的负面影响。建模的不确定性也大大降低。在现实世界的案例中，结合了一年的亚小时电导率传感器数据，硝酸盐浓度的建模不确定性和控制硝酸盐污染的管理成本降低了 70%。 BCMSO 方法提供了一个灵活的框架来适应环境建模中的非常规观测，并且可以轻松扩展到其他建模领域。本文受版权保护。版权所有。</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;摘要&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;减少流域水质 (WWQ) 建模的不确定性仍然是一项重大挑战。一个重要的原因是缺乏足够的水质观测资料，因为传统的实验室水样分析具有很高的人力、财力和时间成本。来自原位传感器的低成本高频水质数据为解决这一问题提供了机会。然而，在复杂自然环境中的长期感知通常会出现更大的误差。本研究旨在开发一种在 WWQ 建模中利用原位传感器数据的新方法，即使用多源观测的贝叶斯校准 (BCMSO)，它可以同时吸收基于实验室的观测和原位传感器数据。硝酸盐模拟的合成案例和真实案例都被用来证明该方法，土壤和水评估工具 (SWAT) 被用作 WWQ 模型。结果表明，传统贝叶斯定标直接同化传感器数据在参数推断和模型模拟中会产生明显的偏差，从而导致对未来预测的偏差，影响管理决策的正确性。然而，在对传感器数据中的错误进行适当处理后，BCMSO 方法可以从传感器数据中提取有意义的信息并防止错误的负面影响。建模的不确定性也大大降低。在实际案例中，结合一年的亚小时电导率传感器数据，硝酸盐浓度的建模不确定性和控制硝酸盐污染的管理成本降低了 70%。 BCMSO 方法提供了一个灵活的框架来适应环境建模中的非常规观测，并且可以轻松扩展到其他建模领域。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;本文受版权保护。保留所有权利。&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator>韩峰，胡兆平，陈能旺，王耀，蒋继平，郑毅</dc:creator><category>研究文章</category><dc:title>在流域水质建模中吸收低成本高频传感器数据：贝叶斯方法</dc:title><dc:identifier>10.1029/2022WR033673</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname>水资源研究</prism:publicationname><prism:doi>10.1029/2022WR033673</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033673?af=R</prism:url><prism:section>研究文章</prism:section></item><item><link/>https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033566?af=R<pubDate> Fri, 14 Apr 2023 12:49:57 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-04-14T12:49:57-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley：水资源研究：目录<prism:coverdate></prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate></prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR033566</guid><title>植物蒸腾中的水龄动态：气候模式和生根深度的影响</title><description>水资源研究，接受的文章。</description><dc:description>摘要 植物蒸腾过程中的水龄揭示了土壤-植物-大气连续体中水分动态的重要过程，该过程受降水输入和根区水分变异性和可用性的调节。然而，气候模式和根系深度对蒸腾中水龄动态的影响研究不足。在这项研究中，根据降水和植物木质部水的稳定同位素组成估计了根区补水的变化，并采用分段线性混合水龄模型来量化五种不同气候下植物蒸腾过程中的水龄。结果表明，在 1 到 229 天之间的范围内，蒸腾中的水龄在所有气候中都非常动态。根区的水分补充揭示了降水是否以及有多少降水进入根区。气候模式控制植物蒸腾中的中值（平均）水龄，但受生根深度的影响。在潮湿气候下，植物主要依赖当月降水的水源（平均约占其水源的60%），而在干燥气候下，植物主要依赖前几个月降水的水源/季节。这些表明气候通过调节降水输入、根区储水和停留时间以及蒸散对植物水源产生深远影响。尽管本研究存在局限性，但我们的研究提供了另一种方法来揭示根区降水分配和植物降水用水的季节性变化，这突出了植被对气候类型之间水分变化的不同反应。本文受版权保护。版权所有。</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;摘要&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;植物蒸腾过程中的水分年龄揭示了土壤-植物-大气连续体中水分动态的重要过程，该过程受降水输入和根区水分变化和有效性的调节。然而，气候模式和根系深度对蒸腾中水龄动态的影响研究不足。在这项研究中，基于降水和植物木质部水的稳定同位素组成估计了根区补水的变化，并采用分段线性混合水龄模型来量化五种不同气候下植物蒸腾过程中的水龄。结果表明，在 1 到 229 天之间的范围内，蒸腾中的水龄在所有气候中都非常动态。根区的水分补充揭示了降水是否以及有多少降水进入根区。气候模式控制植物蒸腾中的中值（平均）水龄，但受生根深度的影响。在潮湿气候下，植物主要依赖当月降水的水源（平均约占其水源的60%），而在干燥气候下，植物主要依赖前几个月降水的水源/季节。这些表明气候通过调节降水输入、根区储水和停留时间以及蒸散对植物水源产生深远影响。尽管这项研究存在局限性，但我们的研究提供了一种替代方法来揭示根区降水分区和植物降水水分利用的季节性变化，这突出了植被对气候类型之间水分变化的不同响应。&lt;/p>; &lt;p >;本文受版权保护。保留所有权利。&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator>罗子东、聂云鹏、陈红松、管华德、张新平、王克林</dc:creator><category>研究文章</category><dc:title>植物蒸腾中的水龄动态：气候模式和生根深度的影响</dc:title><dc:identifier>10.1029/2022WR033566</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname>水资源研究</prism:publicationname><prism:doi>10.1029/2022WR033566</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033566?af=R</prism:url><prism:section>研究文章</prism:section></item><item><link/>https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033881?af=R<pubDate> Fri, 14 Apr 2023 12:49:08 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-04-14T12:49:08-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley：水资源研究：目录<prism:coverdate></prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate></prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR033881</guid><title>城市地表热力径流生成机制及情景模拟</title><description>水资源研究，接受的文章。</description><dc:description>摘要 夏季降水时，不透水地表的热径流流入城市湖泊，引起地表水温升高。这一过程最终导致富营养化湖泊中蓝藻大量繁殖的短期影响和湖泊物种结构和数量变化的长期影响。了解地表空气、下垫面和地表径流之间的热交换过程，揭示热径流形成机制具有重要的科学意义。在这项研究中，实施了土地、地表空气和地表水之间的传热模型，旨在量化实际条件下由地表热负荷引起的地表径流加热过程。结果表明，所建立的两个模型能够准确地模拟换热过程。基于我们的模型模拟和现场测量，我们分析了天气条件、水文条件和下垫面类型对径流温度的影响。研究发现，地表初始温度、风速、降雨强度、导热系数和下垫面透水率分别可以解释观测到的地表径流加热和温度上升速率差异的95.4%和91.9%。初始表面温度是热交换过程中最关键的因素。城市通风的减少会加剧地表径流的热效应。与下垫面透水面相比，不透水面是地表热径流污染形成的主要驱动力。本文受版权保护。版权所有。</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;摘要&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;夏季降水时，不透水地表的热径流流入城市湖泊，引起地表水温升高。这样的过程最终导致富营养化湖泊中蓝藻大量繁殖的短期影响和湖泊物种结构和数量变化的长期影响。了解地表空气、下垫面和地表径流之间的热交换过程，揭示热径流形成机制具有重要的科学意义。在这项研究中，实现了陆地、地表-空气和地表-水之间的传热模型，旨在量化实际条件下地表热负荷引起的地表径流的加热过程。结果表明，所建立的两个模型能够准确地模拟换热过程。基于我们的模型模拟和现场测量，我们分析了天气条件、水文条件和下垫面类型对径流温度的影响。研究发现，地表初始温度、风速、降雨强度、导热系数和下垫面透水率分别可以解释观测到的地表径流加热和温度上升速率差异的95.4%和91.9%。初始表面温度是热交换过程中最关键的因素。城市通风的减少会加剧地表径流的热效应。与下垫面透水面相比，不透水面是地表热径流污染形成的主要驱动力。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;本文受版权保护。保留所有权利。&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator>罗奕、张扬、杨坤、周晓璐、彭宗启</dc:creator><category>研究文章</category><dc:title>城市地表热力径流生成机制及情景模拟</dc:title><dc:identifier>10.1029/2022WR033881</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname>水资源研究</prism:publicationname><prism:doi>10.1029/2022WR033881</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033881?af=R</prism:url><prism:section>研究文章</prism:section></item><item><link/>https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033126?af=R<pubDate> Fri, 14 Apr 2023 12:49:06 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-04-14T12:49:06-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley：水资源研究：目录<prism:coverdate></prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate></prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR033126</guid><title>利用全球导航卫星系统和降水数据建立中国云南气象水文干旱的传播特征</title><description>水资源研究，接受的文章。</description><dc:description>摘要 分析气象水文干旱的时空特征和演变过程，可以再现干旱传播过程，有助于减轻干旱影响，改善水资源管理。虽然新兴研究试图基于前沿空间大地测量观测建立干旱严重度指数，但很少有人使用大地测量数据关注气象到水文干旱的传播特征。在本文中，我们利用全球导航卫星系统 (GNSS) 观测和降水数据，系统地研究了中国西南部云南省的干旱传播。首次确定2011年1月至2021年5月云南发生7次气象干旱和7次水文干旱，气象干旱主要集中在云南北部，持续时间为1～11个月。相比之下，水文干旱比气象干旱更严重，规模更大，持续时间为2-16个月。干旱传播期为2～7个月，西南短，东北长。水汽、降水和蓄水量呈时空分布不均匀的格局，以红河断层（RRF）为界，其相位差也呈现显着的区域差异，说明红河断层不仅影响水资源的空间变化但也影响干旱传播。</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;摘要&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;分析气象水文干旱的时空特征和演变过程，可以再现干旱传播过程，有助于减轻干旱影响，改善水资源管理。虽然新兴研究试图根据前沿空间大地测量观测建立干旱严重度指数，但很少有人使用大地测量数据关注气象到水文干旱的传播特征。在本文中，我们利用全球导航卫星系统 (GNSS) 观测和降水数据，系统地研究了中国西南部云南省的干旱传播。我们首先确定了2011年1月至2021年5月云南发生7次气象干旱和7次水文干旱，气象干旱主要集中在云南北部，持续时间为1-11个月。相比之下，水文干旱比气象干旱更严重，规模更大，持续时间为2-16个月。干旱传播期为2～7个月，西南短，东北长。水汽、降水和蓄水量呈时空分布不均匀的格局，以红河断层（RRF）为界，其相位差也呈现显着的区域差异，说明红河断层不仅影响水资源的空间变化但也会影响干旱传播。&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator>朱海，陈克杰，胡顺强，刘俊国，史海云，魏国光，柴海山，李家峰，王坦</dc:creator><category>研究文章</category><dc:title>利用全球导航卫星系统和降水数据建立中国云南气象水文干旱的传播特征</dc:title><dc:identifier>10.1029/2022WR033126</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname>水资源研究</prism:publicationname><prism:doi>10.1029/2022WR033126</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033126?af=R</prism:url><prism:section>研究文章</prism:section></item><item><link/>https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR032741?af=R<pubDate> Fri, 14 Apr 2023 12:43:28 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-04-14T12:43:28-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley：水资源研究：目录<prism:coverdate></prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate></prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR032741</guid><title>工程河流分叉区域对峰值流量和人为干预的半百年响应</title><description>水资源研究，接受的文章。</description><dc:description> Abstract A bifurcation in an engineered river system (ie, fixed planform and width) has fewer degrees of freedom in its response to interventions and natural changes than a natural bifurcation system. Our objective is to provide insight into how a bifurcation in an engineered river responds to peak flows and human interventions. To this end, we analyze the change in hydraulics, bed level, and bed surface grain size in the region of two bifurcations in the upper Rhine delta in the Netherlands over the last century. We show that, over the last two decades, the water discharge in one bifurcate (the Waal branch) has steadily increased at the expense of the other. This gradual increase in the water discharge of the first branch is associated with its erosion rate being larger than the other branch. The quick succession of two or three peak flow events (1993, 1995, 1998) caused rapid sediment deposition over the upstream part of the bifurcate that has gradually lost discharge, which seems to have triggered the slow change in flow partitioning.</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;A bifurcation in an engineered river system (ie, fixed planform and width) has fewer degrees of freedom in its response to interventions and natural changes than a natural bifurcation system. Our objective is to provide insight into how a bifurcation in an engineered river responds to peak flows and human interventions. To this end, we analyze the change in hydraulics, bed level, and bed surface grain size in the region of two bifurcations in the upper Rhine delta in the Netherlands over the last century. We show that, over the last two decades, the water discharge in one bifurcate (the Waal branch) has steadily increased at the expense of the other. This gradual increase in the water discharge of the first branch is associated with its erosion rate being larger than the other branch. The quick succession of two or three peak flow events (1993, 1995, 1998) caused rapid sediment deposition over the upstream part of the bifurcate that has gradually lost discharge, which seems to have triggered the slow change in flow partitioning.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> M. Kifayath Chowdhury, Astrid Blom, Clàudia Ylla Arbós, Merel C. Verbeek, Max HI Schropp, Ralph MJ Schielen</dc:creator><category> Research Article</category><dc:title> Semicentennial Response of a Bifurcation Region in an Engineered River to Peak Flows and Human Interventions</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2022WR032741</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1029/2022WR032741</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR032741?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> Research Article</prism:section></item><item><link/> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033305?af=R<pubDate> Fri, 14 Apr 2023 12:43:02 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-04-14T12:43:02-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley: Water Resources Research: Table of Contents <prism:coverdate></prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate></prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR033305</guid><title> Hydroclimate Drives Seasonal Riverine Export Across a Gradient of Glacierized High‐Latitude Coastal Catchments</title><description> Water Resources Research, Accepted Article.</description><dc:description> Abstract Glacierized coastal catchments of the Gulf of Alaska are undergoing rapid hydrologic fluctuations in response to climate change. These catchments deliver dissolved and suspended inorganic and organic matter to nearshore marine environments, however, these glacierized coastal catchments are relatively understudied and little is known about total solute and particulate fluxes to the ocean. We present hydrologic, physical, and geochemical data collected during April‐October 2019‐2021 from 10 streams along gradients of glacial fed to non‐glacial (ie, precipitation) fed, in one Southcentral and one Southeast Alaska region. Hydrologic data reveal that glaciers drive the seasonal runoff patterns. The ẟ18O signature and specific conductance show distinctive seasonal variations in stream water sources between the study regions apparently due to the large amounts of rain in Southeast Alaska. Total dissolved solids concentrations and yields were elevated in the Southcentral region, due to lithologic influence on dissolved loads, however, the hydroclimate is the primary driver of the timing of dissolved and suspended yields. We show the yields of dissolved organic carbon is higher and that the δ13CPOC is enriched in the Southeast streams illustrating contrasts in organic carbon export across the Gulf of Alaska. Finally, we illustrate how future yields of solutes and sediments to the Gulf of Alaska may change as watersheds evolve from glacial influenced to precipitation dominated. This integrated analysis provides insights into how watershed characteristics beyond glacier coverage control properties of freshwater inputs to the Gulf of Alaska and the importance of expanding study regions to multiple hydroclimate regimes. This article is protected by copyright. All rights reserved.</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;Glacierized coastal catchments of the Gulf of Alaska are undergoing rapid hydrologic fluctuations in response to climate change. These catchments deliver dissolved and suspended inorganic and organic matter to nearshore marine environments, however, these glacierized coastal catchments are relatively understudied and little is known about total solute and particulate fluxes to the ocean. We present hydrologic, physical, and geochemical data collected during April-October 2019-2021 from 10 streams along gradients of glacial fed to non-glacial (ie, precipitation) fed, in one Southcentral and one Southeast Alaska region. Hydrologic data reveal that glaciers drive the seasonal runoff patterns. The ẟ&lt;sup>;18&lt;/sup>;O signature and specific conductance show distinctive seasonal variations in stream water sources between the study regions apparently due to the large amounts of rain in Southeast Alaska. Total dissolved solids concentrations and yields were elevated in the Southcentral region, due to lithologic influence on dissolved loads, however, the hydroclimate is the primary driver of the timing of dissolved and suspended yields. We show the yields of dissolved organic carbon is higher and that the δ&lt;sup>;13&lt;/sup>;C&lt;sub>;POC&lt;/sub>; is enriched in the Southeast streams illustrating contrasts in organic carbon export across the Gulf of Alaska. Finally, we illustrate how future yields of solutes and sediments to the Gulf of Alaska may change as watersheds evolve from glacial influenced to precipitation dominated. This integrated analysis provides insights into how watershed characteristics beyond glacier coverage control properties of freshwater inputs to the Gulf of Alaska and the importance of expanding study regions to multiple hydroclimate regimes.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This article is protected by copyright. All rights reserved.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> J. Jenckes, LA Munk, DE Ibarra, DF Boutt, J. Fellman, E. Hood</dc:creator><category> Research Article</category><dc:title> Hydroclimate Drives Seasonal Riverine Export Across a Gradient of Glacierized High‐Latitude Coastal Catchments</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2022WR033305</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1029/2022WR033305</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033305?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> Research Article</prism:section></item><item><link/> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033646?af=R<pubDate> Thu, 13 Apr 2023 08:09:48 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-04-13T08:09:48-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley: Water Resources Research: Table of Contents<prism:coverdate> Sat, 01 Apr 2023 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate> Sat, 01 Apr 2023 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR033646</guid><title> Review of Quantitative Applications of the Concept of the Water Planetary Boundary at Different Spatial Scales</title><description> Water Resources Research, Volume 59, Issue 4, April 2023.</description><dc:description> Abstract The water planetary boundary (PB) quantifies a safe operating space for human water consumption and is understood as a control‐variable set at a safe distance from a selected threshold (or dangerous level) based on precautionary principles. The water PB is useful for guiding sustainable development, and various multiscale quantitative assessments of water PB have been conducted. To improve our understanding and guide future applications, we conduct a comprehensive review of all studies published since the concept&#39;s introduction. We identify a total of 288 relevant papers in the literature and perform a systematic review and meta‐analysis of 28 papers providing 488 data records at various spatial scales. The analyses mainly involve the relevant quantification indicators, quantification methods, comparisons of the water PB with the current state of water consumption at different scales, and the identification of associated problems. Finally, we propose 10 outlooks for important future research. This review indicates that the theoretical water‐PB framework, as an early‐stage research area, has gradually developed, despite the few, imperfect available methods. To address the limitations of previous studies, we propose two improvement frameworks for guiding future research: the further improvement of traditional popular approaches to quantifying the multiscale water PB within a consistent scientific framework and an improved framework for quantifying the water PB at various scales to obtain better‐fitting results for different research purposes and study areas. Based on this review, we point out some important issues that have received little attention, including the quantification of safe distances and the linkages between multiscale water PBs.</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;The water planetary boundary (PB) quantifies a safe operating space for human water consumption and is understood as a control-variable set at a safe distance from a selected threshold (or dangerous level) based on precautionary principles. The water PB is useful for guiding sustainable development, and various multiscale quantitative assessments of water PB have been conducted. To improve our understanding and guide future applications, we conduct a comprehensive review of all studies published since the concept&#39;s introduction. We identify a total of 288 relevant papers in the literature and perform a systematic review and meta-analysis of 28 papers providing 488 data records at various spatial scales. The analyses mainly involve the relevant quantification indicators, quantification methods, comparisons of the water PB with the current state of water consumption at different scales, and the identification of associated problems. Finally, we propose 10 outlooks for important future research. This review indicates that the theoretical water-PB framework, as an early-stage research area, has gradually developed, despite the few, imperfect available methods. To address the limitations of previous studies, we propose two improvement frameworks for guiding future research: the further improvement of traditional popular approaches to quantifying the multiscale water PB within a consistent scientific framework and an improved framework for quantifying the water PB at various scales to obtain better-fitting results for different research purposes and study areas. Based on this review, we point out some important issues that have received little attention, including the quantification of safe distances and the linkages between multiscale water PBs.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> Siqi Han, Guoyong Leng, Linfei Yu</dc:creator><category> Review Article</category><dc:title> Review of Quantitative Applications of the Concept of the Water Planetary Boundary at Different Spatial Scales</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2022WR033646</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1029/2022WR033646</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033646?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> Review Article</prism:section><prism:volume> 59</prism:volume><prism:number> 4</prism:number></item><item><link/> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033584?af=R<pubDate> Thu, 13 Apr 2023 08:05:18 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-04-13T08:05:18-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley: Water Resources Research: Table of Contents<prism:coverdate> Sat, 01 Apr 2023 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate> Sat, 01 Apr 2023 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR033584</guid><title> A Portable Device for On‐Site Measurement of Sediment Concentration Through Volume‐Mass Replacement</title><description> Water Resources Research, Volume 59, Issue 4, April 2023.</description><dc:description> Abstract To enable on‐site and near‐real‐time sediment concentration measurements, a novel type of portable device with a constant volume sampling bottle was developed in this study. The device consisted of a sampling bottle, a measuring assembly, and a platform for auxiliary data management. Five representative soils and eight sediment concentrations were used to validate the device accuracy and application. Moreover, a novel concept of sediment effective density (SED) was proposed. Under SED, a linear regression was fit between the measured and actual sediment concentrations. The results revealed that the slopes of the fitting line were close to 1, and the R2 values were greater than 0.999 for five soils. Moreover, for total samples, the root mean square error (RMSE) and Nash–Sutcliffe efficiency coefficient (NSE) values were 5.59 g/L and 0.9996, respectively. Additionally, an average SED of 2.51 g/cm3 was calculated in this study. With an average soil SED of 2.51 g/cm3 and an average soil solid density of 2.65 g/cm3, the RMSE and NSE were 11.85 and 18.50 g/L and 0.9981 and 0.9954, respectively. This result demonstrated that the designed device accurately measured sediment concentration under various conditions. Furthermore, relative to the traditional oven‐drying method, the device could measure sediment concentration near‐real‐time and with high accuracy, which could be useful for researchers with excellent potential. It was recommended to measure the SED in a laboratory or runoff plot because the sediment sources could be identified and obtained. In a field or river, it was recommended to use 2.51 g/cm3 as the SED, which was more accurate than 2.65 g/cm3.</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;To enable on-site and near-real-time sediment concentration measurements, a novel type of portable device with a constant volume sampling bottle was developed in this study. The device consisted of a sampling bottle, a measuring assembly, and a platform for auxiliary data management. Five representative soils and eight sediment concentrations were used to validate the device accuracy and application. Moreover, a novel concept of sediment effective density (SED) was proposed. Under SED, a linear regression was fit between the measured and actual sediment concentrations. The results revealed that the slopes of the fitting line were close to 1, and the R&lt;sup>;2&lt;/sup>; values were greater than 0.999 for five soils. Moreover, for total samples, the root mean square error (RMSE) and Nash–Sutcliffe efficiency coefficient (NSE) values were 5.59 g/L and 0.9996, respectively. Additionally, an average SED of 2.51 g/cm&lt;sup>;3&lt;/sup>; was calculated in this study. With an average soil SED of 2.51 g/cm&lt;sup>;3&lt;/sup>; and an average soil solid density of 2.65 g/cm&lt;sup>;3&lt;/sup>;, the RMSE and NSE were 11.85 and 18.50 g/L and 0.9981 and 0.9954, respectively. This result demonstrated that the designed device accurately measured sediment concentration under various conditions. Furthermore, relative to the traditional oven-drying method, the device could measure sediment concentration near-real-time and with high accuracy, which could be useful for researchers with excellent potential. It was recommended to measure the SED in a laboratory or runoff plot because the sediment sources could be identified and obtained. In a field or river, it was recommended to use 2.51 g/cm&lt;sup>;3&lt;/sup>; as the SED, which was more accurate than 2.65 g/cm&lt;sup>;3&lt;/sup>;.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> Qiuxing Yue, Xiaoyun Zhan, Minghang Guo, Jun Zhao, Baoyuan Liu</dc:creator><category> Method</category><dc:title> A Portable Device for On‐Site Measurement of Sediment Concentration Through Volume‐Mass Replacement</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2022WR033584</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1029/2022WR033584</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033584?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> Method</prism:section><prism:volume> 59</prism:volume><prism:number> 4</prism:number></item><item><link/> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR032578?af=R<pubDate> Thu, 13 Apr 2023 08:01:20 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-04-13T08:01:20-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley: Water Resources Research: Table of Contents<prism:coverdate> Sat, 01 Apr 2023 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate> Sat, 01 Apr 2023 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR032578</guid><title> Subsurface Porewater Flow Accelerates Talik Development Under the Alaska Highway, Yukon: A Prelude to Road Collapse and Final Permafrost Thaw?</title><description> Water Resources Research, Volume 59, Issue 4, April 2023.</description><dc:description> Abstract The presence of taliks (perennially unfrozen zones in permafrost areas) adversely affects the thermal stability of infrastructure in cold regions, including roads. The role of heat advection on talik development and feedback on permafrost degradation has not been quantified methodically in this context. We incorporate a surface energy balance model into a coupled groundwater flow and energy transport numerical model (SUTRA‐ice). The model, calibrated with long‐term observations (1997–2018 on the Alaska Highway), is used to investigate and quantify the role of heat advection on talik initiation and development under a road embankment. Over the 25‐year simulation period, the new model is driven by reconstructed meteorological data and has a good agreement with near surface soil temperatures. The model successfully reproduces the increasing depth to the permafrost table (mean absolute error &lt;0.2 m), and talik development. The results demonstrate that heat advection provides an additional energy source that expedites the rate of permafrost thaw and roughly doubles the rate of permafrost table deepening, compared to purely conductive thawing. Talik initially formed and grew over time under the combined effect of water flow, snow insulation, road construction and climate warming. Talik formation creates a new thermal state under the road embankment, resulting in acceleration of underlying permafrost degradation, due to the positive feedback of heat accumulation created by trapped unfrozen water. In a changing climate, mobile water flow will play a more important role in permafrost thaw and talik development under road embankments, and is likely to significantly increase maintenance costs and reduce the long‐term stability of the infrastructure.</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;The presence of taliks (perennially unfrozen zones in permafrost areas) adversely affects the thermal stability of infrastructure in cold regions, including roads. The role of heat advection on talik development and feedback on permafrost degradation has not been quantified methodically in this context. We incorporate a surface energy balance model into a coupled groundwater flow and energy transport numerical model (SUTRA-ice). The model, calibrated with long-term observations (1997–2018 on the Alaska Highway), is used to investigate and quantify the role of heat advection on talik initiation and development under a road embankment. Over the 25-year simulation period, the new model is driven by reconstructed meteorological data and has a good agreement with near surface soil temperatures. The model successfully reproduces the increasing depth to the permafrost table (mean absolute error &amp;lt;0.2 m), and talik development. The results demonstrate that heat advection provides an additional energy source that expedites the rate of permafrost thaw and roughly doubles the rate of permafrost table deepening, compared to purely conductive thawing. Talik initially formed and grew over time under the combined effect of water flow, snow insulation, road construction and climate warming. Talik formation creates a new thermal state under the road embankment, resulting in acceleration of underlying permafrost degradation, due to the positive feedback of heat accumulation created by trapped unfrozen water. In a changing climate, mobile water flow will play a more important role in permafrost thaw and talik development under road embankments, and is likely to significantly increase maintenance costs and reduce the long-term stability of the infrastructure.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> Lin Chen, Daniel Fortier, Jeffrey M. McKenzie, Clifford I. Voss, Pierrick Lamontagne‐Hallé</dc:creator><category> Research Article</category><dc:title> Subsurface Porewater Flow Accelerates Talik Development Under the Alaska Highway, Yukon: A Prelude to Road Collapse and Final Permafrost Thaw?</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2022WR032578</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1029/2022WR032578</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR032578?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> Research Article</prism:section><prism:volume> 59</prism:volume><prism:number> 4</prism:number></item><item><link/> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR032529?af=R<pubDate> Wed, 12 Apr 2023 13:20:06 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-04-12T01:20:06-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley: Water Resources Research: Table of Contents<prism:coverdate> Sat, 01 Apr 2023 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate> Sat, 01 Apr 2023 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR032529</guid><title> The Role of Inflow and Infiltration (I/I) in Urban Water Balances and Streamflow Regimes: A Hydrograph Analysis Along the Sewershed‐Watershed Continuum</title><description> Water Resources Research, Volume 59, Issue 4, April 2023.</description><dc:description> Abstract Urbanization alters subsurface flow pathways through expansion of sanitary collection and conveyance infrastructure. Inflow and infiltration (I/I) into sewers redistributes slow subsurface flows to fast within‐sewer flows. Acting in concert with connected surface water, redistribution through I/I complicates the net impact of urbanization on streamflow. Elucidation of these processes is key to the characterization and prediction of urban hydrologic cycles. In this study, we collected sanitary sewer flow and streamflow data from 17 sewersheds and 18 watersheds in and around Milwaukee, WI, USA. We compared flow duration curves and baseflow recession characteristics of I/I and streamflow in urban and reference watersheds. Median depth‐normalized I/I (296 mm) was nearly 35% of mean annual precipitation (867 mm), and thereby a major component of the urban drainage budget. I/I flowrates were similar to urban streamflow during high flow events (10th percentile) and larger during intermediate (50th percentile) and low (90th percentile) flow events. Further, I/I recession was slower and more nonlinear in shape than urban streamflow. Increased imperviousness and sewer density were associated with increased high flows, decreased intermediate flows, and quicker streamflow recessions. Sewer density explained more variability in intermediate flows (35%) and baseflow recession rate (49%) than imperviousness (24% and 19% respectively). Based on our findings, I/I takes up valuable volume capacity in sewers, which leads to more frequent overflows and alters streamflow regimes with ecological implications. Thus, I/I should be better considered in the prediction of urban hydrologic fluxes, and the characteristics and hydro‐ecologic impact of I/I should be more thoroughly explored.</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;Urbanization alters subsurface flow pathways through expansion of sanitary collection and conveyance infrastructure. Inflow and infiltration (I/I) into sewers redistributes slow subsurface flows to fast within-sewer flows. Acting in concert with connected surface water, redistribution through I/I complicates the net impact of urbanization on streamflow. Elucidation of these processes is key to the characterization and prediction of urban hydrologic cycles. In this study, we collected sanitary sewer flow and streamflow data from 17 sewersheds and 18 watersheds in and around Milwaukee, WI, USA. We compared flow duration curves and baseflow recession characteristics of I/I and streamflow in urban and reference watersheds. Median depth-normalized I/I (296 mm) was nearly 35% of mean annual precipitation (867 mm), and thereby a major component of the urban drainage budget. I/I flowrates were similar to urban streamflow during high flow events (10th percentile) and larger during intermediate (50th percentile) and low (90th percentile) flow events. Further, I/I recession was slower and more nonlinear in shape than urban streamflow. Increased imperviousness and sewer density were associated with increased high flows, decreased intermediate flows, and quicker streamflow recessions. Sewer density explained more variability in intermediate flows (35%) and baseflow recession rate (49%) than imperviousness (24% and 19% respectively). Based on our findings, I/I takes up valuable volume capacity in sewers, which leads to more frequent overflows and alters streamflow regimes with ecological implications. Thus, I/I should be better considered in the prediction of urban hydrologic fluxes, and the characteristics and hydro-ecologic impact of I/I should be more thoroughly explored.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> Kun Zhang, Spencer Sebo, Walter McDonald, Aditi Bhaskar, William Shuster, Ryan D. Stewart, Anthony J. Parolari</dc:creator><category> Research Article</category><dc:title> The Role of Inflow and Infiltration (I/I) in Urban Water Balances and Streamflow Regimes: A Hydrograph Analysis Along the Sewershed‐Watershed Continuum</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2022WR032529</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1029/2022WR032529</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR032529?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> Research Article</prism:section><prism:volume> 59</prism:volume><prism:number> 4</prism:number></item><item><link/> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033831?af=R<pubDate> Wed, 12 Apr 2023 13:14:57 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-04-12T01:14:57-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley: Water Resources Research: Table of Contents<prism:coverdate> Sat, 01 Apr 2023 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate> Sat, 01 Apr 2023 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR033831</guid><title> A Short‐Term Pumping Strategy for Hydraulic Tomography Based on the Successive Linear Estimator</title><description> Water Resources Research, Volume 59, Issue 4, April 2023.</description><dc:description> Abstract In this study, the random finite element method, a finite element method with random field generation techniques, was applied to investigate the cross correlations between the observed head and hydraulic conductivity and specific storage at different locations and different times in pumping tests. The results show that the two cross correlations between the pumping well and the observation well reach their maximums before pumping reaches a steady state. Specifically, the cross correlation between the observed head and hydraulic conductivity is the greatest when the temporal derivative of the observed head does not change significantly, and that between the observed head and specific storage is the greatest when the temporal derivative (the rate) of the observed head is maximum. Based on the results of cross‐correlation analysis, a short‐term pumping strategy for hydraulic tomography is proposed to obtain the spatial distribution of hydraulic conductivity and specific storage using the successive linear estimator. Furthermore, this strategy was validated by Monte Carlo simulations. This paper points out that the sensitivity and cross‐correlation analyses report the ensemble (averaged) behaviors of any heterogeneous aquifers, which is not necessarily suitable for one realization. Furthermore, Monte Carlo simulation is suggested for validating any groundwater inverse modeling result.</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;In this study, the random finite element method, a finite element method with random field generation techniques, was applied to investigate the cross correlations between the observed head and hydraulic conductivity and specific storage at different locations and different times in pumping tests. The results show that the two cross correlations between the pumping well and the observation well reach their maximums before pumping reaches a steady state. Specifically, the cross correlation between the observed head and hydraulic conductivity is the greatest when the temporal derivative of the observed head does not change significantly, and that between the observed head and specific storage is the greatest when the temporal derivative (the rate) of the observed head is maximum. Based on the results of cross-correlation analysis, a short-term pumping strategy for hydraulic tomography is proposed to obtain the spatial distribution of hydraulic conductivity and specific storage using the successive linear estimator. Furthermore, this strategy was validated by Monte Carlo simulations. This paper points out that the sensitivity and cross-correlation analyses report the ensemble (averaged) behaviors of any heterogeneous aquifers, which is not necessarily suitable for one realization. Furthermore, Monte Carlo simulation is suggested for validating any groundwater inverse modeling result.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> Xiaolan Hou, Rui Hu, Tian‐Chyi Jim Yeh, Yukun Li, Junjie Qi, Yang Song, Huiyang Qiu</dc:creator><category> Research Article</category><dc:title> A Short‐Term Pumping Strategy for Hydraulic Tomography Based on the Successive Linear Estimator</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2022WR033831</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1029/2022WR033831</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033831?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> Research Article</prism:section><prism:volume> 59</prism:volume><prism:number> 4</prism:number></item><item><link/> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR034305?af=R<pubDate> Wed, 12 Apr 2023 13:14:14 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-04-12T01:14:14-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley: Water Resources Research: Table of Contents<prism:coverdate> Sat, 01 Apr 2023 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate> Sat, 01 Apr 2023 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR034305</guid><title> Spatiotemporal Variability of Current and Future Sub‐Daily Rainfall in Japan Using State‐Of‐The‐Art High‐Quality Data Sets</title><description> Water Resources Research, Volume 59, Issue 4, April 2023.</description><dc:description> Abstract Using potentially best available rainfall data sets for the entire country of Japan (spatial scales of 1‐ and 20‐km), we analyze the 1–24 hr and city‐scale (1–400 km2) extreme rainfalls for both current (2006–2020) and future periods (2081–2109) at 1.5 K global warming scenario, complementing previous work that focuses on either coarse spatial and temporal scales or other warming scenarios (eg, RCP and 2 K warming scenarios). A peak‐over‐threshold (POT)‐based approach is applied to compute areal reduction factor (ARF) for subsequently establishing intensity‐duration‐area‐frequency (IDAF) curves. Our results reveal that ARF values generally decrease with increasing area size and increase with longer duration and are affected by multiple underlying physical phenomena. Moreover, we find a greater increase in the rainfall intensities for shorter durations and higher return periods, ranging from 9.4% (1‐hr) to 6.2% (24‐hr), averaged for all return periods and 8.3% (25‐year) to 7.3% (2‐year), averaged for all rainfall durations. Spatially, extreme rainfall intensities are projected to increase by 8.9% in northern Japan (albeit with a less intense rainfall intensity in the current period), which is greater than the rest of the country (6.8%), underscoring the need to focus more on infrastructure designs in northern Japan. The projected IDAF curves further display an increase in the frequency of extreme events at city‐scale, for example, 25‐year extreme rainfall events in 2006–2020 would likely be 5‐10‐year events in 2081–2109. Our results with the state‐of‐the‐art data and implementable approach can be utilized for policymaking to reduce the warming‐induced risks in Japan and beyond.</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;Using potentially best available rainfall data sets for the entire country of Japan (spatial scales of 1- and 20-km), we analyze the 1–24 hr and city-scale (1–400 km&lt;sup>;2&lt;/sup>;) extreme rainfalls for both current (2006–2020) and future periods (2081–2109) at 1.5 K global warming scenario, complementing previous work that focuses on either coarse spatial and temporal scales or other warming scenarios (eg, RCP and 2 K warming scenarios). A peak-over-threshold (POT)-based approach is applied to compute areal reduction factor (ARF) for subsequently establishing intensity-duration-area-frequency (IDAF) curves. Our results reveal that ARF values generally decrease with increasing area size and increase with longer duration and are affected by multiple underlying physical phenomena. Moreover, we find a greater increase in the rainfall intensities for shorter durations and higher return periods, ranging from 9.4% (1-hr) to 6.2% (24-hr), averaged for all return periods and 8.3% (25-year) to 7.3% (2-year), averaged for all rainfall durations. Spatially, extreme rainfall intensities are projected to increase by 8.9% in northern Japan (albeit with a less intense rainfall intensity in the current period), which is greater than the rest of the country (6.8%), underscoring the need to focus more on infrastructure designs in northern Japan. The projected IDAF curves further display an increase in the frequency of extreme events at city-scale, for example, 25-year extreme rainfall events in 2006–2020 would likely be 5-10-year events in 2081–2109. Our results with the state-of-the-art data and implementable approach can be utilized for policymaking to reduce the warming-induced risks in Japan and beyond.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> Wenpeng Zhao, Abhishek, Bijoychandra S. Takhellambam, Jiantao Zhang, Yakun Zhao, Tsuyoshi Kinouchi</dc:creator><category> Research Article</category><dc:title> Spatiotemporal Variability of Current and Future Sub‐Daily Rainfall in Japan Using State‐Of‐The‐Art High‐Quality Data Sets</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2022WR034305</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1029/2022WR034305</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR034305?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> Research Article</prism:section><prism:volume> 59</prism:volume><prism:number> 4</prism:number></item><item><link/> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033342?af=R<pubDate> Tue, 11 Apr 2023 13:07:46 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-04-11T01:07:46-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley: Water Resources Research: Table of Contents<prism:coverdate> Sat, 01 Apr 2023 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate> Sat, 01 Apr 2023 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR033342</guid><title> Is It Possible to Quantify Irrigation Water‐Use by Assimilating a High‐Resolution Satellite Soil Moisture Product?</title><description> Water Resources Research, Volume 59, Issue 4, April 2023.</description><dc:description> Abstract Irrigation is the largest human intervention in the water cycle that can modulate climate extremes, yet irrigation water use (IWU) remains largely unknown in most regions. Microwave remote sensing offers a practical way to quantify IWU by monitoring changes in soil moisture caused by irrigation. However, high‐resolution satellite soil moisture data is typically infrequent (eg, 6–12 days) and thus may miss irrigation events. This study evaluates the ability to quantify IWU by assimilating high‐resolution (1 km) SMAP‐Sentinel 1 remotely sensed soil moisture with a physically based land surface model (LSM) using a particle batch smoother (PBS). A suite of synthetic experiments is devised to evaluate different error sources. Results from the synthetic experiments show that unbiased simulations with known irrigation timing can produce an accurate irrigation estimate with a mean annual bias of 0.45% and a mean R2 of 0.97, relative to observed IWU. Unknown irrigation timing can significantly deteriorate the model performance, resulting in an increased mean annual bias to 23% and decreased mean R2 to 0.36. Adding random noise to synthetic observations does not significantly decrease model performance except for the experiments with low observation frequency (>;12 days). In real‐world experiments, the PBS data assimilation approach underestimates observed IWU by 18.6% when the timing of IWU is known. IWU estimates are consistently significantly higher over irrigated pixels compared to the non‐irrigated pixels, indicating data assimilation skillfully conveys irrigation signals to the LSM.</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;Irrigation is the largest human intervention in the water cycle that can modulate climate extremes, yet irrigation water use (IWU) remains largely unknown in most regions. Microwave remote sensing offers a practical way to quantify IWU by monitoring changes in soil moisture caused by irrigation. However, high-resolution satellite soil moisture data is typically infrequent (eg, 6–12 days) and thus may miss irrigation events. This study evaluates the ability to quantify IWU by assimilating high-resolution (1 km) SMAP-Sentinel 1 remotely sensed soil moisture with a physically based land surface model (LSM) using a particle batch smoother (PBS). A suite of synthetic experiments is devised to evaluate different error sources. Results from the synthetic experiments show that unbiased simulations with known irrigation timing can produce an accurate irrigation estimate with a mean annual bias of 0.45% and a mean &lt;i>;R&lt;/i>; &lt;sup>;2&lt;/sup>; of 0.97, relative to observed IWU. Unknown irrigation timing can significantly deteriorate the model performance, resulting in an increased mean annual bias to 23% and decreased mean &lt;i>;R&lt;/i>; &lt;sup>;2&lt;/sup>; to 0.36. Adding random noise to synthetic observations does not significantly decrease model performance except for the experiments with low observation frequency (&amp;gt;12 days). In real-world experiments, the PBS data assimilation approach underestimates observed IWU by 18.6% when the timing of IWU is known. IWU estimates are consistently significantly higher over irrigated pixels compared to the non-irrigated pixels, indicating data assimilation skillfully conveys irrigation signals to the LSM.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> Ehsan Jalilvand, Ronnie Abolafia‐Rosenzweig, Masoud Tajrishy, Sujay V. Kumar, Mohammad Reza Mohammadi, Narendra N. Das</dc:creator><category> Research Article</category><dc:title> Is It Possible to Quantify Irrigation Water‐Use by Assimilating a High‐Resolution Satellite Soil Moisture Product?</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2022WR033342</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1029/2022WR033342</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033342?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> Research Article</prism:section><prism:volume> 59</prism:volume><prism:number> 4</prism:number></item><item><link/> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033912?af=R<pubDate> Tue, 11 Apr 2023 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-04-11T12:00:00-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley: Water Resources Research: Table of Contents<prism:coverdate> Sat, 01 Apr 2023 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate> Sat, 01 Apr 2023 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR033912</guid><title> Paired Air and Stream Temperature Analysis (PASTA) to Evaluate Groundwater Influence on Streams</title><description> Water Resources Research, Volume 59, Issue 4, April 2023.</description><dc:description> Abstract Groundwater is critical for maintaining stream baseflow and thermal stability; however, the influence of groundwater on streamflow has been difficult to evaluate at broad spatial scales. Techniques such as baseflow separation necessitate streamflow records and do not directly indicate whether groundwater inflow may be sourced from more dynamic shallow flowpaths. We present a web tool application PASTA (Paired Air and Stream Temperature Analysis; https://cuahsi.shinyapps.io/pasta/) that capitalizes on increased public stream temperature data availability and large‐scale, gridded climate observations to provide new and efficient insights regarding relative groundwater influence on streams. PASTA analyzes paired air and stream water temperature signals to evaluate spatiotemporal patterns in stream thermal sensitivity and relative groundwater influence, including inference regarding the dominant source groundwater depth (shallow or deep (ie, approximately >;6 m depth)). The tool is linked to publicly available stream temperature datasets and accepts user‐uploaded datasets. As local air temperature is not often monitored, PASTA pulls daily air temperature data from the comprehensive Daymet products when directly measured data are unavailable, allowing the repurposing of existing stream temperature data. After data are selected or uploaded, the tool (a) fits sinusoidal curves of daily stream and air temperatures by year (water or calendar) to indicate groundwater influence characteristics and (b) performs linear regressions for stream versus air temperatures to indicate stream thermal sensitivity. Results are exported in ASCII file format, creating an efficient and approachable analysis tool for the adoption of newly developed heat tracing analysis from stream reach to landscape scales.</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;Groundwater is critical for maintaining stream baseflow and thermal stability; however, the influence of groundwater on streamflow has been difficult to evaluate at broad spatial scales. Techniques such as baseflow separation necessitate streamflow records and do not directly indicate whether groundwater inflow may be sourced from more dynamic shallow flowpaths. We present a web tool application &lt;i>;PASTA&lt;/i>; (Paired Air and Stream Temperature Analysis; &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;Link to external resource&quot; href=&quot;https://cuahsi.shinyapps.io/pasta/&quot;>;https://cuahsi.shinyapps.io/pasta/&lt;/a>;) that capitalizes on increased public stream temperature data availability and large-scale, gridded climate observations to provide new and efficient insights regarding relative groundwater influence on streams. &lt;i>;PASTA&lt;/i>; analyzes paired air and stream water temperature signals to evaluate spatiotemporal patterns in stream thermal sensitivity and relative groundwater influence, including inference regarding the dominant source groundwater depth (shallow or deep (ie, approximately &amp;gt;6 m depth)). The tool is linked to publicly available stream temperature datasets and accepts user-uploaded datasets. As local air temperature is not often monitored, PASTA pulls daily air temperature data from the comprehensive Daymet products when directly measured data are unavailable, allowing the repurposing of existing stream temperature data. After data are selected or uploaded, the tool (a) fits sinusoidal curves of daily stream and air temperatures by year (water or calendar) to indicate groundwater influence characteristics and (b) performs linear regressions for stream versus air temperatures to indicate stream thermal sensitivity. Results are exported in ASCII file format, creating an efficient and approachable analysis tool for the adoption of newly developed heat tracing analysis from stream reach to landscape scales.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> Danielle K. Hare, Susanne A. Benz, Barret L. Kurylyk, Zachary C. Johnson, Neil C. Terry, Ashley M. Helton</dc:creator><category> Method</category><dc:title> Paired Air and Stream Temperature Analysis (PASTA) to Evaluate Groundwater Influence on Streams</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2022WR033912</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1029/2022WR033912</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033912?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> Method</prism:section><prism:volume> 59</prism:volume><prism:number> 4</prism:number></item><item><link/> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033677?af=R<pubDate> Mon, 10 Apr 2023 11:56:08 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-04-10T11:56:08-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley: Water Resources Research: Table of Contents <prism:coverdate></prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate></prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR033677</guid><title> Tracing the soil water flux in variably saturated zones using temperature data</title><description> Water Resources Research, Accepted Article.</description><dc:description> Abstract The coexistence of water, vapor, and solid phases and the spatiotemporal changes in thermal conductivities in response to variations in water content pose a challenge to the heat‐tracing method used to calculate water flux in variably saturated zones. In this study, a new approach, which adopted finite difference numerical schemes along with the limited‐memory Broyden–Fletcher–Goldfarb–Shanno bounded (L‐BFGS‐B) parameter optimization algorithm, was developed to inversely trace vertical soil water fluxes in variably saturated zones using temperature‐depth time‐series data. The newly developed method did not utilize hydraulic parameters and only temperature time‐series data were used at the adjacent depths as boundary conditions. The soil water, vapor flux, and spatiotemporal variations in thermal conductivity at a given location were optimized by fitting the temperature time‐series at the target depth using the L‐BFGS‐B algorithm. Further, the method was verified through laboratory experiments under different saturated conditions that were conducted in two columns with saturated and free drainage bottom boundaries, and five sets of different flow rates with a relatively stable flow condition. The soil water flux calculated using the proposed method was consistent with the observed data, thus, verifying the reliability of the approach in applications with relatively stable flow rates. Furthermore, the new method was applied to a field site to estimate the time‐varying soil water flux using the measured temperature data. The trends of the calculated soil water flux at different depths were consistent with the field hydrologic conditions and observations. Thus, this study provides a novel computationally efficient and easy‐to‐implement tool to determine soil water flux using temperature measurements.</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;The coexistence of water, vapor, and solid phases and the spatiotemporal changes in thermal conductivities in response to variations in water content pose a challenge to the heat-tracing method used to calculate water flux in variably saturated zones. In this study, a new approach, which adopted finite difference numerical schemes along with the limited-memory Broyden–Fletcher–Goldfarb–Shanno bounded (L-BFGS-B) parameter optimization algorithm, was developed to inversely trace vertical soil water fluxes in variably saturated zones using temperature-depth time-series data. The newly developed method did not utilize hydraulic parameters and only temperature time-series data were used at the adjacent depths as boundary conditions. The soil water, vapor flux, and spatiotemporal variations in thermal conductivity at a given location were optimized by fitting the temperature time-series at the target depth using the L-BFGS-B algorithm. Further, the method was verified through laboratory experiments under different saturated conditions that were conducted in two columns with saturated and free drainage bottom boundaries, and five sets of different flow rates with a relatively stable flow condition. The soil water flux calculated using the proposed method was consistent with the observed data, thus, verifying the reliability of the approach in applications with relatively stable flow rates. Furthermore, the new method was applied to a field site to estimate the time-varying soil water flux using the measured temperature data. The trends of the calculated soil water flux at different depths were consistent with the field hydrologic conditions and observations. Thus, this study provides a novel computationally efficient and easy-to-implement tool to determine soil water flux using temperature measurements.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> Meng Su, Rui Ma, Yunquan Wang, Ziyong Sun, Maosheng Yin, Mengyan Ge</dc:creator><category> Research Article</category><dc:title> Tracing the soil water flux in variably saturated zones using temperature data</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2022WR033677</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1029/2022WR033677</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033677?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> Research Article</prism:section></item><item><link/> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033655?af=R<pubDate> Mon, 10 Apr 2023 11:54:15 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-04-10T11:54:15-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley: Water Resources Research: Table of Contents <prism:coverdate></prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate></prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR033655</guid><title> Evaluation of earth observations and in situ data assimilation for seasonal hydrological forecasting</title><description> Water Resources Research, Accepted Article.</description><dc:description> Abstract Earth Observations are a valuable complement to in situ measurements in hydrology because they provide information in locations where direct measurements are unavailable or prohibitively expensive to make. Recent advances have enabled the assimilation of data sets of different physical variables into hydrological models to better estimate states and fluxes. Along with the meteorological forcings, the assimilated data exert controls on forecasts; it is therefore important to apportion the contributions from the forcing and assimilated data. Quality assessment is sometimes conducted in the pseudo‐reality, which neglects observations and model limitations. Here we introduce a diagnostic framework that accounts for observations to assess the sources of skill and infer the seasonal importance of assimilated and forcing data. We test the framework with a forcing data set from a downscaled Global Circulation Model and assimilate four Earth Observation and two in situ data sets to initialize the forecasts. We investigate the hydrological response and seasonal predictions over a Swedish snowmelt‐dominated catchment using the HYPE model over 2001‐2015. The framework allows assessing the improvement in seasonal skill due to the different assimilated data and meteorological forcing. For the studied catchment, all Earth Observation and in situ data sets add information to the final forecast. The lead times during which data assimilation influences forecast skill also differ between data sets and seasons eg, assimilating snow water equivalent impacts the forecast for more than 20 weeks during winter. Lastly, assimilated data sets are generally more important to streamflow forecasting skill than meteorological forcing in the studied snow‐dominated catchment. This article is protected by copyright. All rights reserved.</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;Earth Observations are a valuable complement to in situ measurements in hydrology because they provide information in locations where direct measurements are unavailable or prohibitively expensive to make. Recent advances have enabled the assimilation of data sets of different physical variables into hydrological models to better estimate states and fluxes. Along with the meteorological forcings, the assimilated data exert controls on forecasts; it is therefore important to apportion the contributions from the forcing and assimilated data. Quality assessment is sometimes conducted in the pseudo-reality, which neglects observations and model limitations. Here we introduce a diagnostic framework that accounts for observations to assess the sources of skill and infer the seasonal importance of assimilated and forcing data. We test the framework with a forcing data set from a downscaled Global Circulation Model and assimilate four Earth Observation and two in situ data sets to initialize the forecasts. We investigate the hydrological response and seasonal predictions over a Swedish snowmelt-dominated catchment using the HYPE model over 2001-2015. The framework allows assessing the improvement in seasonal skill due to the different assimilated data and meteorological forcing. For the studied catchment, all Earth Observation and in situ data sets add information to the final forecast. The lead times during which data assimilation influences forecast skill also differ between data sets and seasons eg, assimilating snow water equivalent impacts the forecast for more than 20 weeks during winter. Lastly, assimilated data sets are generally more important to streamflow forecasting skill than meteorological forcing in the studied snow-dominated catchment.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This article is protected by copyright. All rights reserved.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> Jude L. Musuuza, Louise Crochemore, Ilias G. Pechlivanidis</dc:creator><category> Research Article</category><dc:title> Evaluation of earth observations and in situ data assimilation for seasonal hydrological forecasting</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2022WR033655</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1029/2022WR033655</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033655?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> Research Article</prism:section></item><item><link/> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR032499?af=R<pubDate> Mon, 10 Apr 2023 06:46:39 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-04-10T06:46:39-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley: Water Resources Research: Table of Contents<prism:coverdate> Sat, 01 Apr 2023 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate> Sat, 01 Apr 2023 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR032499</guid><title> The Near‐Bed Flow Structure and Bed Shear Stresses Within Emergent Vegetation</title><description> Water Resources Research, Volume 59, Issue 4, April 2023.</description><dc:description> Abstract The structure of the bottom boundary layer (BBL) in aquatic flows influences a range of biophysical processes, including sediment transport, hyporheic exchange, and biofilm formation. While the structure of BBL above bare sediment beds has been well studied, little is known about the complex near‐bed flow structure within aquatic vegetation. In this study, we used high‐resolution laboratory measurements and numerical Large Eddy Simulations to investigate the near‐bed mean and turbulent flow properties within staggered‐ordered emergent vegetation under a wide range of flow conditions and densities. There is strong spatial variability of key near‐bed flow characteristics on the scale of the vegetation elements. Measurement locations that provide single‐point flow characteristics closest to the spatially averaged values were identified. The spatially averaged BBL thickness is influenced strongly by vegetation density. This impact of vegetation density is engendered through its direct control of near‐bed turbulent kinetic energy (TKE), which in turn is negatively correlated with BBL thickness, both locally in a given flow and across the range of flow conditions studied here. A model based on the near‐bed TKE is developed to predict the BBL thickness and, ultimately, the bed shear stress. Model predictions were in close agreement with the experimental and numerical results. These findings provide new insights into the physical links between near‐bed flow variables and therefore contribute to the understanding of some of the complex biophysical processes present in vegetated flows.</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;The structure of the bottom boundary layer (BBL) in aquatic flows influences a range of biophysical processes, including sediment transport, hyporheic exchange, and biofilm formation. While the structure of BBL above bare sediment beds has been well studied, little is known about the complex near-bed flow structure within aquatic vegetation. In this study, we used high-resolution laboratory measurements and numerical Large Eddy Simulations to investigate the near-bed mean and turbulent flow properties within staggered-ordered emergent vegetation under a wide range of flow conditions and densities. There is strong spatial variability of key near-bed flow characteristics on the scale of the vegetation elements. Measurement locations that provide single-point flow characteristics closest to the spatially averaged values were identified. The spatially averaged BBL thickness is influenced strongly by vegetation density. This impact of vegetation density is engendered through its direct control of near-bed turbulent kinetic energy (TKE), which in turn is negatively correlated with BBL thickness, both locally in a given flow and across the range of flow conditions studied here. A model based on the near-bed TKE is developed to predict the BBL thickness and, ultimately, the bed shear stress. Model predictions were in close agreement with the experimental and numerical results. These findings provide new insights into the physical links between near-bed flow variables and therefore contribute to the understanding of some of the complex biophysical processes present in vegetated flows.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> M. Conde‐Frias, M. Ghisalberti, RJ Lowe, M. Abdolahpour, V. Etminan</dc:creator><category> Research Article</category><dc:title> The Near‐Bed Flow Structure and Bed Shear Stresses Within Emergent Vegetation</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2022WR032499</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1029/2022WR032499</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR032499?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> Research Article</prism:section><prism:volume> 59</prism:volume><prism:number> 4</prism:number></item><item><link/> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033133?af=R<pubDate> Mon, 10 Apr 2023 06:37:29 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-04-10T06:37:29-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley: Water Resources Research: Table of Contents<prism:coverdate> Sat, 01 Apr 2023 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate> Sat, 01 Apr 2023 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR033133</guid><title> On the Spatial Scale Dependence of Long‐Term Persistence in Global Annual Precipitation Data and the Hurst Phenomenon</title><description> Water Resources Research, Volume 59, Issue 4, April 2023.</description><dc:description> Abstract Precipitation deficits are the main physical drivers of droughts across the globe, and their level of persistence can be characterized by the Hurst coefficient H (0.5 &lt; H &lt; 1), with high H indicating strong long‐term persistence (LTP). Previous analyses of point and gridded annual global precipitation datasets have concluded that LTP in precipitation is weak (H ∼ 0.6) which is inconsistent with higher values of H for large river basins, for example, the Nile. Based on an analysis of gridded annual precipitation data for eight selected regions distributed across the globe, an important new finding is that H increases with the spatial scale of averaging, with mean H values at the grid and regional scale of 0.66 and 0.83, respectively. The discovery of enhanced LTP at the regional scale of averaging of precipitation has important implications for characterizing the severity of regional droughts, as well as LTP in the annual flows of large rivers and recharge to major aquifers. Teleconnections with known modes of low frequency variability in the global climate system are demonstrated using correlation analysis and stepwise regression. Despite having several constituent regions exhibiting LTP, the Northern Hemisphere surprisingly has no LTP; this is shown to result from different modes of low frequency climatic variability canceling each other out. LTP for the Southern Hemisphere is moderate, and weak for Global average precipitation. LTP in Blue Nile basin scale precipitation is shown to explain the Hurst Phenomenon in naturalized annual flows for the River Nile, more than 70 years after its discovery by Hurst.</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;Precipitation deficits are the main physical drivers of droughts across the globe, and their level of persistence can be characterized by the Hurst coefficient &lt;i>;H&lt;/i>; (0.5 &amp;lt; &lt;i>;H&lt;/i>; &amp;lt; 1), with high &lt;i>;H&lt;/i>; indicating strong long-term persistence (LTP). Previous analyses of point and gridded annual global precipitation datasets have concluded that LTP in precipitation is weak (&lt;i>;H&lt;/i>; ∼ 0.6) which is inconsistent with higher values of &lt;i>;H&lt;/i>; for large river basins, for example, the Nile. Based on an analysis of gridded annual precipitation data for eight selected regions distributed across the globe, an important new finding is that &lt;i>;H&lt;/i>; increases with the spatial scale of averaging, with mean &lt;i>;H&lt;/i>; values at the grid and regional scale of 0.66 and 0.83, respectively. The discovery of enhanced LTP at the regional scale of averaging of precipitation has important implications for characterizing the severity of regional droughts, as well as LTP in the annual flows of large rivers and recharge to major aquifers. Teleconnections with known modes of low frequency variability in the global climate system are demonstrated using correlation analysis and stepwise regression. Despite having several constituent regions exhibiting LTP, the Northern Hemisphere surprisingly has no LTP; this is shown to result from different modes of low frequency climatic variability canceling each other out. LTP for the Southern Hemisphere is moderate, and weak for Global average precipitation. LTP in Blue Nile basin scale precipitation is shown to explain the Hurst Phenomenon in naturalized annual flows for the River Nile, more than 70 years after its discovery by Hurst.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> Enda O&#39;Connell, Greg O&#39;Donnell, Demetris Koutsoyiannis</dc:creator><category> Research Article</category><dc:title> On the Spatial Scale Dependence of Long‐Term Persistence in Global Annual Precipitation Data and the Hurst Phenomenon</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2022WR033133</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1029/2022WR033133</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033133?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> Research Article</prism:section><prism:volume> 59</prism:volume><prism:number> 4</prism:number></item></channel></rss>