<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:prism="http://prismstandard.org/namespaces/basic/2.0/"><channel><title> Wiley：水资源研究：目录</title><link/>https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R<description>水资源研究目录。最新和 EarlyView 问题的文章列表。</description><language>英文</language><copyright></copyright><managingeditor>wileyonlinelibrary@wiley.com（AGU 出版物）</managingeditor><pubDate> Wed, 19 Apr 2023 07:43:05 +0000</pubDate><lastbuilddate> 2023 年 4 月 19 日星期三 07:43:05 +0000</lastbuilddate><generator> Atypon®文学™</generator><docs> https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs><ttl> 10080</ttl><dc:title> Wiley：水资源研究：目录</dc:title><dc:publisher>威利</dc:publisher><prism:publicationname>水资源研究</prism:publicationname><atom:link href="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"></atom:link><image/><title> Wiley：水资源研究：目录</title><url>https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/pb-assets/journal-banners/19447973.jpg</url><link/> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R<item><link/> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR034095?af=R<pubDate> Tue, 18 Apr 2023 07:54:19 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-04-18T07:54:19-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley：水资源研究：目录<prism:coverdate></prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate></prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR034095</guid><title>利用犹他州帕罗旺河谷的水位、抽水和 InSAR 数据估算含水层系统的蓄水损失</title><description>水资源研究，接受的文章。</description><dc:description>摘要 在犹他州的 Parowan 山谷，地下水位在过去 50 年里下降了 30 米之多，伴随的沉降率高达 5 厘米/年。估算地下水储量变化的传统方法结合使用地下水位和储水量估算值，但其中通常存在相当大的不确定性。在这项研究中，我们展示了一种新方法，该方法依赖于 InSAR 大地测量数据以及地下水位和抽水数据的组合，以估算总地下水储量损失和细粒度和粗粒度储量损失的百分比含水层系统中的层。我们发现，当对整个 Parowan 山谷进行汇总时，细粒层和粗粒层在总地下水储量损失中所占的比例大致相等。然而，在承压含水层中，细粒层是造成大部分储存损失的原因。这对枯竭含水层系统中的地下水来源具有重要意义，因为许多模型并未将细粒层视为水源。我们发现，在 Parowan 山谷，含水层枯竭大约是抽取地下水量的 12.5%，这意味着抽取地下水的其余部分来自净流入。本研究提出了第一种方法，将大地测量和原位地下水数据结合起来，以提供对粗粒度和细粒度间隔的地下水储量变化的估计，这些间隔通常在世界主要未固结含水层系统中大量存在.</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;摘要&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;在犹他州的 Parowan 山谷，地下水位在过去 50 年里下降了 30 米之多，伴随的沉降率高达 5 厘米/年。估算地下水储量变化的传统方法结合使用地下水位和储水量估算值，但其中通常存在相当大的不确定性。在这项研究中，我们展示了一种新方法，该方法依赖于来自 InSAR 的大地测量数据以及地下水位和抽水数据的组合，以估算总地下水储量损失和细粒度和粗粒度储量损失的百分比含水层系统中的层。我们发现，当对整个 Parowan 山谷进行汇总时，细粒层和粗粒层在总地下水储量损失中所占的比例大致相等。然而，在密闭含水层中，细粒层是造成大部分储存损失的原因。这对枯竭含水层系统中的地下水来源具有重要意义，因为许多模型并未将细粒层视为水源。我们发现，在 Parowan 山谷，含水层枯竭大约是抽取地下水量的 12.5%，这意味着抽取地下水的其余部分来自净流入。本研究提出了第一种方法，将大地测量和现场地下水数据结合起来，以提供对粗粒度和细粒度间隔的地下水储量变化的估计，这些间隔通常在世界主要未固结含水层系统中大量存在.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator>瑞安·史密斯、李佳薇、凯瑟琳·格罗特、吉姆·巴特勒</dc:creator><category>研究文章</category><dc:title>利用犹他州帕罗旺河谷的水位、抽水和 InSAR 数据估算含水层系统的蓄水损失</dc:title><dc:identifier>10.1029/2022WR034095</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname>水资源研究</prism:publicationname><prism:doi>10.1029/2022WR034095</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR034095?af=R</prism:url><prism:section>研究文章</prism:section></item><item><link/>https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR032039?af=R<pubDate> Tue, 18 Apr 2023 07:49:26 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-04-18T07:49:26-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley：水资源研究：目录<prism:coverdate></prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate></prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR032039</guid><title>在美国国家水模型的洪水泛滥制图应用中，将高度延伸到最近的排水系统上方以模拟多个河流源</title><description>水资源研究，接受的文章。</description><dc:description> Abstract Height Above Nearest Drainage (HAND) 是一种排水归一化地形指数，是一种能够使用平均合成评级曲线从国家水模型 (NWM) 以大比例和高分辨率生成洪水淹没图 (FIM) 的方法。我们在此强调，HAND 仅限于从最近的流道产生洪水时产生洪水，因此缺乏从多个河流来源产生洪水的能力。 HAND 的一个版本，称为广义主干 (GMS)，提出了将目标流网络离散化为单位 Horton-Strahler 流顺序的段，称为水平路径 (LP)。然后将与每个独立 LP 关联的 FIM 拼接在一起，通过消除相邻支流的影响，有效地将流网络转变为离散的同质单位流序组。当将淹没范围与基准的 FIM 进行比较时，通过显着减少河流交汇处的漏报，可以观察到制图技能的提高。由于通过增加集水区的大小引入阶段流量关系的转变，还观察到误报率有更多的边际降低。我们观察到，将此方法应用于整个河流网络的 4-5% 到 100% 的改进与从没有排水订单减少到 4-5% 的网络的改进幅度大致相同。这一新颖的贡献是在一个新的开源实现中构建的，该实现利用最新的水力调节技术组合来强制排水和输入数据中的计数器限制。</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;摘要&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;最近排水沟上方高度（HAND）是一种排水归一化地形指数，是一种能够根据国家水模型（NWM）制作大比例尺和高水平洪水淹没图（FIM）的方法使用达到平均综合评级曲线的分辨率。我们在此强调，HAND 仅限于从最近的流道产生洪水时产生洪水，因此缺乏从多个河流来源产生洪水的能力。提出了一种称为广义主干 (GMS) 的 HAND 版本，它将目标流网络离散化为称为水平路径 (LP) 的单元 Horton-Strahler 流顺序段。然后将与每个独立 LP 关联的 FIM 拼接在一起，通过消除相邻支流的影响，有效地将流网络转变为离散的同质单位流序组。当将淹没范围与基准的 FIM 进行比较时，通过显着减少河流交汇处的漏报，可以观察到制图技能的提高。由于通过增加集水区的大小引入了水位-流量关系的转变，因此还观察到误报率有更多的边际降低。我们观察到，将此方法应用于整个河流网络的 4-5% 到 100% 的网络的改进与从不减少排水订单到网络的 4-5% 的改进幅度大致相同。这一新颖的贡献是在一个新的开源实现中构建的，该实现利用最新的水力调节技术组合来加强输入数据中的排水和计数器限制。&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator>费尔南多·阿里斯蒂扎巴尔，费尔南多·萨拉斯，格雷戈里·彼得琴科夫，特雷弗·格鲁特，布赖恩·阿万特，布拉德福德·贝茨，瑞安·斯皮斯，尼克·查德威克，扎克瑞·威尔斯，贾斯梅特·贾奇</dc:creator><category>研究文章</category><dc:title>在美国国家水模型的洪水泛滥制图应用中，将高度延伸到最近的排水系统上方以模拟多个河流源</dc:title><dc:identifier>10.1029/2022WR032039</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname>水资源研究</prism:publicationname><prism:doi>10.1029/2022WR032039</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR032039?af=R</prism:url><prism:section>研究文章</prism:section></item><item><link/>https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR034041?af=R<pubDate> Tue, 18 Apr 2023 07:48:32 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-04-18T07:48:32-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley：水资源研究：目录<prism:coverdate></prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate></prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR034041</guid><title>地下水中氯化乙烯的扩散分散同位素分馏：不完全混合的关键作用及其多尺度效应</title><description>水资源研究，接受的文章。</description><dc:description>摘要 扩散-色散过程在多孔介质中普遍存在，对许多自然和工程系统中的溶质传输具有重要意义；然而，它们对地下流通系统中有机污染物同位素分馏的影响尚不清楚。在这项研究中，我们研究了地下水系统中由横向扩散-色散同位素分馏引起的同位素位移在稳定状态下氯化乙烯羽流的碳和氯同位素特征的传播。我们考虑三种不同的空间尺度（即孔隙、实验室和野外尺度），并通过高分辨率孔隙尺度模拟、流通实验和野外尺度数值模拟来探索同位素分馏。使用顺式二氯乙烯（cis-DCE）作为模型污染物进行了实验室规模的实验研究，而在多尺度数值模拟中考虑了顺式-DCE 和三氯乙烯（TCE）。横向位移的孔隙尺度分析表明，在很宽的渗流速度范围内（0.1 – 10 m/天），同位素分馏现象很明显。孔隙尺度模拟阐明了不完全混合的关键作用，它在孔隙通道中维持同位素异数体特异性梯度，并以最快的流速产生最强的同位素分馏（碳为 -6‰；氯为 -10‰）。流通实验的结果也支持同位素体特异性水扩散在实验室规模上的关键作用，在实验室规模上，在装置的出口观察到显着的扩散-色散同位素变化。最后，在异质含水层的横截面中进行的详细的现场尺度数值模拟表明，微观扩散引起的同位素分数在宏观尺度上传播。本文受版权保护。版权所有。</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;摘要&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;扩散-色散过程在多孔介质中无处不在，对许多自然和工程系统中的溶质传输具有重要意义；然而，它们对地下流通系统中有机污染物同位素分馏的影响尚不清楚。在这项研究中，我们研究了地下水系统中由横向扩散-色散同位素分馏引起的同位素位移在稳定状态下氯化乙烯羽流的碳和氯同位素特征的传播。我们考虑三个不同的空间尺度（即孔隙、实验室和野外尺度），并通过高分辨率孔隙尺度模拟、流通实验和野外尺度数值模拟探索同位素分馏。使用顺式二氯乙烯 (cis-DCE) 作为模型污染物进行了实验室规模的实验研究，而在多尺度数值模拟中考虑了顺式-DCE 和三氯乙烯 (TCE)。横向位移的孔隙尺度分析表明，在很宽的渗流速度范围（0.1 – 10 m/天）内存在显着的同位素分馏。孔隙尺度模拟阐明了不完全混合的关键作用，它在孔隙通道中维持同位素体特异性梯度，并以最快的流速产生最强的同位素分馏（碳为 -6‰；氯为 -10‰）。流通实验的结果也支持同位素体特异性水扩散在实验室规模的关键作用，其中在装置的出口处观察到显着的扩散-色散同位素变化。最后，在异质含水层的横截面中进行的详细的现场尺度数值模拟表明，微观扩散引起的同位素分数在宏观尺度上传播。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;本文受版权保护。保留所有权利。&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> Henning Wienkenjohann, Biao Jin, Massimo Rolle</dc:creator><category>研究文章</category><dc:title>地下水中氯化乙烯的扩散分散同位素分馏：不完全混合的关键作用及其多尺度效应</dc:title><dc:identifier>10.1029/2022WR034041</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname>水资源研究</prism:publicationname><prism:doi>10.1029/2022WR034041</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR034041?af=R</prism:url><prism:section>研究文章</prism:section></item><item><link/>https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033360?af=R<pubDate> Tue, 18 Apr 2023 07:48:23 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-04-18T07:48:23-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley：水资源研究：目录<prism:coverdate></prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate></prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR033360</guid><title>三峡工程间接效益的析因CGE分析</title><description>水资源研究，接受的文章。</description><dc:description>摘要 大型水利工程 (LHPs) 在流域洪水风险管理中变得越来越重要。尽管 LHPs 的直接洪水滞留效益已被清楚地表明，但缺乏对其间接影响的全面检查，这些间接影响在环境和经济方面可能更持久和实质性。因此，本研究开发了一种基于因子 CGE 的 LHP 效应分析方法 (FLEA)，以量化 LHP 的间接影响并模拟不同情景下的洪水后恢复策略。 FLEA 将因子分析与动态可计算一般均衡框架相结合，包括洪水期间将水力举措与经济联系起来的洪水模块。 FLEA应用于三峡工程（TGP）。结果表明，三峡工程每年通过供应链创造约 570 亿美元的 GD​​P 和约 12.9 Mt 的二氧化碳当量减排。当洪水来袭时，三峡工程有可能直接节省约 210 亿美元的 GD​​P，并在整个重建期间将长期 GDP 损失减少约 50%。三峡工程可以对制造业产生相当大的间接影响。此外，可能需要改进三峡工程的监管和维护，以减轻与洪水相关的长期损失，这比积极的洪灾后财政刺激措施更为重要。本文受版权保护。版权所有。</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;摘要&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;大型水利工程（LHPs）在流域洪水风险管理中变得越来越重要。尽管 LHPs 的直接洪水滞留效益已被清楚地显示出来，但缺乏对其间接影响的全面检查，这些间接影响在环境和经济方面可能更持久和实质性。因此，本研究开发了一种基于因子 CGE 的 LHP 效应分析方法 (FLEA)，以量化 LHP 的间接影响并模拟不同情景下的洪水后恢复策略。 FLEA 将因子分析与动态可计算一般均衡框架相结合，包括洪水期间将水力举措与经济联系起来的洪水模块。 FLEA应用于三峡工程（TGP）。结果表明，三峡工程每年通过供应链创造约 570 亿美元的 GD​​P 和约 12.9 Mt CO&lt;sub>;2eq&lt;/sub>; 减排。当洪水来袭时，三峡工程有可能直接节省约 210 亿美元的 GD​​P，并在整个重建期间将长期 GDP 损失减少约 50%。三峡工程可以对制造业产生相当大的间接影响。此外，可能需要改进三峡工程的监管和维护，以减轻与洪水相关的长期损失，这比积极的洪灾后财政刺激措施更为重要。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;本文受版权保护。保留所有权利。&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> Dengcheng Han, Guohe Huang, Lirong Liu, Mengyu Zhai, Yupeng Fu, Sichen Gao, 李建勇, Xiaojie Pan</dc:creator><category>研究文章</category><dc:title>三峡工程间接效益的析因CGE分析</dc:title><dc:identifier>10.1029/2022WR033360</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname>水资源研究</prism:publicationname><prism:doi>10.1029/2022WR033360</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033360?af=R</prism:url><prism:section>研究文章</prism:section></item><item><link/>https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033126?af=R<pubDate> Tue, 18 Apr 2023 07:40:37 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-04-18T07:40:37-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley：水资源研究：目录<prism:coverdate>2023 年 4 月 1 日星期六 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate> 2023 年 4 月 1 日星期六 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR033126</guid><title>利用全球导航卫星系统和降水数据建立中国云南气象水文干旱的传播特征</title><description>水资源研究，第 59 卷，第 4 期，2023 年 4 月。</description><dc:description>摘要 分析气象水文干旱的时空特征和演变过程，可以再现干旱传播过程，有助于减轻干旱影响，改善水资源管理。虽然新兴研究试图基于前沿空间大地测量观测建立干旱严重度指数，但很少有人使用大地测量数据关注气象到水文干旱的传播特征。在本文中，我们利用全球导航卫星系统 (GNSS) 观测数据和降水数据，系统地调查了中国西南部云南省的干旱传播情况。我们首先确定了2011年1月至2021年5月云南的7次气象干旱和7次水文干旱，气象干旱主要集中在云南北部，持续时间为1-11个月。相比之下，水文干旱比气象干旱更严重，规模更大，持续时间为2-16个月。干旱传播期为2～7个月，西南短，东北长。水汽、降水和蓄水量呈时空分布不均匀的格局，以红河断层（RRF）为界，其相位差也呈现显着的区域差异，说明红河断层不仅影响水资源的空间变化但也影响干旱传播。</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;摘要&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;分析气象水文干旱的时空特征和演变过程，可以再现干旱传播过程，有助于减轻干旱影响，改善水资源管理。虽然新兴研究试图根据前沿空间大地测量观测建立干旱严重度指数，但很少有人使用大地测量数据关注气象到水文干旱的传播特征。在本文中，我们利用全球导航卫星系统 (GNSS) 观测数据和降水数据，系统地调查了中国西南部云南省的干旱传播情况。我们首先确定了2011年1月至2021年5月云南的7次气象干旱和7次水文干旱，气象干旱主要集中在云南北部，持续时间为1-11个月。相比之下，水文干旱比气象干旱更严重，规模更大，持续时间为2-16个月。干旱传播期为2～7个月，西南短，东北长。水汽、降水和蓄水量呈时空分布不均匀的格局，以红河断层（RRF）为界，其相位差也呈现显着的区域差异，说明红河断层不仅影响水资源的空间变化但也会影响干旱传播。&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator>朱海，陈克杰，胡顺强，刘俊国，史海云，魏国光，柴海山，李家峰，王坦</dc:creator><category>研究文章</category><dc:title>利用全球导航卫星系统和降水数据建立中国云南气象水文干旱的传播特征</dc:title><dc:identifier>10.1029/2022WR033126</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname>水资源研究</prism:publicationname><prism:doi>10.1029/2022WR033126</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033126?af=R</prism:url><prism:section>研究文章</prism:section><prism:volume>59</prism:volume><prism:number> 4个</prism:number></item><item><link/>https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033305?af=R<pubDate> Mon, 17 Apr 2023 12:59:48 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-04-17T12:59:48-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley：水资源研究：目录<prism:coverdate>2023 年 4 月 1 日星期六 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate> 2023 年 4 月 1 日星期六 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR033305</guid><title>水文气候驱动季节性河流出口跨越冰川化高纬度沿海集水区的梯度</title><description>水资源研究，第 59 卷，第 4 期，2023 年 4 月。</description><dc:description>摘要 阿拉斯加湾 (GoA) 冰川化的沿海集水区正在经历快速的水文波动以应对气候变化。这些集水区将溶解和悬浮的无机物和有机物输送到近岸海洋环境，然而，这些冰川化的沿海集水区研究相对不足，对海洋的总溶质和颗粒物通量知之甚少。我们展示了 2019 年 4 月至 2021 年 10 月从 10 条溪流收集的水文、物理和地球化学数据，这些溪流沿着冰川补给到非冰川（即降水）补给的梯度，在一个中南部和一个阿拉斯加东南部地区。水文数据表明，冰川驱动季节性径流模式。 ẟ18O 特征和特定电导率显示研究区域之间的溪流水源具有明显的季节性变化，这显然是由于阿拉斯加东南部的大量降雨造成的。由于岩性对溶解负荷的影响，Southcentral 地区的总溶解固体浓度和产量升高，然而，水文气候是溶解和悬浮产量时间的主要驱动因素。我们显示溶解有机碳的产量更高，并且 δ13CPOC 在东南溪流中富集，说明整个果阿有机碳输出的对比。最后，我们说明了随着分水岭从受冰川影响演变为以降水为主，未来 GoA 的溶质和沉积物产量可能会如何变化。这种综合分析提供了关于冰川覆盖之外的流域特征如何控制淡水输入到果阿的特性以及将研究区域扩展到多种水文气候制度的重要性的见解。</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;摘要&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;阿拉斯加湾 (GoA) 冰川化的沿海集水区正在经历快速的水文波动以应对气候变化。这些集水区将溶解和悬浮的无机物和有机物输送到近岸海洋环境，然而，这些冰川化的沿海集水区研究相对不足，对海洋的总溶质和颗粒物通量知之甚少。我们展示了 2019 年 4 月至 2021 年 10 月期间从 10 条溪流收集的水文、物理和地球化学数据，这些溪流沿着冰川补给到非冰川（即降水）补给的梯度，在阿拉斯加中南部和东南部一个地区。水文数据表明，冰川驱动季节性径流模式。 ẟ&lt;sup>;18&lt;/sup>;O 特征和比电导显示研究区域之间溪流水源的明显季节性变化，这显然是由于阿拉斯加东南部的大量降雨造成的。由于岩性对溶解负荷的影响，Southcentral 地区的总溶解固体浓度和产量升高，然而，水文气候是溶解和悬浮产量时间的主要驱动因素。我们显示溶解有机碳的产量更高，并且 δ&lt;sup>;13&lt;/sup>;C&lt;sub>;POC&lt;/sub>; 在东南溪流中富集，说明整个果阿有机碳输出的对比。最后，我们说明了随着分水岭从受冰川影响演变为以降水为主，未来 GoA 的溶质和沉积物产量可能会如何变化。这一综合分析提供了关于冰川覆盖之外的流域特征如何控制淡水输入果阿的特性以及将研究区域扩展到多种水文气候体系的重要性的见解。&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> J. Jenckes、LA Munk、DE Ibarra、DF Boutt、J. Fellman、E. Hood</dc:creator><category>研究文章</category><dc:title>水文气候驱动季节性河流出口跨越冰川化高纬度沿海集水区的梯度</dc:title><dc:identifier>10.1029/2022WR033305</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname>水资源研究</prism:publicationname><prism:doi>10.1029/2022WR033305</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033305?af=R</prism:url><prism:section>研究文章</prism:section><prism:volume>59</prism:volume><prism:number> 4个</prism:number></item><item><link/>https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR034046?af=R<pubDate> Mon, 17 Apr 2023 12:59:32 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-04-17T12:59:32-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley：水资源研究：目录<prism:coverdate>2023 年 4 月 1 日星期六 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate> 2023 年 4 月 1 日星期六 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR034046</guid><title>独特的水文路径调节着干旱盆地多年生的地表水动态</title><description>水资源研究，第 59 卷，第 4 期，2023 年 4 月。</description><dc:description>摘要 在缺水的超干旱盆地中，人为地下水抽取和气候驱动扰动对地下水-地表水相互作用和生态系统关键地表水的恢复力的影响越来越受到质疑。将地下水与 Sentinel-2 数据的地表水观测相结合，为评估干旱盆地强降水事件后地表水与当地含水层的连通性提供了前所未有的机会。分析了地表水面积和地下水位数据的降水趋势，包括峰值滞后时间、峰值后衰退率和水力梯度变化。结果表明在上游淡水含水层中地表水变化和地下水位波动之间的大降水事件之后可变连通性，而含水层的下坡盐水到半咸水区域表明与含水层几乎没有连通性。降水和地表水响应之间的比较表明，根据地表水体与含水层的盐水到半咸水区域的物理关系，会出现不同的响应。地表水淹没的集总参数模型也限制了降水后响应的可能水文动力学。虽然模拟的地表水流入量似乎主要受流域水力控制，而不是含水层的直接水力连通性，但地表水与邻近地下水位与地表水面积之间的关系表明，当地含水层主要通过排放与地表水体相连地下渗透。模拟结果表明，干旱盆地中邻近卤水的地表水的存在依赖于淡水含水层的上坡排放。我们的结果进一步支持边缘地表水系统可以作为当地含水层的关键补给机制。</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;摘要&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;在缺水的超干旱盆地，人为地下水抽取和气候驱动扰动对地下水-地表水相互作用和生态系统关键地表水恢复力的影响越来越受到质疑。将地下水与 Sentinel-2 数据的地表水观测相结合，为评估干旱盆地强降水事件后地表水与当地含水层的连通性提供了前所未有的机会。分析了地表水面积和地下水位数据的降水趋势，包括峰值滞后时间、峰值后衰退率和水力梯度变化。结果表明，在上游淡水含水层中地表水变化和地下水位波动之间发生大降水事件后，连通性可变，而含水层的下坡盐水到半咸水区域表明与含水层几乎没有连通性。降水和地表水响应之间的比较表明，基于地表水体与含水层的盐水到半咸水区域的物理关系，响应不同。地表水淹没的集总参数模型也限制了降水后响应的可能水文动力学。虽然模拟的地表水流入量似乎主要受流域水力控制，而不是含水层的直接水力连通性，但地表水与邻近地下水位与地表水面积之间的关系表明，当地含水层主要通过排放与地表水体相连地下渗透。模拟结果表明，干旱盆地中邻近卤水的地表水的存在依赖于淡水含水层的上坡排放。我们的结果进一步支持边缘地表水系统可以作为当地含水层的关键补给机制。&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> SV McKnight、DF Boutt、LA Munk、B. Moran</dc:creator><category>研究文章</category><dc:title>独特的水文路径调节着干旱盆地多年生的地表水动态</dc:title><dc:identifier>10.1029/2022WR034046</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname>水资源研究</prism:publicationname><prism:doi>10.1029/2022WR034046</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR034046?af=R</prism:url><prism:section>研究文章</prism:section><prism:volume>59</prism:volume><prism:number> 4个</prism:number></item><item><link/>https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033714?af=R<pubDate> Fri, 14 Apr 2023 14:25:27 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-04-14T02:25:27-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley：水资源研究：目录<prism:coverdate>2023 年 4 月 1 日星期六 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate> 2023 年 4 月 1 日星期六 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR033714</guid><title>洪泛区连接渠道作为三角洲河网水文连通性的关键路径</title><description>水资源研究，第 59 卷，第 4 期，2023 年 4 月。</description><dc:description>摘要 河流分叉对于将水、沉积物和养分分配到三角洲河网的下游支流至关重要。然而，分叉的下游分支可以通过穿过三角洲漫滩的连接通道连接起来。作为下游控制的洪泛区连接通道可以影响河流分叉处的水分配，从而影响河网的水文连通性。然而，它的影响在很大程度上仍然难以捉摸。在这项研究中，我们探讨了连接下游支流的连接渠道如何影响上游分叉处的水分配和两个支流的水分配。调查是通过使用 Delft3D 的理想化数值模拟进行的，然后使用图论分析了对河网水文连通性的级联效应。结果表明，连接通道可以减轻上游分叉处的不对称水分配。然而，这是以在下游出口引起更多不均匀流动为代价的。 The flow adjustment is due to the altered spatial water surface slope in the two branches associated with the flow exchange from one channel to the other via the connecting channel. Further analysis of hydrological connectivity shows that connecting channels can generally reduce the vulnerability of the channel network to hydrological alterations, especially changing inflow, by enhancing flow exchange between the two branches. Our results suggest that connecting channels are critical paths for hydrological connectivity, which have important implications for the management of deltaic river networks and their floodplains.</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;A river bifurcation is critical for distributing water, sediment and nutrients to the downstream branches of deltaic river networks. However, the downstream branches of a bifurcation can be linked by a connecting channel cutting through deltaic floodplains. The floodplain connecting channel as a downstream control can affect water partitioning at the river bifurcation and hence the hydrological connectivity of the river network. However, its effects are still largely elusive. In this study, we explored how a connecting channel linking downstream branches affects water partitioning at the upstream bifurcation and water distribution along the two branches. The investigation was conducted through idealized numerical simulations using Delft3D, followed by analysis of the cascading effects on the hydrological connectivity of river networks using graph theory. The results show that connecting channels can mitigate asymmetric water partitioning at the upstream bifurcation. However, this happens at the expense of inducing more uneven flow at the downstream outlets. The flow adjustment is due to the altered spatial water surface slope in the two branches associated with the flow exchange from one channel to the other via the connecting channel. Further analysis of hydrological connectivity shows that connecting channels can generally reduce the vulnerability of the channel network to hydrological alterations, especially changing inflow, by enhancing flow exchange between the two branches. Our results suggest that connecting channels are critical paths for hydrological connectivity, which have important implications for the management of deltaic river networks and their floodplains.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> Weilun Gao, Zheng Bing Wang, Maarten G. Kleinhans, Chiyuan Miao, Baoshan Cui, Dongdong Shao</dc:creator><category> Research Article</category><dc:title> Floodplain Connecting Channels as Critical Paths for Hydrological Connectivity of Deltaic River Networks</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2022WR033714</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1029/2022WR033714</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033714?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> Research Article</prism:section><prism:volume> 59</prism:volume><prism:number> 4</prism:number></item><item><link/> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033151?af=R<pubDate> Fri, 14 Apr 2023 14:19:47 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-04-14T02:19:47-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley: Water Resources Research: Table of Contents<prism:coverdate> Sat, 01 Apr 2023 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate> Sat, 01 Apr 2023 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR033151</guid><title> Paleo‐Hydrogeological Modeling to Understand Present‐Day Groundwater Salinities in a Low‐Lying Coastal Groundwater System (Northwestern Germany)</title><description> Water Resources Research, Volume 59, Issue 4, April 2023.</description><dc:description> Abstract Groundwater abstraction and drainage are considered to be the main drivers for the salinization of low‐lying coastal groundwater systems, while the role of past boundary conditions is less clear. In this study, 3‐D paleo‐hydrogeological variable‐density groundwater flow and salt transport modeling (“paleo‐modeling”) is applied to reconstruct the evolution of groundwater salinities during the Holocene, that is, the last 9,000 years, in Northwestern Germany. Novel aspects of this study include the consideration of highly resolved time‐variant boundary conditions in a 3‐D paleo‐modeling framework, for example, sea‐level rise, surface elevation and coastline changes, development of drainage networks and groundwater abstraction, as well as the quantification of isolated processes impacting salinization. Results show that salinization was a function of sea‐level rise from 9000 BP until 1300 CE. The creation of the dike line ∼1300 CE set the starting point for increasing anthropogenic control of the hydro(geo)logical system: changes in surface elevation and drainage of low‐lying marshes have become main drivers for salinization after 1600 CE when peat was artificially degenerated. Moreover, changes in the dike line caused by storm floods impacted the salinities. Model results for 2020 CE match well with present‐day salinity observations. Yet, salinization will continue in the future, as the hydro(geo)logical system has not reached an equilibrium. The presented paleo‐modeling framework can be viewed as a blueprint for similar low‐lying coastal groundwater systems, influenced by marine transgression and human development. Thereby, it enables the reconstruction of meaningful present‐day salinity distributions, serving as a vital basis for modeling future groundwater systems in a changing climate.</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;Groundwater abstraction and drainage are considered to be the main drivers for the salinization of low-lying coastal groundwater systems, while the role of past boundary conditions is less clear. In this study, 3-D paleo-hydrogeological variable-density groundwater flow and salt transport modeling (“paleo-modeling”) is applied to reconstruct the evolution of groundwater salinities during the Holocene, that is, the last 9,000 years, in Northwestern Germany. Novel aspects of this study include the consideration of highly resolved time-variant boundary conditions in a 3-D paleo-modeling framework, for example, sea-level rise, surface elevation and coastline changes, development of drainage networks and groundwater abstraction, as well as the quantification of isolated processes impacting salinization. Results show that salinization was a function of sea-level rise from 9000 BP until 1300 CE. The creation of the dike line ∼1300 CE set the starting point for increasing anthropogenic control of the hydro(geo)logical system: changes in surface elevation and drainage of low-lying marshes have become main drivers for salinization after 1600 CE when peat was artificially degenerated. Moreover, changes in the dike line caused by storm floods impacted the salinities. Model results for 2020 CE match well with present-day salinity observations. Yet, salinization will continue in the future, as the hydro(geo)logical system has not reached an equilibrium. The presented paleo-modeling framework can be viewed as a blueprint for similar low-lying coastal groundwater systems, influenced by marine transgression and human development. Thereby, it enables the reconstruction of meaningful present-day salinity distributions, serving as a vital basis for modeling future groundwater systems in a changing climate.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> Stephan L. Seibert, Janek Greskowiak, Friederike Bungenstock, Holger Freund, Martina Karle, Rena Meyer, Gualbert HP Oude Essink, Joeri Engelen, Gudrun Massmann</dc:creator><category> Research Article</category><dc:title> Paleo‐Hydrogeological Modeling to Understand Present‐Day Groundwater Salinities in a Low‐Lying Coastal Groundwater System (Northwestern Germany)</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2022WR033151</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1029/2022WR033151</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033151?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> Research Article</prism:section><prism:volume> 59</prism:volume><prism:number> 4</prism:number></item><item><link/> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR034151?af=R<pubDate> Fri, 14 Apr 2023 12:50:46 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-04-14T12:50:46-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley: Water Resources Research: Table of Contents <prism:coverdate></prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate></prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR034151</guid><title> Influence of bed roughness on flow and turbulence structure around a partially‐buried, isolated freshwater mussel</title><description> Water Resources Research, Accepted Article.</description><dc:description> Abstract The present study uses eddy‐resolving numerical simulations to investigate how bed roughness affects flow and turbulence structure around an isolated, partially‐buried mussel (Unio elongatulus) aligned with the incoming flow. The rough‐bed simulations resolve the flow past the exposed part of a gravel bed, whose surface is obtained from a laboratory experiment that also provides some additional data for validation of the numerical model. Results are also discussed for the limiting case of a horizontal smooth bed. Additionally, the effects of varying the level of burial of the mussel inside the substrate and the discharge through the two mussel siphons are investigated via a set of simulations in which the ratio between the median diameter of the (gravel) particles forming the rough bed, d50, and the height of the exposed part of the mussel, h, varies between 0.10 and 0.22. The increase of the bed roughness is associated with a strong amplification of the turbulence kinetic energy in the near‐wake region. Increasing the bed roughness and/or reducing h intensifies the interactions of the eddies generated by the bed particles with the base and tip vortices induced by the active filtering and by the mussel shell, respectively, which, in turn, induces a more rapid dissipation of these vortices. Increasing the bed roughness also reduces the strength of the main downwelling flow region forming in the wake. The strong downwelling near the symmetry plane is the main reason why the symmetric wake shedding mode dominates in the smooth bed simulations with negligible active filtering. By contrast, the anti‐symmetric wake shedding mode dominates in the simulations conduced with a high value of the bed roughness. The mean streamwise drag force coefficient for the emerged part of the shell and the dilution of the excurrent siphon jet increase with increasing bed roughness. This article is protected by copyright.版权所有。</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;The present study uses eddy-resolving numerical simulations to investigate how bed roughness affects flow and turbulence structure around an isolated, partially-buried mussel (&lt;i>;Unio elongatulus&lt;/i>;) aligned with the incoming flow. The rough-bed simulations resolve the flow past the exposed part of a gravel bed, whose surface is obtained from a laboratory experiment that also provides some additional data for validation of the numerical model. Results are also discussed for the limiting case of a horizontal smooth bed. Additionally, the effects of varying the level of burial of the mussel inside the substrate and the discharge through the two mussel siphons are investigated via a set of simulations in which the ratio between the median diameter of the (gravel) particles forming the rough bed, &lt;i>;d&lt;/i>; &lt;sub>;50&lt;/sub>;, and the height of the exposed part of the mussel, &lt;i>;h&lt;/i>;, varies between 0.10 and 0.22. The increase of the bed roughness is associated with a strong amplification of the turbulence kinetic energy in the near-wake region. Increasing the bed roughness and/or reducing &lt;i>;h&lt;/i>; intensifies the interactions of the eddies generated by the bed particles with the base and tip vortices induced by the active filtering and by the mussel shell, respectively, which, in turn, induces a more rapid dissipation of these vortices. Increasing the bed roughness also reduces the strength of the main downwelling flow region forming in the wake. The strong downwelling near the symmetry plane is the main reason why the symmetric wake shedding mode dominates in the smooth bed simulations with negligible active filtering. By contrast, the anti-symmetric wake shedding mode dominates in the simulations conduced with a high value of the bed roughness. The mean streamwise drag force coefficient for the emerged part of the shell and the dilution of the excurrent siphon jet increase with increasing bed roughness.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This article is protected by copyright. All rights reserved.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> T. Lazzarin, G. Constantinescu, L. Di Micco, H. Wu, F. Lavignani, M. Lo Brutto, D. Termini, DP Viero</dc:creator><category> Research Article</category><dc:title> Influence of bed roughness on flow and turbulence structure around a partially‐buried, isolated freshwater mussel</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2022WR034151</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1029/2022WR034151</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR034151?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> Research Article</prism:section></item><item><link/> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033673?af=R<pubDate> Fri, 14 Apr 2023 12:50:10 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-04-14T12:50:10-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley: Water Resources Research: Table of Contents <prism:coverdate></prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate></prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR033673</guid><title> Assimilating low‐cost high‐frequency sensor data in watershed water quality modeling: A Bayesian approach</title><description> Water Resources Research, Accepted Article.</description><dc:description> Abstract Uncertainty reduction in watershed water quality (WWQ) modeling remains a major challenge. One important reason is the lack of sufficient available water quality observations because traditional laboratory analysis of water samples has high labor, financial and time costs. Low‐cost high‐frequency water quality data from in‐situ sensors provide an opportunity to solve this problem. However, long‐term sensing in complex natural environments usually suffers more significant errors. This study aimed to develop a novel method to utilize in‐situ sensor data in WWQ modeling, namely, the Bayesian calibration using multisource observations (BCMSO), which can simultaneously assimilate laboratory‐based observations and in‐situ sensor data. Both synthetic and real‐world cases of nitrate modeling were used to demonstrate the methodology, and the Soil and Water Assessment Tool (SWAT) was employed as the WWQ model. The results indicated that direct assimilation of sensor data using traditional Bayesian calibration generated obvious deviations in parameter inference and model simulation, which could consequently bias future predictions and affect management decision correctness. However, after proper treatment of errors in sensor data, the BCMSO method could extract meaningful information from sensor data and prevent negative impacts of errors. The modeling uncertainty was also greatly reduced. In the real‐world case, with one year of subhourly electrical conductivity sensor data incorporated, the modeling uncertainty of nitrate concentration and management cost of controlling nitrate pollution were reduced by 70%. The BCMSO method provides a flexible framework to accommodate nonconventional observations in environmental modeling and can be easily extended to other modeling fields. This article is protected by copyright.版权所有。</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;Uncertainty reduction in watershed water quality (WWQ) modeling remains a major challenge. One important reason is the lack of sufficient available water quality observations because traditional laboratory analysis of water samples has high labor, financial and time costs. Low-cost high-frequency water quality data from in-situ sensors provide an opportunity to solve this problem. However, long-term sensing in complex natural environments usually suffers more significant errors. This study aimed to develop a novel method to utilize in-situ sensor data in WWQ modeling, namely, the Bayesian calibration using multisource observations (BCMSO), which can simultaneously assimilate laboratory-based observations and in-situ sensor data. Both synthetic and real-world cases of nitrate modeling were used to demonstrate the methodology, and the Soil and Water Assessment Tool (SWAT) was employed as the WWQ model. The results indicated that direct assimilation of sensor data using traditional Bayesian calibration generated obvious deviations in parameter inference and model simulation, which could consequently bias future predictions and affect management decision correctness. However, after proper treatment of errors in sensor data, the BCMSO method could extract meaningful information from sensor data and prevent negative impacts of errors. The modeling uncertainty was also greatly reduced. In the real-world case, with one year of subhourly electrical conductivity sensor data incorporated, the modeling uncertainty of nitrate concentration and management cost of controlling nitrate pollution were reduced by 70%. The BCMSO method provides a flexible framework to accommodate nonconventional observations in environmental modeling and can be easily extended to other modeling fields.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This article is protected by copyright. All rights reserved.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> Feng Han, Zhaoping Hu, Nengwang Chen, Yao Wang, Jiping Jiang, Yi Zheng</dc:creator><category> Research Article</category><dc:title> Assimilating low‐cost high‐frequency sensor data in watershed water quality modeling: A Bayesian approach</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2022WR033673</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1029/2022WR033673</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033673?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> Research Article</prism:section></item><item><link/> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033566?af=R<pubDate> Fri, 14 Apr 2023 12:49:57 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-04-14T12:49:57-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley: Water Resources Research: Table of Contents <prism:coverdate></prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate></prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR033566</guid><title> Water age dynamics in plant transpiration: The effects of climate patterns and rooting depth</title><description> Water Resources Research, Accepted Article.</description><dc:description> Abstract Water ages in plant transpiration reveal important processes of water dynamics in soil‐plant‐atmosphere continuum, which is regulated by water variability and availability in both precipitation inputs and root zone. However, the impacts of climate patterns and rooting depth on water age dynamics in transpiration are inadequately investigated. In this study, variations in root‐zone water replenishment are estimated based on stable isotope compositions of precipitation and plant xylem water, and a piecewise linear mixing water age model is employed to quantify water ages in plant transpiration under five different climates. The results show that water ages in transpiration are very dynamic in all climates with a range between 1 and 229 days. Water replenishments in the root‐zone reveal whether and how much precipitation enters the root zone. Climate patterns control median (mean) water age in plant transpiration but modified by rooting depth. In wet climates, plants mainly rely on water source that originates from precipitation in the current month (accounting for about 60% on average of their water sources), while plants in dry climates largely rely on water source that originates from precipitation fallen on previous months/seasons. These indicate that climate has profound impacts on plant water source by regulating precipitation inputs, root zone water storage and residence time, and evapotranspiration. Despite the limitations of this study, our study provides an alternative way to reveal the precipitation partitioning in root‐zone and seasonal changes in plant water use of precipitation, which highlights different vegetation responses to water variability between climate types. This article is protected by copyright.版权所有。</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;Water ages in plant transpiration reveal important processes of water dynamics in soil-plant-atmosphere continuum, which is regulated by water variability and availability in both precipitation inputs and root zone. However, the impacts of climate patterns and rooting depth on water age dynamics in transpiration are inadequately investigated. In this study, variations in root-zone water replenishment are estimated based on stable isotope compositions of precipitation and plant xylem water, and a piecewise linear mixing water age model is employed to quantify water ages in plant transpiration under five different climates. The results show that water ages in transpiration are very dynamic in all climates with a range between 1 and 229 days. Water replenishments in the root-zone reveal whether and how much precipitation enters the root zone. Climate patterns control median (mean) water age in plant transpiration but modified by rooting depth. In wet climates, plants mainly rely on water source that originates from precipitation in the current month (accounting for about 60% on average of their water sources), while plants in dry climates largely rely on water source that originates from precipitation fallen on previous months/seasons. These indicate that climate has profound impacts on plant water source by regulating precipitation inputs, root zone water storage and residence time, and evapotranspiration. Despite the limitations of this study, our study provides an alternative way to reveal the precipitation partitioning in root-zone and seasonal changes in plant water use of precipitation, which highlights different vegetation responses to water variability between climate types.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This article is protected by copyright. All rights reserved.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> Zidong Luo, Yunpeng Nie, Hongsong Chen, Huade Guan, Xinping Zhang, Kelin Wang</dc:creator><category> Research Article</category><dc:title> Water age dynamics in plant transpiration: The effects of climate patterns and rooting depth</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2022WR033566</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1029/2022WR033566</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033566?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> Research Article</prism:section></item><item><link/> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033881?af=R<pubDate> Fri, 14 Apr 2023 12:49:08 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-04-14T12:49:08-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley: Water Resources Research: Table of Contents <prism:coverdate></prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate></prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR033881</guid><title> Urban surface thermal runoff generation mechanism and scenario simulation</title><description> Water Resources Research, Accepted Article.</description><dc:description> Abstract When precipitation happens in summer, the thermal runoff from impervious surfaces flow into urban lakes, causing the rise of the surface water temperature. Such a process eventually leads to the short‐term effects of cyanobacteria blooms in eutrophic lakes and the long‐term effects of changes in the structure and quantity of lake species. It is of great scientific significance to understand the heat exchange process between surface air, underlying surface, and surface runoff and reveal the thermal runoff formation mechanism. In this study, the heat transfer models between land, surface‐air, and surface‐water were implemented, aiming to quantify the heating process of surface runoff caused by surface heat load under real conditions. The results show that the two established models can accurately simulate the heat exchange process. Based on our model simulations and field measurements, we analyzed the impact of weather conditions, hydrological conditions, and underlying surface types on runoff temperature. The study finds that the initial surface temperature, wind speed, rainfall intensity, thermal conductivity, and the underlying surface&#39;s water permeability can explain 95.4% and 91.9% of the observed differences in surface runoff heating and temperature increase rate, respectively. The initial surface temperature is the most critical factor in the heat exchange process. The reduction of urban ventilation will aggravate the heat effect of surface runoff. Compared with the underlying permeable surface, the impervious surface is the main driving force for the formation of surface thermal runoff pollution. This article is protected by copyright.版权所有。</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;When precipitation happens in summer, the thermal runoff from impervious surfaces flow into urban lakes, causing the rise of the surface water temperature. Such a process eventually leads to the short-term effects of cyanobacteria blooms in eutrophic lakes and the long-term effects of changes in the structure and quantity of lake species. It is of great scientific significance to understand the heat exchange process between surface air, underlying surface, and surface runoff and reveal the thermal runoff formation mechanism. In this study, the heat transfer models between land, surface-air, and surface-water were implemented, aiming to quantify the heating process of surface runoff caused by surface heat load under real conditions. The results show that the two established models can accurately simulate the heat exchange process. Based on our model simulations and field measurements, we analyzed the impact of weather conditions, hydrological conditions, and underlying surface types on runoff temperature. The study finds that the initial surface temperature, wind speed, rainfall intensity, thermal conductivity, and the underlying surface&#39;s water permeability can explain 95.4% and 91.9% of the observed differences in surface runoff heating and temperature increase rate, respectively. The initial surface temperature is the most critical factor in the heat exchange process. The reduction of urban ventilation will aggravate the heat effect of surface runoff. Compared with the underlying permeable surface, the impervious surface is the main driving force for the formation of surface thermal runoff pollution.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This article is protected by copyright. All rights reserved.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> Yi Luo, Yang Zhang, Kun Yang, Xiaolu Zhou, Zongqi Peng</dc:creator><category> Research Article</category><dc:title> Urban surface thermal runoff generation mechanism and scenario simulation</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2022WR033881</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1029/2022WR033881</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033881?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> Research Article</prism:section></item><item><link/> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR032741?af=R<pubDate> Fri, 14 Apr 2023 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-04-14T12:00:00-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley: Water Resources Research: Table of Contents <prism:coverdate></prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate></prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR032741</guid><title> Semicentennial Response of a Bifurcation Region in an Engineered River to Peak Flows and Human Interventions</title><description> Water Resources Research, Accepted Article.</description><dc:description> Abstract A bifurcation in an engineered river system (ie, fixed planform and width) has fewer degrees of freedom in its response to interventions and natural changes than a natural bifurcation system. Our objective is to provide insight into how a bifurcation in an engineered river responds to peak flows and human interventions. To this end, we analyze the change in hydraulics, bed level, and bed surface grain size in the region of two bifurcations in the upper Rhine delta in the Netherlands over the last century. We show that, over the last two decades, the water discharge in one bifurcate (the Waal branch) has steadily increased at the expense of the other. This gradual increase in the water discharge of the first branch is associated with its erosion rate being larger than the other branch. The quick succession of two or three peak flow events (1993, 1995, 1998) caused rapid sediment deposition over the upstream part of the bifurcate that has gradually lost discharge, which seems to have triggered the slow change in flow partitioning.</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;A bifurcation in an engineered river system (ie, fixed planform and width) has fewer degrees of freedom in its response to interventions and natural changes than a natural bifurcation system. Our objective is to provide insight into how a bifurcation in an engineered river responds to peak flows and human interventions. To this end, we analyze the change in hydraulics, bed level, and bed surface grain size in the region of two bifurcations in the upper Rhine delta in the Netherlands over the last century. We show that, over the last two decades, the water discharge in one bifurcate (the Waal branch) has steadily increased at the expense of the other. This gradual increase in the water discharge of the first branch is associated with its erosion rate being larger than the other branch. The quick succession of two or three peak flow events (1993, 1995, 1998) caused rapid sediment deposition over the upstream part of the bifurcate that has gradually lost discharge, which seems to have triggered the slow change in flow partitioning.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> M. Kifayath Chowdhury, Astrid Blom, Clàudia Ylla Arbós, Merel C. Verbeek, Max HI Schropp, Ralph MJ Schielen</dc:creator><category> Research Article</category><dc:title> Semicentennial Response of a Bifurcation Region in an Engineered River to Peak Flows and Human Interventions</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2022WR032741</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1029/2022WR032741</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR032741?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> Research Article</prism:section></item><item><link/> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033646?af=R<pubDate> Thu, 13 Apr 2023 08:09:48 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-04-13T08:09:48-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley: Water Resources Research: Table of Contents<prism:coverdate> Sat, 01 Apr 2023 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate> Sat, 01 Apr 2023 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR033646</guid><title> Review of Quantitative Applications of the Concept of the Water Planetary Boundary at Different Spatial Scales</title><description> Water Resources Research, Volume 59, Issue 4, April 2023.</description><dc:description> Abstract The water planetary boundary (PB) quantifies a safe operating space for human water consumption and is understood as a control‐variable set at a safe distance from a selected threshold (or dangerous level) based on precautionary principles. The water PB is useful for guiding sustainable development, and various multiscale quantitative assessments of water PB have been conducted. To improve our understanding and guide future applications, we conduct a comprehensive review of all studies published since the concept&#39;s introduction. We identify a total of 288 relevant papers in the literature and perform a systematic review and meta‐analysis of 28 papers providing 488 data records at various spatial scales. The analyses mainly involve the relevant quantification indicators, quantification methods, comparisons of the water PB with the current state of water consumption at different scales, and the identification of associated problems. Finally, we propose 10 outlooks for important future research. This review indicates that the theoretical water‐PB framework, as an early‐stage research area, has gradually developed, despite the few, imperfect available methods. To address the limitations of previous studies, we propose two improvement frameworks for guiding future research: the further improvement of traditional popular approaches to quantifying the multiscale water PB within a consistent scientific framework and an improved framework for quantifying the water PB at various scales to obtain better‐fitting results for different research purposes and study areas. Based on this review, we point out some important issues that have received little attention, including the quantification of safe distances and the linkages between multiscale water PBs.</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;The water planetary boundary (PB) quantifies a safe operating space for human water consumption and is understood as a control-variable set at a safe distance from a selected threshold (or dangerous level) based on precautionary principles. The water PB is useful for guiding sustainable development, and various multiscale quantitative assessments of water PB have been conducted. To improve our understanding and guide future applications, we conduct a comprehensive review of all studies published since the concept&#39;s introduction. We identify a total of 288 relevant papers in the literature and perform a systematic review and meta-analysis of 28 papers providing 488 data records at various spatial scales. The analyses mainly involve the relevant quantification indicators, quantification methods, comparisons of the water PB with the current state of water consumption at different scales, and the identification of associated problems. Finally, we propose 10 outlooks for important future research. This review indicates that the theoretical water-PB framework, as an early-stage research area, has gradually developed, despite the few, imperfect available methods. To address the limitations of previous studies, we propose two improvement frameworks for guiding future research: the further improvement of traditional popular approaches to quantifying the multiscale water PB within a consistent scientific framework and an improved framework for quantifying the water PB at various scales to obtain better-fitting results for different research purposes and study areas. Based on this review, we point out some important issues that have received little attention, including the quantification of safe distances and the linkages between multiscale water PBs.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> Siqi Han, Guoyong Leng, Linfei Yu</dc:creator><category> Review Article</category><dc:title> Review of Quantitative Applications of the Concept of the Water Planetary Boundary at Different Spatial Scales</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2022WR033646</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1029/2022WR033646</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033646?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> Review Article</prism:section><prism:volume> 59</prism:volume><prism:number> 4</prism:number></item><item><link/> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033584?af=R<pubDate> Thu, 13 Apr 2023 08:05:18 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-04-13T08:05:18-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley: Water Resources Research: Table of Contents<prism:coverdate> Sat, 01 Apr 2023 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate> Sat, 01 Apr 2023 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR033584</guid><title> A Portable Device for On‐Site Measurement of Sediment Concentration Through Volume‐Mass Replacement</title><description> Water Resources Research, Volume 59, Issue 4, April 2023.</description><dc:description> Abstract To enable on‐site and near‐real‐time sediment concentration measurements, a novel type of portable device with a constant volume sampling bottle was developed in this study. The device consisted of a sampling bottle, a measuring assembly, and a platform for auxiliary data management. Five representative soils and eight sediment concentrations were used to validate the device accuracy and application. Moreover, a novel concept of sediment effective density (SED) was proposed. Under SED, a linear regression was fit between the measured and actual sediment concentrations. The results revealed that the slopes of the fitting line were close to 1, and the R2 values were greater than 0.999 for five soils. Moreover, for total samples, the root mean square error (RMSE) and Nash–Sutcliffe efficiency coefficient (NSE) values were 5.59 g/L and 0.9996, respectively. Additionally, an average SED of 2.51 g/cm3 was calculated in this study. With an average soil SED of 2.51 g/cm3 and an average soil solid density of 2.65 g/cm3, the RMSE and NSE were 11.85 and 18.50 g/L and 0.9981 and 0.9954, respectively. This result demonstrated that the designed device accurately measured sediment concentration under various conditions. Furthermore, relative to the traditional oven‐drying method, the device could measure sediment concentration near‐real‐time and with high accuracy, which could be useful for researchers with excellent potential. It was recommended to measure the SED in a laboratory or runoff plot because the sediment sources could be identified and obtained. In a field or river, it was recommended to use 2.51 g/cm3 as the SED, which was more accurate than 2.65 g/cm3.</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;To enable on-site and near-real-time sediment concentration measurements, a novel type of portable device with a constant volume sampling bottle was developed in this study. The device consisted of a sampling bottle, a measuring assembly, and a platform for auxiliary data management. Five representative soils and eight sediment concentrations were used to validate the device accuracy and application. Moreover, a novel concept of sediment effective density (SED) was proposed. Under SED, a linear regression was fit between the measured and actual sediment concentrations. The results revealed that the slopes of the fitting line were close to 1, and the R&lt;sup>;2&lt;/sup>; values were greater than 0.999 for five soils. Moreover, for total samples, the root mean square error (RMSE) and Nash–Sutcliffe efficiency coefficient (NSE) values were 5.59 g/L and 0.9996, respectively. Additionally, an average SED of 2.51 g/cm&lt;sup>;3&lt;/sup>; was calculated in this study. With an average soil SED of 2.51 g/cm&lt;sup>;3&lt;/sup>; and an average soil solid density of 2.65 g/cm&lt;sup>;3&lt;/sup>;, the RMSE and NSE were 11.85 and 18.50 g/L and 0.9981 and 0.9954, respectively. This result demonstrated that the designed device accurately measured sediment concentration under various conditions. Furthermore, relative to the traditional oven-drying method, the device could measure sediment concentration near-real-time and with high accuracy, which could be useful for researchers with excellent potential. It was recommended to measure the SED in a laboratory or runoff plot because the sediment sources could be identified and obtained. In a field or river, it was recommended to use 2.51 g/cm&lt;sup>;3&lt;/sup>; as the SED, which was more accurate than 2.65 g/cm&lt;sup>;3&lt;/sup>;.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> Qiuxing Yue, Xiaoyun Zhan, Minghang Guo, Jun Zhao, Baoyuan Liu</dc:creator><category> Method</category><dc:title> A Portable Device for On‐Site Measurement of Sediment Concentration Through Volume‐Mass Replacement</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2022WR033584</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1029/2022WR033584</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033584?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> Method</prism:section><prism:volume> 59</prism:volume><prism:number> 4</prism:number></item><item><link/> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR032578?af=R<pubDate> Thu, 13 Apr 2023 08:01:20 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-04-13T08:01:20-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley: Water Resources Research: Table of Contents<prism:coverdate> Sat, 01 Apr 2023 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate> Sat, 01 Apr 2023 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR032578</guid><title> Subsurface Porewater Flow Accelerates Talik Development Under the Alaska Highway, Yukon: A Prelude to Road Collapse and Final Permafrost Thaw?</title><description> Water Resources Research, Volume 59, Issue 4, April 2023.</description><dc:description> Abstract The presence of taliks (perennially unfrozen zones in permafrost areas) adversely affects the thermal stability of infrastructure in cold regions, including roads. The role of heat advection on talik development and feedback on permafrost degradation has not been quantified methodically in this context. We incorporate a surface energy balance model into a coupled groundwater flow and energy transport numerical model (SUTRA‐ice). The model, calibrated with long‐term observations (1997–2018 on the Alaska Highway), is used to investigate and quantify the role of heat advection on talik initiation and development under a road embankment. Over the 25‐year simulation period, the new model is driven by reconstructed meteorological data and has a good agreement with near surface soil temperatures. The model successfully reproduces the increasing depth to the permafrost table (mean absolute error &lt;0.2 m), and talik development. The results demonstrate that heat advection provides an additional energy source that expedites the rate of permafrost thaw and roughly doubles the rate of permafrost table deepening, compared to purely conductive thawing. Talik initially formed and grew over time under the combined effect of water flow, snow insulation, road construction and climate warming. Talik formation creates a new thermal state under the road embankment, resulting in acceleration of underlying permafrost degradation, due to the positive feedback of heat accumulation created by trapped unfrozen water. In a changing climate, mobile water flow will play a more important role in permafrost thaw and talik development under road embankments, and is likely to significantly increase maintenance costs and reduce the long‐term stability of the infrastructure.</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;The presence of taliks (perennially unfrozen zones in permafrost areas) adversely affects the thermal stability of infrastructure in cold regions, including roads. The role of heat advection on talik development and feedback on permafrost degradation has not been quantified methodically in this context. We incorporate a surface energy balance model into a coupled groundwater flow and energy transport numerical model (SUTRA-ice). The model, calibrated with long-term observations (1997–2018 on the Alaska Highway), is used to investigate and quantify the role of heat advection on talik initiation and development under a road embankment. Over the 25-year simulation period, the new model is driven by reconstructed meteorological data and has a good agreement with near surface soil temperatures. The model successfully reproduces the increasing depth to the permafrost table (mean absolute error &amp;lt;0.2 m), and talik development. The results demonstrate that heat advection provides an additional energy source that expedites the rate of permafrost thaw and roughly doubles the rate of permafrost table deepening, compared to purely conductive thawing. Talik initially formed and grew over time under the combined effect of water flow, snow insulation, road construction and climate warming. Talik formation creates a new thermal state under the road embankment, resulting in acceleration of underlying permafrost degradation, due to the positive feedback of heat accumulation created by trapped unfrozen water. In a changing climate, mobile water flow will play a more important role in permafrost thaw and talik development under road embankments, and is likely to significantly increase maintenance costs and reduce the long-term stability of the infrastructure.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> Lin Chen, Daniel Fortier, Jeffrey M. McKenzie, Clifford I. Voss, Pierrick Lamontagne‐Hallé</dc:creator><category> Research Article</category><dc:title> Subsurface Porewater Flow Accelerates Talik Development Under the Alaska Highway, Yukon: A Prelude to Road Collapse and Final Permafrost Thaw?</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2022WR032578</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1029/2022WR032578</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR032578?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> Research Article</prism:section><prism:volume> 59</prism:volume><prism:number> 4</prism:number></item><item><link/> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR032529?af=R<pubDate> Wed, 12 Apr 2023 13:20:06 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-04-12T01:20:06-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley: Water Resources Research: Table of Contents<prism:coverdate> Sat, 01 Apr 2023 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate> Sat, 01 Apr 2023 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR032529</guid><title> The Role of Inflow and Infiltration (I/I) in Urban Water Balances and Streamflow Regimes: A Hydrograph Analysis Along the Sewershed‐Watershed Continuum</title><description> Water Resources Research, Volume 59, Issue 4, April 2023.</description><dc:description> Abstract Urbanization alters subsurface flow pathways through expansion of sanitary collection and conveyance infrastructure. Inflow and infiltration (I/I) into sewers redistributes slow subsurface flows to fast within‐sewer flows. Acting in concert with connected surface water, redistribution through I/I complicates the net impact of urbanization on streamflow. Elucidation of these processes is key to the characterization and prediction of urban hydrologic cycles. In this study, we collected sanitary sewer flow and streamflow data from 17 sewersheds and 18 watersheds in and around Milwaukee, WI, USA. We compared flow duration curves and baseflow recession characteristics of I/I and streamflow in urban and reference watersheds. Median depth‐normalized I/I (296 mm) was nearly 35% of mean annual precipitation (867 mm), and thereby a major component of the urban drainage budget. I/I flowrates were similar to urban streamflow during high flow events (10th percentile) and larger during intermediate (50th percentile) and low (90th percentile) flow events. Further, I/I recession was slower and more nonlinear in shape than urban streamflow. Increased imperviousness and sewer density were associated with increased high flows, decreased intermediate flows, and quicker streamflow recessions. Sewer density explained more variability in intermediate flows (35%) and baseflow recession rate (49%) than imperviousness (24% and 19% respectively). Based on our findings, I/I takes up valuable volume capacity in sewers, which leads to more frequent overflows and alters streamflow regimes with ecological implications. Thus, I/I should be better considered in the prediction of urban hydrologic fluxes, and the characteristics and hydro‐ecologic impact of I/I should be more thoroughly explored.</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;Urbanization alters subsurface flow pathways through expansion of sanitary collection and conveyance infrastructure. Inflow and infiltration (I/I) into sewers redistributes slow subsurface flows to fast within-sewer flows. Acting in concert with connected surface water, redistribution through I/I complicates the net impact of urbanization on streamflow. Elucidation of these processes is key to the characterization and prediction of urban hydrologic cycles. In this study, we collected sanitary sewer flow and streamflow data from 17 sewersheds and 18 watersheds in and around Milwaukee, WI, USA. We compared flow duration curves and baseflow recession characteristics of I/I and streamflow in urban and reference watersheds. Median depth-normalized I/I (296 mm) was nearly 35% of mean annual precipitation (867 mm), and thereby a major component of the urban drainage budget. I/I flowrates were similar to urban streamflow during high flow events (10th percentile) and larger during intermediate (50th percentile) and low (90th percentile) flow events. Further, I/I recession was slower and more nonlinear in shape than urban streamflow. Increased imperviousness and sewer density were associated with increased high flows, decreased intermediate flows, and quicker streamflow recessions. Sewer density explained more variability in intermediate flows (35%) and baseflow recession rate (49%) than imperviousness (24% and 19% respectively). Based on our findings, I/I takes up valuable volume capacity in sewers, which leads to more frequent overflows and alters streamflow regimes with ecological implications. Thus, I/I should be better considered in the prediction of urban hydrologic fluxes, and the characteristics and hydro-ecologic impact of I/I should be more thoroughly explored.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> Kun Zhang, Spencer Sebo, Walter McDonald, Aditi Bhaskar, William Shuster, Ryan D. Stewart, Anthony J. Parolari</dc:creator><category> Research Article</category><dc:title> The Role of Inflow and Infiltration (I/I) in Urban Water Balances and Streamflow Regimes: A Hydrograph Analysis Along the Sewershed‐Watershed Continuum</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2022WR032529</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1029/2022WR032529</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR032529?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> Research Article</prism:section><prism:volume> 59</prism:volume><prism:number> 4</prism:number></item><item><link/> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033831?af=R<pubDate> Wed, 12 Apr 2023 13:14:57 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-04-12T01:14:57-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley: Water Resources Research: Table of Contents<prism:coverdate> Sat, 01 Apr 2023 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate> Sat, 01 Apr 2023 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR033831</guid><title> A Short‐Term Pumping Strategy for Hydraulic Tomography Based on the Successive Linear Estimator</title><description> Water Resources Research, Volume 59, Issue 4, April 2023.</description><dc:description> Abstract In this study, the random finite element method, a finite element method with random field generation techniques, was applied to investigate the cross correlations between the observed head and hydraulic conductivity and specific storage at different locations and different times in pumping tests. The results show that the two cross correlations between the pumping well and the observation well reach their maximums before pumping reaches a steady state. Specifically, the cross correlation between the observed head and hydraulic conductivity is the greatest when the temporal derivative of the observed head does not change significantly, and that between the observed head and specific storage is the greatest when the temporal derivative (the rate) of the observed head is maximum. Based on the results of cross‐correlation analysis, a short‐term pumping strategy for hydraulic tomography is proposed to obtain the spatial distribution of hydraulic conductivity and specific storage using the successive linear estimator. Furthermore, this strategy was validated by Monte Carlo simulations. This paper points out that the sensitivity and cross‐correlation analyses report the ensemble (averaged) behaviors of any heterogeneous aquifers, which is not necessarily suitable for one realization. Furthermore, Monte Carlo simulation is suggested for validating any groundwater inverse modeling result.</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;In this study, the random finite element method, a finite element method with random field generation techniques, was applied to investigate the cross correlations between the observed head and hydraulic conductivity and specific storage at different locations and different times in pumping tests. The results show that the two cross correlations between the pumping well and the observation well reach their maximums before pumping reaches a steady state. Specifically, the cross correlation between the observed head and hydraulic conductivity is the greatest when the temporal derivative of the observed head does not change significantly, and that between the observed head and specific storage is the greatest when the temporal derivative (the rate) of the observed head is maximum. Based on the results of cross-correlation analysis, a short-term pumping strategy for hydraulic tomography is proposed to obtain the spatial distribution of hydraulic conductivity and specific storage using the successive linear estimator. Furthermore, this strategy was validated by Monte Carlo simulations. This paper points out that the sensitivity and cross-correlation analyses report the ensemble (averaged) behaviors of any heterogeneous aquifers, which is not necessarily suitable for one realization. Furthermore, Monte Carlo simulation is suggested for validating any groundwater inverse modeling result.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> Xiaolan Hou, Rui Hu, Tian‐Chyi Jim Yeh, Yukun Li, Junjie Qi, Yang Song, Huiyang Qiu</dc:creator><category> Research Article</category><dc:title> A Short‐Term Pumping Strategy for Hydraulic Tomography Based on the Successive Linear Estimator</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2022WR033831</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1029/2022WR033831</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033831?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> Research Article</prism:section><prism:volume> 59</prism:volume><prism:number> 4</prism:number></item><item><link/> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR034305?af=R<pubDate> Wed, 12 Apr 2023 13:14:14 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-04-12T01:14:14-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley: Water Resources Research: Table of Contents<prism:coverdate> Sat, 01 Apr 2023 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate> Sat, 01 Apr 2023 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR034305</guid><title> Spatiotemporal Variability of Current and Future Sub‐Daily Rainfall in Japan Using State‐Of‐The‐Art High‐Quality Data Sets</title><description> Water Resources Research, Volume 59, Issue 4, April 2023.</description><dc:description> Abstract Using potentially best available rainfall data sets for the entire country of Japan (spatial scales of 1‐ and 20‐km), we analyze the 1–24 hr and city‐scale (1–400 km2) extreme rainfalls for both current (2006–2020) and future periods (2081–2109) at 1.5 K global warming scenario, complementing previous work that focuses on either coarse spatial and temporal scales or other warming scenarios (eg, RCP and 2 K warming scenarios). A peak‐over‐threshold (POT)‐based approach is applied to compute areal reduction factor (ARF) for subsequently establishing intensity‐duration‐area‐frequency (IDAF) curves. Our results reveal that ARF values generally decrease with increasing area size and increase with longer duration and are affected by multiple underlying physical phenomena. Moreover, we find a greater increase in the rainfall intensities for shorter durations and higher return periods, ranging from 9.4% (1‐hr) to 6.2% (24‐hr), averaged for all return periods and 8.3% (25‐year) to 7.3% (2‐year), averaged for all rainfall durations. Spatially, extreme rainfall intensities are projected to increase by 8.9% in northern Japan (albeit with a less intense rainfall intensity in the current period), which is greater than the rest of the country (6.8%), underscoring the need to focus more on infrastructure designs in northern Japan. The projected IDAF curves further display an increase in the frequency of extreme events at city‐scale, for example, 25‐year extreme rainfall events in 2006–2020 would likely be 5‐10‐year events in 2081–2109. Our results with the state‐of‐the‐art data and implementable approach can be utilized for policymaking to reduce the warming‐induced risks in Japan and beyond.</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;Using potentially best available rainfall data sets for the entire country of Japan (spatial scales of 1- and 20-km), we analyze the 1–24 hr and city-scale (1–400 km&lt;sup>;2&lt;/sup>;) extreme rainfalls for both current (2006–2020) and future periods (2081–2109) at 1.5 K global warming scenario, complementing previous work that focuses on either coarse spatial and temporal scales or other warming scenarios (eg, RCP and 2 K warming scenarios). A peak-over-threshold (POT)-based approach is applied to compute areal reduction factor (ARF) for subsequently establishing intensity-duration-area-frequency (IDAF) curves. Our results reveal that ARF values generally decrease with increasing area size and increase with longer duration and are affected by multiple underlying physical phenomena. Moreover, we find a greater increase in the rainfall intensities for shorter durations and higher return periods, ranging from 9.4% (1-hr) to 6.2% (24-hr), averaged for all return periods and 8.3% (25-year) to 7.3% (2-year), averaged for all rainfall durations. Spatially, extreme rainfall intensities are projected to increase by 8.9% in northern Japan (albeit with a less intense rainfall intensity in the current period), which is greater than the rest of the country (6.8%), underscoring the need to focus more on infrastructure designs in northern Japan. The projected IDAF curves further display an increase in the frequency of extreme events at city-scale, for example, 25-year extreme rainfall events in 2006–2020 would likely be 5-10-year events in 2081–2109. Our results with the state-of-the-art data and implementable approach can be utilized for policymaking to reduce the warming-induced risks in Japan and beyond.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> Wenpeng Zhao, Abhishek, Bijoychandra S. Takhellambam, Jiantao Zhang, Yakun Zhao, Tsuyoshi Kinouchi</dc:creator><category> Research Article</category><dc:title> Spatiotemporal Variability of Current and Future Sub‐Daily Rainfall in Japan Using State‐Of‐The‐Art High‐Quality Data Sets</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2022WR034305</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1029/2022WR034305</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR034305?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> Research Article</prism:section><prism:volume> 59</prism:volume><prism:number> 4</prism:number></item><item><link/> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033342?af=R<pubDate> Tue, 11 Apr 2023 13:07:46 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-04-11T01:07:46-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley: Water Resources Research: Table of Contents<prism:coverdate> Sat, 01 Apr 2023 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate> Sat, 01 Apr 2023 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR033342</guid><title> Is It Possible to Quantify Irrigation Water‐Use by Assimilating a High‐Resolution Satellite Soil Moisture Product?</title><description> Water Resources Research, Volume 59, Issue 4, April 2023.</description><dc:description> Abstract Irrigation is the largest human intervention in the water cycle that can modulate climate extremes, yet irrigation water use (IWU) remains largely unknown in most regions. Microwave remote sensing offers a practical way to quantify IWU by monitoring changes in soil moisture caused by irrigation. However, high‐resolution satellite soil moisture data is typically infrequent (eg, 6–12 days) and thus may miss irrigation events. This study evaluates the ability to quantify IWU by assimilating high‐resolution (1 km) SMAP‐Sentinel 1 remotely sensed soil moisture with a physically based land surface model (LSM) using a particle batch smoother (PBS). A suite of synthetic experiments is devised to evaluate different error sources. Results from the synthetic experiments show that unbiased simulations with known irrigation timing can produce an accurate irrigation estimate with a mean annual bias of 0.45% and a mean R2 of 0.97, relative to observed IWU. Unknown irrigation timing can significantly deteriorate the model performance, resulting in an increased mean annual bias to 23% and decreased mean R2 to 0.36. Adding random noise to synthetic observations does not significantly decrease model performance except for the experiments with low observation frequency (>;12 days). In real‐world experiments, the PBS data assimilation approach underestimates observed IWU by 18.6% when the timing of IWU is known. IWU estimates are consistently significantly higher over irrigated pixels compared to the non‐irrigated pixels, indicating data assimilation skillfully conveys irrigation signals to the LSM.</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;Irrigation is the largest human intervention in the water cycle that can modulate climate extremes, yet irrigation water use (IWU) remains largely unknown in most regions. Microwave remote sensing offers a practical way to quantify IWU by monitoring changes in soil moisture caused by irrigation. However, high-resolution satellite soil moisture data is typically infrequent (eg, 6–12 days) and thus may miss irrigation events. This study evaluates the ability to quantify IWU by assimilating high-resolution (1 km) SMAP-Sentinel 1 remotely sensed soil moisture with a physically based land surface model (LSM) using a particle batch smoother (PBS). A suite of synthetic experiments is devised to evaluate different error sources. Results from the synthetic experiments show that unbiased simulations with known irrigation timing can produce an accurate irrigation estimate with a mean annual bias of 0.45% and a mean &lt;i>;R&lt;/i>; &lt;sup>;2&lt;/sup>; of 0.97, relative to observed IWU. Unknown irrigation timing can significantly deteriorate the model performance, resulting in an increased mean annual bias to 23% and decreased mean &lt;i>;R&lt;/i>; &lt;sup>;2&lt;/sup>; to 0.36. Adding random noise to synthetic observations does not significantly decrease model performance except for the experiments with low observation frequency (&amp;gt;12 days). In real-world experiments, the PBS data assimilation approach underestimates observed IWU by 18.6% when the timing of IWU is known. IWU estimates are consistently significantly higher over irrigated pixels compared to the non-irrigated pixels, indicating data assimilation skillfully conveys irrigation signals to the LSM.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> Ehsan Jalilvand, Ronnie Abolafia‐Rosenzweig, Masoud Tajrishy, Sujay V. Kumar, Mohammad Reza Mohammadi, Narendra N. Das</dc:creator><category> Research Article</category><dc:title> Is It Possible to Quantify Irrigation Water‐Use by Assimilating a High‐Resolution Satellite Soil Moisture Product?</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2022WR033342</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1029/2022WR033342</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033342?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> Research Article</prism:section><prism:volume> 59</prism:volume><prism:number> 4</prism:number></item></channel></rss>