<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:prism="http://prismstandard.org/namespaces/basic/2.0/"><channel><title> Wiley：水资源研究：目录</title><link/>https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R<description>水资源研究目录。最新和 EarlyView 问题的文章列表。</description><language>英文</language><copyright></copyright><managingeditor>wileyonlinelibrary@wiley.com（AGU 出版物）</managingeditor><pubDate> Sun, 12 Feb 2023 08:30:14 +0000</pubDate><lastbuilddate> 2023 年 2 月 12 日，星期日 08:30:14 +0000</lastbuilddate><generator> Atypon®文学™</generator><docs> https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs><ttl> 10080</ttl><dc:title> Wiley：水资源研究：目录</dc:title><dc:publisher>威利</dc:publisher><prism:publicationname>水资源研究</prism:publicationname><atom:link href="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"></atom:link><image/><title> Wiley：水资源研究：目录</title><url>https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/pb-assets/journal-banners/19447973.jpg</url><link/> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R<item><link/> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033168?af=R<pubDate> Sat, 11 Feb 2023 04:58:54 -0800</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-02-11T04:58:54-08:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley：水资源研究：目录<prism:coverdate></prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate></prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR033168</guid><title>用于缩减大规模河流模型的 Saint-Venant 方程的物理信息神经网络</title><description>水资源研究，接受的文章。</description><dc:description>摘要 正在改进沿海地区的大型河流模型，以提高对沿海过程、灾害和气候变化响应的科学认识。然而，潮汐河流物理表示中的粗网格分辨率和近似值限制了此类模型在解决复杂流动动力学方面的性能，尤其是在江河-海洋界面附近，导致洪水泛滥的模拟不准确。在这项研究中，我们提出了一种基于最先进的物理信息神经网络 (PINN) 的机器学习 (ML) 框架，以模拟子网格尺度下的缩小流。首先，我们证明 PINN 能够吸收各种类型的观测值并直接求解一维 (1-D) 圣维南方程 (SVE)。我们在几个综合案例研究中对漫滩和明渠进行了流动模拟。 PINN 性能根据解析解和数值模型进行评估。我们的结果表明，水深的 PINN 解具有令人满意的精度，同化了有限的观测值。在风暴潮和潮汐引起的洪水波传播的情况下，提出了一种基于傅立叶特征嵌入的新神经网络架构，该架构无缝编码 PINN 公式中的周期性潮汐边界条件。此外，我们表明，基于 PINN 的降尺度可以通过同化观测数据产生更合理的沿河水深亚网格解。 PINN 解决方案在解决亚网格尺度的地形和动态流态方面优于简单的线性插值。这项研究为提高大型模型的仿真能力以表征精细的沿海过程提供了一条有前途的途径。本文受版权保护。版权所有。</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;摘要&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;沿海地区正在完善大型河流模型，以提高对沿海过程、灾害和气候变化响应的科学认识。然而，潮汐河流物理表示中的粗网格分辨率和近似值限制了此类模型在解决复杂流动动力学方面的性能，尤其是在江河-海洋界面附近，导致洪水泛滥的模拟不准确。在这项研究中，我们提出了一种基于最先进的物理信息神经网络 (PINN) 的机器学习 (ML) 框架，以模拟子网格尺度下的缩小流。首先，我们证明 PINN 能够吸收各种类型的观测值并直接求解一维 (1-D) 圣维南方程 (SVE)。我们在几个综合案例研究中对漫滩和明渠进行了流动模拟。 PINN 性能根据解析解和数值模型进行评估。我们的结果表明，水深的 PINN 解具有令人满意的精度，同化了有限的观测值。在风暴潮和潮汐引起的洪水波传播的情况下，提出了一种基于傅立叶特征嵌入的新神经网络架构，该架构无缝编码 PINN 公式中的周期性潮汐边界条件。此外，我们表明，基于 PINN 的降尺度可以通过同化观测数据产生更合理的沿河水深亚网格解。 PINN 解决方案在解决亚网格尺度的地形和动态流态方面优于简单的线性插值。这项研究为提高大型模型的仿真能力以表征精细海岸过程提供了一条有前途的途径。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;本文受版权保护。保留所有权利。&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator>冯冬雨、谭泽立、何其志</dc:creator><category>研究文章</category><dc:title>用于缩减大规模河流模型的 Saint-Venant 方程的物理信息神经网络</dc:title><dc:identifier>10.1029/2022WR033168</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname>水资源研究</prism:publicationname><prism:doi>10.1029/2022WR033168</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033168?af=R</prism:url><prism:section>研究文章</prism:section></item><item><link/>https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR032475?af=R<pubDate> Sat, 11 Feb 2023 02:10:15 -0800</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-02-11T02:10:15-08:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley：水资源研究：目录<prism:coverdate></prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate></prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR032475</guid><title>小圆盘张力渗透仪导水率的改进计算</title><description>水资源研究，接受的文章。</description><dc:description>摘要 由于张力渗透仪通过有限尺寸的圆盘施加水，因此渗透水会横向和向下移动。只有该流量的垂直分量表示水力传导率 K，因此计算 K 的算法必须包括一种将该分量与总流量隔离开来的方法。一些常用的公式通过减去横向扩散流的估计值来校正多维效应。然而，对于直径小于约 200 毫米的圆盘，横向扩散构成了总流量的很大一部分，以至于这些减法公式失去了相当大的准确性，有时甚至过度校正以至于产生 K 的负数。其他方法依赖于经验主义，即与非饱和流理论不完全一致，需要先了解某些土壤特性。我们开发了一个新公式，该公式使用乘法因子而不是减法项来实现所需的校正。为了进行测试，我们使用代码 VS2DRTI 求解 Richardson-Richards 方程生成的合成数据进行了数值实验，用于不同的介质和一系列磁盘尺寸，包括广泛使用的 45 毫米直径。我们将根据我们的公式计算出的 K 值与用于生成模拟数据的实际 K 值以及其他已发布公式的结果进行了比较。这种比较表明，我们的方法提供了一种基于非饱和流理论的算法，该算法可以为小圆盘生成更可靠的值，而无需事先了解土壤特性。</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;摘要&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;由于张力渗透仪通过有限尺寸的圆盘施加水，因此渗透水会横向和向下移动。只有该流量的垂直分量表示水力传导率 &lt;i>;K&lt;/i>;，因此计算 &lt;i>;K&lt;/i>; 的算法必须包括将该分量与总流量隔离的方法。一些常用的公式通过减去横向扩散流的估计值来校正多维效应。然而，对于直径小于约 200 毫米的圆盘，横向扩散构成了总流量的很大一部分，以至于这些减法公式失去了相当大的准确性，有时甚至会严重过度校正以产生 &lt;i>;K&lt;/i>; 的负数。其他方法依赖于与非饱和流动理论不完全一致的经验主义，并且需要先了解某些土壤特性。我们开发了一个新公式，该公式使用乘法因子而不是减法项来实现所需的校正。为了进行测试，我们使用代码 VS2DRTI 求解 Richardson-Richards 方程生成的合成数据进行了数值实验，用于不同的介质和一系列磁盘尺寸，包括广泛使用的 45 毫米直径。我们将根据我们的公式计算出的 &lt;i>;K&lt;/i>; 值与用于生成模拟数据的实际 &lt;i>;K&lt;/i>; 值以及其他已发布公式的结果进行了比较。这一比较表明，我们的方法提供了一种基于非饱和流理论的算法，无需事先了解土壤特性即可为小圆盘生成更可靠的值。&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator>约翰·R·尼莫、佩奇·R·沃斯</dc:creator><category>研究文章</category><dc:title>小圆盘张力渗透仪导水率的改进计算</dc:title><dc:identifier>10.1029/2022WR032475</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname>水资源研究</prism:publicationname><prism:doi>10.1029/2022WR032475</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR032475?af=R</prism:url><prism:section>研究文章</prism:section></item><item><link/>https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR032472?af=R<pubDate> Fri, 10 Feb 2023 12:13:32 -0800</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-02-10T12:13:32-08:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley：水资源研究：目录<prism:coverdate></prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate></prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR032472</guid><title>地表处于水和能量平衡耦合的临界点</title><description>水资源研究，接受的文章。</description><dc:description>摘要 根据蒸发状态是水限制还是能量限制，地表水和能量平衡可以耦合或解耦合。随着景观在干旱期间失去土壤水分，可能会发生状态之间的转变，这意味着水-能量-碳耦合的非线性变化。经常在这两种模式之间切换的地区，即不受任何一种模式支配的地区，特别容易受到气候变率和变化的影响。为了可靠地识别这些临界点，我们根据来自遥感的全球土壤水分数据集识别干燥事件。事件识别不依赖于降水信息，并且相对于测量噪声是稳健的。然后，描绘蒸发状态转变的土壤水分阈值由顺序蒙特卡罗采样和两阶段参数化策略确定。基于全球范围内估计的土壤水分阈值，我们估计了基于观测的可用水指数，这些指数量化了土壤水分对蒸发的非线性控制。该框架使用土壤水分主动被动 (SMAP) 土壤水分反演在全球范围内进行了测试和应用。结合描述蒸发状态转换频率的新的临界点指标，我们确定了在全球范围内经常在不同蒸发状态之间切换的区域。考虑到土壤水分的单位变化，这些地区的地表水和能量的耦合方式将经历最大的变化。</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;摘要&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;地表水和能量平衡可以耦合或不耦合，这取决于蒸发状态是水限制还是能量限制。随着景观在干旱期间失去土壤水分，可能会发生制度之间的转变，这意味着水 - 能量 - 碳耦合的非线性变化。经常在这两种模式之间切换的地区，即不受任何一种模式支配的地区，特别容易受到气候变率和变化的影响。为了可靠地识别这些临界点，我们根据来自遥感的全球土壤水分数据集识别干燥事件。事件识别不依赖于降水信息，并且相对于测量噪声是稳健的。然后，描述蒸发状态转变的土壤水分阈值由顺序蒙特卡罗采样和两阶段参数化策略确定。基于全球范围内估计的土壤水分阈值，我们估计了基于观测的可用水指数，这些指数量化了土壤水分对蒸发的非线性控制。该框架使用土壤水分主动被动 (SMAP) 土壤水分反演在全球范围内进行了测试和应用。结合描述蒸发状态转换频率的新的临界点指标，我们确定了在全球范围内经常在不同蒸发状态之间切换的区域。考虑到土壤水分的单位变化，这些地区的地表水和能量的耦合方式将经历最大的变化。&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> Jianzhi Dong、Ruzbeh Akbar、Andrew F. Feldman、Daniel Short Gianotti、Dara Entekhabi</dc:creator><category>研究文章</category><dc:title>地表处于水和能量平衡耦合的临界点</dc:title><dc:identifier>10.1029/2022WR032472</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname>水资源研究</prism:publicationname><prism:doi>10.1029/2022WR032472</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR032472?af=R</prism:url><prism:section>研究文章</prism:section></item><item><link/>https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033537?af=R<pubDate> Fri, 10 Feb 2023 09:02:48 -0800</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-02-10T09:02:48-08:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley：水资源研究：目录<prism:coverdate></prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate></prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR033537</guid><title>渗流速度对孔隙堵塞生长行为的影响及其对多孔介质细粒运移过程中渗透率降低的影响</title><description>水资源研究，接受的文章。</description><dc:description>摘要 流体流动驱动的细粒运移常常导致多孔介质中的孔隙堵塞，从而降低多孔介质的渗透率。堵塞会在各种实践中造成严重问题，例如油气藏的地层损坏、流体抽取或注入效率的降低、过滤膜中颗粒引起的污染，甚至是地质结构沉积物破坏的风险。然而，渗流速度对细粒引起的孔隙堵塞的空间增长模式的影响仍不清楚。本研究通过一系列柱实验和同步 X 射线计算机断层扫描成像，探讨了由流动驱动的细粒在多孔介质中的迁移和积累引起的孔隙堵塞生长行为以及相关的渗透率降低。特别是，X 射线图像分析捕获了细粒的空间分布，从而捕获了各种渗流速度下的同质或异质（局部）堵塞生长模式。我们的结果表明，渗流速度的增加增加了局部堵塞增长的可能性，这归因于沙粒对细粒的直接拦截。与均匀的堵塞增长相比，局部堵塞增长导致渗透性更快地降低。本研究提供了关于细粒分布和相关渗透率变化的控制良好的实验数据，从而深入了解细粒在多孔介质中引起的堵塞行为。</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;流体流动驱动的细粒运移常常导致多孔介质孔隙堵塞，从而降低多孔介质的渗透率。堵塞会在各种实践中造成严重问题，例如油气藏的地层损坏、流体抽取或注入效率的降低、过滤膜中颗粒引起的污染，甚至是地质结构沉积物破坏的风险。然而，渗流速度对细粒引起的孔隙堵塞的空间增长模式的影响仍不清楚。本研究通过一系列柱实验和同步 X 射线计算机断层扫描成像，探讨了由流动驱动的细粒在多孔介质中的迁移和积累引起的孔隙堵塞生长行为以及相关的渗透率降低。特别是，X 射线图像分析捕获了细粒的空间分布，从而捕获了各种渗流速度下的同质或异质（局部）堵塞生长模式。我们的结果表明，渗流速度的增加增加了局部堵塞增长的可能性，这归因于沙粒对细粒的直接拦截。与均匀的堵塞增长相比，局部堵塞增长导致渗透性更快地降低。所提出的研究提供了关于细粒分布和相关渗透率变化的控制良好的实验数据，这有助于深入了解多孔介质中细粒引起的堵塞行为。&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> Gyeol Han, Tae-Hyuk Kwon</dc:creator><category>研究文章</category><dc:title>渗流速度对孔隙堵塞生长行为的影响及其对多孔介质细粒运移过程中渗透率降低的影响</dc:title><dc:identifier>10.1029/2022WR033537</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname>水资源研究</prism:publicationname><prism:doi>10.1029/2022WR033537</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033537?af=R</prism:url><prism:section>研究文章</prism:section></item><item><link/>https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR032815?af=R<pubDate> Fri, 10 Feb 2023 08:46:58 -0800</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-02-10T08:46:58-08:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley：水资源研究：目录<prism:coverdate>2023 年 2 月 1 日，星期三 00:00:00 -0800</prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate> 2023 年 2 月 1 日，星期三 00:00:00 -0800</prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR032815</guid><title>美国本土洪水具有地貌特征和降水变化的尺度</title><description>水资源研究，第 59 卷，第 2 期，2023 年 2 月。</description><dc:description>摘要 准确的洪水风险评估需要全面了解洪水对区域驱动因素和气候因素的敏感性。本文介绍了洪水（持续时间、峰值、流量）与流域地貌特征（即流域面积、坡度、海拔）和降水模式（降雨积累、变化）的比例关系。 20 世纪和 21 世纪初来自美国本土的水文气候数据网络流量计的长期每日径流观测被用于根据洪水阶段信息创建洪水事件数据库。使用全球历史气候学网络每日数据集计算与这些洪水相对应的前期每日降雨量累积和变化。开发了两个贝叶斯尺度模型，并研究了尺度指数的空间组织。基线模型将洪水的比例量化为地貌特征。动态模型量化了洪水与前期降水分布的比例，后者进一步取决于地貌特征。结果表明，小型和低海拔盆地对前期降雨分布的洪水峰值响应更强，而高海拔陡峭的盆地对洪水持续时间和洪水量的响应较低。动态模型表明洪水缩放率存在显着变化，洪水持续时间的最大比率高达 40% 和 4.5%，高峰期的比率最大为 64% 和 44%，东北地区的洪水量最大为 98% 和 40% 、沿海东南部和西北地区分别有加剧的降雨积累和变化。这项研究通过在动态陆地大气扰动的背景下更好地告知洪水属性来推进洪水预测。</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;摘要&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;准确的洪水风险评估需要全面了解洪水对区域驱动因素和气候因素的敏感性。本文介绍了洪水（持续时间、峰值、流量）与流域地貌特征（即流域面积、坡度、海拔）和降水模式（降雨积累、变化）的比例关系。 20 世纪和 21 世纪初来自美国本土的水文气候数据网络水流测量仪的长期每日水流观测被用于根据洪水阶段信息创建洪水事件数据库。使用全球历史气候学网络每日数据集计算与这些洪水相对应的前期每日降雨量累积和变化。开发了两个贝叶斯尺度模型，并研究了尺度指数的空间组织。基线模型将洪水的比例量化为地貌特征。动态模型量化了洪水与前期降水分布的比例，后者进一步取决于地貌特征。结果表明，小型和低海拔盆地对前期降雨分布的洪峰放大响应更强，而高海拔陡峭的盆地对洪水持续时间和洪水量的响应较低。动态模型表明洪水缩放率存在显着变化，洪水持续时间的最大比率高达 40% 和 4.5%，高峰期的比率最大为 64% 和 44%，东北地区的洪水量最大为 98% 和 40% 、沿海东南部和西北地区分别有加剧的降雨积累和变化。这项研究通过在动力陆地-大气扰动的背景下更好地告知洪水属性来推进洪水预测。&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator>纳赛尔·纳吉比、纳雷什·德维尼尼</dc:creator><category>研究文章</category><dc:title>美国本土洪水具有地貌特征和降水变化的尺度</dc:title><dc:identifier>10.1029/2022WR032815</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname>水资源研究</prism:publicationname><prism:doi>10.1029/2022WR032815</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR032815?af=R</prism:url><prism:section>研究文章</prism:section><prism:volume>59</prism:volume><prism:number> 2个</prism:number></item><item><link/>https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033519?af=R<pubDate> Fri, 10 Feb 2023 08:46:58 -0800</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-02-10T08:46:58-08:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley：水资源研究：目录<prism:coverdate>2023 年 2 月 1 日，星期三 00:00:00 -0800</prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate> 2023 年 2 月 1 日，星期三 00:00:00 -0800</prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR033519</guid><title>农业大中型水库对西北干旱石羊河流域水文过程的影响</title><description>水资源研究，第 59 卷，第 2 期，2023 年 2 月。</description><dc:description>摘要 干旱地区农业大中型水库增加了当地水文系统的水分压力，增加了水生态系统的压力，也威胁着水资源的可持续性。然而，关于农业水库如何影响内陆河流域水文的研究有限，这阻碍了对这些系统可持续用水的全面评估。我们探索利用水的稳定同位素来评估农业水库对干旱石羊河流域水文和水资源可持续利用的影响。结果表明，这个干旱地区的农业大中型水库改变了当地的同位素水文模式，增加了水体蒸发并丰富了水库附近水体的同位素组成。因此，下游沙漠水库库水蒸发损失高达30.7%。库水还与周围的地下水进行交换，由于库区蒸发，对当地降水贡献了22%。对单个储层的详细研究表明，同位素组成在储层表面最富集，然后逐渐向底部耗尽。多个大中型水库的累积效应深刻地改变了内陆河流域的水文过程，导致这些系统中蒸发导致的水流失。</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;摘要&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;干旱地区的农业大中型水库增加了当地水文系统的用水压力，增加了水生态系统的压力，也威胁着水资源的可持续性。然而，关于农业水库如何影响内陆河流域水文的研究有限，这阻碍了对这些系统可持续用水的全面评估。我们探索利用水的稳定同位素来评估农业水库对干旱石羊河流域水文和水资源可持续利用的影响。结果表明，这个干旱地区的农业大中型水库改变了当地的同位素水文模式，增加了水体蒸发并丰富了水库附近水体的同位素组成。因此，下游沙漠水库库水蒸发损失高达30.7%。库水还与周围的地下水进行交换，由于库区蒸发，对当地降水贡献了22%。对单个储层的详细研究表明，同位素组成在储层表面最富集，然后逐渐向底部耗尽。多个大中型水库的累积效应深刻改变了内陆河流域的水文过程，导致这些系统中蒸发导致的水量流失。&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator>桑立元、朱国峰、许元晓、孙志刚、张转霞、童华立</dc:creator><category>研究文章</category><dc:title>农业大中型水库对西北干旱石羊河流域水文过程的影响</dc:title><dc:identifier>10.1029/2022WR033519</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname>水资源研究</prism:publicationname><prism:doi>10.1029/2022WR033519</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033519?af=R</prism:url><prism:section>研究文章</prism:section><prism:volume>59</prism:volume><prism:number> 2个</prism:number></item><item><link/>https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033282?af=R<pubDate> Fri, 10 Feb 2023 08:40:30 -0800</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-02-10T08:40:30-08:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley：水资源研究：目录<prism:coverdate>2023 年 2 月 1 日，星期三 00:00:00 -0800</prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate> 2023 年 2 月 1 日，星期三 00:00:00 -0800</prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR033282</guid><title>用环境示踪剂观测和贝叶斯不确定性量化限制山区系统中基岩地下水停留时间</title><description>水资源研究，第 59 卷，第 2 期，2023 年 2 月。</description><dc:description>摘要 地下水停留时间分布为流域内的水文过程提供了基本见解。然而，在山区流域研究中，可以限制地下水在广泛时间尺度内停留时间的观察仍然很少。我们使用环境示踪剂（CFC-12、SF6、3H 和 4He）调查美国科罗拉多州东河流域沿山坡的地下水停留时间。我们开发了一个贝叶斯推理框架，该框架应用马尔可夫链蒙特卡罗 (MCMC) 方法来估算惰性气体补给温度、海拔和过量空气参数以及由此产生的环境示踪剂浓度。然后使用 MCMC 将环境示踪剂的不确定性传播到用集总参数模型推断的地下水平均停留时间的估计值。除陆生 4He 外，所有样品均含有 3H、CFC-12 和 SF6，这表明存在以现代和前现代停留时间为特征的水混合物。 4He 指数平均停留时间范围从上坡井的数百年到坡脚井的数千年，假设平均地壳生产率。我们发现需要具有单独的新旧混合分数的二元混合停留时间分布来预测 4He、CFC-12、SF6 和 3H 观测值，支持流动路径混合在该基岩系统中的重要性。我们的发现表明，断裂的基岩含有地下水，其停留时间从几十年到几千年不等，这表明沿山坡的补给动态和流动路径混合是可变的，并强调了通过对广泛范围内的输送敏感的观测来表征地下水系统的重要性。停留时间。</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;摘要&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;地下水停留时间分布为流域内的水文过程提供了基本的见解。然而，在山区流域研究中，可以限制地下水在广泛时间尺度内停留时间的观察仍然很少。我们使用环境示踪剂（CFC-12、SF&lt;sub>;6&lt;/sub>;、&lt;sup>;3&lt;/sup>;H 和&lt;sup>;4&lt;/sup>;He）来调查沿山坡的地下水停留时间美国科罗拉多州东河流域。我们开发了一个贝叶斯推理框架，该框架应用马尔可夫链蒙特卡罗 (MCMC) 方法来估算惰性气体补给温度、海拔和过量空气参数以及由此产生的环境示踪剂浓度。然后使用 MCMC 将环境示踪剂的不确定性传播到用集总参数模型推断的地下水平均停留时间的估计值。除了陆生的 &lt;sup>;4&lt;/sup>;He，所有样品都含有 &lt;sup>;3&lt;/sup>;H、CFC-12 和 SF&lt;sub>;6&lt;/sub>;，这表明水的混合物具有现代和前现代居住时间。 &lt;sup>;4&lt;/sup>;假设平均地壳生产率，他的指数平均停留时间从上坡井的数百年到趾坡井的数千年不等。我们发现需要具有不同新旧混合分数的二元混合停留时间分布来预测 &lt;sup>;4&lt;/sup>;He、CFC-12、SF&lt;sub>;6&lt;/sub>; 和 &lt;sup>;3&lt; /sup>;H 观察结果支持流路混合在该基岩系统中的重要性。我们的发现表明，断裂的基岩含有地下水，其停留时间从几十年到几千年不等，这表明沿山坡的补给动态和流动路径混合是可变的，并强调了通过对广泛范围内的输送敏感的观测来表征地下水系统的重要性。停留时间。&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> Nicholas E. Thiros、Erica R. Siirila-Woodburn、P. James Dennedy-Frank、Kenneth H. Williams、W. Payton Gardner</dc:creator><category>研究文章</category><dc:title>用环境示踪剂观测和贝叶斯不确定性量化限制山区系统中基岩地下水停留时间</dc:title><dc:identifier>10.1029/2022WR033282</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname>水资源研究</prism:publicationname><prism:doi>10.1029/2022WR033282</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033282?af=R</prism:url><prism:section>研究文章</prism:section><prism:volume>59</prism:volume><prism:number> 2个</prism:number></item><item><link/>https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033056?af=R<pubDate> Fri, 10 Feb 2023 08:40:30 -0800</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-02-10T08:40:30-08:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley：水资源研究：目录<prism:coverdate>2023 年 2 月 1 日，星期三 00:00:00 -0800</prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate> 2023 年 2 月 1 日，星期三 00:00:00 -0800</prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR033056</guid><title>稳定的水同位素作为浅层含水层井地表水入侵的指标：寒冷气候的观点</title><description>水资源研究，第 59 卷，第 2 期，2023 年 2 月。</description><dc:description>摘要 浅层含水层中的地下水通常用于寒冷气候下的社区供水。浅层地下水本来就容易受到土地利用和地表水入侵威胁饮用水使用的污染。我们使用来自芬兰北部用于饮用水供应的浅层冰川含水层的稳定水同位素的大规模快照数据集来评估地表水入侵风险和补给条件。该数据集由长期稳定的水同位素降水数据、地理信息系统邻近分析和多元统计数据补充。同位素分析表明，暖季贡献了该地区年总降水量的 60% 左右。这反映在含水层的同位素组成中，因为它代表了暖季和冷季降水的大致相等的混合。地下水同位素数据通过线路条件过剩 (lc-excess) 归一化为降水输入，用于标记受地表水入侵影响的供水井。邻近分析表明，一些水井可能受到来自砾石坑池塘、湖泊和泥炭地排水系统的侵入的影响。在更大范围内，与芬兰北部内陆地区相比，沿海地区的水井更容易蒸发水（入侵），原因是可用水量较低且存在人造结构。这种具有 lc-excess 的稳定水同位素的应用不仅对于补给研究而且在供水井地表水污染风险评估的水管理中都是一种有用的方法。</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;Groundwater in shallow aquifers is commonly used for community water supply in cold climates. Shallow groundwaters are inherently susceptible to contamination from land-use and surface water intrusion threatening drinking water usage. We used a large-scale snapshot data set of stable water isotopes from shallow glaciofluvial aquifers used for drinking water supply in Northern Finland to assess surface water intrusion risks and recharge conditions. This data set was supplemented by long-term stable water isotope precipitation data, Geographic Information System proximity analysis and multivariate statistics. The isotope analysis suggest that a warm season contributes about 60% to the total annual precipitation in the region. This is reflected in the aquifers isotopic composition as it represents an approximately equal mixture of warm and cold season precipitation. Groundwater isotope data normalized to precipitation inputs by line-conditioned excess (lc-excess) was used to flag the water supply wells impacted by surface water intrusions. The proximity analysis showed some of the wells may be affected by intrusions from gravel pit ponds, lakes and peatland drainage. On the larger scale, the wells in coastal areas were more likely to have evaporated water (intrusion) compared to inland regions of Northern Finland due to lower water availability and the presence of man-made structures. This application of stable water isotopes with lc-excess is a useful approach not only for recharge studies but also within water management for supply well surface water contamination risk assessment.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> Vadim Yapiyev, Pekka M. Rossi, Pertti Ala‐Aho, Hannu Marttila</dc:creator><category> Research Article</category><dc:title> Stable Water Isotopes as an Indicator of Surface Water Intrusion in Shallow Aquifer Wells: A Cold Climate Perspective</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2022WR033056</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1029/2022WR033056</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033056?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> Research Article</prism:section><prism:volume> 59</prism:volume><prism:number> 2个</prism:number></item><item><link/>https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033910?af=R<pubDate> Thu, 09 Feb 2023 23:15:25 -0800</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-02-09T11:15:25-08:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley: Water Resources Research: Table of Contents <prism:coverdate></prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate></prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR033910</guid><title> Impact of matrix diffusion on heat transport through heterogeneous fractured aquifers</title><description> Water Resources Research, Accepted Article.</description><dc:description> Abstract Heat transport in fractured aquifers is determined by the combined effects of flow velocity heterogeneity in the fracture system, and diffusive exchange between the fluid in the fractures and the rock matrix, which can be assumed as impervious. We analyze the impacts of this diffusive exchange on the response to heat transport, as opposite to the pure advective displacement, which governs solute transport. We focus on the post‐peak behavior where we observe pre‐asymptotic regimes with slopes that differ from the signature of matrix diffusion, which exhibits a decay rate of ‐3/2. This deviation is driven by the variability of both velocity field and fracture aperture field. We derive theoretical models that predict these pre‐asymptotic tails under three extreme cases that can be related with specific network structures, ie, networks dominated by large or small fractures, networks with highly or poorly channelized flow. These theoretical predictions are compared with results from numerical simulations in different sets of three‐dimensional discrete fracture networks. We determine that the combined observation of solute and heat transport responses allows classifying the network in terms of connectivity structure, and partially characterizing the fracture aperture variability in terms of upscaled parameters. This article is protected by copyright.版权所有。</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;Heat transport in fractured aquifers is determined by the combined effects of flow velocity heterogeneity in the fracture system, and diffusive exchange between the fluid in the fractures and the rock matrix, which can be assumed as impervious. We analyze the impacts of this diffusive exchange on the response to heat transport, as opposite to the pure advective displacement, which governs solute transport. We focus on the post-peak behavior where we observe pre-asymptotic regimes with slopes that differ from the signature of matrix diffusion, which exhibits a decay rate of -3/2. This deviation is driven by the variability of both velocity field and fracture aperture field. We derive theoretical models that predict these pre-asymptotic tails under three extreme cases that can be related with specific network structures, ie, networks dominated by large or small fractures, networks with highly or poorly channelized flow. These theoretical predictions are compared with results from numerical simulations in different sets of three-dimensional discrete fracture networks. We determine that the combined observation of solute and heat transport responses allows classifying the network in terms of connectivity structure, and partially characterizing the fracture aperture variability in terms of upscaled parameters.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This article is protected by copyright. All rights reserved.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> Silvia Simone, Olivier Bour, Philippe Davy</dc:creator><category> Research Article</category><dc:title> Impact of matrix diffusion on heat transport through heterogeneous fractured aquifers</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2022WR033910</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1029/2022WR033910</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033910?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> Research Article</prism:section></item><item><link/> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR032821?af=R<pubDate> Thu, 09 Feb 2023 11:28:03 -0800</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-02-09T11:28:03-08:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley: Water Resources Research: Table of Contents <prism:coverdate></prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate></prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR032821</guid><title> Toward a catchment‐scale assessment of flood peak attenuation by multiple reservoirs</title><description> Water Resources Research, Accepted Article.</description><dc:description> Abstract The estimation of reservoirs impact on flood peak reduction at the catchment scale is of fundamental importance for risk assessment and planning purposes. It is generally addressed using detailed hydrologic‐hydrodynamic simulations or simple, empirically‐based indices. The former provide detailed results, at the cost of a large amount of information and high computational efforts; the latter are cost‐effective and simple, yet they generally provide approximate results. A promising compromise between the two is the physically‐based attenuation index ℛ, based on the concept of equivalent reservoir; ℛ was recently proposed in the literature to estimate the impact of multiple reservoirs located in series along the main channel, based on the assumption of rectangular catchment. In this work, we extend the equivalent reservoir approach to a generic catchment, with any shape and without restrictions on the location of the reservoirs. For an effective assessment of the method, we also introduce the novel concept of Reservoir‐influenced Instantaneous Unit Hydrograph (RIUH); the RIUH can be derived using a Monte Carlo procedure to include the effects of reservoirs on the IUH. Simulations of numerous fictitious reservoir configurations in a real basin demonstrate the potential of the methods in reproducing the attenuation effect. Remarkably, an average error of 3 − 5% exists between ℛ and the peak reduction of a less simplified reality (RIUH). Finally, we provide a global, catchment‐scale application of the attenuation index, which constitutes an effective tool for the evaluation of each reservoir in managed catchment system and the design or planning of new hydraulic infrastructures. This article is protected by copyright.版权所有。</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;The estimation of reservoirs impact on flood peak reduction at the catchment scale is of fundamental importance for risk assessment and planning purposes. It is generally addressed using detailed hydrologic-hydrodynamic simulations or simple, empirically-based indices. The former provide detailed results, at the cost of a large amount of information and high computational efforts; the latter are cost-effective and simple, yet they generally provide approximate results. A promising compromise between the two is the physically-based attenuation index ℛ, based on the concept of equivalent reservoir; ℛ was recently proposed in the literature to estimate the impact of multiple reservoirs located in series along the main channel, based on the assumption of rectangular catchment. In this work, we extend the equivalent reservoir approach to a generic catchment, with any shape and without restrictions on the location of the reservoirs. For an effective assessment of the method, we also introduce the novel concept of Reservoir-influenced Instantaneous Unit Hydrograph (RIUH); the RIUH can be derived using a Monte Carlo procedure to include the effects of reservoirs on the IUH. Simulations of numerous fictitious reservoir configurations in a real basin demonstrate the potential of the methods in reproducing the attenuation effect. Remarkably, an average error of 3 − 5% exists between ℛ and the peak reduction of a less simplified reality (RIUH). Finally, we provide a global, catchment-scale application of the attenuation index, which constitutes an effective tool for the evaluation of each reservoir in managed catchment system and the design or planning of new hydraulic infrastructures.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This article is protected by copyright. All rights reserved.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> S. Cipollini, E. Volpi, A. Fiori</dc:creator><category> Research Article</category><dc:title> Toward a catchment‐scale assessment of flood peak attenuation by multiple reservoirs</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2022WR032821</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1029/2022WR032821</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR032821?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> Research Article</prism:section></item><item><link/> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033267?af=R<pubDate> Thu, 09 Feb 2023 05:36:23 -0800</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-02-09T05:36:23-08:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley: Water Resources Research: Table of Contents <prism:coverdate></prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate></prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR033267</guid><title> Upscaling permeability using multiscale X‐ray‐CT images with digital rock modeling and deep learning techniques</title><description> Water Resources Research, Accepted Article.</description><dc:description> Abstract This study presents a workflow to predict the upscaled absolute permeability of the rock core direct from CT images whose resolution are not sufficient to allow direct pore‐scale permeability computation. This workflow exploits the deep learning technique with the data of raw CT images of rocks and their corresponding permeability value obtained by performing flow simulation on high resolution CT images. The permeability map of a much larger region in the rock core is predicted by the trained neural network. Finally, the upscaled permeability of the entire rock core is calculated by the Darcy flow solver, and the results showed a good agreement with the experiment data. This proposed deep‐learning based upscaling method allows estimating the permeability of large‐scale core samples while preserving the effects of fine‐scale pore structure variations due to the local heterogeneity. This article is protected by copyright.版权所有。</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;This study presents a workflow to predict the upscaled absolute permeability of the rock core direct from CT images whose resolution are not sufficient to allow direct pore-scale permeability computation. This workflow exploits the deep learning technique with the data of raw CT images of rocks and their corresponding permeability value obtained by performing flow simulation on high resolution CT images. The permeability map of a much larger region in the rock core is predicted by the trained neural network. Finally, the upscaled permeability of the entire rock core is calculated by the Darcy flow solver, and the results showed a good agreement with the experiment data. This proposed deep-learning based upscaling method allows estimating the permeability of large-scale core samples while preserving the effects of fine-scale pore structure variations due to the local heterogeneity.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This article is protected by copyright. All rights reserved.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> Fei Jiang, Yaotian Guo, Takeshi Tsuji, Yoshitake Kato, Mai Shimokawara, Lionel Esteban, Mojtaba Seyyedi, Marina Pervukhina, Maxim Lebedev, Ryuta Kitamura</dc:creator><category> Research Article</category><dc:title> Upscaling permeability using multiscale X‐ray‐CT images with digital rock modeling and deep learning techniques</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2022WR033267</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1029/2022WR033267</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033267?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> Research Article</prism:section></item><item><link/> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033285?af=R<pubDate> Thu, 09 Feb 2023 03:33:26 -0800</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-02-09T03:33:26-08:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley: Water Resources Research: Table of Contents <prism:coverdate></prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate></prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR033285</guid><title> Prioritizing irrigation‐system upgrades to maximize improvements to agricultural drain‐network water quality: A graph‐theoretic approach</title><description> Water Resources Research, Accepted Article.</description><dc:description> Abstract We develop and demonstrate an approach to optimally prioritize fields for irrigation‐system upgrades to improve agricultural‐drain discharge water quality. The approach accounts for attenuation of pollutants transported along complex drain networks from fields to drain‐network outlets. The approach produces a Pareto‐optimal cost curve of irrigation‐system upgrade combinations that compromise between maximizing the reduction of drain‐outlet loads and minimizing upgrade implementation costs. The approach utilizes a graph‐theoretic data structure to organize drain‐network data, route drain‐network flow paths, and formulate objectives and constraints for multi‐objective optimization. Due to the linearity of the objective functions and constraints, Pareto‐optimal solutions are obtained along the cost curve by prioritizing fields by decreasing load‐reduction/cost ratio (pollutant load‐reduction per cost). Multi‐objective optimization will identify additional Pareto‐optimal solutions along the cost curve providing additional compromises. The approach allows for a computationally‐efficient prioritization, providing a level of complexity that is able to incorporate commonly available data. The cost curve is highly sensitive to the pollutant attenuation coefficient, with higher attenuation coefficients resulting in low sensitivity of load reduction to cost. While the focus of this work is on irrigation‐system upgrades, there are other conservation actions and/or land‐use change scenarios that this method could also prioritize. Analyses of this nature could prove valuable in improving the allocation of limited conservation funding and/or developing cost‐effective water quality trading programs. We demonstrate the approach on a collection of drain networks around Grand View, Idaho, USA with the objective to reduce total phosphorus loads to the Snake River.</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;We develop and demonstrate an approach to optimally prioritize fields for irrigation-system upgrades to improve agricultural-drain discharge water quality. The approach accounts for attenuation of pollutants transported along complex drain networks from fields to drain-network outlets. The approach produces a Pareto-optimal cost curve of irrigation-system upgrade combinations that compromise between maximizing the reduction of drain-outlet loads and minimizing upgrade implementation costs. The approach utilizes a graph-theoretic data structure to organize drain-network data, route drain-network flow paths, and formulate objectives and constraints for multi-objective optimization. Due to the linearity of the objective functions and constraints, Pareto-optimal solutions are obtained along the cost curve by prioritizing fields by decreasing load-reduction/cost ratio (pollutant load-reduction per cost). Multi-objective optimization will identify additional Pareto-optimal solutions along the cost curve providing additional compromises. The approach allows for a computationally-efficient prioritization, providing a level of complexity that is able to incorporate commonly available data. The cost curve is highly sensitive to the pollutant attenuation coefficient, with higher attenuation coefficients resulting in low sensitivity of load reduction to cost. While the focus of this work is on irrigation-system upgrades, there are other conservation actions and/or land-use change scenarios that this method could also prioritize. Analyses of this nature could prove valuable in improving the allocation of limited conservation funding and/or developing cost-effective water quality trading programs. We demonstrate the approach on a collection of drain networks around Grand View, Idaho, USA with the objective to reduce total phosphorus loads to the Snake River.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> Dylan R Harp, Anthony S Orlando, Elliot Hohn, Aditya Sood, Tommy Franzen, Maddee Rubenson, David L Atchison, Dion Webster, Nick Osman, Theresa K Burcsu, David Primozich</dc:creator><category> Research Article</category><dc:title> Prioritizing irrigation‐system upgrades to maximize improvements to agricultural drain‐network water quality: A graph‐theoretic approach</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2022WR033285</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1029/2022WR033285</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033285?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> Research Article</prism:section></item><item><link/> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033506?af=R<pubDate> Thu, 09 Feb 2023 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-02-09T12:00:00-08:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley: Water Resources Research: Table of Contents<prism:coverdate> Wed, 01 Feb 2023 00:00:00 -0800</prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate> Wed, 01 Feb 2023 00:00:00 -0800</prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR033506</guid><title> A Comparison of Hydrological and Geophysical Calibration Data in Layered Hydrologic Models of Mountain Hillslopes</title><description> Water Resources Research, Volume 59, Issue 2, February 2023.</description><dc:description> Abstract Both hydrological and geophysical data can be used to calibrate hillslope hydrologic models. However, these data often reflect hydrological dynamics occurring at disparate spatial scales. Their use as sole objectives in model calibrations may thus result in different optimum hydraulic parameters and hydrologic model behavior. This is especially true for mountain hillslopes where the subsurface is often heterogeneous and the representative elementary volume can be on the scale of several m3. This study explores differences in hydraulic parameters and hillslope‐scale storage and flux dynamics of models calibrated with different hydrological and geophysical data. Soil water content, groundwater level, and two time‐lapse electrical resistivity tomography (ERT) data sets (transfer resistance and inverted resistivity) from two mountain hillslopes in Wyoming, USA, are used to calibrate physics‐based surface–subsurface hydrologic models of the hillslopes. Calibrations are performed using each data set independently and all data together resulting in five calibrated parameter sets at each site. Model predicted hillslope runoff and internal hydrological dynamics vary significantly depending on the calibration data set. Results indicate that water content calibration data yield models that overestimate near‐surface water storage in mountain hillslopes. Groundwater level calibration data yield models that more reasonably represent hillslope‐scale storage and flux dynamics. Additionally, ERT calibration data yield models with reasonable hillslope runoff predictions but relatively poor predictions of internal hillslope dynamics. These observations highlight the importance of carefully selecting data for hydrologic model calibration in mountain environments. Poor selection of calibration data may yield models with limited predictive capability depending on modeling goals and model complexity.</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;Both hydrological and geophysical data can be used to calibrate hillslope hydrologic models. However, these data often reflect hydrological dynamics occurring at disparate spatial scales. Their use as sole objectives in model calibrations may thus result in different optimum hydraulic parameters and hydrologic model behavior. This is especially true for mountain hillslopes where the subsurface is often heterogeneous and the representative elementary volume can be on the scale of several m&lt;sup>;3&lt;/sup>;. This study explores differences in hydraulic parameters and hillslope-scale storage and flux dynamics of models calibrated with different hydrological and geophysical data. Soil water content, groundwater level, and two time-lapse electrical resistivity tomography (ERT) data sets (transfer resistance and inverted resistivity) from two mountain hillslopes in Wyoming, USA, are used to calibrate physics-based surface–subsurface hydrologic models of the hillslopes. Calibrations are performed using each data set independently and all data together resulting in five calibrated parameter sets at each site. Model predicted hillslope runoff and internal hydrological dynamics vary significantly depending on the calibration data set. Results indicate that water content calibration data yield models that overestimate near-surface water storage in mountain hillslopes. Groundwater level calibration data yield models that more reasonably represent hillslope-scale storage and flux dynamics. Additionally, ERT calibration data yield models with reasonable hillslope runoff predictions but relatively poor predictions of internal hillslope dynamics. These observations highlight the importance of carefully selecting data for hydrologic model calibration in mountain environments. Poor selection of calibration data may yield models with limited predictive capability depending on modeling goals and model complexity.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> MS Pleasants, TJ Kelleners, AD Parsekian, KM Befus</dc:creator><category> Research Article</category><dc:title> A Comparison of Hydrological and Geophysical Calibration Data in Layered Hydrologic Models of Mountain Hillslopes</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2022WR033506</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1029/2022WR033506</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033506?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> Research Article</prism:section><prism:volume> 59</prism:volume><prism:number> 2个</prism:number></item><item><link/>https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR032653?af=R<pubDate> Tue, 07 Feb 2023 06:42:25 -0800</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-02-07T06:42:25-08:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley: Water Resources Research: Table of Contents <prism:coverdate></prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate></prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR032653</guid><title> Efficient Optimization of Energy Recovery from Geothermal Reservoirs with Recurrent Neural Network Predictive Models</title><description> Water Resources Research, Accepted Article.</description><dc:description> Abstract Improving the long‐term energy production performance of geothermal reservoirs can be accomplished by optimizing field development and management plans. Reliable prediction models, however, are needed to evaluate and optimize the performance of the underlying reservoirs under various operation and development strategies. In traditional frameworks, physics‐based simulation models are used to predict the energy production performance of geothermal reservoirs. However, detailed simulation models are not trivial to construct, require a reliable description of the reservoir conditions and properties, and entail high computational complexity. Data‐driven predictive models can offer an efficient alternative for use in optimization workflows. This paper presents an optimization framework for net power generation in geothermal reservoirs using a variant of the recurrent neural network (RNN) as a data‐driven predictive model. The RNN architecture is developed and trained to replace the simulation model for computationally efficient prediction of the objective function and its gradients with respect to the well control variables. The net power generation performance of the field is optimized by automatically adjusting the mass flow rate of production and injection wells over 12 years, using a gradient‐based local search algorithm. Two field‐scale examples are presented to investigate the performance of the developed data‐driven prediction and optimization framework. The prediction and optimization results from the RNN model are evaluated through comparison with the results obtained by using a numerical simulation model of a real geothermal reservoir.</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;Improving the long-term energy production performance of geothermal reservoirs can be accomplished by optimizing field development and management plans. Reliable prediction models, however, are needed to evaluate and optimize the performance of the underlying reservoirs under various operation and development strategies. In traditional frameworks, physics-based simulation models are used to predict the energy production performance of geothermal reservoirs. However, detailed simulation models are not trivial to construct, require a reliable description of the reservoir conditions and properties, and entail high computational complexity. Data-driven predictive models can offer an efficient alternative for use in optimization workflows. This paper presents an optimization framework for net power generation in geothermal reservoirs using a variant of the recurrent neural network (RNN) as a data-driven predictive model. The RNN architecture is developed and trained to replace the simulation model for computationally efficient prediction of the objective function and its gradients with respect to the well control variables. The net power generation performance of the field is optimized by automatically adjusting the mass flow rate of production and injection wells over 12 years, using a gradient-based local search algorithm. Two field-scale examples are presented to investigate the performance of the developed data-driven prediction and optimization framework. The prediction and optimization results from the RNN model are evaluated through comparison with the results obtained by using a numerical simulation model of a real geothermal reservoir.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> Zhen Qin, Anyue Jiang, Dave Faulder, Trenton T. Cladouhos, Behnam Jafarpour</dc:creator><category> Research Article</category><dc:title> Efficient Optimization of Energy Recovery from Geothermal Reservoirs with Recurrent Neural Network Predictive Models</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2022WR032653</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1029/2022WR032653</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR032653?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> Research Article</prism:section></item><item><link/> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR032920?af=R<pubDate> Tue, 07 Feb 2023 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-02-07T12:00:00-08:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley: Water Resources Research: Table of Contents<prism:coverdate> Wed, 01 Feb 2023 00:00:00 -0800</prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate> Wed, 01 Feb 2023 00:00:00 -0800</prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR032920</guid><title> Using the Shallow Strain Tensor to Characterize Deep Geologic Reservoirs</title><description> Water Resources Research, Volume 59, Issue 2, February 2023.</description><dc:description> Abstract Storing and recovering water, carbon, and heat from geologic reservoirs is central to managing resources in a changing climate. We tested the hypothesis that the strain tensor caused by injecting or producing fluids can be measured at shallow depths and interpreted to advance understanding of underlying deep aquifers or reservoirs. Geodetic‐grade strainmeters were deployed at 30 m depth overlying the Bartlesville Formation, a 500‐m‐deep sandstone near Tulsa, OK. The strainmeters are 220 m east of injection well 9A completed in a permeable lens at the base of the Bartlesville Formation. Water was injected into well 9A at approximately 1.0 L/s during four tests that ranged in duration from a few hours to a few weeks. The horizontal strain increased (tension) and the circumferential strain was a few times larger than the radial strain. The vertical strain decreased (compression) during injection. Strain rates were approximately 100 nε/day during the first few hours, but the rates decreased and were approximately 10 nε/day during most of the tests. Four independent methods of poroelastic simulation and inversion predict reservoir properties and geometries that are similar to each other and consistent with independent information about the reservoir. All strain interpretations predict that a boundary to the permeable lens occurs beneath the vicinity of the strainmeters, which is consistent with core data from the site. The boundary of the permeable lens is located by matching the vertical, radial and circumferential strains, which demonstrates the value of measuring the strain tensor.</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;Storing and recovering water, carbon, and heat from geologic reservoirs is central to managing resources in a changing climate. We tested the hypothesis that the strain tensor caused by injecting or producing fluids can be measured at shallow depths and interpreted to advance understanding of underlying deep aquifers or reservoirs. Geodetic-grade strainmeters were deployed at 30 m depth overlying the Bartlesville Formation, a 500-m-deep sandstone near Tulsa, OK. The strainmeters are 220 m east of injection well 9A completed in a permeable lens at the base of the Bartlesville Formation. Water was injected into well 9A at approximately 1.0 L/s during four tests that ranged in duration from a few hours to a few weeks. The horizontal strain increased (tension) and the circumferential strain was a few times larger than the radial strain. The vertical strain decreased (compression) during injection. Strain rates were approximately 100 nε/day during the first few hours, but the rates decreased and were approximately 10 nε/day during most of the tests. Four independent methods of poroelastic simulation and inversion predict reservoir properties and geometries that are similar to each other and consistent with independent information about the reservoir. All strain interpretations predict that a boundary to the permeable lens occurs beneath the vicinity of the strainmeters, which is consistent with core data from the site. The boundary of the permeable lens is located by matching the vertical, radial and circumferential strains, which demonstrates the value of measuring the strain tensor.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> Lawrence C. Murdoch, Scott DeWolf, Leonid N. Germanovich, Stephen Moysey, Alex Hanna, Soheil Roudini, Robert Moak</dc:creator><category> Research Article</category><dc:title> Using the Shallow Strain Tensor to Characterize Deep Geologic Reservoirs</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2022WR032920</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1029/2022WR032920</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR032920?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> Research Article</prism:section><prism:volume> 59</prism:volume><prism:number> 2个</prism:number></item><item><link/>https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR032385?af=R<pubDate> Tue, 07 Feb 2023 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-02-07T12:00:00-08:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley: Water Resources Research: Table of Contents<prism:coverdate> Wed, 01 Feb 2023 00:00:00 -0800</prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate> Wed, 01 Feb 2023 00:00:00 -0800</prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR032385</guid><title> Stable Water Isotopologue Fractionation During Soil‐Water Evaporation: Analysis Using a Coupled Soil‐Atmosphere Model</title><description> Water Resources Research, Volume 59, Issue 2, February 2023.</description><dc:description> Abstract The atmosphere‐soil system forms a highly coupled system, which makes key processes such as evaporation complex to analyze as the mass, energy, and momentum transfer is influenced by both domains. To enhance the understanding of evaporation processes from soils, stable water isotopologues are suitable tools to trace water movement within these systems as heavier isotopologues enrich in the residual liquid phase. Due to the complex coupled processes involved in simulating soil‐water evaporation accurately, quantifying fractionation during flow and transport processes at the soil‐atmosphere interface remains an open research area. In this work, we present a multi‐phase multi‐component transport model that resolves flow through the near‐surface atmosphere and the soil, and models transport and fractionation of the stable water isotopologues using the numerical simulation environment DuMux. Using this coupled model, we simulate transport and fractionation processes of stable water isotopologues in soils and the atmosphere by solving compositional flow equations and by using suitable coupling conditions at the soil‐atmosphere interface instead of commonly used parameterization. In a series of examples of evaporation from bare soil, the transport and distribution of stable water isotopologues are evaluated numerically with varied conditions and assumptions, including different atmospheric conditions (turbulent/laminar flow, wind speed) and their impact on the spatial and temporal distribution of the isotopic composition. Building on these results, we observed how the enrichment of the isotopologues in soil is linked with the different stages of the evaporation process. A qualitative study is conducted to verify single fractionation processes in our approach.</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;The atmosphere-soil system forms a highly coupled system, which makes key processes such as evaporation complex to analyze as the mass, energy, and momentum transfer is influenced by both domains. To enhance the understanding of evaporation processes from soils, stable water isotopologues are suitable tools to trace water movement within these systems as heavier isotopologues enrich in the residual liquid phase. Due to the complex coupled processes involved in simulating soil-water evaporation accurately, quantifying fractionation during flow and transport processes at the soil-atmosphere interface remains an open research area. In this work, we present a multi-phase multi-component transport model that resolves flow through the near-surface atmosphere and the soil, and models transport and fractionation of the stable water isotopologues using the numerical simulation environment DuMu&lt;sup>;x&lt;/sup>;. Using this coupled model, we simulate transport and fractionation processes of stable water isotopologues in soils and the atmosphere by solving compositional flow equations and by using suitable coupling conditions at the soil-atmosphere interface instead of commonly used parameterization. In a series of examples of evaporation from bare soil, the transport and distribution of stable water isotopologues are evaluated numerically with varied conditions and assumptions, including different atmospheric conditions (turbulent/laminar flow, wind speed) and their impact on the spatial and temporal distribution of the isotopic composition. Building on these results, we observed how the enrichment of the isotopologues in soil is linked with the different stages of the evaporation process. A qualitative study is conducted to verify single fractionation processes in our approach.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> Stefanie Kiemle, Katharina Heck, Edward Coltman, Rainer Helmig</dc:creator><category> Research Article</category><dc:title> Stable Water Isotopologue Fractionation During Soil‐Water Evaporation: Analysis Using a Coupled Soil‐Atmosphere Model</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2022WR032385</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1029/2022WR032385</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR032385?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> Research Article</prism:section><prism:volume> 59</prism:volume><prism:number> 2个</prism:number></item><item><link/>https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2021WR031347?af=R<pubDate> Tue, 07 Feb 2023 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-02-07T12:00:00-08:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley: Water Resources Research: Table of Contents<prism:coverdate> Wed, 01 Feb 2023 00:00:00 -0800</prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate> Wed, 01 Feb 2023 00:00:00 -0800</prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2021WR031347</guid><title> Assessment of Impacts of Climate Change on Indian Riverine Thermal Regimes Using Hybrid Deep Learning Methods</title><description> Water Resources Research, Volume 59, Issue 2, February 2023.</description><dc:description> Abstract Understanding the riverine thermal regimes is challenging due to sparse spatiotemporal data of river water temperatures (RWTs). The development of systematic models combined with machine learning models under data‐limited context has not been intensively studied for the prediction of RWT. The present study developed hybrid models using long short‐term memory (LSTM), integrated with (a) k‐nearest neighbor (k‐NN) bootstrap resampling algorithms (kNN‐LSTM) to address the data limitations of RWT prediction and (b) discrete wavelet transform (WT) approach (WT‐LSTM) to address the time–frequency localized features of RWT prediction. The study assessed the climate change impacts on RWT using an ensemble of National Aeronautics Space Administration Earth Exchange Global Daily Downscaled Projections of air temperature with Representative Concentration Pathway scenarios 4.5 and 8.5 for seven major polluted river catchments of India. The hybrid kNN‐LSTM has effectively predicted RWT at monthly time scales under data limitations and outperformed the standalone LSTM, WT‐LSTM, and hybrid three‐parameter version air2stream models. The RWT increase for Tunga‐Bhadra, Musi, Ganga, and Narmada basins is predicted as 3.0, 4.0, 4.6, and 4.7°C, respectively, for 2071–2100.</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;Understanding the riverine thermal regimes is challenging due to sparse spatiotemporal data of river water temperatures (RWTs). The development of systematic models combined with machine learning models under data-limited context has not been intensively studied for the prediction of RWT. The present study developed hybrid models using long short-term memory (LSTM), integrated with (a) k-nearest neighbor (k-NN) bootstrap resampling algorithms (kNN-LSTM) to address the data limitations of RWT prediction and (b) discrete wavelet transform (WT) approach (WT-LSTM) to address the time–frequency localized features of RWT prediction. The study assessed the climate change impacts on RWT using an ensemble of National Aeronautics Space Administration Earth Exchange Global Daily Downscaled Projections of air temperature with Representative Concentration Pathway scenarios 4.5 and 8.5 for seven major polluted river catchments of India. The hybrid kNN-LSTM has effectively predicted RWT at monthly time scales under data limitations and outperformed the standalone LSTM, WT-LSTM, and hybrid three-parameter version air2stream models. The RWT increase for Tunga-Bhadra, Musi, Ganga, and Narmada basins is predicted as 3.0, 4.0, 4.6, and 4.7°C, respectively, for 2071–2100.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> S. Rehana, M. Rajesh</dc:creator><category> Research Article</category><dc:title> Assessment of Impacts of Climate Change on Indian Riverine Thermal Regimes Using Hybrid Deep Learning Methods</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2021WR031347</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1029/2021WR031347</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2021WR031347?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> Research Article</prism:section><prism:volume> 59</prism:volume><prism:number> 2个</prism:number></item><item><link/>https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR032426?af=R<pubDate> Tue, 07 Feb 2023 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-02-07T12:00:00-08:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley: Water Resources Research: Table of Contents<prism:coverdate> Wed, 01 Feb 2023 00:00:00 -0800</prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate> Wed, 01 Feb 2023 00:00:00 -0800</prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR032426</guid><title> Groundwater Plays an Important Role in Controlling Riverine Dissolved Organic Matter in a Cold Alpine Catchment, the Qinghai–Tibet Plateau</title><description> Water Resources Research, Volume 59, Issue 2, February 2023.</description><dc:description> Abstract In cold alpine areas, the hydrological control on dissolved organic matter (DOM) export in relation to permafrost distribution remains uncertain on a catchment scale. To address this, the seasonal variations in DOM chemical features of groundwater and stream water were examined from 2013 to 2019 in a representative catchment on the northeastern Qinghai–Tibet Plateau, which is covered by both permafrost (at elevations higher than 3,500 m asl) and seasonally frozen areas. The results show that the highest dissolved organic carbon (DOC) concentration occurred during the thawing period (April–May), while the highest DOC flux occurred during the thawed period (June–early October). In the permafrost area, the freeze–thaw process significantly influenced the groundwater flow paths and DOM. During the thawing period, with shallow groundwater flow path through the organic soil layer, the stream water DOM recharged by suprapermafrost groundwater was characterized by high aromaticity and high DOC concentrations. During the thawed period, the deepening groundwater flow path through the mineral layer and dilution by overland flow, resulted in low DOC concentrations and DOM with lower aromaticity in stream water. When groundwater flowed from the permafrost area into the porous aquifers in the seasonally frozen area, the groundwater flow path also affected DOM dynamics. The stream water at the catchment outlet, which received groundwater discharge from the porous aquifer, showed a lower peak DOC concentration, a higher proportion of protein‐like DOM, and a higher contribution of cold season DOC flux to annual DOC flux when compared to the water flowing out from the permafrost area. Our work highlights the role of the thick, porous aquifer in the seasonally frozen area in regulating DOM export. The results suggest that the cold alpine area may exhibit a stronger positive feedback to climate warming than that in Arctic areas.</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;In cold alpine areas, the hydrological control on dissolved organic matter (DOM) export in relation to permafrost distribution remains uncertain on a catchment scale. To address this, the seasonal variations in DOM chemical features of groundwater and stream water were examined from 2013 to 2019 in a representative catchment on the northeastern Qinghai–Tibet Plateau, which is covered by both permafrost (at elevations higher than 3,500 m asl) and seasonally frozen areas. The results show that the highest dissolved organic carbon (DOC) concentration occurred during the thawing period (April–May), while the highest DOC flux occurred during the thawed period (June–early October). In the permafrost area, the freeze–thaw process significantly influenced the groundwater flow paths and DOM. During the thawing period, with shallow groundwater flow path through the organic soil layer, the stream water DOM recharged by suprapermafrost groundwater was characterized by high aromaticity and high DOC concentrations. During the thawed period, the deepening groundwater flow path through the mineral layer and dilution by overland flow, resulted in low DOC concentrations and DOM with lower aromaticity in stream water. When groundwater flowed from the permafrost area into the porous aquifers in the seasonally frozen area, the groundwater flow path also affected DOM dynamics. The stream water at the catchment outlet, which received groundwater discharge from the porous aquifer, showed a lower peak DOC concentration, a higher proportion of protein-like DOM, and a higher contribution of cold season DOC flux to annual DOC flux when compared to the water flowing out from the permafrost area. Our work highlights the role of the thick, porous aquifer in the seasonally frozen area in regulating DOM export. The results suggest that the cold alpine area may exhibit a stronger positive feedback to climate warming than that in Arctic areas.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> Yalu Hu, Rui Ma, Ziyong Sun, Yan Zheng, Zhao Pan, Lusong Zhao</dc:creator><category> Research Article</category><dc:title> Groundwater Plays an Important Role in Controlling Riverine Dissolved Organic Matter in a Cold Alpine Catchment, the Qinghai–Tibet Plateau</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2022WR032426</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1029/2022WR032426</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR032426?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> Research Article</prism:section><prism:volume> 59</prism:volume><prism:number> 2个</prism:number></item><item><link/>https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR032943?af=R<pubDate> Mon, 06 Feb 2023 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-02-06T12:00:00-08:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley: Water Resources Research: Table of Contents<prism:coverdate> Wed, 01 Feb 2023 00:00:00 -0800</prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate> Wed, 01 Feb 2023 00:00:00 -0800</prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR032943</guid><title> Experiments and Simulations on Plume Spreading by Engineered Injection and Extraction in Refractive Index Matched Porous Media</title><description> Water Resources Research, Volume 59, Issue 2, February 2023.</description><dc:description> Abstract Engineered injection and extraction (EIE) is an in situ groundwater remediation strategy that imposes an engineered spatially and temporally varying velocity field to spread an amendment into the contaminant plume to promote mixing and contaminant degradation through reaction. Here we present a coordinated suite of laboratory experiments and numerical simulations that apply EIE using two pumping sequences: A folding sequence that manipulates plume geometry by stretching and folding, and an oscillating sequence that imposes velocity perpendicular to the plume interface in accordance with previously‐reported active spreading theory. Laboratory experiments investigated spreading and mixing of a non‐reactive tracer using refractive index matched porous media and laser‐induced fluorescence, with remarkable reproducibility between replicates. Numerical simulations matched the experimental results and simulated reactive transport by post‐processing sequentially injected non‐reactive tracer plumes representing the contaminant and the amendment assuming rapid reaction (ie, high Damköhler number). This study provides the first experimental verification of EIE using Darcy‐scale imaging, demonstrates a novel experimental method to mimic reactive transport at the high‐Damköhler number limit, and confirms active spreading theory.</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;Engineered injection and extraction (EIE) is an in situ groundwater remediation strategy that imposes an engineered spatially and temporally varying velocity field to spread an amendment into the contaminant plume to promote mixing and contaminant degradation through reaction. Here we present a coordinated suite of laboratory experiments and numerical simulations that apply EIE using two pumping sequences: A folding sequence that manipulates plume geometry by stretching and folding, and an oscillating sequence that imposes velocity perpendicular to the plume interface in accordance with previously-reported active spreading theory. Laboratory experiments investigated spreading and mixing of a non-reactive tracer using refractive index matched porous media and laser-induced fluorescence, with remarkable reproducibility between replicates. Numerical simulations matched the experimental results and simulated reactive transport by post-processing sequentially injected non-reactive tracer plumes representing the contaminant and the amendment assuming rapid reaction (ie, high Damköhler number). This study provides the first experimental verification of EIE using Darcy-scale imaging, demonstrates a novel experimental method to mimic reactive transport at the high-Damköhler number limit, and confirms active spreading theory.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> Lauren J. Sather, Eric J. Roth, Roseanna M. Neupauer, John P. Crimaldi, David C. Mays</dc:creator><category> Research Article</category><dc:title> Experiments and Simulations on Plume Spreading by Engineered Injection and Extraction in Refractive Index Matched Porous Media</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2022WR032943</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1029/2022WR032943</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR032943?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> Research Article</prism:section><prism:volume> 59</prism:volume><prism:number> 2个</prism:number></item><item><link/>https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR032201?af=R<pubDate> Mon, 06 Feb 2023 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-02-06T12:00:00-08:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley: Water Resources Research: Table of Contents<prism:coverdate> Wed, 01 Feb 2023 00:00:00 -0800</prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate> Wed, 01 Feb 2023 00:00:00 -0800</prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR032201</guid><title> Stochastic Watershed Model Ensembles for Long‐Range Planning: Verification and Validation</title><description> Water Resources Research, Volume 59, Issue 2, February 2023.</description><dc:description> Abstract Deterministic watershed models (DWMs) are used in nearly all hydrologic planning, design, and management activities, yet they cannot generate streamflow ensembles needed for hydrologic risk management (HRM). The stochastic component of DWMs is often ignored in practice, leading to a systematic bias in extreme events. Since traditional stochastic streamflow models used in HRM struggle to account for anthropogenic change, there is a need to convert DWMs into stochastic watershed models (SWMs) to generate ensembles for use in HRM. A DWM can be converted to an SWM using a post‐processing (pp) approach to add error to the DWM predictions. Many pp methods advanced in the area of flood forecasting are useful in HRM and for correcting extreme event biases. Selecting a suitable error model for pp is challenging due to nonnormality, skewness, heteroscedasticity, and autocorrelation. We develop a parsimonious pp method based on an autoregressive (AR) model of the logarithm of the ratio of the observations and simulations, which leads to AR model residuals that are approximately symmetric and independent. We document the value of pp for improving flood and low flow frequency analysis and we reintroduce the concepts of verification and validation of stochastic streamflow ensembles to ensure that the SWM can reproduce both statistics it was and was not designed to reproduce, respectively. These concepts are illustrated on a Massachusetts basin using the USGS Precipitation Runoff Modeling System, with an additional analysis indicating the approach may be applicable to 1,225 other sites across the United States.</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;Deterministic watershed models (DWMs) are used in nearly all hydrologic planning, design, and management activities, yet they cannot generate streamflow ensembles needed for hydrologic risk management (HRM). The stochastic component of DWMs is often ignored in practice, leading to a systematic bias in extreme events. Since traditional stochastic streamflow models used in HRM struggle to account for anthropogenic change, there is a need to convert DWMs into stochastic watershed models (SWMs) to generate ensembles for use in HRM. A DWM can be converted to an SWM using a post-processing (pp) approach to add error to the DWM predictions. Many pp methods advanced in the area of flood forecasting are useful in HRM and for correcting extreme event biases. Selecting a suitable error model for pp is challenging due to nonnormality, skewness, heteroscedasticity, and autocorrelation. We develop a parsimonious pp method based on an autoregressive (AR) model of the logarithm of the ratio of the observations and simulations, which leads to AR model residuals that are approximately symmetric and independent. We document the value of pp for improving flood and low flow frequency analysis and we reintroduce the concepts of verification and validation of stochastic streamflow ensembles to ensure that the SWM can reproduce both statistics it was and was not designed to reproduce, respectively. These concepts are illustrated on a Massachusetts basin using the USGS Precipitation Runoff Modeling System, with an additional analysis indicating the approach may be applicable to 1,225 other sites across the United States.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> Ghazal Shabestanipour, Zachary Brodeur, William H. Farmer, Scott Steinschneider, Richard M. Vogel, Jonathan R. Lamontagne</dc:creator><category> Research Article</category><dc:title> Stochastic Watershed Model Ensembles for Long‐Range Planning: Verification and Validation</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2022WR032201</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1029/2022WR032201</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR032201?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> Research Article</prism:section><prism:volume> 59</prism:volume><prism:number> 2个</prism:number></item><item><link/>https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033334?af=R<pubDate> Mon, 06 Feb 2023 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-02-06T12:00:00-08:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley: Water Resources Research: Table of Contents<prism:coverdate> Wed, 01 Feb 2023 00:00:00 -0800</prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate> Wed, 01 Feb 2023 00:00:00 -0800</prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR033334</guid><title> Linking Seasonal Changes in Organic Matter Composition and Nutrients to Shifting Hydraulic Gradients in Coastal Urban Canals</title><description> Water Resources Research, Volume 59, Issue 2, February 2023.</description><dc:description> Abstract The capacity for coastal river networks to transport and transform dissolved organic matter (DOM) is widely accepted. However, climate‐induced shifts in stormwater runoff and tidal extension alter fresh and marine water source contributions, associated DOM, and processing rates of nutrients entering coastal canals. We investigate how time‐variable interactions among coastal water source contributions influence the concentrations of dissolved organic carbon (DOC), nutrients, and DOM composition in urban canals. We quantified the spatiotemporal variability of DOM quality and nutrient concentrations to determine contributions of tidal marine water, rainwater, stormwater runoff, and groundwater to three coastal urban canals of Miami, Florida (USA). We created a Bayesian Monte Carlo mixing model using measurements of fluorescent DOM (fDOM), DOC concentrations, δ18O and δ2H isotopic signatures, and chloride (Cl−). Fractional contributions of groundwater averaged 17% in the dry season and 26% at peak high tide during the subtropical wet season (September–November). The canal‐to‐marine head difference (CMHD) was a primary driver of groundwater contributions to coastal urban canals and monthly patterns of fDOM/DOC. High tide (>;1 m) and discharge events were found to connect canals to upstream sources of terrestrial DOM. Loading of terrestrially sourced DOC and DOM is pulsed to urban canals, shunted downstream and supplemented by microbially sourced DOM during the wet season at high tide. Overall, we demonstrate that a combined tracer approach with isotopes and fDOM can help identify groundwater contributions to coastal waterways and that autochthonous fDOM may prime the degradation of carbon or nutrients as the CMHD pushes inland.</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;The capacity for coastal river networks to transport and transform dissolved organic matter (DOM) is widely accepted. However, climate-induced shifts in stormwater runoff and tidal extension alter fresh and marine water source contributions, associated DOM, and processing rates of nutrients entering coastal canals. We investigate how time-variable interactions among coastal water source contributions influence the concentrations of dissolved organic carbon (DOC), nutrients, and DOM composition in urban canals. We quantified the spatiotemporal variability of DOM quality and nutrient concentrations to determine contributions of tidal marine water, rainwater, stormwater runoff, and groundwater to three coastal urban canals of Miami, Florida (USA). We created a Bayesian Monte Carlo mixing model using measurements of fluorescent DOM (fDOM), DOC concentrations, δ&lt;sup>;18&lt;/sup>;O and δ&lt;sup>;2&lt;/sup>;H isotopic signatures, and chloride (Cl&lt;sup>;−&lt;/sup>;). Fractional contributions of groundwater averaged 17% in the dry season and 26% at peak high tide during the subtropical wet season (September–November). The canal-to-marine head difference (CMHD) was a primary driver of groundwater contributions to coastal urban canals and monthly patterns of fDOM/DOC. High tide (&amp;gt;1 m) and discharge events were found to connect canals to upstream sources of terrestrial DOM. Loading of terrestrially sourced DOC and DOM is pulsed to urban canals, shunted downstream and supplemented by microbially sourced DOM during the wet season at high tide. Overall, we demonstrate that a combined tracer approach with isotopes and fDOM can help identify groundwater contributions to coastal waterways and that autochthonous fDOM may prime the degradation of carbon or nutrients as the CMHD pushes inland.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> Matthew A. Smith, JS Kominoski, RM Price, OI Abdul‐Aziz, TG Troxler</dc:creator><category> Research Article</category><dc:title> Linking Seasonal Changes in Organic Matter Composition and Nutrients to Shifting Hydraulic Gradients in Coastal Urban Canals</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2022WR033334</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1029/2022WR033334</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033334?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> Research Article</prism:section><prism:volume> 59</prism:volume><prism:number> 2个</prism:number></item></channel></rss>