<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:prism="http://prismstandard.org/namespaces/basic/2.0/"><channel><title> Wiley：水资源研究：目录</title><link/>https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R<description>水资源研究目录。最新和 EarlyView 问题的文章列表。</description><language>英文</language><copyright></copyright><managingeditor>wileyonlinelibrary@wiley.com（AGU 出版物）</managingeditor><pubDate> Fri, 10 Feb 2023 08:48:25 +0000</pubDate><lastbuilddate> 2023 年 2 月 10 日星期五 08:48:25 +0000</lastbuilddate><generator> Atypon®文学™</generator><docs> https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs><ttl> 10080</ttl><dc:title> Wiley：水资源研究：目录</dc:title><dc:publisher>威利</dc:publisher><prism:publicationname>水资源研究</prism:publicationname><atom:link href="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"></atom:link><image/><title> Wiley：水资源研究：目录</title><url>https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/pb-assets/journal-banners/19447973.jpg</url><link/> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R<item><link/> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033910?af=R<pubDate> Thu, 09 Feb 2023 23:15:25 -0800</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-02-09T11:15:25-08:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley：水资源研究：目录<prism:coverdate></prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate></prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR033910</guid><title>基质扩散对非均质裂隙含水层传热的影响</title><description>水资源研究，接受的文章。</description><dc:description>摘要 裂隙含水层中的热传输取决于裂隙系统中流速的不均匀性以及裂隙中流体与岩石基质之间的扩散交换，岩石基质可以假设为不透水的。我们分析了这种扩散交换对热传输响应的影响，这与控制溶质传输的纯平流位移相反。我们专注于峰后行为，在该行为中，我们观察到具有不同于矩阵扩散特征的斜率的渐近状态，其表现出 ‐3/2 的衰减率。这种偏差是由速度场和裂缝孔径场的可变性驱动的。我们推导了预测这些预渐近尾部的理论模型，这些模型在可能与特定网络结构相关的三种极端情况下进行预测，即由大裂缝或小裂缝主导的网络，具有高度或不良渠道化流量的网络。将这些理论预测与不同三维离散裂缝网络集的数值模拟结果进行了比较。我们确定溶质和热传输响应的综合观察允许根据连通性结构对网络进行分类，并根据放大参数部分表征裂缝孔径的可变性。本文受版权保护。版权所有。</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;摘要&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;裂隙含水层中的热传输取决于裂隙系统中流速的不均匀性以及裂隙中流体与岩石基质之间的扩散交换的综合影响，可以假设为不透水的。我们分析了这种扩散交换对热传输响应的影响，这与控制溶质传输的纯平流位移相反。我们专注于峰后行为，在该行为中，我们观察到具有不同于矩阵扩散特征的斜率的渐近状态，其显示出 -3/2 的衰减率。这种偏差是由速度场和裂缝孔径场的可变性驱动的。我们推导了预测这些预渐近尾部的理论模型，这些模型在可能与特定网络结构相关的三种极端情况下进行预测，即由大裂缝或小裂缝主导的网络，具有高度或不良渠道化流量的网络。将这些理论预测与不同组三维离散裂缝网络中的数值模拟结果进行比较。我们确定，结合观察溶质和热传输响应，可以根据连接结构对网络进行分类，并根据放大参数部分表征裂缝孔径的可变性。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;本文受版权保护。保留所有权利。&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator>西尔维娅·西蒙妮、奥利维尔·布尔、菲利普·戴维</dc:creator><category>研究文章</category><dc:title>基质扩散对非均质裂隙含水层传热的影响</dc:title><dc:identifier>10.1029/2022WR033910</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname>水资源研究</prism:publicationname><prism:doi>10.1029/2022WR033910</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033910?af=R</prism:url><prism:section>研究文章</prism:section></item><item><link/>https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR032821?af=R<pubDate> Thu, 09 Feb 2023 11:28:03 -0800</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-02-09T11:28:03-08:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley：水资源研究：目录<prism:coverdate></prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate></prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR032821</guid><title>多个水库对洪峰衰减的流域规模评估</title><description>水资源研究，接受的文章。</description><dc:description>摘要 估算水库对流域规模洪峰减少的影响对于风险评估和规划目的至关重要。它通常使用详细的水文-流体动力学模拟或简单的、基于经验的指数来解决。前者以大量信息和高计算量为代价提供详细结果；后者具有成本效益且简单，但它们通常提供近似结果。两者之间的一个有前途的折衷是基于物理的衰减指数ℛ，基于等效水库的概念； ℛ 最近在文献中提出，基于矩形集水区的假设，估计沿主河道串联的多个水库的影响。在这项工作中，我们将等效水库方法扩展到具有任何形状且对水库位置没有限制的通用集水区。为了对该方法进行有效评估，我们还引入了水库影响瞬时单位过程线 (RIUH) 的新概念； RIUH 可以使用 Monte Carlo 程序导出，以包括水库对 IUH 的影响。对真实盆地中众多虚拟水库配置的模拟证明了这些方法在再现衰减效应方面的潜力。值得注意的是，ℛ 和不太简化的现实 (RIUH) 的峰值减少之间存在 3 − 5% 的平均误差。最后，我们提供了衰减指数的全球流域规模应用，它构成了评估受管理流域系统中每个水库以及新水利基础设施设计或规划的有效工具。本文受版权保护。版权所有。</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;摘要&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;在流域范围内估算水库对洪峰减少的影响对于风险评估和规划目的至关重要。它通常使用详细的水文-流体动力学模拟或简单的、基于经验的指数来解决。前者以大量信息和高计算量为代价提供详细结果；后者既经济又简单，但通常只能提供近似的结果。两者之间的一个有前途的折衷是基于物理的衰减指数ℛ，基于等效水库的概念； ℛ 最近在文献中提出，基于矩形集水区的假设，估计沿主河道串联的多个水库的影响。在这项工作中，我们将等效水库方法扩展到具有任何形状且对水库位置没有限制的通用集水区。为了对该方法进行有效评估，我们还引入了 Reservoir-influenced Instantaneous Unit Hydrograph (RIUH) 的新概念； RIUH 可以使用 Monte Carlo 程序导出，以包括水库对 IUH 的影响。对真实盆地中众多虚拟水库配置的模拟证明了这些方法在再现衰减效应方面的潜力。值得注意的是，ℛ 和不太简化的现实 (RIUH) 的峰值减少之间存在 3 − 5% 的平均误差。最后，我们提供了衰减指数在全球、流域范围内的应用，它构成了评估管理流域系统中每个水库以及设计或规划新水利基础设施的有效工具。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;本文受版权保护。保留所有权利。&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> S. Cipollini、E. Volpi、A. Fiori</dc:creator><category>研究文章</category><dc:title>多个水库对洪峰衰减的流域规模评估</dc:title><dc:identifier>10.1029/2022WR032821</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname>水资源研究</prism:publicationname><prism:doi>10.1029/2022WR032821</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR032821?af=R</prism:url><prism:section>研究文章</prism:section></item><item><link/>https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033506?af=R<pubDate> Thu, 09 Feb 2023 06:32:55 -0800</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-02-09T06:32:55-08:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley：水资源研究：目录<prism:coverdate>2023 年 2 月 1 日，星期三 00:00:00 -0800</prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate> 2023 年 2 月 1 日，星期三 00:00:00 -0800</prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR033506</guid><title>山坡层状水文模型中水文和地球物理校准数据的比较</title><description>水资源研究，第 59 卷，第 2 期，2023 年 2 月。</description><dc:description>摘要 水文和地球物理数据均可用于标定山坡水文模型。然而，这些数据通常反映了在不同空间尺度上发生的水文动态。因此，将它们用作模型校准的唯一目标可能会导致不同的最佳水力参数和水文模型行为。对于山坡尤其如此，那里的地下通常是不均匀的，代表性的基本体积可能在几立方米的规模上。本研究探讨了使用不同水文和地球物理数据校准的模型在水力参数和山坡尺度存储和通量动力学方面的差异。来自美国怀俄明州两个山坡的土壤含水量、地下水位和两个延时电阻率层析成像 (ERT) 数据集（传输电阻和反电阻率）用于校准基于物理学的地表-地下水文模型山坡。校准是使用每个数据集独立执行的，所有数据一起在每个站点产生五个校准参数集。根据校准数据集，模型预测的山坡径流和内部水文动态变化很大。结果表明，含水量校准数据产生的模型高估了山坡的近地表水储量。地下水位校准数据产生的模型更合理地代表了山坡规模的储存和通量动态。此外，ERT 校准数据产生的模型具有合理的山坡径流预测，但对内部山坡动力学的预测相对较差。这些观察结果突出了在山区环境中仔细选择水文模型校准数据的重要性。根据建模目标和模型复杂性，校准数据选择不当可能会产生预测能力有限的模型。</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;摘要&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;水文和地球物理数据均可用于校准山坡水文模型。然而，这些数据通常反映了在不同空间尺度上发生的水文动态。因此，将它们用作模型校准的唯一目标可能会导致不同的最佳水力参数和水文模型行为。对于山坡尤其如此，那里的地下通常是不均匀的，代表性的基本体积可以在几 m&lt;sup>;3&lt;/sup>; 的尺度上。本研究探讨了使用不同水文和地球物理数据校准的模型在水力参数和山坡尺度存储和通量动力学方面的差异。来自美国怀俄明州两个山坡的土壤含水量、地下水位和两个延时电阻率层析成像 (ERT) 数据集（传输电阻和反电阻率）用于校准基于物理学的地表-地下水文模型山坡。校准是使用每个数据集独立执行的，所有数据一起在每个站点产生五个校准参数集。根据校准数据集，模型预测的山坡径流和内部水文动态变化很大。结果表明，含水量校准数据产生的模型高估了山坡的近地表水储量。地下水位校准数据产生的模型更合理地代表了山坡规模的储存和通量动态。此外，ERT 校准数据产生的模型具有合理的山坡径流预测，但对内部山坡动力学的预测相对较差。这些观察结果突出了在山区环境中仔细选择水文模型校准数据的重要性。校准数据选择不当可能会产生预测能力有限的模型，具体取决于建模目标和模型复杂性。&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> MS Pleasants、TJ Kelleners、AD Parsekian、KM Befus</dc:creator><category>研究文章</category><dc:title>山坡层状水文模型中水文和地球物理校准数据的比较</dc:title><dc:identifier>10.1029/2022WR033506</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname>水资源研究</prism:publicationname><prism:doi>10.1029/2022WR033506</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033506?af=R</prism:url><prism:section>研究文章</prism:section><prism:volume>59</prism:volume><prism:number> 2个</prism:number></item><item><link/>https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033267?af=R<pubDate> Thu, 09 Feb 2023 05:36:23 -0800</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-02-09T05:36:23-08:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley：水资源研究：目录<prism:coverdate></prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate></prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR033267</guid><title>使用数字岩石建模和深度学习技术的多尺度 X 射线 CT 图像放大渗透率</title><description>水资源研究，接受的文章。</description><dc:description>摘要 本研究提出了一种直接从 CT 图像预测岩心放大绝对渗透率的工作流程，CT 图像的分辨率不足以进行直接的孔隙尺度渗透率计算。该工作流程利用深度学习技术，利用岩石原始 CT 图像数据及其通过对高分辨率 CT 图像执行流动模拟获得的相应渗透率值。岩心中更大区域的渗透率图由经过训练的神经网络预测。最后，利用达西流求解器计算了整个岩心的放大渗透率，结果与实验数据吻合较好。这种提出的基于深度学习的放大方法允许估计大规模岩心样品的渗透率，同时保留由于局部异质性引起的精细孔隙结构变化的影响。本文受版权保护。版权所有。</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;摘要&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;本研究提出了一种直接从 CT 图像预测岩心放大绝对渗透率的工作流程，CT 图像的分辨率不足以进行直接的孔隙尺度渗透率计算。该工作流程利用深度学习技术，利用岩石原始 CT 图像数据及其通过对高分辨率 CT 图像执行流动模拟获得的相应渗透率值。岩心中更大区域的渗透率图由经过训练的神经网络预测。最后，利用达西流求解器计算了整个岩心的放大渗透率，结果与实验数据吻合较好。这种基于深度学习的放大方法允许估计大尺度岩心样品的渗透率，同时保留由于局部非均质性引起的精细孔隙结构变化的影响。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;本文受版权保护。保留所有权利。&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator>姜飞、郭耀天、Takeshi Tsuji、Yoshitake Kato、Mai Shimokawara、Lionel Esteban、Mojtaba Seyyedi、Marina Pervukhina、Maxim Lebedev、Ryuta Kitamura</dc:creator><category>研究文章</category><dc:title>使用数字岩石建模和深度学习技术的多尺度 X 射线 CT 图像放大渗透率</dc:title><dc:identifier>10.1029/2022WR033267</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname>水资源研究</prism:publicationname><prism:doi>10.1029/2022WR033267</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033267?af=R</prism:url><prism:section>研究文章</prism:section></item><item><link/>https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033285?af=R<pubDate> Thu, 09 Feb 2023 03:33:26 -0800</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-02-09T03:33:26-08:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley：水资源研究：目录<prism:coverdate></prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate></prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR033285</guid><title>优先升级灌溉系统以最大限度地改善农业排水网络水质：图论方法</title><description>水资源研究，接受的文章。</description><dc:description>摘要 我们开发并展示了一种优化灌溉系统升级田地优先顺序的方法，以改善农业排水排放水质。该方法考虑了沿复杂排水网络从田地到排水网络出口的污染物衰减。该方法产生了灌溉系统升级组合的帕累托最优成本曲线，该曲线在最大程度地减少排水口负荷和最小化升级实施成本之间进行折衷。该方法利用图论数据结构来组织排水网络数据、路由排水网络流路径，并为多目标优化制定目标和约束条件。由于目标函数和约束的线性，通过降低负荷减少/成本比（污染物负荷减少单位成本）对领域进行优先排序，沿着成本曲线获得帕累托最优解。多目标优化将沿着成本曲线确定额外的帕累托最优解，提供额外的折衷。该方法允许进行计算高效的优先级排序，提供能够合并常用数据的复杂程度。成本曲线对污染物衰减系数高度敏感，衰减系数越高，导致减负荷对成本的敏感性越低。虽然这项工作的重点是灌溉系统升级，但该方法还可以优先考虑其他保护行动和/或土地利用变化情景。这种性质的分析在改进有限保护资金的分配和/​​或开发具有成本效益的水质交易计划方面可能很有价值。我们在美国爱达荷州格兰德维尤周围的一系列排水网络上展示了该方法，目的是减少蛇河的总磷负荷。</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;摘要&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;我们开发并展示了一种优化灌溉系统升级田地优先顺序的方法，以改善农业排水排放水质。该方法考虑了沿复杂排水网络从田地到排水网络出口的污染物衰减。该方法产生了灌溉系统升级组合的帕累托最优成本曲线，该曲线在最大程度地减少排水口负荷和最小化升级实施成本之间进行折衷。该方法利用图论数据结构来组织排水网络数据、路由排水网络流路径，并为多目标优化制定目标和约束条件。由于目标函数和约束的线性，通过降低负荷减少/成本比（污染物负荷减少单位成本）对领域进行优先排序，沿着成本曲线获得帕累托最优解。多目标优化将沿着成本曲线确定额外的帕累托最优解，提供额外的折衷。该方法允许进行计算高效的优先级排序，提供能够合并常用数据的复杂程度。成本曲线对污染物衰减系数高度敏感，衰减系数越高，导致减负荷对成本的敏感性越低。虽然这项工作的重点是灌溉系统升级，但该方法还可以优先考虑其他保护行动和/或土地利用变化情景。这种性质的分析在改进有限保护资金的分配和/​​或开发具有成本效益的水质交易计划方面可能很有价值。我们在美国爱达荷州格兰德维尤周围的一系列排水网络上展示了该方法，目的是减少蛇河的总磷负荷。&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator>迪伦·R·哈普、安东尼·S·奥兰多、埃利奥特·霍恩、阿迪蒂亚·苏德、汤米·弗兰岑、麦迪·鲁本森、大卫·L·艾奇森、迪翁·韦伯斯特、尼克·奥斯曼、特蕾莎·K·布尔苏、大卫·普里莫齐奇</dc:creator><category>研究文章</category><dc:title>优先升级灌溉系统以最大限度地改善农业排水网络水质：图论方法</dc:title><dc:identifier>10.1029/2022WR033285</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname>水资源研究</prism:publicationname><prism:doi>10.1029/2022WR033285</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033285?af=R</prism:url><prism:section>研究文章</prism:section></item><item><link/>https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR032653?af=R<pubDate> Tue, 07 Feb 2023 06:42:25 -0800</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-02-07T06:42:25-08:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley：水资源研究：目录<prism:coverdate></prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate></prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR032653</guid><title>使用递归神经网络预测模型有效优化地热水库的能量回收</title><description>水资源研究，接受的文章。</description><dc:description>摘要 可以通过优化油田开发和管理计划来提高地热储层的长期能源生产性能。然而，需要可靠的预测模型来评估和优化底层油藏在各种运营和开发策略下的性能。在传统框架中，基于物理的模拟模型用于预测地热储层的能源生产性能。然而，详细的模拟模型构建起来并不容易，需要对储层条件和特性进行可靠的描述，并且需要很高的计算复杂性。数据驱动的预测模型可以提供用于优化工作流程的有效替代方案。本文提出了一种地热储层净发电优化框架，使用递归神经网络 (RNN) 的变体作为数据驱动的预测模型。开发和训练 RNN 架构以取代仿真模型，以计算高效地预测目标函数及其相对于井控变量的梯度。使用基于梯度的局部搜索算法，通过自动调整超过 12 年的生产和注入井的质量流量来优化油田的净发电性能。提出了两个现场规模的例子来研究开发的数据驱动预测和优化框架的性能。通过与使用真实地热储层数值模拟模型获得的结果进行比较，对 RNN 模型的预测和优化结果进行了评估。</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;摘要&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;提高地热储层的长期能源生产性能可以通过优化油田开发和管理计划来实现。然而，需要可靠的预测模型来评估和优化底层油藏在各种运营和开发策略下的性能。在传统框架中，基于物理的模拟模型用于预测地热储层的能源生产性能。然而，详细的模拟模型构建起来并不容易，需要对储层条件和特性进行可靠的描述，并且需要很高的计算复杂性。数据驱动的预测模型可以提供用于优化工作流程的有效替代方案。本文提出了一种优化框架，该框架使用递归神经网络 (RNN) 的变体作为数据驱动的预测模型，用于地热储层中的净发电量。开发和训练 RNN 架构以取代仿真模型，以计算高效地预测目标函数及其相对于井控变量的梯度。通过使用基于梯度的局部搜索算法自动调整超过 12 年的生产井和注入井的质量流量，优化了该油田的净发电性能。提出了两个现场规模的例子来研究开发的数据驱动的预测和优化框架的性能。通过与真实地热储层数值模拟模型的对比，对RNN模型的预测和优化结果进行了评价。&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> Zhen Qin、Anyue Jiang、Dave Faulder、Trenton T. Cladouhos、Behnam Jafarpour</dc:creator><category>研究文章</category><dc:title>使用递归神经网络预测模型有效优化地热水库的能量回收</dc:title><dc:identifier>10.1029/2022WR032653</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname>水资源研究</prism:publicationname><prism:doi>10.1029/2022WR032653</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR032653?af=R</prism:url><prism:section>研究文章</prism:section></item><item><link/>https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR032920?af=R<pubDate> Tue, 07 Feb 2023 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-02-07T12:00:00-08:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley：水资源研究：目录<prism:coverdate>2023 年 2 月 1 日，星期三 00:00:00 -0800</prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate> 2023 年 2 月 1 日，星期三 00:00:00 -0800</prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR032920</guid><title>使用浅层应变张量表征深层地质储层</title><description>水资源研究，第 59 卷，第 2 期，2023 年 2 月。</description><dc:description>摘要 从地质储层中储存和回收水、碳和热量是在不断变化的气候中管理资源的核心。我们测试了这样一个假设，即由注入或生产流体引起的应变张量可以在浅层测量并解释以促进对底层深层含水层或储层的理解。大地测量级应变计部署在 Bartlesville 地层上方 30 米深的地方，巴特尔斯维尔地层是俄克拉荷马州塔尔萨附近 500 米深的砂岩。应变计位于注入井 9A 以东 220 米处，在 Bartlesville 地层底部的渗透透镜中完成。在持续时间从几小时到几周不等的四次测试中，水以大约 1.0 L/s 的速度注入 9A 井。水平应变增加（张力），周向应变比径向应变大几倍。垂直应变在注射过程中降低（压缩）。在最初的几个小时内，应变率约为 100 nε/天，但在大多数测试期间，应变率下降并约为 10 nε/天。四种独立的多孔弹性模拟和反演方法预测的储层特性和几何形状彼此相似，并且与储层的独立信息一致。所有应变解释都预测可渗透透镜的边界出现在应变计附近，这与现场的核心数据一致。通过匹配垂直、径向和周向应变来定位透光透镜的边界，这证明了测量应变张量的价值。</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;摘要&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;从地质储层中储存和回收水、碳和热量是在不断变化的气候中管理资源的核心。我们测试了这样一个假设，即由注入或生产流体引起的应变张量可以在浅层测量并解释以促进对底层深层含水层或储层的理解。大地测量级应变仪部署在 Bartlesville 地层上方 30 米深的地方，巴特尔斯维尔地层是俄克拉荷马州塔尔萨附近 500 米深的砂岩。应变计位于注入井 9A 以东 220 米处，在 Bartlesville 地层底部的渗透透镜中完成。在持续时间从几小时到几周不等的四次测试中，水以大约 1.0 L/s 的速度注入 9A 井。水平应变增加（张力），周向应变比径向应变大几倍。垂直应变在注射过程中降低（压缩）。在最初的几个小时内，应变率约为 100 nε/天，但在大多数测试期间，应变率下降并约为 10 nε/天。四种独立的多孔弹性模拟和反演方法预测的储层特性和几何形状彼此相似，并且与储层的独立信息一致。所有应变解释都预测可渗透透镜的边界出现在应变计附近，这与现场的核心数据一致。通过匹配垂直、径向和环向应变来定位透水透镜的边界，体现了测量应变张量的价值。&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator>劳伦斯·C·默多克、斯科特·德沃尔夫、列昂尼德·N·日耳曼诺维奇、斯蒂芬·莫伊西、亚历克斯·汉纳、索海尔·鲁迪尼、罗伯特·莫克</dc:creator><category>研究文章</category><dc:title>使用浅层应变张量表征深层地质储层</dc:title><dc:identifier>10.1029/2022WR032920</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname>水资源研究</prism:publicationname><prism:doi>10.1029/2022WR032920</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR032920?af=R</prism:url><prism:section>研究文章</prism:section><prism:volume>59</prism:volume><prism:number> 2个</prism:number></item><item><link/>https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR032385?af=R<pubDate> Tue, 07 Feb 2023 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-02-07T12:00:00-08:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley：水资源研究：目录<prism:coverdate>2023 年 2 月 1 日，星期三 00:00:00 -0800</prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate> 2023 年 2 月 1 日，星期三 00:00:00 -0800</prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR032385</guid><title>土壤-水蒸发过程中稳定的水同位素体分馏：使用土壤-大气耦合模型进行分析</title><description>水资源研究，第 59 卷，第 2 期，2023 年 2 月。</description><dc:description>摘要 大气-土壤系统形成一个高度耦合的系统，这使得蒸发等关键过程变得复杂，因为质量、能量和动量传递受到这两个域的影响。为了加强对土壤蒸发过程的理解，稳定的水同位素体是追踪这些系统内水运动的合适工具，因为较重的同位素体富集在残留液相中。由于准确模拟土壤-水蒸发涉及复杂的耦合过程，土壤-大气界面流动和传输过程中的量化分馏仍然是一个开放的研究领域。在这项工作中，我们提出了一个多相多组分传输模型，该模型解决了通过近地表大气和土壤的流动，并使用数值模拟环境 DuMux 模拟了稳定的水同位素体的传输和分馏。使用这种耦合模型，我们通过求解成分流动方程并在土壤-大气界面使用合适的耦合条件而不是常用的参数化来模拟稳定的水同位素体在土壤和大气中的传输和分馏过程。在一系列裸土蒸发的例子中，稳定的水同位素体的传输和分布在不同的条件和假设下进行了数值评估，包括不同的大气条件（湍流/层流、风速）及其对空间和时间分布的影响的同位素组成。基于这些结果，我们观察了土壤中同位素体的富集如何与蒸发过程的不同阶段相关联。进行定性研究以验证我们方法中的单一分馏过程。</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;摘要&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;大气-土壤系统形成一个高度耦合的系统，这使得蒸发等关键过程变得复杂，因为质量、能量和动量传递受到两个域的影响。为了加强对土壤蒸发过程的理解，稳定的水同位素体是追踪这些系统内水运动的合适工具，因为较重的同位素体富集在残留液相中。 Due to the complex coupled processes involved in simulating soil-water evaporation accurately, quantifying fractionation during flow and transport processes at the soil-atmosphere interface remains an open research area. In this work, we present a multi-phase multi-component transport model that resolves flow through the near-surface atmosphere and the soil, and models transport and fractionation of the stable water isotopologues using the numerical simulation environment DuMu&lt;sup>;x&lt;/sup>;. Using this coupled model, we simulate transport and fractionation processes of stable water isotopologues in soils and the atmosphere by solving compositional flow equations and by using suitable coupling conditions at the soil-atmosphere interface instead of commonly used parameterization. In a series of examples of evaporation from bare soil, the transport and distribution of stable water isotopologues are evaluated numerically with varied conditions and assumptions, including different atmospheric conditions (turbulent/laminar flow, wind speed) and their impact on the spatial and temporal distribution of the isotopic composition. Building on these results, we observed how the enrichment of the isotopologues in soil is linked with the different stages of the evaporation process. A qualitative study is conducted to verify single fractionation processes in our approach.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> Stefanie Kiemle, Katharina Heck, Edward Coltman, Rainer Helmig</dc:creator><category> Research Article</category><dc:title> Stable Water Isotopologue Fractionation During Soil‐Water Evaporation: Analysis Using a Coupled Soil‐Atmosphere Model</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2022WR032385</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1029/2022WR032385</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR032385?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> Research Article</prism:section><prism:volume> 59</prism:volume><prism:number> 2个</prism:number></item><item><link/>https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2021WR031347?af=R<pubDate> Tue, 07 Feb 2023 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-02-07T12:00:00-08:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley: Water Resources Research: Table of Contents<prism:coverdate> Wed, 01 Feb 2023 00:00:00 -0800</prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate> Wed, 01 Feb 2023 00:00:00 -0800</prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2021WR031347</guid><title> Assessment of Impacts of Climate Change on Indian Riverine Thermal Regimes Using Hybrid Deep Learning Methods</title><description> Water Resources Research, Volume 59, Issue 2, February 2023.</description><dc:description> Abstract Understanding the riverine thermal regimes is challenging due to sparse spatiotemporal data of river water temperatures (RWTs). The development of systematic models combined with machine learning models under data‐limited context has not been intensively studied for the prediction of RWT. The present study developed hybrid models using long short‐term memory (LSTM), integrated with (a) k‐nearest neighbor (k‐NN) bootstrap resampling algorithms (kNN‐LSTM) to address the data limitations of RWT prediction and (b) discrete wavelet transform (WT) approach (WT‐LSTM) to address the time–frequency localized features of RWT prediction. The study assessed the climate change impacts on RWT using an ensemble of National Aeronautics Space Administration Earth Exchange Global Daily Downscaled Projections of air temperature with Representative Concentration Pathway scenarios 4.5 and 8.5 for seven major polluted river catchments of India. The hybrid kNN‐LSTM has effectively predicted RWT at monthly time scales under data limitations and outperformed the standalone LSTM, WT‐LSTM, and hybrid three‐parameter version air2stream models. The RWT increase for Tunga‐Bhadra, Musi, Ganga, and Narmada basins is predicted as 3.0, 4.0, 4.6, and 4.7°C, respectively, for 2071–2100.</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;Understanding the riverine thermal regimes is challenging due to sparse spatiotemporal data of river water temperatures (RWTs). The development of systematic models combined with machine learning models under data-limited context has not been intensively studied for the prediction of RWT. The present study developed hybrid models using long short-term memory (LSTM), integrated with (a) k-nearest neighbor (k-NN) bootstrap resampling algorithms (kNN-LSTM) to address the data limitations of RWT prediction and (b) discrete wavelet transform (WT) approach (WT-LSTM) to address the time–frequency localized features of RWT prediction. The study assessed the climate change impacts on RWT using an ensemble of National Aeronautics Space Administration Earth Exchange Global Daily Downscaled Projections of air temperature with Representative Concentration Pathway scenarios 4.5 and 8.5 for seven major polluted river catchments of India. The hybrid kNN-LSTM has effectively predicted RWT at monthly time scales under data limitations and outperformed the standalone LSTM, WT-LSTM, and hybrid three-parameter version air2stream models. The RWT increase for Tunga-Bhadra, Musi, Ganga, and Narmada basins is predicted as 3.0, 4.0, 4.6, and 4.7°C, respectively, for 2071–2100.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> S. Rehana, M. Rajesh</dc:creator><category> Research Article</category><dc:title> Assessment of Impacts of Climate Change on Indian Riverine Thermal Regimes Using Hybrid Deep Learning Methods</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2021WR031347</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1029/2021WR031347</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2021WR031347?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> Research Article</prism:section><prism:volume> 59</prism:volume><prism:number> 2个</prism:number></item><item><link/>https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR032426?af=R<pubDate> Tue, 07 Feb 2023 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-02-07T12:00:00-08:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley: Water Resources Research: Table of Contents<prism:coverdate> Wed, 01 Feb 2023 00:00:00 -0800</prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate> Wed, 01 Feb 2023 00:00:00 -0800</prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR032426</guid><title> Groundwater Plays an Important Role in Controlling Riverine Dissolved Organic Matter in a Cold Alpine Catchment, the Qinghai–Tibet Plateau</title><description> Water Resources Research, Volume 59, Issue 2, February 2023.</description><dc:description> Abstract In cold alpine areas, the hydrological control on dissolved organic matter (DOM) export in relation to permafrost distribution remains uncertain on a catchment scale. To address this, the seasonal variations in DOM chemical features of groundwater and stream water were examined from 2013 to 2019 in a representative catchment on the northeastern Qinghai–Tibet Plateau, which is covered by both permafrost (at elevations higher than 3,500 m asl) and seasonally frozen areas. The results show that the highest dissolved organic carbon (DOC) concentration occurred during the thawing period (April–May), while the highest DOC flux occurred during the thawed period (June–early October). In the permafrost area, the freeze–thaw process significantly influenced the groundwater flow paths and DOM. During the thawing period, with shallow groundwater flow path through the organic soil layer, the stream water DOM recharged by suprapermafrost groundwater was characterized by high aromaticity and high DOC concentrations. During the thawed period, the deepening groundwater flow path through the mineral layer and dilution by overland flow, resulted in low DOC concentrations and DOM with lower aromaticity in stream water. When groundwater flowed from the permafrost area into the porous aquifers in the seasonally frozen area, the groundwater flow path also affected DOM dynamics. The stream water at the catchment outlet, which received groundwater discharge from the porous aquifer, showed a lower peak DOC concentration, a higher proportion of protein‐like DOM, and a higher contribution of cold season DOC flux to annual DOC flux when compared to the water flowing out from the permafrost area. Our work highlights the role of the thick, porous aquifer in the seasonally frozen area in regulating DOM export. The results suggest that the cold alpine area may exhibit a stronger positive feedback to climate warming than that in Arctic areas.</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;In cold alpine areas, the hydrological control on dissolved organic matter (DOM) export in relation to permafrost distribution remains uncertain on a catchment scale. To address this, the seasonal variations in DOM chemical features of groundwater and stream water were examined from 2013 to 2019 in a representative catchment on the northeastern Qinghai–Tibet Plateau, which is covered by both permafrost (at elevations higher than 3,500 m asl) and seasonally frozen areas. The results show that the highest dissolved organic carbon (DOC) concentration occurred during the thawing period (April–May), while the highest DOC flux occurred during the thawed period (June–early October). In the permafrost area, the freeze–thaw process significantly influenced the groundwater flow paths and DOM. During the thawing period, with shallow groundwater flow path through the organic soil layer, the stream water DOM recharged by suprapermafrost groundwater was characterized by high aromaticity and high DOC concentrations. During the thawed period, the deepening groundwater flow path through the mineral layer and dilution by overland flow, resulted in low DOC concentrations and DOM with lower aromaticity in stream water. When groundwater flowed from the permafrost area into the porous aquifers in the seasonally frozen area, the groundwater flow path also affected DOM dynamics. The stream water at the catchment outlet, which received groundwater discharge from the porous aquifer, showed a lower peak DOC concentration, a higher proportion of protein-like DOM, and a higher contribution of cold season DOC flux to annual DOC flux when compared to the water flowing out from the permafrost area. Our work highlights the role of the thick, porous aquifer in the seasonally frozen area in regulating DOM export. The results suggest that the cold alpine area may exhibit a stronger positive feedback to climate warming than that in Arctic areas.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> Yalu Hu, Rui Ma, Ziyong Sun, Yan Zheng, Zhao Pan, Lusong Zhao</dc:creator><category> Research Article</category><dc:title> Groundwater Plays an Important Role in Controlling Riverine Dissolved Organic Matter in a Cold Alpine Catchment, the Qinghai–Tibet Plateau</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2022WR032426</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1029/2022WR032426</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR032426?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> Research Article</prism:section><prism:volume> 59</prism:volume><prism:number> 2个</prism:number></item><item><link/>https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR032943?af=R<pubDate> Mon, 06 Feb 2023 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-02-06T12:00:00-08:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley: Water Resources Research: Table of Contents<prism:coverdate> Wed, 01 Feb 2023 00:00:00 -0800</prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate> Wed, 01 Feb 2023 00:00:00 -0800</prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR032943</guid><title> Experiments and Simulations on Plume Spreading by Engineered Injection and Extraction in Refractive Index Matched Porous Media</title><description> Water Resources Research, Volume 59, Issue 2, February 2023.</description><dc:description> Abstract Engineered injection and extraction (EIE) is an in situ groundwater remediation strategy that imposes an engineered spatially and temporally varying velocity field to spread an amendment into the contaminant plume to promote mixing and contaminant degradation through reaction. Here we present a coordinated suite of laboratory experiments and numerical simulations that apply EIE using two pumping sequences: A folding sequence that manipulates plume geometry by stretching and folding, and an oscillating sequence that imposes velocity perpendicular to the plume interface in accordance with previously‐reported active spreading theory. Laboratory experiments investigated spreading and mixing of a non‐reactive tracer using refractive index matched porous media and laser‐induced fluorescence, with remarkable reproducibility between replicates. Numerical simulations matched the experimental results and simulated reactive transport by post‐processing sequentially injected non‐reactive tracer plumes representing the contaminant and the amendment assuming rapid reaction (ie, high Damköhler number). This study provides the first experimental verification of EIE using Darcy‐scale imaging, demonstrates a novel experimental method to mimic reactive transport at the high‐Damköhler number limit, and confirms active spreading theory.</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;Engineered injection and extraction (EIE) is an in situ groundwater remediation strategy that imposes an engineered spatially and temporally varying velocity field to spread an amendment into the contaminant plume to promote mixing and contaminant degradation through reaction. Here we present a coordinated suite of laboratory experiments and numerical simulations that apply EIE using two pumping sequences: A folding sequence that manipulates plume geometry by stretching and folding, and an oscillating sequence that imposes velocity perpendicular to the plume interface in accordance with previously-reported active spreading theory. Laboratory experiments investigated spreading and mixing of a non-reactive tracer using refractive index matched porous media and laser-induced fluorescence, with remarkable reproducibility between replicates. Numerical simulations matched the experimental results and simulated reactive transport by post-processing sequentially injected non-reactive tracer plumes representing the contaminant and the amendment assuming rapid reaction (ie, high Damköhler number). This study provides the first experimental verification of EIE using Darcy-scale imaging, demonstrates a novel experimental method to mimic reactive transport at the high-Damköhler number limit, and confirms active spreading theory.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> Lauren J. Sather, Eric J. Roth, Roseanna M. Neupauer, John P. Crimaldi, David C. Mays</dc:creator><category> Research Article</category><dc:title> Experiments and Simulations on Plume Spreading by Engineered Injection and Extraction in Refractive Index Matched Porous Media</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2022WR032943</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1029/2022WR032943</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR032943?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> Research Article</prism:section><prism:volume> 59</prism:volume><prism:number> 2个</prism:number></item><item><link/>https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR032201?af=R<pubDate> Mon, 06 Feb 2023 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-02-06T12:00:00-08:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley: Water Resources Research: Table of Contents<prism:coverdate> Wed, 01 Feb 2023 00:00:00 -0800</prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate> Wed, 01 Feb 2023 00:00:00 -0800</prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR032201</guid><title> Stochastic Watershed Model Ensembles for Long‐Range Planning: Verification and Validation</title><description> Water Resources Research, Volume 59, Issue 2, February 2023.</description><dc:description> Abstract Deterministic watershed models (DWMs) are used in nearly all hydrologic planning, design, and management activities, yet they cannot generate streamflow ensembles needed for hydrologic risk management (HRM). The stochastic component of DWMs is often ignored in practice, leading to a systematic bias in extreme events. Since traditional stochastic streamflow models used in HRM struggle to account for anthropogenic change, there is a need to convert DWMs into stochastic watershed models (SWMs) to generate ensembles for use in HRM. A DWM can be converted to an SWM using a post‐processing (pp) approach to add error to the DWM predictions. Many pp methods advanced in the area of flood forecasting are useful in HRM and for correcting extreme event biases. Selecting a suitable error model for pp is challenging due to nonnormality, skewness, heteroscedasticity, and autocorrelation. We develop a parsimonious pp method based on an autoregressive (AR) model of the logarithm of the ratio of the observations and simulations, which leads to AR model residuals that are approximately symmetric and independent. We document the value of pp for improving flood and low flow frequency analysis and we reintroduce the concepts of verification and validation of stochastic streamflow ensembles to ensure that the SWM can reproduce both statistics it was and was not designed to reproduce, respectively. These concepts are illustrated on a Massachusetts basin using the USGS Precipitation Runoff Modeling System, with an additional analysis indicating the approach may be applicable to 1,225 other sites across the United States.</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;Deterministic watershed models (DWMs) are used in nearly all hydrologic planning, design, and management activities, yet they cannot generate streamflow ensembles needed for hydrologic risk management (HRM). The stochastic component of DWMs is often ignored in practice, leading to a systematic bias in extreme events. Since traditional stochastic streamflow models used in HRM struggle to account for anthropogenic change, there is a need to convert DWMs into stochastic watershed models (SWMs) to generate ensembles for use in HRM. A DWM can be converted to an SWM using a post-processing (pp) approach to add error to the DWM predictions. Many pp methods advanced in the area of flood forecasting are useful in HRM and for correcting extreme event biases. Selecting a suitable error model for pp is challenging due to nonnormality, skewness, heteroscedasticity, and autocorrelation. We develop a parsimonious pp method based on an autoregressive (AR) model of the logarithm of the ratio of the observations and simulations, which leads to AR model residuals that are approximately symmetric and independent. We document the value of pp for improving flood and low flow frequency analysis and we reintroduce the concepts of verification and validation of stochastic streamflow ensembles to ensure that the SWM can reproduce both statistics it was and was not designed to reproduce, respectively. These concepts are illustrated on a Massachusetts basin using the USGS Precipitation Runoff Modeling System, with an additional analysis indicating the approach may be applicable to 1,225 other sites across the United States.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> Ghazal Shabestanipour, Zachary Brodeur, William H. Farmer, Scott Steinschneider, Richard M. Vogel, Jonathan R. Lamontagne</dc:creator><category> Research Article</category><dc:title> Stochastic Watershed Model Ensembles for Long‐Range Planning: Verification and Validation</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2022WR032201</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1029/2022WR032201</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR032201?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> Research Article</prism:section><prism:volume> 59</prism:volume><prism:number> 2个</prism:number></item><item><link/>https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033334?af=R<pubDate> Mon, 06 Feb 2023 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-02-06T12:00:00-08:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley: Water Resources Research: Table of Contents<prism:coverdate> Wed, 01 Feb 2023 00:00:00 -0800</prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate> Wed, 01 Feb 2023 00:00:00 -0800</prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR033334</guid><title> Linking Seasonal Changes in Organic Matter Composition and Nutrients to Shifting Hydraulic Gradients in Coastal Urban Canals</title><description> Water Resources Research, Volume 59, Issue 2, February 2023.</description><dc:description> Abstract The capacity for coastal river networks to transport and transform dissolved organic matter (DOM) is widely accepted. However, climate‐induced shifts in stormwater runoff and tidal extension alter fresh and marine water source contributions, associated DOM, and processing rates of nutrients entering coastal canals. We investigate how time‐variable interactions among coastal water source contributions influence the concentrations of dissolved organic carbon (DOC), nutrients, and DOM composition in urban canals. We quantified the spatiotemporal variability of DOM quality and nutrient concentrations to determine contributions of tidal marine water, rainwater, stormwater runoff, and groundwater to three coastal urban canals of Miami, Florida (USA). We created a Bayesian Monte Carlo mixing model using measurements of fluorescent DOM (fDOM), DOC concentrations, δ18O and δ2H isotopic signatures, and chloride (Cl−). Fractional contributions of groundwater averaged 17% in the dry season and 26% at peak high tide during the subtropical wet season (September–November). The canal‐to‐marine head difference (CMHD) was a primary driver of groundwater contributions to coastal urban canals and monthly patterns of fDOM/DOC. High tide (>;1 m) and discharge events were found to connect canals to upstream sources of terrestrial DOM. Loading of terrestrially sourced DOC and DOM is pulsed to urban canals, shunted downstream and supplemented by microbially sourced DOM during the wet season at high tide. Overall, we demonstrate that a combined tracer approach with isotopes and fDOM can help identify groundwater contributions to coastal waterways and that autochthonous fDOM may prime the degradation of carbon or nutrients as the CMHD pushes inland.</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;The capacity for coastal river networks to transport and transform dissolved organic matter (DOM) is widely accepted. However, climate-induced shifts in stormwater runoff and tidal extension alter fresh and marine water source contributions, associated DOM, and processing rates of nutrients entering coastal canals. We investigate how time-variable interactions among coastal water source contributions influence the concentrations of dissolved organic carbon (DOC), nutrients, and DOM composition in urban canals. We quantified the spatiotemporal variability of DOM quality and nutrient concentrations to determine contributions of tidal marine water, rainwater, stormwater runoff, and groundwater to three coastal urban canals of Miami, Florida (USA). We created a Bayesian Monte Carlo mixing model using measurements of fluorescent DOM (fDOM), DOC concentrations, δ&lt;sup>;18&lt;/sup>;O and δ&lt;sup>;2&lt;/sup>;H isotopic signatures, and chloride (Cl&lt;sup>;−&lt;/sup>;). Fractional contributions of groundwater averaged 17% in the dry season and 26% at peak high tide during the subtropical wet season (September–November). The canal-to-marine head difference (CMHD) was a primary driver of groundwater contributions to coastal urban canals and monthly patterns of fDOM/DOC. High tide (&amp;gt;1 m) and discharge events were found to connect canals to upstream sources of terrestrial DOM. Loading of terrestrially sourced DOC and DOM is pulsed to urban canals, shunted downstream and supplemented by microbially sourced DOM during the wet season at high tide. Overall, we demonstrate that a combined tracer approach with isotopes and fDOM can help identify groundwater contributions to coastal waterways and that autochthonous fDOM may prime the degradation of carbon or nutrients as the CMHD pushes inland.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> Matthew A. Smith, JS Kominoski, RM Price, OI Abdul‐Aziz, TG Troxler</dc:creator><category> Research Article</category><dc:title> Linking Seasonal Changes in Organic Matter Composition and Nutrients to Shifting Hydraulic Gradients in Coastal Urban Canals</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2022WR033334</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1029/2022WR033334</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033334?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> Research Article</prism:section><prism:volume> 59</prism:volume><prism:number> 2个</prism:number></item><item><link/>https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033443?af=R<pubDate> Fri, 03 Feb 2023 22:44:43 -0800</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-02-03T10:44:43-08:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley: Water Resources Research: Table of Contents <prism:coverdate></prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate></prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR033443</guid><title> Self‐regulation mechanisms in porous media: The origin of the diversity of fluid displacement patterns</title><description> Water Resources Research, Accepted Article.</description><dc:description> Abstract During two‐phase fluid displacement in a porous medium, self‐regulation mechanisms provide negative feedback to approach a state of minimum operating power. The versatility of these self‐regulation mechanisms results in a large diversity of fluid displacement patterns. For example, the introduction of a highly tortuous displacement channel, the appearance of the retention and development regions of the displaced phase, and the expansion of the displacement path area of the invading phase are the macroscopic responses of the two‐phase flow system to the self‐regulation mechanisms under different constraints. These new findings provide compelling physical explanations for the underlying mechanisms governing fluid displacement pattern transitions and the influence of inertial effects on the displacement patterns. This article is protected by copyright.版权所有。</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;During two-phase fluid displacement in a porous medium, self-regulation mechanisms provide negative feedback to approach a state of minimum operating power. The versatility of these self-regulation mechanisms results in a large diversity of fluid displacement patterns. For example, the introduction of a highly tortuous displacement channel, the appearance of the retention and development regions of the displaced phase, and the expansion of the displacement path area of the invading phase are the macroscopic responses of the two-phase flow system to the self-regulation mechanisms under different constraints. These new findings provide compelling physical explanations for the underlying mechanisms governing fluid displacement pattern transitions and the influence of inertial effects on the displacement patterns.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This article is protected by copyright. All rights reserved.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> Xiaokang Guo, Runcong Liu, Xiaodong Wang</dc:creator><category> Research Article</category><dc:title> Self‐regulation mechanisms in porous media: The origin of the diversity of fluid displacement patterns</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2022WR033443</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1029/2022WR033443</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033443?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> Research Article</prism:section></item><item><link/> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033613?af=R<pubDate> Fri, 03 Feb 2023 22:26:57 -0800</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-02-03T10:26:57-08:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley: Water Resources Research: Table of Contents <prism:coverdate></prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate></prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR033613</guid><title> Solute Trapping and the Mechanisms of Non‐Fickian Transport in Partially Saturated Porous Media</title><description> Water Resources Research, Accepted Article.</description><dc:description> Abstract We study the upscaling of pore‐scale solute transport in partially saturated porous media at different saturation degrees. The interaction between structural heterogeneity, phases distribution and small‐scale flow dynamics induces complex flow patterns and broad probability distributions of flow, which control key aspects of transport, such as residence and arrival times, dispersion, and spatial solute distributions, as well as chemical reactions. A continuous‐time random walk (CTRW) framework that integrates the processes of advection, diffusion, and trapping in immobile zones is used to upscale and evaluate the transport of diluted solutes. Results of this model were compared to direct numerical simulations solving the advection‐diffusion equation in experimental saturation patterns. The comparison between simulations results, with different Péclet numbers (Pe), and the physics‐based upscaled CTRW approach allows for a quantitative analysis of the governing factors of transport in partially saturated porous media. This analysis shows that the fluid phase saturation decreases the advective tortuosity, the media&#39;s characteristic length, the fraction of the immobile region, and the mean trapping time. At the same time, for a given saturation degree, the normalized mean trapping time is proportional to the Pe. This suggests that the characteristic trapping length is proportional to the media&#39;s characteristic (correlation) length. Moreover, the trapping frequency decreases with increasing Pe.</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;We study the upscaling of pore-scale solute transport in partially saturated porous media at different saturation degrees. The interaction between structural heterogeneity, phases distribution and small-scale flow dynamics induces complex flow patterns and broad probability distributions of flow, which control key aspects of transport, such as residence and arrival times, dispersion, and spatial solute distributions, as well as chemical reactions. A continuous-time random walk (CTRW) framework that integrates the processes of advection, diffusion, and trapping in immobile zones is used to upscale and evaluate the transport of diluted solutes. Results of this model were compared to direct numerical simulations solving the advection-diffusion equation in experimental saturation patterns. The comparison between simulations results, with different Péclet numbers (&lt;i>;Pe&lt;/i>;), and the physics-based upscaled CTRW approach allows for a quantitative analysis of the governing factors of transport in partially saturated porous media. This analysis shows that the fluid phase saturation decreases the advective tortuosity, the media&#39;s characteristic length, the fraction of the immobile region, and the mean trapping time. At the same time, for a given saturation degree, the normalized mean trapping time is proportional to the &lt;i>;Pe&lt;/i>;. This suggests that the characteristic trapping length is proportional to the media&#39;s characteristic (correlation) length. Moreover, the trapping frequency decreases with increasing &lt;i>;Pe&lt;/i>;.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> Ilan Ben‐Noah, Juan J. Hidalgo, Joaquin Jimenez‐Martinez, Marco Dentz</dc:creator><category> Research Article</category><dc:title> Solute Trapping and the Mechanisms of Non‐Fickian Transport in Partially Saturated Porous Media</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2022WR033613</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1029/2022WR033613</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033613?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> Research Article</prism:section></item><item><link/> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR032091?af=R<pubDate> Fri, 03 Feb 2023 15:55:12 -0800</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-02-03T03:55:12-08:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley: Water Resources Research: Table of Contents <prism:coverdate></prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate></prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR032091</guid><title> A new approach for assessing groundwater recharge by combining GRACE and baseflow with case studies in karst areas of southwest China</title><description> Water Resources Research, Accepted Article.</description><dc:description> Abstract A new approach combining groundwater storage change (GWSC) derived from Gravity Recovery and Climate Experiment (GRACE) satellite data and baseflow was proposed to estimate groundwater recharge at large spatial scales but a short (monthly) time scale. This method was applied in two typical karst basins of southwest China, the Wujiang River basin (WRB, ∼87,900 km2, ∼70% karstification) and Xijiang River Basin (XRB, ∼360,000 km2, ∼44% karstification). The 2006‐2012 monthly baseflow was first separated from in situ streamflow through multivariate regression analysis. Groundwater recharge was estimated using separated baseflow and GWSC estimated from GRACE data and observation‐based groundwater‐level data. The comparison between GRACE‐ and observation‐based recharge in the larger XRB shows better consistency, while that in the smaller WRB shows larger discrepancies. Considering the associated uncertainty (60‐93 mm/yr), the 2006‐2012 mean recharge in two basins, ranging 199‐225 mm/yr (17‐19% of precipitation) is comparable to bulletin‐reported estimates (∼145 mm/yr). Both the degree of karstification and aquifer water table depth influence recharge and discharge processes in karst areas of southwest China. The more karstic WRB exhibits more rapid infiltration (due to more developed permeable epikarst zone) and higher discharge capability (due to more developed underground drainage systems), particularly during dry periods (2009, 2011, and winter). Baseflow exhibits a shorter time lag to recharge and GWSC in the XRB than WRB owing to more quick flow, lower storage with more rapid infiltration, and shorter mean groundwater residence time. Observation‐based monthly recharge reflects different rainfall‐infiltration‐runoff processes under different rainfall intensities, particularly in the WRB.</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;A new approach combining groundwater storage change (GWSC) derived from Gravity Recovery and Climate Experiment (GRACE) satellite data and baseflow was proposed to estimate groundwater recharge at large spatial scales but a short (monthly) time scale. This method was applied in two typical karst basins of southwest China, the Wujiang River basin (WRB, ∼87,900 km&lt;sup>;2&lt;/sup>;, ∼70% karstification) and Xijiang River Basin (XRB, ∼360,000 km&lt;sup>;2&lt;/sup>;, ∼44% karstification). The 2006-2012 monthly baseflow was first separated from &lt;i>;in situ&lt;/i>; streamflow through multivariate regression analysis. Groundwater recharge was estimated using separated baseflow and GWSC estimated from GRACE data and observation-based groundwater-level data. The comparison between GRACE- and observation-based recharge in the larger XRB shows better consistency, while that in the smaller WRB shows larger discrepancies. Considering the associated uncertainty (60-93 mm/yr), the 2006-2012 mean recharge in two basins, ranging 199-225 mm/yr (17-19% of precipitation) is comparable to bulletin-reported estimates (∼145 mm/yr). Both the degree of karstification and aquifer water table depth influence recharge and discharge processes in karst areas of southwest China. The more karstic WRB exhibits more rapid infiltration (due to more developed permeable epikarst zone) and higher discharge capability (due to more developed underground drainage systems), particularly during dry periods (2009, 2011, and winter). Baseflow exhibits a shorter time lag to recharge and GWSC in the XRB than WRB owing to more quick flow, lower storage with more rapid infiltration, and shorter mean groundwater residence time. Observation-based monthly recharge reflects different rainfall-infiltration-runoff processes under different rainfall intensities, particularly in the WRB.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> Zhiyong Huang, Pat J.‐F. Yeh, Jiu Jimmy Jiao, Xin Luo, Yun Pan, Yuannan Long, Chong Zhang, Longqun Zheng</dc:creator><category> Research Article</category><dc:title> A new approach for assessing groundwater recharge by combining GRACE and baseflow with case studies in karst areas of southwest China</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2022WR032091</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1029/2022WR032091</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR032091?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> Research Article</prism:section></item><item><link/> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033238?af=R<pubDate> Fri, 03 Feb 2023 12:43:53 -0800</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-02-03T12:43:53-08:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley: Water Resources Research: Table of Contents <prism:coverdate></prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate></prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR033238</guid><title> Climate and human impacts on hydrological processes and flood risk in southern Louisiana</title><description> Water Resources Research, Accepted Article.</description><dc:description> Abstract Satellite observations of coastal Louisiana indicate an overall land loss over recent decades, which could be attributed to climate and human‐induced factors, including sea level rise (SLR). Climate‐induced hydrological change (CHC) has impacted the way flood control structures are used, altering the spatiotemporal water distribution. Based on “what‐if” scenarios, we determine relative impacts of SLR and CHC on increased flood risk over southern Louisiana and examine the role of water management, via flood control structures, in mitigating flood risk over the region. Our findings show that CHC has increased flood risk over the past 28 years. The number of affected people increases as extreme hydrological events become more exceptional. Water management reduces flood risk to urban areas and croplands, especially during exceptional hydrological events. For example, currently (ie, 2016‐2020 period), CHC‐induced flooding puts an additional 73km2 of cropland under flood risk at least half of the time (median flood event) and 65km2 once a year (annual flood event), when compared to a past period (1993‐1997). A ten‐ to twenty‐fold increase relative to SLR‐induced flooding. CHC also increases population vulnerability in southern Louisiana to flooding; additional 9900 residents currently live under flood risk at least half of the time, and that number increases to 27,400 for annual flood events. Residents vulnerable to SLR‐induced flooding is lower (6000 and 3300 residents, respectively). Conclusions are that CHC is a major factor that should be accounted for flood resilience and that water management interventions can mitigate risks to human life and activities.</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;Satellite observations of coastal Louisiana indicate an overall land loss over recent decades, which could be attributed to climate and human-induced factors, including sea level rise (SLR). Climate-induced hydrological change (CHC) has impacted the way flood control structures are used, altering the spatiotemporal water distribution. Based on “what-if” scenarios, we determine relative impacts of SLR and CHC on increased flood risk over southern Louisiana and examine the role of water management, via flood control structures, in mitigating flood risk over the region. Our findings show that CHC has increased flood risk over the past 28 years. The number of affected people increases as extreme hydrological events become more exceptional. Water management reduces flood risk to urban areas and croplands, especially during exceptional hydrological events. For example, currently (ie, 2016-2020 period), CHC-induced flooding puts an additional 73km&lt;sup>;2&lt;/sup>; of cropland under flood risk at least half of the time (median flood event) and 65km&lt;sup>;2&lt;/sup>; once a year (annual flood event), when compared to a past period (1993-1997). A ten- to twenty-fold increase relative to SLR-induced flooding. CHC also increases population vulnerability in southern Louisiana to flooding; additional 9900 residents currently live under flood risk at least half of the time, and that number increases to 27,400 for annual flood events. Residents vulnerable to SLR-induced flooding is lower (6000 and 3300 residents, respectively). Conclusions are that CHC is a major factor that should be accounted for flood resilience and that water management interventions can mitigate risks to human life and activities.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> Augusto Getirana, Sujay Kumar, Goutam Konapala, Wanshu Nie, Kim Locke, Bryant Loomis, Charon Birkett, Martina Ricko, Marc Simard</dc:creator><category> Research Article</category><dc:title> Climate and human impacts on hydrological processes and flood risk in southern Louisiana</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2022WR033238</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1029/2022WR033238</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033238?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> Research Article</prism:section></item><item><link/> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR032621?af=R<pubDate> Fri, 03 Feb 2023 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-02-03T12:00:00-08:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley: Water Resources Research: Table of Contents<prism:coverdate> Wed, 01 Feb 2023 00:00:00 -0800</prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate> Wed, 01 Feb 2023 00:00:00 -0800</prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR032621</guid><title> Estimation of Surface Soil Moisture by a Multi‐Elevation UAV‐Based Ground Penetrating Radar</title><description> Water Resources Research, Volume 59, Issue 2, February 2023.</description><dc:description> Abstract The measurement of soil moisture is important for a wide range of applications, including ecosystem conservation and agricultural management. However, most traditional measurement methods, for example, time‐domain reflectometry (TDR), are unsuitable for mapping field scale variability. In this study, we propose a method that uses an unmanned aerial vehicle (UAV) to support a ground penetrating radar (GPR) system for spatial scanning investigation at different elevations above ground level. This method measures the surface reflectivity to estimate the soil moisture, exploiting the linear relationship between the ratio of the reflected and the direct wave amplitudes along with the reciprocal of GPR antenna height. This relationship is deduced in this study based on the point source assumptions of a transmitter antenna and ground reflections, which is confirmed by numerical simulation results using the gprMax software. Unlike previous air‐launched GPR methods, the UAV‐GPR method presented here removes the limitations of a steady transmitter power and a fixed GPR survey height and the need for calibration of antenna transfer functions and geophysical inversion calculations, and thus is simpler and more convenient for field applications. We test the method at field sites within the riparian zone and a river‐island grassland adjacent to the Yangtze River. The results from the field study illustrate comparable measured soil moisture to those obtained invasively using TDR. The root mean square error of surface reflectivity and soil moisture values between UAV‐GPR with eight antenna height investigations and TDR in the grassland are 0.03 and 0.05 cm3/cm3, respectively.</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;The measurement of soil moisture is important for a wide range of applications, including ecosystem conservation and agricultural management. However, most traditional measurement methods, for example, time-domain reflectometry (TDR), are unsuitable for mapping field scale variability. In this study, we propose a method that uses an unmanned aerial vehicle (UAV) to support a ground penetrating radar (GPR) system for spatial scanning investigation at different elevations above ground level. This method measures the surface reflectivity to estimate the soil moisture, exploiting the linear relationship between the ratio of the reflected and the direct wave amplitudes along with the reciprocal of GPR antenna height. This relationship is deduced in this study based on the point source assumptions of a transmitter antenna and ground reflections, which is confirmed by numerical simulation results using the gprMax software. Unlike previous air-launched GPR methods, the UAV-GPR method presented here removes the limitations of a steady transmitter power and a fixed GPR survey height and the need for calibration of antenna transfer functions and geophysical inversion calculations, and thus is simpler and more convenient for field applications. We test the method at field sites within the riparian zone and a river-island grassland adjacent to the Yangtze River. The results from the field study illustrate comparable measured soil moisture to those obtained invasively using TDR. The root mean square error of surface reflectivity and soil moisture values between UAV-GPR with eight antenna height investigations and TDR in the grassland are 0.03 and 0.05 cm&lt;sup>;3&lt;/sup>;/cm&lt;sup>;3&lt;/sup>;, respectively.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> Qinbo Cheng, Qiuju Su, Andrew Binley, Jintao liu, Zhicai Zhang, Xi Chen</dc:creator><category> Research Article</category><dc:title> Estimation of Surface Soil Moisture by a Multi‐Elevation UAV‐Based Ground Penetrating Radar</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2022WR032621</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1029/2022WR032621</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR032621?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> Research Article</prism:section><prism:volume> 59</prism:volume><prism:number> 2个</prism:number></item><item><link/>https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2021WR030740?af=R<pubDate> Fri, 03 Feb 2023 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-02-03T12:00:00-08:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley: Water Resources Research: Table of Contents<prism:coverdate> Wed, 01 Feb 2023 00:00:00 -0800</prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate> Wed, 01 Feb 2023 00:00:00 -0800</prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2021WR030740</guid><title> Transport Dynamics of Large Wood in a Stream Channel Affected by Spur Dikes</title><description> Water Resources Research, Volume 59, Issue 2, February 2023.</description><dc:description> Abstract The damage to river engineering structures induced by large‐wood (LW) jams is one of the significant problems in river management. For example, typical bridge damage in alluvial areas in Japan, such as wash away, is often caused by the accumulation of large wood materials. The densely transported large wood pieces are an important factor in the accumulation process. We investigated the influence of local flows generated by hydraulic structures on the initial stage of the concentration of large wood pieces. First, we experimentally investigated the flow structures generated by spur dikes in a 0.6 m wide channel and the trajectory of large wood pieces. Then, we numerically investigated the influence of external force on the transport mechanisms of large wood pieces. We employed a simplified Basset‐Boussinesq‐Oseen model to evaluate each term of the momentum equation of the particles and calculated the trajectories of the wood pieces previously observed experimentally. The results showed that the transported large wood pieces were concentrated in low‐vorticity regions of the water surface. This tendency was more prevalent in short pieces (10 mm) than in long pieces (40 mm) because the influence of the relatively small‐scale patterns of the pressure gradient of the surrounding water surface might be spatially averaged for long pieces. This tendency has not been explicitly elucidated in previous works; thus, this knowledge is expected to be key in controlling LW transport, such as detecting the possible regions where LW jams occur or designing efficient inlet sections of LW retention facilities.</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;The damage to river engineering structures induced by large-wood (LW) jams is one of the significant problems in river management. For example, typical bridge damage in alluvial areas in Japan, such as wash away, is often caused by the accumulation of large wood materials. The densely transported large wood pieces are an important factor in the accumulation process. We investigated the influence of local flows generated by hydraulic structures on the initial stage of the concentration of large wood pieces. First, we experimentally investigated the flow structures generated by spur dikes in a 0.6 m wide channel and the trajectory of large wood pieces. Then, we numerically investigated the influence of external force on the transport mechanisms of large wood pieces. We employed a simplified Basset-Boussinesq-Oseen model to evaluate each term of the momentum equation of the particles and calculated the trajectories of the wood pieces previously observed experimentally. The results showed that the transported large wood pieces were concentrated in low-vorticity regions of the water surface. This tendency was more prevalent in short pieces (10 mm) than in long pieces (40 mm) because the influence of the relatively small-scale patterns of the pressure gradient of the surrounding water surface might be spatially averaged for long pieces. This tendency has not been explicitly elucidated in previous works; thus, this knowledge is expected to be key in controlling LW transport, such as detecting the possible regions where LW jams occur or designing efficient inlet sections of LW retention facilities.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> R. Akahori, S. Yamaguchi, H. Yabe, Y. Shimizu</dc:creator><category> Research Article</category><dc:title> Transport Dynamics of Large Wood in a Stream Channel Affected by Spur Dikes</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2021WR030740</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1029/2021WR030740</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2021WR030740?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> Research Article</prism:section><prism:volume> 59</prism:volume><prism:number> 2个</prism:number></item><item><link/>https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033012?af=R<pubDate> Thu, 02 Feb 2023 00:18:22 -0800</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-02-02T12:18:22-08:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley: Water Resources Research: Table of Contents <prism:coverdate></prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate></prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR033012</guid><title> STAEBLE: A surface‐temperature‐ and available‐energy‐based lake evaporation model</title><description> Water Resources Research, Accepted Article.</description><dc:description> Abstract A mass transfer evaporation model is proposed that uses MODIS water surface temperature data and land‐based meteorological data, and employs a new approach to calibrate the transfer coefficient via closure of the long‐term energy budget of the lake. Some of the longstanding issues of developing and applying lake evaporation models are reviewed, including the adequacy of using land‐based meteorological data, the difficulty of applying transfer coefficients with fixed values calibrated elsewhere, and the need to estimate rates of change of stored enthalpy when the model involves energy budget concepts. Publicly available data from a 5‐year measurement campaign at Lake Mead allow quantification of the effect of using land‐based data, and subsequent testing of the proposed model. We show that atmospheric stability effects are very important, and that their incorporation by means of existing stability functions in the literature produces good results with a one‐parameter model that can be locally calibrated with the same input data used by the model, without the need for local measurements. The model is simple in its structure and data requirements, and can be widely applied.</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;A mass transfer evaporation model is proposed that uses MODIS water surface temperature data and land-based meteorological data, and employs a new approach to calibrate the transfer coefficient via closure of the long-term energy budget of the lake. Some of the longstanding issues of developing and applying lake evaporation models are reviewed, including the adequacy of using land-based meteorological data, the difficulty of applying transfer coefficients with fixed values calibrated elsewhere, and the need to estimate rates of change of stored enthalpy when the model involves energy budget concepts. Publicly available data from a 5-year measurement campaign at Lake Mead allow quantification of the effect of using land-based data, and subsequent testing of the proposed model. We show that atmospheric stability effects are very important, and that their incorporation by means of existing stability functions in the literature produces good results with a one-parameter model that can be locally calibrated with the same input data used by the model, without the need for local measurements. The model is simple in its structure and data requirements, and can be widely applied.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> Nelson Luís Dias, Lucas EB Hoeltgebaum, Irani Santos</dc:creator><category> Research Article</category><dc:title> STAEBLE: A surface‐temperature‐ and available‐energy‐based lake evaporation model</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2022WR033012</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1029/2022WR033012</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033012?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> Research Article</prism:section></item><item><link/> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033119?af=R<pubDate> Thu, 02 Feb 2023 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-02-02T12:00:00-08:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley: Water Resources Research: Table of Contents<prism:coverdate> Wed, 01 Feb 2023 00:00:00 -0800</prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate> Wed, 01 Feb 2023 00:00:00 -0800</prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR033119</guid><title> Effect of Pore‐Wall Roughness and Péclet Number on Conservative Solute Transport in Saturated Porous Media</title><description> Water Resources Research, Volume 59, Issue 2, February 2023.</description><dc:description> Abstract While modeling solute transport has been an active subject of research in the past few decades, the influence of pore‐wall roughness on contaminant migration has not yet been addressed. We therefore conduct particle tracking simulations in three porous domains that have different pore‐wall roughness characteristics. Specifically, we consider five surface fractal dimensions ds = 1.0, 1.1, 1.2, 1.4, and 1.6, and four different Péclet numbers Pe = 10, 102, 103, and 105. Overall, arrival time distributions are simulated for 60 scenarios (3 domains  5 surface fractal dimensions  4 Péclet numbers) some of which show heavy‐tailed patterns indicating non‐Fickian transport. To interpret the simulations and quantify the transport behavior, we analyze the resulting arrival time distributions by the continuous time random walk (CTRW) approach. Results show that, on average, as the surface fractal dimension increases from 1.0 to 1.6, the CTRW model parameters , an exponent showing the degree of anomalous transport, v, the average solute velocity, and t2, the cut‐off time to Fickian transport, remain nearly constant. However, the dispersion coefficient, D, increases and the characteristic transition time, t1, decreases. We found t1 and D are more sensitive to pore‐wall roughness compared to the other CTRW parameters. We also found that as the Péclet number increases from 10 to 105, on average, v and D increase, t1 and decrease, and t2 remains nearly constant. The simulations demonstrate that the exponent and the dispersion coefficient are correlated to the average solute velocity.</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;While modeling solute transport has been an active subject of research in the past few decades, the influence of pore-wall roughness on contaminant migration has not yet been addressed. We therefore conduct particle tracking simulations in three porous domains that have different pore-wall roughness characteristics. Specifically, we consider five surface fractal dimensions &lt;i>;d&lt;/i>; &lt;sub>;s&lt;/sub>; = 1.0, 1.1, 1.2, 1.4, and 1.6, and four different Péclet numbers &lt;i>;Pe&lt;/i>; = 10, 10&lt;sup>;2&lt;/sup>;, 10&lt;sup>;3&lt;/sup>;, and 10&lt;sup>;5&lt;/sup>;. Overall, arrival time distributions are simulated for 60 scenarios (3 domains  5 surface fractal dimensions  4 Péclet numbers) some of which show heavy-tailed patterns indicating non-Fickian transport. To interpret the simulations and quantify the transport behavior, we analyze the resulting arrival time distributions by the continuous time random walk (CTRW) approach. Results show that, on average, as the surface fractal dimension increases from 1.0 to 1.6, the CTRW model parameters , an exponent showing the degree of anomalous transport, &lt;i>;v&lt;/i>;, the average solute velocity, and &lt;i>;t&lt;/i>; &lt;sub>;2&lt;/sub>;, the cut-off time to Fickian transport, remain nearly constant. However, the dispersion coefficient, &lt;i>;D&lt;/i>;, increases and the characteristic transition time, &lt;i>;t&lt;/i>; &lt;sub>;1&lt;/sub>;, decreases. We found &lt;i>;t&lt;/i>; &lt;sub>;1&lt;/sub>; and &lt;i>;D&lt;/i>; are more sensitive to pore-wall roughness compared to the other CTRW parameters. We also found that as the Péclet number increases from 10 to 10&lt;sup>;5&lt;/sup>;, on average, &lt;i>;v&lt;/i>; and &lt;i>;D&lt;/i>; increase, &lt;i>;t&lt;/i>; &lt;sub>;1&lt;/sub>; and decrease, and &lt;i>;t&lt;/i>; &lt;sub>;2&lt;/sub>; remains nearly constant. The simulations demonstrate that the exponent and the dispersion coefficient are correlated to the average solute velocity.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> Behzad Ghanbarian, Yashar Mehmani, Brian Berkowitz</dc:creator><category> Research Article</category><dc:title> Effect of Pore‐Wall Roughness and Péclet Number on Conservative Solute Transport in Saturated Porous Media</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2022WR033119</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1029/2022WR033119</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033119?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> Research Article</prism:section><prism:volume> 59</prism:volume><prism:number> 2个</prism:number></item></channel></rss>