<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:prism="http://prismstandard.org/namespaces/basic/2.0/"><channel><title> Wiley：水资源研究：目录</title><link/>https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R<description>水资源研究目录。最新和 EarlyView 问题的文章列表。</description><language>英文</language><copyright></copyright><managingeditor>wileyonlinelibrary@wiley.com（AGU 出版物）</managingeditor><pubDate> Tue, 04 Apr 2023 08:14:21 +0000</pubDate><lastbuilddate> 2023 年 4 月 4 日星期二 08:14:21 +0000</lastbuilddate><generator> Atypon®文学™</generator><docs> https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs><ttl> 10080</ttl><dc:title> Wiley：水资源研究：目录</dc:title><dc:publisher>威利</dc:publisher><prism:publicationname>水资源研究</prism:publicationname><atom:link href="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"></atom:link><image/><title> Wiley：水资源研究：目录</title><url>https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/pb-assets/journal-banners/19447973.jpg</url><link/> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R<item><link/> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR032811?af=R<pubDate> Mon, 03 Apr 2023 12:25:04 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-04-03T12:25:04-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley：水资源研究：目录<prism:coverdate>2023 年 4 月 1 日星期六 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate> 2023 年 4 月 1 日星期六 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR032811</guid><title>跨气候制度每日实际蒸散量的复杂性和可预测性</title><description>水资源研究，第 59 卷，第 4 期，2023 年 4 月。</description><dc:description>摘要 由于与周围环境的复杂相互作用，实际蒸散量 (ETa) 的估算具有挑战性；因此，了解 ETa 的复杂性和可预测性及其影响因素对于改进 ETa 估计至关重要。基于 FLUXNET 和 ChinaFLUX 数据集，我们首先检查每日 ETa 是否表现出混沌行为，然后使用混沌理论研究每日 ETa 的复杂性和可预测性如何在气候制度和生态系统之间变化。递归图和相关维数 (CD) 分析的结果表明，日常 ETa 中存在混沌行为，这意味着控制 ETa 过程的系统是确定性的，控制变量数量有限。重复量化分析进一步揭示了 ETa 过程的不同程度的复杂性（例如，范围从 0.01% 到 40.7% 的确定性 DET）。具体而言，每日 ETa 具有更强的确定性特性（例如，更高的 DET 和更低的 CD 值），因此在潮湿和干旱地区具有更高的可预测性；然而，由于与环境因素的相互作用更加复杂，亚湿润和半干旱地区出现了更高程度的每日 ETa 复杂性。此外，对日常 ETa 复杂性的主要环境控制因气候和地表条件而异。结果表明，能源和水供应以及日平均温度和相对湿度是整个地点 ETa 复杂性的主要控制因素，而叶面积指数在较干燥的地点也发挥了重要作用。作为第一次尝试，这项研究提供了额外的途径来使用混沌理论从全局角度理解 ETa 过程的复杂性。</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;实际蒸散量（ET&lt;sub>; &lt;i>;a&lt;/i>; &lt;/sub>;）的估算由于其与周围环境的复杂相互作用而具有挑战性；因此，了解 ET&lt;sub>; &lt;i>;a&lt;/i>; &lt;/sub>; 的复杂性和可预测性及其影响因素对于改进 ET&lt;sub>; &lt;i>;a&lt;/i>; &lt;/sub>; 估计至关重要.基于 FLUXNET 和 ChinaFLUX 数据集，我们首先检查每日 ET&lt;sub>; &lt;i>;a&lt;/i>; &lt;/sub>; 是否表现出混沌行为，然后研究每日 ET&lt;sub>; &lt;i>;a&lt;/i>; &lt;/sub>; 使用混沌理论，复杂性和可预测性因气候制度和生态系统而异。递归图和相关维数（CD）分析结果表明，日常 ET&lt;sub>; &lt;i>;a&lt;/i>; &lt;/sub>; 存在混沌行为，暗示系统控制 ET&lt;sub>; &lt;i>;a&lt; /i>; &lt;/sub>; 过程是确定性的，只有有限数量的控制变量。重复量化分析进一步揭示了 ET&lt;sub>; &lt;i>;a&lt;/i>; &lt;/sub>; 过程（例如，范围从 0.01% 到 40.7% 的确定性 DET）在整个站点的不同程度的复杂性。具体而言，每日 ET&lt;sub>; &lt;i>;a&lt;/i>; &lt;/sub>; 具有更强的确定性特性（例如，更高的 DET 和更低的 CD 值），因此在潮湿和干旱地区具有更高的可预测性；然而，由于与环境因素的相互作用更加复杂，亚湿润和半干旱地区出现了更高程度的每日 ET&lt;sub>; &lt;i>;a&lt;/i>; &lt;/sub>; 复杂性。此外，日常 ET&lt;sub>; &lt;i>;a&lt;/i>; &lt;/sub>; 复杂性的主要环境控制因气候和地表条件而异。结果表明，能量和水供应以及日平均温度和相对湿度是整个地点 ET&lt;sub>; &lt;i>;a&lt;/i>; &lt;/sub>; 复杂性的主要控制因素，而叶面积指数也发挥了重要作用在较干燥的地点发挥作用。作为第一次尝试，本研究使用混沌理论从全球视角为理解 ET&lt;sub>; &lt;i>;a&lt;/i>; &lt;/sub>; 过程的复杂性提供了额外的途径。&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator>狄崇礼、王铁军、韩琼、麦麦、王立春、陈曦</dc:creator><category>研究文章</category><dc:title>跨气候制度每日实际蒸散量的复杂性和可预测性</dc:title><dc:identifier>10.1029/2022WR032811</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname>水资源研究</prism:publicationname><prism:doi>10.1029/2022WR032811</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR032811?af=R</prism:url><prism:section>研究文章</prism:section><prism:volume>59</prism:volume><prism:number> 4个</prism:number></item><item><link/>https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2021WR031854?af=R<pubDate> Mon, 03 Apr 2023 12:19:02 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-04-03T12:19:02-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley：水资源研究：目录<prism:coverdate>2023 年 4 月 1 日星期六 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate> 2023 年 4 月 1 日星期六 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2021WR031854</guid><title>使用两步 Kappa 方法改进极端降雨频率分析</title><description>水资源研究，第 59 卷，第 4 期，2023 年 4 月。</description><dc:description>摘要 通过降雨频率分析准确估算极端降雨的年超出概率（AEPs）是防洪减灾工程设计的关键步骤。在这里，我们展示了如何通过将四参数 Kappa 分布拟合到超过阈值的峰值 (POT) 序列来改进降雨频率曲线的估计。为了将 Kappa 分布拟合到 POT 数据，我们提出了一种基于最大似然估计的两步拟合方法，该方法分别对风暴强度和到达频率进行建模。首先，拟合描述风暴强度的广义帕累托分布 (GPA)，然后拟合风暴到达的二项分布。我们将这种两步 Kappa 方法的性能与类似的两步广义极值 (GEV) 方法以及拟合到年度最大值序列 (AMS) 的 Kappa 和 GEV 分布进行比较，使用代表澳大利亚的合成数据和真实世界数据气候情况。实验表明，与将 GEV 或 Kappa 分布拟合到 AMS 相比，在两步 Kappa 方法中利用来自 POT 系列的额外信息显着改善了分位数估计并减少了不确定性，特别是对于稀有分位数。当 Kappa 而不是 GEV 很好地代表极端降雨的偏峰度特性时，两步 Kappa 方法在外推下会产生无偏分位数，而使用 GEV 可能会导致高度偏倚的估计。从这些结果来看，我们认为两步 Kappa 方法适用于现场和区域降雨频率分析，因为它可以适应从 GPA 到 GEV 的分布，而不会遇到通常与四参数分布相关的过度拟合问题。</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;摘要&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;通过降雨频率分析准确估算极端降雨的年超标概率（AEPs）是防洪减灾工程设计中的关键步骤。在这里，我们展示了如何通过将四参数 Kappa 分布拟合到峰值超过阈值 (POT) 系列来改进降雨频率曲线的估计。为了将 Kappa 分布拟合到 POT 数据，我们提出了一种基于最大似然估计的两步拟合方法，该方法分别对风暴强度和到达频率进行建模。首先，拟合描述风暴强度的广义帕累托分布 (GPA)，然后拟合风暴到达的二项分布。我们将这种两步 Kappa 方法的性能与类似的两步广义极值 (GEV) 方法以及拟合到年度最大值序列 (AMS) 的 Kappa 和 GEV 分布进行比较，使用代表澳大利亚的合成数据和真实世界数据气候情况。实验表明，与将 GEV 或 Kappa 分布拟合到 AMS 相比，在两步 Kappa 方法中利用来自 POT 系列的额外信息显着改善了分位数估计并减少了不确定性，特别是对于稀有分位数。当 Kappa 而不是 GEV 很好地代表了极端降雨的偏峰度特性时，两步 Kappa 方法在外推下会产生无偏分位数，而使用 GEV 会导致高度偏倚的估计。从这些结果来看，我们认为两步 Kappa 方法适用于现场和区域降雨频率分析，因为它可以适应从 GPA 到 GEV 的分布，而不会遇到通常与四参数分布相关的过度拟合问题。&lt;/ p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator>德克兰·奥谢、罗里·内森、阿希什·夏尔马、康拉德·沃斯科</dc:creator><category>研究文章</category><dc:title>使用两步 Kappa 方法改进极端降雨频率分析</dc:title><dc:identifier>10.1029/2021WR031854</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname>水资源研究</prism:publicationname><prism:doi>10.1029/2021WR031854</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2021WR031854?af=R</prism:url><prism:section>研究文章</prism:section><prism:volume>59</prism:volume><prism:number> 4个</prism:number></item><item><link/>https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2021WR031745?af=R<pubDate> Mon, 03 Apr 2023 12:15:00 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-04-03T12:15:00-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley：水资源研究：目录<prism:coverdate>2023 年 4 月 1 日星期六 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate> 2023 年 4 月 1 日星期六 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2021WR031745</guid><title>使用贝叶斯动态线性模型的管道爆裂在线预警系统</title><description>水资源研究，第 59 卷，第 4 期，2023 年 4 月。</description><dc:description>摘要 管道破裂是供水网络中经常出现的问题，快速检测它们对于最大限度地降低市政当局的经济和环境成本至关重要。本研究提出了一种将贝叶斯动态线性模型 (DLM) 应用于水流时间序列并结合异常值监测工具的突发检测方法。该模型用于表征实际流量，并且对于每次，在移动到下一个观察之前递归地获得提前一步的预测分布。离群值检测方法包括将主要模型与替代模型进行比较，其中平均流量被转移到更高的值（因为突发往往会增加流量）以评估哪个模型最适合观察到的数据。如果选择替代模型，则会发出突发警报。为验证该方法的性能，将 DLM 和监测工具应用于哈利法克斯（加拿大）两个地区计量区 (DMA) 的 2 年流量数据，并使用历史中断数据集评估模型准确性。该模型能够检测到高达 75% 和 71.2% 的管道破裂，在第一个和第二个 DMA 中的误报率分别为 5.15% 和 12%。最后，所提出的模型允许直接解释模型参数、流量与感兴趣的预测变量之间的非线性关系，自然地描述未来预测的不确定性，可以轻松容纳缺失值，并且可以调整以最大化中断检测或最小化误报率以适应水利基础设施管理者的具体目标。</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;摘要&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;管道破裂是供水网络中经常出现的问题，快速检测它们对于最大限度地降低市政当局的经济和环境成本至关重要。本研究提出了一种将贝叶斯动态线性模型 (DLM) 应用于水流时间序列并结合异常值监测工具的突发检测方法。该模型用于表征实际流量，并且对于每次，在移动到下一个观察之前递归地获得一步超前预测分布。离群值检测方法包括将主要模型与替代模型进行比较，其中平均流量被转移到更高的值（因为突发往往会增加流量）以评估哪个模型最适合观察到的数据。如果选择替代模型，则会发出突发警报。为验证该方法的性能，将 DLM 和监测工具应用于哈利法克斯（加拿大）两个地区计量区 (DMA) 的 2 年流量数据，并使用历史中断数据集评估模型准确性。该模型能够检测到高达 75% 和 71.2% 的管道破裂，在第一个和第二个 DMA 中的误报率分别为 5.15% 和 12%。最后，所提出的模型允许直接解释模型参数、流量与感兴趣的预测变量之间的非线性关系，自然地描述未来预测的不确定性，可以轻松容纳缺失值，并且可以调整以最大化中断检测或最小化误报率以适应水利基础设施管理者的具体目标。&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> Renato Henriques-Silva、Sophie Duchesne、Nicolas Fortin St-Gelais、Naysan Saran、Alexandra M. Schmidt</dc:creator><category>研究文章</category><dc:title>使用贝叶斯动态线性模型的管道爆裂在线预警系统</dc:title><dc:identifier>10.1029/2021WR031745</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname>水资源研究</prism:publicationname><prism:doi>10.1029/2021WR031745</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2021WR031745?af=R</prism:url><prism:section>研究文章</prism:section><prism:volume>59</prism:volume><prism:number> 4个</prism:number></item><item><link/>https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2023WR034894?af=R<pubDate> Mon, 03 Apr 2023 07:29:55 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-04-03T07:29:55-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley：水资源研究：目录<prism:coverdate></prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate></prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2023WR034894</guid><title>自动符号升级：扩展适用性制度的模型生成，第 2 部分</title><description>水资源研究，接受的文章。</description><dc:description>摘要 在两篇论文系列的第二部分中，我们详细介绍了系统实施第 1 部分中介绍的广义闭包形式策略的算法程序。该策略扩展了均质化模型相对于经典均质化理论的适用性，如第 1 部分所示，其中升级模型是在适度反应的物理状态下严格推导出来的。在将算法编码到自动升级框架 Symbolica 中后，我们升级了两个反应性质量传递问题，并通过证明均质化理论预测的绝对误差估计得到满足，对生成的非线性均质化模型进行了数值验证。在这两个问题中，非平凡的闭包形式和闭包问题都是使用编码策略自动制定的，无需人工交互，也没有关于系统所需闭包的先验知识。我们希望这些演示能激发人们对多尺度建模的自动化分析框架的进一步兴趣，因为这种能力对于在地质多孔介质中生成复杂现象的严格多尺度模型来说是无价的。本文受版权保护。版权所有。</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;摘要&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;在这两个论文系列的第二部分中，我们详细介绍了系统实施第 1 部分中介绍的广义闭包形式策略的算法过程。该策略扩展了同质化模型在以下方面的适用性：经典均质化理论，如第 1 部分所示，其中放大模型是在适度反应的物理状态下严格导出的。将算法编码为 &lt;span style=&quot;font-family:sans-serif&quot;>;Symbolica&lt;/span>;（一种自动升级框架）后，我们升级了两个反应性质量传输问题，并通过显示绝对均匀化理论预测的误差估计得到满足。在这两个问题中，非平凡的闭包形式和闭包问题都是使用编码策略自动制定的，无需人工交互，也没有关于系统所需闭包的先验知识。我们希望这些演示能激发人们对多尺度建模的自动化分析框架的进一步兴趣，因为此类功能对于生成地质多孔介质中复杂现象的严格多尺度模型非常宝贵。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;本文受版权保护。保留所有权利。&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator>凯尔 Pietrzyk，伊莱尼亚巴蒂亚托</dc:creator><category>研究文章</category><dc:title>自动符号升级：扩展适用性制度的模型生成，第 2 部分</dc:title><dc:identifier>10.1029/2023WR034894</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname>水资源研究</prism:publicationname><prism:doi>10.1029/2023WR034894</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2023WR034894?af=R</prism:url><prism:section>研究文章</prism:section></item><item><link/>https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR032392?af=R<pubDate> Sat, 01 Apr 2023 10:24:22 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-04-01T10:24:22-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley：水资源研究：目录<prism:coverdate>2023 年 4 月 1 日星期六 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate> 2023 年 4 月 1 日星期六 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR032392</guid><title>来自排水沟的数据：捕捉慢性沿海洪水的多种驱动因素的传感器框架</title><description>水资源研究，第 59 卷，第 4 期，2023 年 4 月。</description><dc:description>摘要 验潮水位通常用作陆地洪水发生率的代表。这些指标可用于预测海平面上升 (SLR) 将如何增加沿海洪水的频率。然而，验潮仪没有考虑到沿海洪水的陆地来源，因此洪水阈值和从中得出的代理可能低估了当前和未来的沿海洪水频率。在这里，我们提出了一个新的传感器框架，用于测量沿海洪水的发生率，该框架捕获地下和陆地对洪水的贡献。低成本、开源传感器框架由雨水渠水位传感器、道路摄像机和实时传输数据的无线网关组成。在北卡罗来纳州博福特镇的 5 个月部署期间，记录了 24 次洪水事件。这些事件中有 25% 是由陆上资源驱动的——降雨，加上中等涨潮和雨水渠容量减少。因此，我们发现洪水频率高于完全依赖潮位计水位来确定洪水发生率的代理建议的频率。这一发现可能会扩展到雨水网络由于 SLR 而导致排水能力下降的其他地方。我们的结果突出了直接检测 SW 网络以捕获沿海洪水的多个驱动因素的好处。更准确地估计低洼沿海社区洪水的频率和驱动因素可以制定更有效的长期适应战略。</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;摘要&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;验潮水位通常用作陆地洪水发生率的代表。这些代理变量可用于预测海平面上升 (SLR) 将如何增加沿海洪水的频率。然而，验潮仪不考虑沿海洪水的陆地来源，因此洪水阈值和从中得出的代理可能低估了当前和未来的沿海洪水频率。在这里，我们提出了一个新的传感器框架，用于测量沿海洪水的发生率，该框架捕获地下和陆地对洪水的贡献。低成本、开源传感器框架由雨水渠水位传感器、道路摄像机和实时传输数据的无线网关组成。在北卡罗来纳州博福特镇的 5 个月部署期间，记录了 24 次洪水事件。这些事件中有 25% 是由陆源驱动的——降雨、中等涨潮和雨水渠容量减少。因此，我们发现洪水频率高于完全依赖潮位计水位来确定洪水发生率的代理建议的频率。这一发现可能会扩展到雨水网络由于 SLR 而导致排水能力下降的其他地方。我们的结果突出了直接检测 SW 网络以捕获沿海洪水的多个驱动因素的好处。更准确地估计低洼沿海社区洪水的频率和驱动因素可以制定更有效的长期适应战略。&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator>亚当·戈尔德、凯瑟琳·阿纳德、劳伦·格里姆利、瑞安·内夫、艾玛·鲁迪·斯雷布尼克、托马斯·塞伦、安东尼·惠普尔、日野美雪</dc:creator><category>方法</category><dc:title>来自排水沟的数据：捕捉慢性沿海洪水的多种驱动因素的传感器框架</dc:title><dc:identifier>10.1029/2022WR032392</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname>水资源研究</prism:publicationname><prism:doi>10.1029/2022WR032392</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR032392?af=R</prism:url><prism:section>方法</prism:section><prism:volume>59</prism:volume><prism:number> 4个</prism:number></item><item><link/>https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033229?af=R<pubDate> Sat, 01 Apr 2023 09:38:56 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-04-01T09:38:56-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley：水资源研究：目录<prism:coverdate>2023 年 4 月 1 日星期六 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate> 2023 年 4 月 1 日星期六 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR033229</guid><title>明渠流中回旋微生物的环境传输</title><description>水资源研究，第 59 卷，第 4 期，2023 年 4 月。</description><dc:description>摘要 微生物等活性粒子在剪切流中的输运现象丰富而复杂，对各种生物和环境应用具有重要意义。最近的研究表明，藻类的运动性和回旋性可以极大地影响它们在水中的运输。然而，当经典泰勒色散模型不适用时，很少有人关注初始和瞬态传输状态。为了解决这个问题，我们采用 Gill 的广义色散模型来处理像溶质这样的被动粒子，它有可能准确地描述整个传输过程。我们首次将 Gill 模型扩展到活性粒子，并彻底研究了游动、回转和流动剪切对明渠流中微生物分散的影响。我们首先从理论上求解瞬态漂移和分散系数，在此基础上我们得到微生物浓度分布的解析解，并通过数值求解控制方程进一步验证这些结果。我们发现，当没有流动时，微生物的纵向分散可以通过水面附近的重力积累而减弱，同时通过微生物更强的游动能力得到增强。流动切变的作用不影响渐近浓度分布的形式，但可以大大提高瞬态漂移速度和弥散性。通过结合直接数值模拟和随机游走模拟，我们进一步分析了湍流对微生物分散的影响。湍流的增加被证明会降低浓度分布的垂直不均匀性，以及在传输过程中主动行为对漂移和泰勒色散的相对贡献。</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;摘要&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;微生物等活性粒子在剪切流中的输运现象丰富而复杂，对各种生物和环境应用具有重要意义。最近的研究表明，藻类的运动性和回旋性可以极大地影响它们在水中的运输。然而，当经典泰勒色散模型不适用时，很少有人关注初始和瞬态传输状态。为了解决这个问题，我们采用 Gill 的广义色散模型来处理像溶质这样的被动粒子，它有可能准确地描述整个传输过程。我们首次将 Gill 模型扩展到活性粒子，并彻底研究了游动、回转和流动剪切对明渠流中微生物分散的影响。我们首先从理论上求解瞬态漂移和分散系数，在此基础上我们得到微生物浓度分布的解析解，并通过数值求解控制方程进一步验证这些结果。我们发现，当没有流动时，微生物的纵向分散可以通过水面附近的重力积累而减弱，同时通过微生物更强的游动能力得到增强。流动切变的作用不影响渐近浓度分布的形式，但可以大大提高瞬态漂移速度和弥散性。通过结合直接数值模拟和随机游走模拟，我们进一步分析了湍流对微生物分散的影响。湍流的增加降低了浓度分布的垂直不均匀性，以及传输过程中主动行为对漂移和泰勒色散的相对贡献。&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator>李光淼，龚政，蒋伟全，詹杰，王博涵，傅旭东，徐梦珍，吴子</dc:creator><category>研究文章</category><dc:title>明渠流中回旋微生物的环境传输</dc:title><dc:identifier>10.1029/2022WR033229</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname>水资源研究</prism:publicationname><prism:doi>10.1029/2022WR033229</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033229?af=R</prism:url><prism:section>研究文章</prism:section><prism:volume>59</prism:volume><prism:number> 4个</prism:number></item><item><link/>https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR034046?af=R<pubDate> Fri, 31 Mar 2023 23:30:51 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-03-31T11:30:51-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley：水资源研究：目录<prism:coverdate></prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate></prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR034046</guid><title>不同的水文路径调节超干旱盆地多年生的地表水动态</title><description>水资源研究，接受的文章。</description><dc:description>摘要 在水资源紧张的超干旱盆地中，人为地下水抽取和气候驱动扰动对地下水-地表水相互作用和生态系统关键地表水的恢复力的影响越来越受到质疑。将地下水与 Sentinel-2 数据的地表水观测相结合，为评估干旱盆地强降水事件后地表水与当地含水层的连通性提供了前所未有的机会。分析了地表水面积和地下水位数据的降水趋势，包括峰值滞后时间、峰值后衰退率和水力梯度变化。结果表明在上游淡水含水层中地表水变化和地下水位波动之间的大降水事件之后可变连通性，而含水层的下坡盐水到半咸水区域表明与含水层几乎没有连通性。降水和地表水响应之间的比较表明，根据地表水体与含水层的盐水到半咸水区域的物理关系，会出现不同的响应。地表水淹没的集总参数模型也限制了降水后响应的可能水文动力学。虽然模拟的地表水流入量似乎主要受流域水力控制，而不是含水层的直接水力连通性，但地表水与邻近地下水位与地表水面积之间的关系表明，当地含水层主要通过排放与地表水体相连地下渗透。模拟结果表明，干旱盆地中邻近卤水的地表水的存在依赖于淡水含水层的上坡排放。我们的结果进一步支持边缘地表水系统可以作为当地含水层的关键补给机制。</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;摘要&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;在缺水的超干旱盆地，人们对人为地下水抽取和气候驱动的扰动对地下水-地表水相互作用的影响以及对生态系统至关重要的地表水的恢复力产生了越来越多的问题。将地下水与 Sentinel-2 数据的地表水观测相结合，为评估干旱盆地强降水事件后地表水与当地含水层的连通性提供了前所未有的机会。分析了地表水面积和地下水位数据的降水趋势，包括峰值滞后时间、峰值后衰退率和水力梯度变化。结果表明，在上游淡水含水层中地表水变化和地下水位波动之间发生大降水事件后，连通性可变，而含水层的下坡盐水到半咸水区域表明与含水层几乎没有连通性。降水和地表水响应之间的比较表明，基于地表水体与含水层的盐水到半咸水区域的物理关系，响应不同。地表水淹没的集总参数模型也限制了降水后响应的可能水文动力学。虽然模拟的地表水流入量似乎主要受流域水力控制，而不是含水层的直接水力连通性，但地表水与邻近地下水位与地表水面积之间的关系表明，当地含水层主要通过排放与地表水体相连地下渗透。模拟结果表明，干旱盆地中邻近卤水的地表水的存在依赖于淡水含水层的上坡排放。我们的结果进一步支持边缘地表水系统可以作为当地含水层的关键补给机制。&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> SV McKnight、DF Boutt、LA Munk、B. Moran</dc:creator><category>研究文章</category><dc:title>不同的水文路径调节超干旱盆地多年生的地表水动态</dc:title><dc:identifier>10.1029/2022WR034046</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname>水资源研究</prism:publicationname><prism:doi>10.1029/2022WR034046</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR034046?af=R</prism:url><prism:section>研究文章</prism:section></item><item><link/>https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR034092?af=R<pubDate> Fri, 31 Mar 2023 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-03-31T12:00:00-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley：水资源研究：目录<prism:coverdate></prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate></prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR034092</guid><title>通过数据驱动的稀疏传感在美国测量不当的流域中进行流量预测</title><description>水资源研究，接受的文章。</description><dc:description>摘要 许多河流和溪流没有测量或测量不当，预测此类流域的流量具有挑战性。尽管流信号来自具有不同频率的过程，但它们可能是“稀疏的”或在变换后的特征空间中具有“低维”表示。在这种情况下，如果可以通过降维从测量流域中的流量数据中识别出此适当的特征空间，则可以通过进行一些测量来预测测量不当的流域中的流量。本研究利用这个名为数据驱动稀疏感知 (DSS) 的框架来预测美国本土 543 个流域的日尺度流量。从同一气候区域内流域的水流训练数据中提取了一个定制的特征库，该特征空间用于重建测量不佳的流域中的水流并确定测量的最佳时间。在不同地区，以融雪为主和以基流为主的流域（例如，落基山脉）的径流可以通过更少的径流测量得到更有效的预测。 The prediction efficiency in some rainfall‐dominated regions, eg, New England and the Pacific coast, increased significantly with an increasing number of measurements. The spatial variability of prediction efficiency can be attributed to the process‐driven mechanisms and the dimensionality of watershed dynamics. Storage‐dominated systems are lower‐dimensional and more predictable than rainfall‐dominated systems. Measurements taken during periods with large streamflow magnitudes and/or variances are more informative and lead to better predictions. This study demonstrates that DSS can be an especially useful technique to integrate ground‐based measurements with remotely sensed data for streamflow prediction, sensor placement, and watershed classification.</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;Many rivers and streams are ungauged or poorly gauged and predicting streamflow in such watersheds is challenging. Although streamflow signals result from processes with different frequencies, they can be “sparse” or have a “lower-dimensional” representation in a transformed feature space. In such cases, if this appropriate feature space can be identified from streamflow data in gauged watersheds by dimensionality reduction, streamflow in poorly gauged watersheds can be predicted with a few measurements taken. This study utilized this framework, named data-driven sparse sensing (DSS), to predict daily-scale streamflow in 543 watersheds across the contiguous United States. A tailored library of features was extracted from streamflow training data in watersheds within the same climatic region, and this feature space was used to reconstruct streamflow in poorly gauged watersheds and identify the optimal timings for measurement. Among different regions, streamflow in snowmelt-dominated and baseflow-dominated watersheds (eg, Rocky Mountains) was more effectively predicted with fewer streamflow measurements taken. The prediction efficiency in some rainfall-dominated regions, eg, New England and the Pacific coast, increased significantly with an increasing number of measurements. The spatial variability of prediction efficiency can be attributed to the process-driven mechanisms and the dimensionality of watershed dynamics. Storage-dominated systems are lower-dimensional and more predictable than rainfall-dominated systems. Measurements taken during periods with large streamflow magnitudes and/or variances are more informative and lead to better predictions. This study demonstrates that DSS can be an especially useful technique to integrate ground-based measurements with remotely sensed data for streamflow prediction, sensor placement, and watershed classification.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> Kun Zhang, Mitul Luhar, Manuela I. Brunner, Anthony J. Parolari</dc:creator><category> Research Article</category><dc:title> Streamflow prediction in poorly gauged watersheds in the United States through data‐driven sparse sensing</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2022WR034092</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1029/2022WR034092</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR034092?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> Research Article</prism:section></item><item><link/> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033133?af=R<pubDate> Thu, 30 Mar 2023 15:22:56 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-03-30T03:22:56-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley: Water Resources Research: Table of Contents <prism:coverdate></prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate></prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR033133</guid><title> On the spatial scale dependence of long‐term persistence in global annual precipitation data and the Hurst Phenomenon</title><description> Water Resources Research, Accepted Article.</description><dc:description> Abstract Precipitation deficits are the main physical drivers of droughts across the globe, and their level of persistence can be characterised by the Hurst coefficient H (0.5&lt;H&lt;1), with high H indicating strong long‐term persistence (LTP). Previous analyses of point and gridded annual global precipitation datasets have concluded that LTP in precipitation is weak (H∼0.6) which is inconsistent with higher values of H for large river basins eg the Nile. Based on an analysis of gridded annual precipitation data for eight selected regions distributed across the globe, an important new finding is that H increases with the spatial scale of averaging, with mean H values at the grid and regional scale of 0.66 and 0.83, respectively. The discovery of enhanced LTP at the regional scale of averaging of precipitation has important implications for characterising the severity of regional droughts, as well as LTP in the annual flows of large rivers and recharge to major aquifers. Teleconnections with known modes of low frequency variability in the global climate system are demonstrated using correlation analysis and stepwise regression. Despite having several constituent regions exhibiting LTP, the Northern Hemisphere surprisingly has no LTP; this is shown to result from different modes of low frequency climatic variability cancelling each other out. LTP for the Southern Hemisphere is moderate, and weak for Global average precipitation. LTP in Blue Nile basin scale precipitation is shown to explain the Hurst Phenomenon in naturalised annual flows for the River Nile, more than seventy years after its discovery by Hurst.</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;Precipitation deficits are the main physical drivers of droughts across the globe, and their level of persistence can be characterised by the Hurst coefficient H (0.5&amp;lt;H&amp;lt;1), with high H indicating strong long-term persistence (LTP). Previous analyses of point and gridded annual global precipitation datasets have concluded that LTP in precipitation is weak (H∼0.6) which is inconsistent with higher values of H for large river basins eg the Nile. Based on an analysis of gridded annual precipitation data for eight selected regions distributed across the globe, an important new finding is that H increases with the spatial scale of averaging, with mean H values at the grid and regional scale of 0.66 and 0.83, respectively. The discovery of enhanced LTP at the regional scale of averaging of precipitation has important implications for characterising the severity of regional droughts, as well as LTP in the annual flows of large rivers and recharge to major aquifers. Teleconnections with known modes of low frequency variability in the global climate system are demonstrated using correlation analysis and stepwise regression. Despite having several constituent regions exhibiting LTP, the Northern Hemisphere surprisingly has no LTP; this is shown to result from different modes of low frequency climatic variability cancelling each other out. LTP for the Southern Hemisphere is moderate, and weak for Global average precipitation. LTP in Blue Nile basin scale precipitation is shown to explain the Hurst Phenomenon in naturalised annual flows for the River Nile, more than seventy years after its discovery by Hurst.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> Enda O&#39;Connell, Greg O&#39;Donnell, Demetris Koutsoyiannis</dc:creator><category> Research Article</category><dc:title> On the spatial scale dependence of long‐term persistence in global annual precipitation data and the Hurst Phenomenon</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2022WR033133</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1029/2022WR033133</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033133?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> Research Article</prism:section></item><item><link/> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR034188?af=R<pubDate> Thu, 30 Mar 2023 11:24:51 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-03-30T11:24:51-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley: Water Resources Research: Table of Contents <prism:coverdate></prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate></prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR034188</guid><title> Long‐Lead Drought Forecasting across the Continental United States using Burg Entropy Spectral Analysis with a Multiresolution Approach</title><description> Water Resources Research, Accepted Article.</description><dc:description> Abstract Amid climate change, extreme droughts have occurred more frequently, accompanied by increasing socio‐economic‐environmental losses. To be prepared for upcoming droughts, proactive drought management planning based on drought forecasting is being highlighted. This study, therefore, developed a long‐term drought forecasting model using Burg entropy spectral analysis with the maximal overlap discrete wavelet transform across the continental US (CONUS). The model forecasted monthly self‐calibrated Palmer Drought Severity Index (scPDSI) up to median lead times of 12 months with root mean square error less than 0.8 and the modified Nash‐Sutcliffe efficiency coefficient greater than 0.6 across CONUS. The lead‐time with an acceptable accuracy was affected by how the model parameterized low‐frequency structure of scPDSI that was significantly correlated to sea surface temperature climate mode. The correlation between low‐frequency signals and Niño‐3.4 tended to be weaker for the regions located at higher elevations. Thus, higher variability in spectral structures of low‐frequency signals at higher elevation‐regions led to shorter memory/persistency of time series that shortened the forecast lead time. Besides, higher variability in precipitation linked to the variability of scPDIS also shortened the forecast lead time. To appraise the applicability of the suggested forecast model to drought management planning, drought characteristics (ie, severity, duration, area) were obtained by the three‐dimensional drought clustering algorithm for the forecasted and observed scPDSI. Then, risk was analyzed for drought characteristics using the vine copula. Risk analysis for drought characteristics forecasted up to a 12‐month lead time showed the potential for applicability of the model to drought mitigation plans. This article is protected by copyright.版权所有。</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;Amid climate change, extreme droughts have occurred more frequently, accompanied by increasing socio-economic-environmental losses. To be prepared for upcoming droughts, proactive drought management planning based on drought forecasting is being highlighted. This study, therefore, developed a long-term drought forecasting model using Burg entropy spectral analysis with the maximal overlap discrete wavelet transform across the continental US (CONUS). The model forecasted monthly self-calibrated Palmer Drought Severity Index (scPDSI) up to median lead times of 12 months with root mean square error less than 0.8 and the modified Nash-Sutcliffe efficiency coefficient greater than 0.6 across CONUS. The lead-time with an acceptable accuracy was affected by how the model parameterized low-frequency structure of scPDSI that was significantly correlated to sea surface temperature climate mode. The correlation between low-frequency signals and Niño-3.4 tended to be weaker for the regions located at higher elevations. Thus, higher variability in spectral structures of low-frequency signals at higher elevation-regions led to shorter memory/persistency of time series that shortened the forecast lead time. Besides, higher variability in precipitation linked to the variability of scPDIS also shortened the forecast lead time. To appraise the applicability of the suggested forecast model to drought management planning, drought characteristics (ie, severity, duration, area) were obtained by the three-dimensional drought clustering algorithm for the forecasted and observed scPDSI. Then, risk was analyzed for drought characteristics using the vine copula. Risk analysis for drought characteristics forecasted up to a 12-month lead time showed the potential for applicability of the model to drought mitigation plans.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This article is protected by copyright. All rights reserved.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> Jeongwoo Han, Vijay P. Singh</dc:creator><category> Research Article</category><dc:title> Long‐Lead Drought Forecasting across the Continental United States using Burg Entropy Spectral Analysis with a Multiresolution Approach</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2022WR034188</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1029/2022WR034188</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR034188?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> Research Article</prism:section></item><item><link/> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2023WR034503?af=R<pubDate> Thu, 30 Mar 2023 09:15:15 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-03-30T09:15:15-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley: Water Resources Research: Table of Contents<prism:coverdate> Sat, 01 Apr 2023 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate> Sat, 01 Apr 2023 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2023WR034503</guid><title> An Analytical Method to Estimate Groundwater Depletion of an Aquitard Due To Variable Drawdowns in Adjacent Aquifers</title><description> Water Resources Research, Volume 59, Issue 4, April 2023.</description><dc:description> Abstract Computing aquitard depletion, which is often overlooked, is of great significance for the assessment of groundwater resources and land subsidence. The issue is viewed as troublesome because of the additional computational burden, the poorly known hydrogeological parameters of the aquitard, and the lack of drawdown history in pumped aquifers. In this study, an analytical solution is derived to describe the drawdown variation in a nonlinear‐consolidated aquitard under the condition of variable drawdowns in adjacent aquifers. Based on the analytical solution, we study the characteristics of groundwater dynamics and water balance under the conditions of linearly increasing drawdown of aquifers in adjacent aquifers. In addition, we put forward a method to calculate the depletion and hydrogeological parameters of an aquitard corresponding to variable drawdowns in adjacent aquifers, applicable even when historical drawdown data are lacking. The accuracy of the method is generally very good, but results improve when the drawdown history of pumped aquifers is divided into more periods for estimation. Groundwater depletion of the aquitard increases with increasing compression index, coefficient of consolidation, thickness of aquitard, rate of drawdown change in the adjacent aquifer, while decreasing with initial void ratio, and initial effective stress. The proposed approach is demonstrated at a field site in Shanghai city of China, and it would help for the effective management of groundwater resources and estimation of the global transfer from groundwater to surface water.</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;Computing aquitard depletion, which is often overlooked, is of great significance for the assessment of groundwater resources and land subsidence. The issue is viewed as troublesome because of the additional computational burden, the poorly known hydrogeological parameters of the aquitard, and the lack of drawdown history in pumped aquifers. In this study, an analytical solution is derived to describe the drawdown variation in a nonlinear-consolidated aquitard under the condition of variable drawdowns in adjacent aquifers. Based on the analytical solution, we study the characteristics of groundwater dynamics and water balance under the conditions of linearly increasing drawdown of aquifers in adjacent aquifers. In addition, we put forward a method to calculate the depletion and hydrogeological parameters of an aquitard corresponding to variable drawdowns in adjacent aquifers, applicable even when historical drawdown data are lacking. The accuracy of the method is generally very good, but results improve when the drawdown history of pumped aquifers is divided into more periods for estimation. Groundwater depletion of the aquitard increases with increasing compression index, coefficient of consolidation, thickness of aquitard, rate of drawdown change in the adjacent aquifer, while decreasing with initial void ratio, and initial effective stress. The proposed approach is demonstrated at a field site in Shanghai city of China, and it would help for the effective management of groundwater resources and estimation of the global transfer from groundwater to surface water.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> Zhaofeng Li, Hao Li, Xianxuan Xiao, Walter A. Illman, Ruizhe Wang, , Qiang Zhang</dc:creator><category> Research Article</category><dc:title> An Analytical Method to Estimate Groundwater Depletion of an Aquitard Due To Variable Drawdowns in Adjacent Aquifers</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2023WR034503</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1029/2023WR034503</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2023WR034503?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> Research Article</prism:section><prism:volume> 59</prism:volume><prism:number> 4个</prism:number></item><item><link/>https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033256?af=R<pubDate> Thu, 30 Mar 2023 09:15:02 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-03-30T09:15:02-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley: Water Resources Research: Table of Contents<prism:coverdate> Sat, 01 Apr 2023 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate> Sat, 01 Apr 2023 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR033256</guid><title> Toward Sustainable Water Infrastructure: The State‐Of‐The‐Art for Modeling the Failure Probability of Water Pipes</title><description> Water Resources Research, Volume 59, Issue 4, April 2023.</description><dc:description> Abstract Failures of water distribution networks (WDNs) are rising at an exponential rate, necessitating immediate attention. An effective way to reduce the failure rate is to develop accurate predictive models for the failure probability of water pipes, which are the most critical assets of WDNs. Despite the fact that researchers have invested efforts to develop various predictive models, the extant literature lacks a complete state‐of‐the‐art review. To fill this gap, this study employs a mixed approach (ie, quantitative and qualitative) by providing (a) a bibliometric analysis of existing scholarly literature, (b) a systematic review of the techniques used in modeling the failure probability of water pipes, including physical, statistical, and machine‐learning (ML)‐based models, and (c) identified gaps and future research directions. The bibliometric analysis shows that ML‐based models are emerging and, hence understudied as compared to the physical and statistical‐based models. Regarding the systematic review, a proper understanding of the development of each model has been provided in addition to their advantages and critiques. Furthermore, failure probability integration methods are discussed. Findings reveal that the social and operation‐related predictors have been understudied, thereby suggesting their further exploration. This study adds to the existing body of knowledge by providing water utilities and academics with a comprehensive understanding of the probability of water pipe failure, which will be useful in the decision‐making process and network management.</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;Failures of water distribution networks (WDNs) are rising at an exponential rate, necessitating immediate attention. An effective way to reduce the failure rate is to develop accurate predictive models for the failure probability of water pipes, which are the most critical assets of WDNs. Despite the fact that researchers have invested efforts to develop various predictive models, the extant literature lacks a complete state-of-the-art review. To fill this gap, this study employs a mixed approach (ie, quantitative and qualitative) by providing (a) a bibliometric analysis of existing scholarly literature, (b) a systematic review of the techniques used in modeling the failure probability of water pipes, including physical, statistical, and machine-learning (ML)-based models, and (c) identified gaps and future research directions. The bibliometric analysis shows that ML-based models are emerging and, hence understudied as compared to the physical and statistical-based models. Regarding the systematic review, a proper understanding of the development of each model has been provided in addition to their advantages and critiques. Furthermore, failure probability integration methods are discussed. Findings reveal that the social and operation-related predictors have been understudied, thereby suggesting their further exploration. This study adds to the existing body of knowledge by providing water utilities and academics with a comprehensive understanding of the probability of water pipe failure, which will be useful in the decision-making process and network management.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> Ridwan Taiwo, Mohamed El Amine Ben Seghier, Tarek Zayed</dc:creator><category> Review Article</category><dc:title> Toward Sustainable Water Infrastructure: The State‐Of‐The‐Art for Modeling the Failure Probability of Water Pipes</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2022WR033256</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1029/2022WR033256</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033256?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> Review Article</prism:section><prism:volume> 59</prism:volume><prism:number> 4个</prism:number></item><item><link/>https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033780?af=R<pubDate> Wed, 29 Mar 2023 08:38:28 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-03-29T08:38:28-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley: Water Resources Research: Table of Contents <prism:coverdate></prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate></prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR033780</guid><title> Sensitivity Analysis: An operational picture</title><description> Water Resources Research, Accepted Article.</description><dc:description> Abstract Modelling is crucial to understand the behavior of environmental systems. A deeper comprehension of a model can be aided by global sensitivity analysis. Variability ascribed to model variables could have a stochastic (ie, lack of knowledge) or an operational (ie, possible design values) origin. Despite the possible different nature in the variability, current global sensitivity analysis strategies do not distinguish the latter in their formal derivations/developments. We propose to disentangle the variability in the operational and stochastic variables while assessing the model output sensitivity with respect to the former. Two operational sensitivity indices are introduced that serve to characterize the sensitivity of a model output of interest with respect to an operational variable in terms of (a) its average (with respect to the stochastic variables) intensity and (b) its degree of fluctuation (across the set of possible realizations of the stochastic variables), respectively. We exemplify our developments considering two scenarios. Results highlight the relevance of employing an operational global sensitivity analysis when the focus is on the influence of operational variables on model output. This article is protected by copyright.版权所有。</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;Modelling is crucial to understand the behavior of environmental systems. A deeper comprehension of a model can be aided by global sensitivity analysis. &lt;i>;Variability&lt;/i>; ascribed to model variables could have a stochastic (ie, lack of knowledge) or an operational (ie, possible design values) origin. Despite the possible different nature in the &lt;i>;variability&lt;/i>;, current global sensitivity analysis strategies do not distinguish the latter in their formal derivations/developments. We propose to disentangle the &lt;i>;variability&lt;/i>; in the operational and stochastic variables while assessing the model output sensitivity with respect to the former. Two operational sensitivity indices are introduced that serve to characterize the sensitivity of a model output of interest with respect to an operational variable in terms of (&lt;i>;a&lt;/i>;) its average (with respect to the stochastic variables) intensity and (&lt;i>;b&lt;/i>;) its degree of fluctuation (across the set of possible realizations of the stochastic variables), respectively. We exemplify our developments considering two scenarios. Results highlight the relevance of employing an operational global sensitivity analysis when the focus is on the influence of operational variables on model output.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This article is protected by copyright. All rights reserved.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> A. Dell&#39;Oca</dc:creator><category> Research Article</category><dc:title> Sensitivity Analysis: An operational picture</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2022WR033780</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1029/2022WR033780</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033780?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> Research Article</prism:section></item><item><link/> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033595?af=R<pubDate> Wed, 29 Mar 2023 08:14:43 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-03-29T08:14:43-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley: Water Resources Research: Table of Contents<prism:coverdate> Sat, 01 Apr 2023 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate> Sat, 01 Apr 2023 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR033595</guid><title> Bed Stability of Step‐Pool Channels With Macrorough Sidewalls</title><description> Water Resources Research, Volume 59, Issue 4, April 2023.</description><dc:description> Abstract A step‐pool bed morphology often develops in steep mountain streams. The main controlling parameters of step formation and stability are hydraulic forcing, sediment transport, and granular effects (ie, grain‐grain interlocking, jamming). Previous studies found macrorough sidewalls to further increase bed stability due to grain‐sidewall interlocking but the effect of the reduced bed shear stress caused by sidewall friction was not explicitly considered. The present study aims at untangling hydraulic effects induced by the macrorough sidewalls and granular effects, that is, grain‐sidewall interaction. Flume experiments with five types of macrorough sidewalls were conducted under clear‐water conditions for bed slopes ranging between 4% and 10% and jamming ratios 5.3 &lt; Wm/d84 &lt; 11.2, where Wm is the mean channel width and d84 is a characteristic grain size of the sediment mixture. A modified sidewall correction procedure accounting for sidewall friction was applied to estimate bed shear stress. Bed stability considerably increased with increasing sidewall roughness. The dimensionless bed shear stress θRb controlled step occurrence as the system evolved toward a state of a maximum number of steps for critical Shields ratios θRb/θc ≈ 1. Contrary to the expectations, fewer steps formed in the roughest sidewall experiments as few very stable steps inhibited sediment relocation and therewith step formation. Steps were more frequently located in the constrictions caused by the macrorough elements and sustained higher bed shear stress increments. Overall, hydraulic effects fully explained the increase in bed stability in moderately rough sidewall experiments whereas granular effects became important in channels with strong local constrictions.</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;A step-pool bed morphology often develops in steep mountain streams. The main controlling parameters of step formation and stability are hydraulic forcing, sediment transport, and granular effects (ie, grain-grain interlocking, jamming). Previous studies found macrorough sidewalls to further increase bed stability due to grain-sidewall interlocking but the effect of the reduced bed shear stress caused by sidewall friction was not explicitly considered. The present study aims at untangling hydraulic effects induced by the macrorough sidewalls and granular effects, that is, grain-sidewall interaction. Flume experiments with five types of macrorough sidewalls were conducted under clear-water conditions for bed slopes ranging between 4% and 10% and jamming ratios 5.3 &amp;lt; &lt;i>;W&lt;/i>; &lt;sub>; &lt;i>;m&lt;/i>; &lt;/sub>;/&lt;i>;d&lt;/i>; &lt;sub>;84&lt;/sub>; &amp;lt; 11.2, where &lt;i>;W&lt;/i>; &lt;sub>; &lt;i>;m&lt;/i>; &lt;/sub>; is the mean channel width and &lt;i>;d&lt;/i>; &lt;sub>;84&lt;/sub>; is a characteristic grain size of the sediment mixture. A modified sidewall correction procedure accounting for sidewall friction was applied to estimate bed shear stress. Bed stability considerably increased with increasing sidewall roughness. The dimensionless bed shear stress &lt;i>;θ&lt;/i>; &lt;sub>; &lt;i>;Rb&lt;/i>; &lt;/sub>; controlled step occurrence as the system evolved toward a state of a maximum number of steps for critical Shields ratios &lt;i>;θ&lt;/i>; &lt;sub>; &lt;i>;Rb&lt;/i>; &lt;/sub>;/&lt;i>;θ&lt;/i>; &lt;sub>; &lt;i>;c&lt;/i>; &lt;/sub>; ≈ 1. Contrary to the expectations, fewer steps formed in the roughest sidewall experiments as few very stable steps inhibited sediment relocation and therewith step formation. Steps were more frequently located in the constrictions caused by the macrorough elements and sustained higher bed shear stress increments. Overall, hydraulic effects fully explained the increase in bed stability in moderately rough sidewall experiments whereas granular effects became important in channels with strong local constrictions.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> F. Maager, B. Hohermuth, RM Boes, V. Weitbrecht</dc:creator><category> Research Article</category><dc:title> Bed Stability of Step‐Pool Channels With Macrorough Sidewalls</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2022WR033595</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1029/2022WR033595</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033595?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> Research Article</prism:section><prism:volume> 59</prism:volume><prism:number> 4个</prism:number></item><item><link/>https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR032559?af=R<pubDate> Wed, 29 Mar 2023 05:08:49 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-03-29T05:08:49-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley: Water Resources Research: Table of Contents <prism:coverdate></prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate></prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR032559</guid><title> An economic model of spatial and temporal water trade in the Australian southern Murray‐Darling Basin</title><description> Water Resources Research, Accepted Article.</description><dc:description> Abstract Within the Australian southern Murray‐Darling Basin water markets have become a key institutional response to water scarcity and environmental problems. These markets facilitate trading of water among many users and across multiple connected regions. Increasingly, these markets also support intertemporal transfers via the carryover of user water allocations within public water storages. While trading can improve the spatial allocation of water, carryover can improve the temporal allocation by ensuring storage reserves reflect prevailing user supply and reliability preferences. This paper presents an economic model of water markets and irrigated agriculture in the southern Murray‐Darling Basin. A reduced‐form statistical model of water demand is estimated using historical irrigation and water market data. This statistical model is placed within an economic partial‐equilibrium framework accounting for both inter‐regional trade and inter‐year carryover. The model is solved numerically for a dynamic market equilibrium given assumptions over future stochastic water supplies. Out‐of‐sample tests show the model can realistically simulate water market prices and irrigation activity across the basin. The model is applied to estimate the economic benefits of inter‐regional water trading and inter‐year carryover. Results show around a third of the economic benefits of water markets in the region can be attributed to inter‐year carryover.</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;Within the Australian southern Murray-Darling Basin water markets have become a key institutional response to water scarcity and environmental problems. These markets facilitate trading of water among many users and across multiple connected regions. Increasingly, these markets also support intertemporal transfers via the carryover of user water allocations within public water storages. While trading can improve the spatial allocation of water, carryover can improve the temporal allocation by ensuring storage reserves reflect prevailing user supply and reliability preferences. This paper presents an economic model of water markets and irrigated agriculture in the southern Murray-Darling Basin. A reduced-form statistical model of water demand is estimated using historical irrigation and water market data. This statistical model is placed within an economic partial-equilibrium framework accounting for both inter-regional trade and inter-year carryover. The model is solved numerically for a dynamic market equilibrium given assumptions over future stochastic water supplies. Out-of-sample tests show the model can realistically simulate water market prices and irrigation activity across the basin. The model is applied to estimate the economic benefits of inter-regional water trading and inter-year carryover. Results show around a third of the economic benefits of water markets in the region can be attributed to inter-year carryover.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> Neal Hughes, Mihir Gupta, Linden Whittle, Tim Westwood</dc:creator><category> Research Article</category><dc:title> An economic model of spatial and temporal water trade in the Australian southern Murray‐Darling Basin</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2022WR032559</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1029/2022WR032559</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR032559?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> Research Article</prism:section></item><item><link/> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR032984?af=R<pubDate> Tue, 28 Mar 2023 20:58:52 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-03-28T08:58:52-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley: Water Resources Research: Table of Contents <prism:coverdate></prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate></prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR032984</guid><title> Laboratory investigation into the effect of the storage capacity of a city block on unsteady urban flood flows</title><description> Water Resources Research, Accepted Article.</description><dc:description> Abstract The increasing occurrence of urban flooding in recent years demands a more accurate flood hazard assessment. Therefore, a better understanding of the predominant hydraulic processes in urban flood flows is required. The present paper reports an experimental study conducted in a laboratory scale model, which represents an urban area consisting of a rectangular city block and four surrounding streets. The objective is to quantify the impact of open areas within the city block on the key features of floodwaters. Tests are carried out under unsteady flow conditions, by using three inflow hydrographs with different unsteadiness levels. For each inflow hydrograph, the space available for floodwater volume storage within the block (storage capacity, ϕ) is varied, keeping the boundary conditions unchanged. A case where the city block has no space for floodwater storage (ie, ϕ = 0) is used as a reference case. The results indicate that the unsteadiness level of the inflow hydrograph, especially during the rising stage, has a strong influence on the floodwater volume stored within the city block. The increase in storage capacity within the city block leads to a reduction of the global peak outflow discharge, a decrease in flow depths and a local increase in velocities in some streets and within the city block. Finally, with these variations in floodwater features, the level of risk to pedestrians is also impacted, increasing locally when the storage capacity of the block increases. This article is protected by copyright.版权所有。</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;The increasing occurrence of urban flooding in recent years demands a more accurate flood hazard assessment. Therefore, a better understanding of the predominant hydraulic processes in urban flood flows is required. The present paper reports an experimental study conducted in a laboratory scale model, which represents an urban area consisting of a rectangular city block and four surrounding streets. The objective is to quantify the impact of open areas within the city block on the key features of floodwaters. Tests are carried out under unsteady flow conditions, by using three inflow hydrographs with different unsteadiness levels. For each inflow hydrograph, the space available for floodwater volume storage within the block (storage capacity, &lt;i>;ϕ&lt;/i>;) is varied, keeping the boundary conditions unchanged. A case where the city block has no space for floodwater storage (ie, &lt;i>;ϕ&lt;/i>; = 0) is used as a reference case. The results indicate that the unsteadiness level of the inflow hydrograph, especially during the rising stage, has a strong influence on the floodwater volume stored within the city block. The increase in storage capacity within the city block leads to a reduction of the global peak outflow discharge, a decrease in flow depths and a local increase in velocities in some streets and within the city block. Finally, with these variations in floodwater features, the level of risk to pedestrians is also impacted, increasing locally when the storage capacity of the block increases.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This article is protected by copyright. All rights reserved.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> Miguel Angel Mejía‐Morales, Emmanuel Mignot, André Paquier, Sébastien Proust</dc:creator><category> Research Article</category><dc:title> Laboratory investigation into the effect of the storage capacity of a city block on unsteady urban flood flows</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2022WR032984</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1029/2022WR032984</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR032984?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> Research Article</prism:section></item><item><link/> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR034211?af=R<pubDate> Tue, 28 Mar 2023 11:37:05 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-03-28T11:37:05-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley: Water Resources Research: Table of Contents <prism:coverdate></prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate></prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR034211</guid><title> New insights into freezing behavior of saturated and air‐entrained porous media via a micromechanics‐based thermo‐hydro‐mechanical model</title><description> Water Resources Research, Accepted Article.</description><dc:description> Abstract A micromechanics‐based thermo‐hydro‐mechanical model for capturing the freezing behavior of porous media is devised, where a microstructure‐dependent constitutive relation, thermo‐hydro‐mechanical conditions, and the origin of freezing deformation are comprehensively considered. A micromechanical upscaling approach is proposed to improve the physical understanding of the freezing behavior of porous media. Comparisons against experimental and theoretical results suggest that the present model is a reliable means to predict the freezing deformation of saturated and air‐entrained porous media. The results show that the freezing deformation induced by the hydraulic pressure strongly depends on the boundary and air‐entrained conditions, and the undercooling phenomenon can be captured well. Moreover, the magnitude of surface energy (0 ∼ 8 MPa) is in the ascending order of saturated undrained, drained, and air‐entrained conditions. The proposed model sheds light on the quantitative effects of freezing rate, liquid water transfer, and pore shape on the freezing deformation of porous media, which can provide insights into the freezing resistance mechanism of porous media. This article is protected by copyright.版权所有。</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;A micromechanics-based thermo-hydro-mechanical model for capturing the freezing behavior of porous media is devised, where a microstructure-dependent constitutive relation, thermo-hydro-mechanical conditions, and the origin of freezing deformation are comprehensively considered. A micromechanical upscaling approach is proposed to improve the physical understanding of the freezing behavior of porous media. Comparisons against experimental and theoretical results suggest that the present model is a reliable means to predict the freezing deformation of saturated and air-entrained porous media. The results show that the freezing deformation induced by the hydraulic pressure strongly depends on the boundary and air-entrained conditions, and the undercooling phenomenon can be captured well. Moreover, the magnitude of surface energy (0 ∼ 8 MPa) is in the ascending order of saturated undrained, drained, and air-entrained conditions. The proposed model sheds light on the quantitative effects of freezing rate, liquid water transfer, and pore shape on the freezing deformation of porous media, which can provide insights into the freezing resistance mechanism of porous media.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This article is protected by copyright. All rights reserved.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> Weiqi Guo, Fengjuan Wang, Yang Wu, Jinyang Jiang, Wenxiang Xu</dc:creator><category> Research Article</category><dc:title> New insights into freezing behavior of saturated and air‐entrained porous media via a micromechanics‐based thermo‐hydro‐mechanical model</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2022WR034211</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1029/2022WR034211</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR034211?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> Research Article</prism:section></item><item><link/> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033831?af=R<pubDate> Tue, 28 Mar 2023 09:59:27 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-03-28T09:59:27-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley: Water Resources Research: Table of Contents <prism:coverdate></prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate></prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR033831</guid><title> A Short‐term Pumping Strategy for Hydraulic Tomography Based on the Successive Linear Estimator</title><description> Water Resources Research, Accepted Article.</description><dc:description> Abstract In this study, the random finite element method (RFEM), a finite element method with random field generation techniques, was applied to investigate the cross‐correlations between the observed head and hydraulic conductivity and specific storage at different locations and different times in pumping tests. The results show that the two cross‐correlations between the pumping well and the observation well reach their maximums before pumping reaches a steady state. Specifically, the cross‐correlation between the observed head and hydraulic conductivity is the greatest when the temporal derivative of the observed head does not change significantly, and that between the observed head and specific storage is the greatest when the temporal derivative (the rate) of the observed head is maximum. Based on the results of cross‐correlation analysis, a short‐term pumping strategy for HT is proposed to obtain the spatial distribution of hydraulic conductivity and specific storage using the successive linear estimator. Furthermore, this strategy was validated by Monte Carlo simulations. This paper points out that the sensitivity and cross‐correlation analyses report the ensemble (averaged) behaviors of any heterogeneous aquifers, which is not necessarily suitable for one realization. Furthermore, Monte Carlo simulation is suggested for validating any groundwater inverse modeling result. This article is protected by copyright.版权所有。</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;In this study, the random finite element method (RFEM), a finite element method with random field generation techniques, was applied to investigate the cross-correlations between the observed head and hydraulic conductivity and specific storage at different locations and different times in pumping tests. The results show that the two cross-correlations between the pumping well and the observation well reach their maximums before pumping reaches a steady state. Specifically, the cross-correlation between the observed head and hydraulic conductivity is the greatest when the temporal derivative of the observed head does not change significantly, and that between the observed head and specific storage is the greatest when the temporal derivative (the rate) of the observed head is maximum. Based on the results of cross-correlation analysis, a short-term pumping strategy for HT is proposed to obtain the spatial distribution of hydraulic conductivity and specific storage using the successive linear estimator. Furthermore, this strategy was validated by Monte Carlo simulations. This paper points out that the sensitivity and cross-correlation analyses report the ensemble (averaged) behaviors of any heterogeneous aquifers, which is not necessarily suitable for one realization. Furthermore, Monte Carlo simulation is suggested for validating any groundwater inverse modeling result.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This article is protected by copyright. All rights reserved.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> Xiaolan Hou, Rui Hu, Tian‐Chyi Jim Yeh, Yukun Li, Junjie Qi, Yang Song, Huiyang Qiu</dc:creator><category> Research Article</category><dc:title> A Short‐term Pumping Strategy for Hydraulic Tomography Based on the Successive Linear Estimator</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2022WR033831</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1029/2022WR033831</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033831?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> Research Article</prism:section></item><item><link/> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033600?af=R<pubDate> Tue, 28 Mar 2023 08:48:41 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-03-28T08:48:41-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley: Water Resources Research: Table of Contents <prism:coverdate></prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate></prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR033600</guid><title> Automated Symbolic Upscaling: Model Generation for Extended Applicability Regimes, Part 1</title><description> Water Resources Research, Accepted Article.</description><dc:description> Abstract In porous media theory, upscaling techniques are fundamental to deriving rigorous Darcy‐scale models for flow and reactive transport in subsurface systems. Due to limitations in classical techniques, a number of ad hoc approaches have been proposed to address physical regimes in which reactive timescales are similar to, or faster than, diffusive timescales. In Part 1 of this two part series, we present a strategy for expanding the applicability of classical homogenization theory by generalizing the assumed closure form. We detail the implementation of this strategy on two reactive mass transport problems with moderately reactive physics. The strategy produces nontrivial homogenized models with emergent terms and effective parameters that couple reactive, diffusive, and advective transport. The differences in equation forms between the macroscopic and pore‐scale descriptions advise caution to further studies where the forms of macroscopic equations are assumed, as opposed to rigorously derived. Numerical validation is provided for each problem to show that the error estimates of homogenization theory are satisfied, and to justify the implemented strategy. In Part 2, the presented strategy is automated using symbolic computing to expedite its implementation. This article is protected by copyright.版权所有。</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;In porous media theory, upscaling techniques are fundamental to deriving rigorous Darcy-scale models for flow and reactive transport in subsurface systems. Due to limitations in classical techniques, a number of &lt;i>;ad hoc&lt;/i>; approaches have been proposed to address physical regimes in which reactive timescales are similar to, or faster than, diffusive timescales. In Part 1 of this two part series, we present a strategy for expanding the applicability of classical homogenization theory by generalizing the assumed closure form. We detail the implementation of this strategy on two reactive mass transport problems with moderately reactive physics. The strategy produces nontrivial homogenized models with emergent terms and effective parameters that couple reactive, diffusive, and advective transport. The differences in equation forms between the macroscopic and pore-scale descriptions advise caution to further studies where the forms of macroscopic equations are assumed, as opposed to rigorously derived. Numerical validation is provided for each problem to show that the error estimates of homogenization theory are satisfied, and to justify the implemented strategy. In Part 2, the presented strategy is automated using symbolic computing to expedite its implementation.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This article is protected by copyright. All rights reserved.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> Kyle Pietrzyk, Ilenia Battiato</dc:creator><category> Research Article</category><dc:title> Automated Symbolic Upscaling: Model Generation for Extended Applicability Regimes, Part 1</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2022WR033600</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1029/2022WR033600</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033600?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> Research Article</prism:section></item><item><link/> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/wrcr.26014?af=R<pubDate> Tue, 28 Mar 2023 05:28:23 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-03-28T05:28:23-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley: Water Resources Research: Table of Contents<prism:coverdate> Sat, 01 Apr 2023 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate> Sat, 01 Apr 2023 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1002/wrcr.26014</guid><title> Issue Information</title><description> Water Resources Research, Volume 59, Issue 4, April 2023.</description><dc:description> No abstract is available for this article.</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;p>;No abstract is available for this article.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator></dc:creator><category> Issue Information</category><dc:title> Issue Information</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1002/wrcr.26014</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1002/wrcr.26014</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/wrcr.26014?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> Issue Information</prism:section><prism:volume> 59</prism:volume><prism:number> 4个</prism:number></item><item><link/>https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033151?af=R<pubDate> Tue, 28 Mar 2023 01:24:50 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-03-28T01:24:50-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley: Water Resources Research: Table of Contents <prism:coverdate></prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate></prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR033151</guid><title> Paleo‐Hydrogeological Modeling to Understand Present‐Day Groundwater Salinities in a Low‐Lying Coastal Groundwater System (Northwestern Germany)</title><description> Water Resources Research, Accepted Article.</description><dc:description> Abstract Groundwater abstraction and drainage are considered to be main drivers for salinization of low‐lying coastal groundwater systems, while the role of past boundary conditions is less clear. In this study, 3‐D paleo‐hydrogeological variable‐density groundwater flow and salt transport modeling (&#39;paleo‐modeling&#39;) is applied to reconstruct the evolution of groundwater salinities during the Holocene, ie, the last 9000 years, in Northwestern Germany. Novel aspects of this study include the consideration of highly resolved time‐variant boundary conditions in a 3‐D paleo‐modeling framework, eg, sea‐level rise, surface elevation and coastline changes, development of drainage networks and groundwater abstraction, as well as the quantification of isolated processes impacting salinization. Results show that salinization was a function of sea‐level rise from 9000 BP until 1300 AD. The creation of the dike line ∼1300 AD set the starting point for increasing anthropogenic control of the hydro(geo)logical system: changes in surface elevation and drainage of low‐lying marshes have become main drivers for salinization after 1600 AD, when peat was artificially degenerated. Moreover, changes of the dike line caused by storm floods impacted the salinities. Model results for 2020 AD match well with present‐day salinity observations. Yet, salinization will continue in the future, as the hydro(geo)logical system has not reached an equilibrium. The presented paleo‐modeling framework can be viewed as blueprint for similar low‐lying coastal groundwater systems, influenced by marine transgression and human development. Thereby, it enables the reconstruction of meaningful present‐day salinity distributions, serving as vital basis for modeling of future groundwater systems in a changing climate. This article is protected by copyright.版权所有。</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;Groundwater abstraction and drainage are considered to be main drivers for salinization of low-lying coastal groundwater systems, while the role of past boundary conditions is less clear. In this study, 3-D paleo-hydrogeological variable-density groundwater flow and salt transport modeling (&#39;paleo-modeling&#39;) is applied to reconstruct the evolution of groundwater salinities during the Holocene, ie, the last 9000 years, in Northwestern Germany. Novel aspects of this study include the consideration of highly resolved time-variant boundary conditions in a 3-D paleo-modeling framework, eg, sea-level rise, surface elevation and coastline changes, development of drainage networks and groundwater abstraction, as well as the quantification of isolated processes impacting salinization. Results show that salinization was a function of sea-level rise from 9000 BP until 1300 AD. The creation of the dike line ∼1300 AD set the starting point for increasing anthropogenic control of the hydro(geo)logical system: changes in surface elevation and drainage of low-lying marshes have become main drivers for salinization after 1600 AD, when peat was artificially degenerated. Moreover, changes of the dike line caused by storm floods impacted the salinities. Model results for 2020 AD match well with present-day salinity observations. Yet, salinization will continue in the future, as the hydro(geo)logical system has not reached an equilibrium. The presented paleo-modeling framework can be viewed as blueprint for similar low-lying coastal groundwater systems, influenced by marine transgression and human development. Thereby, it enables the reconstruction of meaningful present-day salinity distributions, serving as vital basis for modeling of future groundwater systems in a changing climate.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This article is protected by copyright. All rights reserved.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> Stephan L. Seibert, Janek Greskowiak, Friederike Bungenstock, Holger Freund, Martina Karle, Rena Meyer, Gualbert HP Oude Essink, Joeri Engelen, Gudrun Massmann</dc:creator><category> Research Article</category><dc:title> Paleo‐Hydrogeological Modeling to Understand Present‐Day Groundwater Salinities in a Low‐Lying Coastal Groundwater System (Northwestern Germany)</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2022WR033151</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1029/2022WR033151</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033151?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> Research Article</prism:section></item></channel></rss>