<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:prism="http://prismstandard.org/namespaces/basic/2.0/"><channel><title> Wiley：水资源研究：目录</title><link/>https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R<description>水资源研究目录。最新和 EarlyView 问题的文章列表。</description><language>英文</language><copyright></copyright><managingeditor>wileyonlinelibrary@wiley.com（AGU 出版物）</managingeditor><pubDate> Tue, 21 Feb 2023 08:34:26 +0000</pubDate><lastbuilddate> 2023 年 2 月 21 日星期二 08:34:26 +0000</lastbuilddate><generator> Atypon®文学™</generator><docs> https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs><ttl> 10080</ttl><dc:title> Wiley：水资源研究：目录</dc:title><dc:publisher>威利</dc:publisher><prism:publicationname>水资源研究</prism:publicationname><atom:link href="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"></atom:link><image/><title> Wiley：水资源研究：目录</title><url>https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/pb-assets/journal-banners/19447973.jpg</url><link/> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R<item><link/> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR032415?af=R<pubDate> Mon, 20 Feb 2023 18:08:36 -0800</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-02-20T06:08:36-08:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley：水资源研究：目录<prism:coverdate></prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate></prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR032415</guid><title>退耕还林项目可能不会通过降低潮湿喀斯特地貌中的可用水量来威胁生态系统的可持续性</title><description>水资源研究，接受的文章。</description><dc:description>摘要 退耕还林工程可能导致高蒸发蒸腾（ET），加剧缺水，并加剧许多缺水地区生态系统与人类之间的水需求冲突。然而，目前尚不清楚植被恢复如何影响降水丰富但渗漏快的湿润喀斯特地区的蒸散量。特别是，现有的 ET 测量方法不能同时适用于这种高度异质和分散的景观中的各种生态系统，这一点具有挑战性。为了解决这个问题，本研究首次开发了一种新的ET测量系统，通过集成多种技术，连续三年对多种植被恢复类型的ET进行量化，并确定其在湿润喀斯特地区的控制因素。结果表明：（1）自然恢复不同演替阶段，次生林ET（680±7 mm yr-1）>;灌木（564±16 mm yr-1）>;草（546±12 mm yr-1） ) >; 农田 (513 ± 8 mm yr‐1) (P &lt; 0.05); (2) 所有生态系统的ET远小于降水量(1059±63 mm yr-1)但更接近潜在ET(849±11 mm yr-1)，土壤水分一直保持在>;0.20 cm3cm-3在生长季节； (3)太阳辐射和水汽压亏缺是影响蒸散量的两个主要因素(P&lt;0.01)，而蒸散量与土壤水分无显着关系(P>;0.05)。结果表明，在潮湿的喀斯特地区，从农田恢复的植被恢复增加了 ET，但可能不会导致植被可持续性缺水，至少在正常气候条件下是这样。本文受版权保护。版权所有。</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;摘要&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;退耕还林工程可能导致高蒸发蒸腾（ET），加剧缺水，并加剧许多缺水地区生态系统与人类之间的水需求冲突。然而，目前尚不清楚植被恢复如何影响降水丰富但渗漏快的湿润喀斯特地区的蒸散量。特别是，现有的 ET 测量方法不能同时适用于这种高度异质和分散的景观中的各种生态系统，这一点具有挑战性。为了解决这个问题，本研究首次开发了一种新的ET测量系统，通过集成多种技术，连续三年对多种植被恢复类型的ET进行量化，并确定其在湿润喀斯特地区的控制因素。结果表明：（1）在自然恢复的不同演替阶段，次生林ET（680±7 mm yr&lt;sup>;-1&lt;/sup>;）>;;灌木 (564 ± 16 mm yr&lt;sup>;-1&lt;/sup>;) >;草 (546 ± 12 mm yr&lt;sup>;-1&lt;/sup>;) >;农田 (513 ± 8 mm yr&lt;sup>;-1&lt;/sup>;) (P &lt; 0.05); (2) 所有生态系统的ET远小于降水量(1059±63 mm yr&lt;sup>;-1&lt;/sup>;)但更接近潜在ET(849±11 mm yr&lt;sup>;-1&lt;/sup>;) ), 土壤水分一直保持在 &amp;gt;生长期0.20 cm&lt;sup>;3&lt;/sup>;cm&lt;sup>;-3&lt;/sup>;； (3)太阳辐射和水汽压亏缺是影响蒸散量的两个主要因素(&lt;i>;P&lt;/i>; &lt;0.01)，而蒸散量与土壤水分(&lt;i>;P&lt;/i)无显着关系>;＞0.05)。结果表明，在潮湿的喀斯特地区，从农田恢复的植被恢复增加了 ET，但可能不会导致植被可持续性缺水，至少在正常气候条件下是这样。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;本文受版权保护。保留所有权利。&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator>易如洲, 徐先利, 张耀华, 叶宗达, 王克林</dc:creator><category>研究文章</category><dc:title>退耕还林项目可能不会通过降低潮湿喀斯特地貌中的可用水量来威胁生态系统的可持续性</dc:title><dc:identifier>10.1029/2022WR032415</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname>水资源研究</prism:publicationname><prism:doi>10.1029/2022WR032415</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR032415?af=R</prism:url><prism:section>研究文章</prism:section></item><item><link/>https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR032317?af=R<pubDate> Mon, 20 Feb 2023 18:04:46 -0800</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-02-20T06:04:46-08:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley：水资源研究：目录<prism:coverdate></prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate></prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR032317</guid><title>风暴潮屏障关闭对河口盐水入侵和分层的影响</title><description>水资源研究，接受的文章。</description><dc:description>摘要 为减少沿海洪水风险，世界上许多河口都建造或提议了门控风暴潮屏障。过去的研究表明，即使在开放的情况下，屏障系统的固定基础设施也会增加河口分层和盐分入侵，从而可能影响水质和生态过程。然而，浪涌屏障关闭可能会暂时阻止潮汐交换，从而对河口条件产生更大的影响。在这个项目中，我们使用现有的区域三维水动力模型，修改以模拟浪涌屏障关闭和重新打开，以研究对哈德逊河河口盐分入侵和分层的影响。在一系列闸门关闭频率、持续时间和河流流量的模拟场景中，我们评估了闸门关闭引起的变化，以及恢复到正常状态的时间。我们对哈德逊河的研究结果表明，长时间关闭闸门（三天或更长时间）且流量较低会暂时导致盐分入侵和分层，超出最近的历史极端值。此外，在海平面上升和屏障管理的现实情景下，最早可能在 2070 年发生的每月频率关闭不允许在低流量条件下恢复，并可能导致河口物理条件发生持久变化。因此，长时间关闭和高频关闭都对市政供水构成威胁。本研究展示了一个框架，用于理解任何拟议的浪涌屏障系统的潜在影响，并有助于提高我们对相应生态影响的理解。本文受版权保护。版权所有。</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;摘要&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;为了降低沿海洪水风险，世界上许多河口已经建造或提议设置门控风暴潮屏障。过去的研究表明，即使在开放的情况下，屏障系统的固定基础设施也会增加河口分层和盐分入侵，从而可能影响水质和生态过程。然而，浪涌屏障关闭可能会暂时阻止潮汐交换，从而对河口条件产生更大的影响。在这个项目中，我们使用现有的区域三维水动力模型，修改以模拟浪涌屏障关闭和重新打开，以研究对哈德逊河河口盐分入侵和分层的影响。在一系列闸门关闭频率、持续时间和河流流量的模拟场景中，我们评估了闸门关闭引起的变化，以及恢复到正常状态的时间。我们对哈德逊河的研究结果表明，长时间关闭闸门（三天或更长时间）和低流量会暂时导致盐分入侵和分层，超出最近的历史极端值。此外，在海平面上升和屏障管理的现实情景下，最早可能在 2070 年发生的每月频率关闭不允许在低流量条件下恢复，并可能导致河口物理条件发生持久变化。因此，长时间关闭和高频关闭都对市政供水构成威胁。这项研究展示了一个框架，用于理解任何拟议的浪涌屏障系统的潜在影响，并有助于提高我们对相应生态影响的理解。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;本文受版权保护。保留所有权利。&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> Ziyu Chen, Philip M. Orton</dc:creator><category>研究文章</category><dc:title>风暴潮屏障关闭对河口盐水入侵和分层的影响</dc:title><dc:identifier>10.1029/2022WR032317</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname>水资源研究</prism:publicationname><prism:doi>10.1029/2022WR032317</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR032317?af=R</prism:url><prism:section>研究文章</prism:section></item><item><link/>https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033309?af=R<pubDate> Mon, 20 Feb 2023 17:58:47 -0800</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-02-20T05:58:47-08:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley：水资源研究：目录<prism:coverdate></prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate></prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR033309</guid><title>河岸淡水透镜体对洪水的反应</title><description>水资源研究，接受的文章。</description><dc:description>摘要 咸水漫滩含水层中的淡水透镜体（以下简称“透镜体”）对河流洪水事件很敏感。然而，人们很少考虑大面积漫滩淹没对盐水含水层的影响，而且之前也没有在受控实验室条件下进行过研究。我们在二维（横截面）沙池（即代表咸水漫滩含水层）内进行了实验室实验，并建立了实验室和现场规模的数值模型来检查透镜对洪水事件的响应。进行了三组实验来探索漫滩淹没的不同横向范围。实验镜头的时间行为被量化，并与采用校准实验室参数的可变密度数值模型进行比较，显示出良好的一致性。结果表明，更广泛的洪泛区淹没会导致更大的透镜体（正如预期的那样）。基于野外尺度数值模型进行的敏感性分析表明，漫滩淹没范围、导水率和弥散度是控制洪水后透镜体范围和体积衰退的关键因素。在洪泛区淹没的实地模拟中，由于伴随较高地下水流速的扩散增强，整个透镜体在洪水退潮期间显着盐化，在最终恢复到稳态条件之前可能进一步分裂成几个孤立的淡水体。重要的是，现场规模的数值结果表明，在洪水事件发生后，邻近河流的盐负荷立即增加，这与墨累河（南澳大利亚）的报告一致。这些结果为洪水事件与透镜体行为之间的关系提供了重要的新见解，突出了洪水事件对咸水漫滩的中期和长期条件的重要性。</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;摘要&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;咸水漫滩含水层内的淡水透镜体（以下简称“透镜体”）对河流洪水事件很敏感。然而，人们很少考虑大面积漫滩淹没对盐水含水层的影响，而且之前也没有在受控实验室条件下进行过研究。我们在二维（横截面）沙池（即代表咸水漫滩含水层）内进行了实验室实验，并建立了实验室和野外规模的数值模型来检查透镜对洪水事件的响应。进行了三组实验来探索漫滩淹没的不同横向范围。实验镜头的时间行为被量化，并与采用校准实验室参数的可变密度数值模型进行比较，显示出良好的一致性。结果表明，更广泛的洪泛区淹没会导致更大的透镜体（正如预期的那样）。基于野外尺度数值模型进行的敏感性分析表明，漫滩淹没范围、导水率和弥散度是控制洪水后透镜体范围和体积衰退的关键因素。在洪泛区淹没的实地模拟中，整个透镜体在洪水退潮期间显着盐化，这是由于伴随着较高的地下水速度而增强的分散性，这可能会进一步分裂成几个孤立的淡水体，然后最终恢复到稳态条件。重要的是，现场规模的数值结果表明，在洪水事件发生后，邻近河流的盐负荷立即增加，这与墨累河（南澳大利亚）的报告一致。这些结果为洪水事件与透镜体行为之间的关系提供了重要的新见解，突出了洪水事件对咸水漫滩的中期和长期条件的重要性。&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> Huiqiang Wu、Amir Jazayeri、Adrian D. Werner、Hongwu Tang、Chunhui Lu</dc:creator><category>研究文章</category><dc:title>河岸淡水透镜体对洪水的反应</dc:title><dc:identifier>10.1029/2022WR033309</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname>水资源研究</prism:publicationname><prism:doi>10.1029/2022WR033309</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033309?af=R</prism:url><prism:section>研究文章</prism:section></item><item><link/>https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033939?af=R<pubDate> Mon, 20 Feb 2023 15:59:46 -0800</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-02-20T03:59:46-08:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley：水资源研究：目录<prism:coverdate></prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate></prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR033939</guid><title>城市洪水建模：不确定性量化和基于物理的高斯过程回归预测</title><description>水资源研究，接受的文章。</description><dc:description>摘要 估计洪水模型预测中的不确定性对于许多应用都很重要，包括风险评估和洪水预报。我们关注基于物理学的城市洪水模型的不确定性。我们考虑模型的复杂性和不确定性对关键输入参数的影响。还研究了降雨强度对水深预测不确定性的影响。作为一项测试研究，我们选择了明尼阿波利斯市部分地区的互连渠道和池塘路由 (ICPR) 模型。使用多级蒙特卡罗 (MC) 模拟方法，根据整体方差对 ICPR 模型预测洪水深度的不确定性进行量化。我们的结果表明，研究领域的不确定性是高度局部化的。模型简化，例如忽略地下水流，会导致过度自信的预测，即与更复杂的模型相比，预测的准确性和不确定性都较低。我们发现，对于相同数量的不确定参数，增加模型分辨率会降低模型预测的不确定性（并增加 MC 方法的计算成本）。我们采用多级 MC 方法来降低高分辨率 ICPR 模型中估计不确定性的成本。最后，我们使用基于物理的高斯过程回归方法对洪水深度的均值和协方差进行整体估计，以进行实时洪水深度预测。我们表明，即使测量很少，所提出的框架也会产生比 ICPR 模型的平均预测更准确的预测。本文受版权保护。版权所有。</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;摘要&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;估计洪水模型预测中的不确定性对于许多应用都很重要，包括风险评估和洪水预报。我们关注基于物理的城市洪水模型的不确定性。我们考虑模型的复杂性和不确定性对关键输入参数的影响。还研究了降雨强度对水深预测不确定性的影响。作为一项测试研究，我们选择了明尼阿波利斯市部分地区的互连渠道和池塘路由 (ICPR) 模型。使用多级蒙特卡罗 (MC) 模拟方法根据整体方差对 ICPR 模型预测洪水深度的不确定性进行量化。我们的结果表明，研究领域的不确定性是高度局部化的。模型简化，例如忽略地下水流，会导致过度自信的预测，即与更复杂的模型相比，预测的准确性和不确定性都较低。我们发现，对于相同数量的不确定参数，增加模型分辨率会降低模型预测的不确定性（并增加 MC 方法的计算成本）。我们采用多级 MC 方法来降低高分辨率 ICPR 模型中估计不确定性的成本。最后，我们使用基于物理的高斯过程回归方法对洪水深度的均值和协方差进行整体估计，以进行实时洪水深度预测。我们表明，即使使用很少的测量值，所提出的框架也会产生比 ICPR 模型的平均预测更准确的预测。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;本文受版权保护。保留所有权利。&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> Amir H. Kohanpur、Siddharth Saksena、Sayan Dey、J. Michael Johnson、M. Sadegh Riasi、Lilit Yeghiazarian、Alexandre M. Tartakovsky</dc:creator><category>研究文章</category><dc:title>城市洪水建模：不确定性量化和基于物理的高斯过程回归预测</dc:title><dc:identifier>10.1029/2022WR033939</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname>水资源研究</prism:publicationname><prism:doi>10.1029/2022WR033939</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033939?af=R</prism:url><prism:section>研究文章</prism:section></item><item><link/>https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033660?af=R<pubDate> Mon, 20 Feb 2023 15:58:19 -0800</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-02-20T03:58:19-08:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley：水资源研究：目录<prism:coverdate></prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate></prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR033660</guid><title>贝叶斯校准指向三维水动力油藏建模中的误解</title><description>水资源研究，接受的文章。</description><dc:description>摘要三维 (3d) 数值模型是研究水库和湖泊中复杂水动力流动模式的最新技术。这种完全复杂的模型在计算上要求很高，并且它们的校准在时间、主观决策和测量数据可用性方面具有挑战性。此外，物理上不切实际的模型假设或校准参数的组合可能仍未被发现并导致过度拟合。在这项研究中，我们研究了所谓的贝叶斯校准是否以及如何帮助表征由测量数据和校准参数组合驱动的错误模型设置。贝叶斯校准建立在机器学习的最新发展之上，并使用高斯过程仿真器作为替代模型，其运行速度比 3d 数值模型快得多。我们将抽水蓄能水库的 Delft3D-FLOW 模型作为背景水平涡流粘度和扩散系数以及初始水温剖面的函数进行贝叶斯校准。我们考虑了三种具有不同程度错误假设和不同流速和水温测量用途的场景。其中一种情景强制进行完全不切实际的快速湖泊分层，并且仍然产生与更正确的全球统计情景（例如均方根误差 (RMSE)）同样好的校准精度。贝叶斯校准产生的不确定性评估表明，完全不现实的情景通过高度不确定的混合相关模型参数迫使湖泊快速分层。因此，贝叶斯校准通过后验分布的几何特征来描述模型假设的校准质量和正确性。例如，最可能的校准参数值（后验分布最大值）处于校准范围限制或具有广泛的不确定性，表明模型假设和校准不佳。</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;摘要&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;三维 (3d) 数值模型是研究水库和湖泊中复杂水动力流动模式的最新技术。这种完全复杂的模型在计算上要求很高，并且它们的校准在时间、主观决策和测量数据可用性方面具有挑战性。此外，物理上不切实际的模型假设或校准参数的组合可能仍未被发现并导致过度拟合。在这项研究中，我们研究了所谓的贝叶斯校准是否以及如何帮助表征由测量数据和校准参数组合驱动的错误模型设置。贝叶斯校准建立在机器学习的最新发展之上，并使用高斯过程仿真器作为替代模型，其运行速度比 3d 数值模型快得多。我们将抽水蓄能水库的 Delft3D-FLOW 模型作为背景水平涡流粘度和扩散系数以及初始水温剖面的函数进行贝叶斯校准。我们考虑了三种具有不同程度错误假设和不同流速和水温测量用途的场景。其中一种情景强制进行完全不切实际的快速湖泊分层，并且仍然产生与更正确的全球统计情景（例如均方根误差 (RMSE)）同样好的校准精度。贝叶斯校准产生的不确定性评估表明，完全不切实际的情景通过高度不确定的混合相关模型参数迫使湖泊快速分层。因此，贝叶斯校准通过后验分布的几何特征来描述模型假设的校准质量和正确性。例如，最可能的校准参数值（后验分布最大值）处于校准范围极限或具有广泛的不确定性，表明模型假设和校准不佳。&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator>塞巴斯蒂安·施温特、塞尔吉奥·卡劳·梅德拉诺、基里安·穆里斯、费利克斯·贝克尔斯、斯蒂芬·豪恩、沃尔夫冈·诺瓦克、西尔克·维普雷希特、谢尔盖·奥拉迪什金</dc:creator><category>研究文章</category><dc:title>贝叶斯校准指向三维水动力油藏建模中的误解</dc:title><dc:identifier>10.1029/2022WR033660</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname>水资源研究</prism:publicationname><prism:doi>10.1029/2022WR033660</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033660?af=R</prism:url><prism:section>研究文章</prism:section></item><item><link/>https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033879?af=R<pubDate> Mon, 20 Feb 2023 13:38:10 -0800</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-02-20T01:38:10-08:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley：水资源研究：目录<prism:coverdate></prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate></prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR033879</guid><title>土壤粒径对丘-水坑型微地形粗糙度与土壤侵蚀率之间关系的影响：Hairsine-Rose 模型分析</title><description>水资源研究，接受的文章。</description><dc:description>摘要 微地形对侵蚀的影响尚不明确，过去几十年的研究结果相互矛盾，阻碍了对降雨径流引起的土壤侵蚀数量和质量的全面认识和准确预测。在这项研究中，我们在由各种大小的土丘和水坑组成的山坡上应用了动态波和 Hairsine-Rose 模型模拟器。对于沉降速度为 和降雨强度为 的被测土壤颗粒，我们发现土壤侵蚀量受微地形粗糙度的显着影响，即使在相同的降雨径流条件下也是如此。此外，我们发现土壤粒径可以潜在地决定微地形粗糙度与坡地土壤侵蚀率之间是否存在正比关系或反比关系。也就是说，当地表层由相对较小的土壤颗粒组成时，与光滑的微地形相比，粗糙的微地形加速了土壤侵蚀速率。相反，当它由大的土壤颗粒组成时，至少在测试条件下，光滑微地形上的土壤侵蚀比粗糙微地形上的土壤侵蚀增加更多。最后揭示了微观形貌尺度铠装过程的进展与微观形貌粗糙度以及晶粒尺寸密切相关。因此，为了适当考虑微地形在土壤侵蚀问题中的作用，必须从物理上考虑与装甲相关的拾取、平流和沉积过程。如果没有足够的关于这些特征的信息，预计土壤侵蚀的预测精度会很低，不仅是在数量上，而且在土壤侵蚀的质量上也是如此。本文受版权保护。版权所有。</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;摘要&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;微地形对侵蚀的影响尚不明确，过去几十年的研究结果相互矛盾，阻碍了对降雨径流引起的土壤侵蚀数量和质量的全面认识和准确预测。在这项研究中，我们在由各种大小的土丘和水坑组成的山坡上应用了动态波和 Hairsine-Rose 模型模拟器。对于沉降速度为 且降雨强度为 的被测土壤颗粒，我们发现土壤侵蚀量受微地形粗糙度的显着影响，即使在相同的降雨径流条件下也是如此。此外，我们发现土壤粒径可以潜在地决定微地形粗糙度与坡地土壤侵蚀率之间是否存在正比关系或反比关系。也就是说，当地表层由相对较小的土壤颗粒组成时，与光滑的微地形相比，粗糙的微地形加速了土壤侵蚀速率。相反，当它由大的土壤颗粒组成时，至少在测试条件下，光滑微地形上的土壤侵蚀比粗糙微地形上的土壤侵蚀增加更多。最后揭示了微观形貌尺度铠装过程的进展与微观形貌粗糙度以及晶粒尺寸密切相关。因此，为了适当考虑微地形在土壤侵蚀问题中的作用，必须从物理上考虑与装甲相关的拾取、平流和沉积过程。如果没有足够的关于这些特征的信息，预计土壤侵蚀的预测精度很低，不仅是数量，而且是质量。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;本文受版权保护。保留所有权利。&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> Soyoung Kim、Minyeob Jeong、Jongho Kim、Dae-Hong Kim</dc:creator><category>研究文章</category><dc:title>土壤粒径对丘-水坑型微地形粗糙度与土壤侵蚀率之间关系的影响：Hairsine-Rose 模型分析</dc:title><dc:identifier>10.1029/2022WR033879</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname>水资源研究</prism:publicationname><prism:doi>10.1029/2022WR033879</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033879?af=R</prism:url><prism:section>研究文章</prism:section></item><item><link/>https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR032958?af=R<pubDate> Mon, 20 Feb 2023 09:49:50 -0800</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-02-20T09:49:50-08:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley：水资源研究：目录<prism:coverdate></prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate></prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR032958</guid><title>双源能量平衡蒸散模型的两种替代方案</title><description>水资源研究，接受的文章。</description><dc:description>摘要 环境模型对其近似算法的不准确性很敏感，这可能会使模型模拟产生偏差，甚至导致错误的概念。我们提出了双源蒸散 (ET) 模型的两个替代方案，它们利用克劳修斯-克拉佩龙关系 (CCR) 的更准确近似。通过与观察到的半小时涡度协方差 (EC) 通量进行比较来评估模型性能。还评估了显热动力学和限制行为的模型表示，以确定模型不准确的原因。我们的分析表明，此处使用的新指数近似显着减少了能量平衡方程解引起的误差。在此评估的条件下，所提出的并联和串联模型都比 Shuttleworth-Wallace (SW) 模型更准确，但我们不能断定新模型在更广泛的条件下始终更准确。新模型可以正确地再现几个理论极限行为，而 SW 模型在几个重要的极限情况下产生概念上不正确的结果，在这些情况下，一些关键电导接近零和无穷大。重要的是，这些模型严重低估了夜间观察到的潜热通量；夜间模型不足的主要原因被认为是估计电导的不确定性和强迫数据错误。与新模型相关的核心概念和过程通过温度与特定湿度的关系图进行描述，以探索 ET 模型背后的理论。通过这些努力，我们预计会做出更可靠的 ET 预测，从而全面了解植被与大气的相互作用。本文受版权保护。版权所有。</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;摘要&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;环境模型对其近似算法的不准确性很敏感，这可能会使模型模拟产生偏差，甚至导致错误的概念。我们提出了双源蒸散 (ET) 模型的两个替代方案，它们利用克劳修斯-克拉佩龙关系 (CCR) 的更准确的近似值。通过与观察到的每半小时涡度协方差 (EC) 通量的比较来评估模型性能。还评估了显热动力学和限制行为的模型表示，以确定模型不准确的原因。我们的分析表明，此处使用的新指数近似显着减少了能量平衡方程解引起的误差。在此评估的条件下，所提出的并行和串行模型都比 Shuttleworth-Wallace (SW) 模型更准确，但我们不能断定新模型在更广泛的条件下始终更准确。新模型可以正确地再现几个理论极限行为，而 SW 模型在几个重要的极限情况下产生概念上不正确的结果，在这些情况下，一些关键电导接近零和无穷大。重要的是，这些模型严重低估了夜间观察到的潜热通量；夜间模型不足的主要原因被认为是估计电导的不确定性和强迫数据错误。与新模型相关的核心概念和过程通过温度与特定湿度的关系图进行描述，以探索 ET 模型背后的理论。通过这些努力，我们预计会做出更可靠的 ET 预测，从而全面了解植被与大气的相互作用。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;本文受版权保护。保留所有权利。&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator>郭晓薇、赵紫荆、田伟、邱忠琪、杨泽伟、王福兵</dc:creator><category>研究文章</category><dc:title>双源能量平衡蒸散模型的两种替代方案</dc:title><dc:identifier>10.1029/2022WR032958</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname>水资源研究</prism:publicationname><prism:doi>10.1029/2022WR032958</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR032958?af=R</prism:url><prism:section>研究文章</prism:section></item><item><link/>https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR032821?af=R<pubDate> Fri, 17 Feb 2023 08:44:48 -0800</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-02-17T08:44:48-08:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley：水资源研究：目录<prism:coverdate>Wed, 01 Feb 2023 00:00:00 -0800</prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate> Wed, 01 Feb 2023 00:00:00 -0800</prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR032821</guid><title> Toward a Catchment‐Scale Assessment of Flood Peak Attenuation by Multiple Reservoirs</title><description> Water Resources Research, Volume 59, Issue 2, February 2023.</description><dc:description> Abstract The estimation of reservoirs impact on flood peak reduction at the catchment scale is of fundamental importance for risk assessment and planning purposes. It is generally addressed using detailed hydrologic‐hydrodynamic simulations or simple, empirically based indices. The former provide detailed results, at the cost of a large amount of information and high computational efforts; the latter are cost‐effective and simple, yet they generally provide approximate results. A promising compromise between the two is the physically based attenuation index , based on the concept of equivalent reservoir; was recently proposed in the literature to estimate the impact of multiple reservoirs located in series along the main channel, based on the assumption of rectangular catchment. In this work, we extend the equivalent reservoir approach to a generic catchment, with any shape and without restrictions on the location of the reservoirs. For an effective assessment of the method, we also introduce the novel concept of Reservoir‐influenced Instantaneous Unit Hydrograph (RIUH); the RIUH can be derived using a Monte Carlo procedure to include the effects of reservoirs on the Instantaneous Unit Hydrograph. Simulations of numerous fictitious reservoir configurations in a real basin demonstrate the potential of the methods in reproducing the attenuation effect. Remarkably, an average error of 3%–5% exists between and the peak reduction of a less simplified reality (RIUH). Finally, we provide a global, catchment‐scale application of the attenuation index, which constitutes an effective tool for the evaluation of each reservoir in managed catchment system and the design or planning of new hydraulic infrastructures.</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;The estimation of reservoirs impact on flood peak reduction at the catchment scale is of fundamental importance for risk assessment and planning purposes. It is generally addressed using detailed hydrologic-hydrodynamic simulations or simple, empirically based indices. The former provide detailed results, at the cost of a large amount of information and high computational efforts; the latter are cost-effective and simple, yet they generally provide approximate results. A promising compromise between the two is the physically based attenuation index , based on the concept of equivalent reservoir; was recently proposed in the literature to estimate the impact of multiple reservoirs located in series along the main channel, based on the assumption of rectangular catchment. In this work, we extend the equivalent reservoir approach to a generic catchment, with any shape and without restrictions on the location of the reservoirs. For an effective assessment of the method, we also introduce the novel concept of Reservoir-influenced Instantaneous Unit Hydrograph (RIUH); the RIUH can be derived using a Monte Carlo procedure to include the effects of reservoirs on the Instantaneous Unit Hydrograph. Simulations of numerous fictitious reservoir configurations in a real basin demonstrate the potential of the methods in reproducing the attenuation effect. Remarkably, an average error of 3%–5% exists between and the peak reduction of a less simplified reality (RIUH). Finally, we provide a global, catchment-scale application of the attenuation index, which constitutes an effective tool for the evaluation of each reservoir in managed catchment system and the design or planning of new hydraulic infrastructures.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> S. Cipollini, E. Volpi, A. Fiori</dc:creator><category> Research Article</category><dc:title> Toward a Catchment‐Scale Assessment of Flood Peak Attenuation by Multiple Reservoirs</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2022WR032821</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1029/2022WR032821</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR032821?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> Research Article</prism:section><prism:volume> 59</prism:volume><prism:number> 2个</prism:number></item><item><link/>https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033238?af=R<pubDate> Fri, 17 Feb 2023 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-02-17T12:00:00-08:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley: Water Resources Research: Table of Contents<prism:coverdate> Wed, 01 Feb 2023 00:00:00 -0800</prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate> Wed, 01 Feb 2023 00:00:00 -0800</prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR033238</guid><title> Climate and Human Impacts on Hydrological Processes and Flood Risk in Southern Louisiana</title><description> Water Resources Research, Volume 59, Issue 2, February 2023.</description><dc:description> Abstract Satellite observations of coastal Louisiana indicate an overall land loss over recent decades, which could be attributed to climate and human‐induced factors, including sea level rise (SLR). Climate‐induced hydrological change (CHC) has impacted the way flood control structures are used, altering the spatiotemporal water distribution. Based on “what‐if” scenarios, we determine relative impacts of SLR and CHC on increased flood risk over southern Louisiana and examine the role of water management, via flood control structures, in mitigating flood risk over the region. Our findings show that CHC has increased flood risk over the past 28 years. The number of affected people increases as extreme hydrological events become more exceptional. Water management reduces flood risk to urban areas and croplands, especially during exceptional hydrological events. For example, currently (ie, 2016–2020 period), CHC‐induced flooding puts an additional 73 km2 of cropland under flood risk at least half of the time (median flood event) and 65 km2 once a year (annual flood event), when compared to a past period (1993–1997). A 10‐ to 20‐fold increase relative to SLR‐induced flooding. CHC also increases population vulnerability in southern Louisiana to flooding; additional 9,900 residents currently live under flood risk at least half of the time, and that number increases to 27,400 for annual flood events. Residents vulnerable to SLR‐induced flooding is lower (6,000 and 3,300 residents, respectively). Conclusions are that CHC is a major factor that should be accounted for flood resilience and that water management interventions can mitigate risks to human life and activities.</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;Satellite observations of coastal Louisiana indicate an overall land loss over recent decades, which could be attributed to climate and human-induced factors, including sea level rise (SLR). Climate-induced hydrological change (CHC) has impacted the way flood control structures are used, altering the spatiotemporal water distribution. Based on “what-if” scenarios, we determine relative impacts of SLR and CHC on increased flood risk over southern Louisiana and examine the role of water management, via flood control structures, in mitigating flood risk over the region. Our findings show that CHC has increased flood risk over the past 28 years. The number of affected people increases as extreme hydrological events become more exceptional. Water management reduces flood risk to urban areas and croplands, especially during exceptional hydrological events. For example, currently (ie, 2016–2020 period), CHC-induced flooding puts an additional 73 km&lt;sup>;2&lt;/sup>; of cropland under flood risk at least half of the time (median flood event) and 65 km&lt;sup>;2&lt;/sup>; once a year (annual flood event), when compared to a past period (1993–1997). A 10- to 20-fold increase relative to SLR-induced flooding. CHC also increases population vulnerability in southern Louisiana to flooding; additional 9,900 residents currently live under flood risk at least half of the time, and that number increases to 27,400 for annual flood events. Residents vulnerable to SLR-induced flooding is lower (6,000 and 3,300 residents, respectively). Conclusions are that CHC is a major factor that should be accounted for flood resilience and that water management interventions can mitigate risks to human life and activities.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> Augusto Getirana, Sujay Kumar, Goutam Konapala, Wanshu Nie, Kim Locke, Bryant Loomis, Charon Birkett, Martina Ricko, Marc Simard</dc:creator><category> Research Article</category><dc:title> Climate and Human Impacts on Hydrological Processes and Flood Risk in Southern Louisiana</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2022WR033238</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1029/2022WR033238</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033238?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> Research Article</prism:section><prism:volume> 59</prism:volume><prism:number> 2个</prism:number></item><item><link/>https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR032121?af=R<pubDate> Thu, 16 Feb 2023 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-02-16T12:00:00-08:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley: Water Resources Research: Table of Contents<prism:coverdate> Wed, 01 Feb 2023 00:00:00 -0800</prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate> Wed, 01 Feb 2023 00:00:00 -0800</prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR032121</guid><title> Fracture Intensity Impacts on Reaction Front Propagation and Mineral Weathering in Three‐Dimensional Fractured Media</title><description> Water Resources Research, Volume 59, Issue 2, February 2023.</description><dc:description> Abstract Studying reaction front propagation in heterogeneous natural settings is challenging, but numerical simulations can provide insight into the varying spatial and temporal scales of reaction front propagation. Here, the impact of increasing fracture intensity on mineral dissolution rates, and the extent of reaction front propagation is investigated using reactive transport simulations in upscaled discrete fracture network domains with varied fracture intensity. Domain‐averaged dissolution rates vary less than 0.5 log units regardless of the fracture intensity, but the spatial distribution of reactions is controlled by the location and number of dead‐end fractures and the number of connected flowpaths through the domain. Higher fracture intensities lead to more weathering in the domain because of more available mineral for water‐rock interactions. We find that reaction fronts propagate through the primary flowpaths in the first 10,000 years of the simulation for a 10‐m length domain, then propagate into secondary flowpaths and dead‐end fractures between 10,000 and 100,000 years, and finally into the matrix over timescales of hundreds of thousands of years. The domain‐averaged reaction rates decrease through time corresponding to a transition from dissolution in advection‐dominated, fast‐flowing pathways, to dissolution in transport‐limited zones of disconnected fractures and matrix. Matrix dissolution, or dissolution under transport‐limited conditions, is the dominant process at late times in these simulations. The results of these simulations recreate the observed paradox found in nature where highly fractured hillslopes tend to be more weathered but have slower weathering rates, while hillslopes with fewer fractures, are less weathered but have higher dissolution rates.</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;Studying reaction front propagation in heterogeneous natural settings is challenging, but numerical simulations can provide insight into the varying spatial and temporal scales of reaction front propagation. Here, the impact of increasing fracture intensity on mineral dissolution rates, and the extent of reaction front propagation is investigated using reactive transport simulations in upscaled discrete fracture network domains with varied fracture intensity. Domain-averaged dissolution rates vary less than 0.5 log units regardless of the fracture intensity, but the spatial distribution of reactions is controlled by the location and number of dead-end fractures and the number of connected flowpaths through the domain. Higher fracture intensities lead to more weathering in the domain because of more available mineral for water-rock interactions. We find that reaction fronts propagate through the primary flowpaths in the first 10,000 years of the simulation for a 10-m length domain, then propagate into secondary flowpaths and dead-end fractures between 10,000 and 100,000 years, and finally into the matrix over timescales of hundreds of thousands of years. The domain-averaged reaction rates decrease through time corresponding to a transition from dissolution in advection-dominated, fast-flowing pathways, to dissolution in transport-limited zones of disconnected fractures and matrix. Matrix dissolution, or dissolution under transport-limited conditions, is the dominant process at late times in these simulations. The results of these simulations recreate the observed paradox found in nature where highly fractured hillslopes tend to be more weathered but have slower weathering rates, while hillslopes with fewer fractures, are less weathered but have higher dissolution rates.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> EM Andrews, JD Hyman, MR Sweeney, S. Karra, JD Moulton, A. Navarre‐Sitchler</dc:creator><category> Research Article</category><dc:title> Fracture Intensity Impacts on Reaction Front Propagation and Mineral Weathering in Three‐Dimensional Fractured Media</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2022WR032121</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1029/2022WR032121</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR032121?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> Research Article</prism:section><prism:volume> 59</prism:volume><prism:number> 2个</prism:number></item><item><link/>https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR032328?af=R<pubDate> Thu, 16 Feb 2023 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-02-16T12:00:00-08:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley: Water Resources Research: Table of Contents <prism:coverdate></prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate></prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR032328</guid><title> Spatially explicit linkages between redox potential cycles and soil moisture fluctuations</title><description> Water Resources Research, Accepted Article.</description><dc:description> Abstract Reduction‐oxidation cycles measured through soil redox potential (Eh) are associated with dynamic soil microbial activity. Understanding changes in the composition of, and resource use by, soil microbial communities requires Eh predictability under shifting hydrologic drivers. Here, 50‐cm soil column installations are manipulated to vary hydrologic and geochemical conditions, and are extensively monitored by a dense instrumental deployment to record the depth‐time variation of physical and biogeochemical conditions. We contrast measurements of Eh, soil saturation and key compounds in water samples (probing the majority of soil microbial metabolisms) with computations of the relevant state variables, to investigate the interplay between soil moisture and redox potential dynamics. Our results highlight the importance of joint spatially resolved hydrologic flow/transport and redox processes, the worth of contrasting experiments and computations for a sufficient understanding of the Eh dynamics, and the minimum amount of biogeochemistry needed to characterize the dynamics of electron donors/acceptors that are responsible for the patterns of Eh not directly explained by physical oxic/anoxic transitions. As an example, measured concentrations of sulfate, ammonium and iron II suggest coexistence of both oxic and anoxic conditions. We find that the local saturation velocity (a threshold value of the time derivative of soil saturation) exerts a significant hysteretic control on oxygen intrusion and on the cycling of redox potentials, in contrast with approaches using a single threshold saturation level as the determinant of anoxic conditions. Our findings improve our ability to target how and where hotspots of activity develop within soil microbial communities.</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;Reduction-oxidation cycles measured through soil redox potential (&lt;i>;E&lt;/i>; &lt;sub>; &lt;i>;h&lt;/i>; &lt;/sub>;) are associated with dynamic soil microbial activity. Understanding changes in the composition of, and resource use by, soil microbial communities requires &lt;i>;E&lt;/i>; &lt;sub>; &lt;i>;h&lt;/i>; &lt;/sub>; predictability under shifting hydrologic drivers. Here, 50-cm soil column installations are manipulated to vary hydrologic and geochemical conditions, and are extensively monitored by a dense instrumental deployment to record the depth-time variation of physical and biogeochemical conditions. We contrast measurements of &lt;i>;E&lt;/i>; &lt;sub>; &lt;i>;h&lt;/i>; &lt;/sub>;, soil saturation and key compounds in water samples (probing the majority of soil microbial metabolisms) with computations of the relevant state variables, to investigate the interplay between soil moisture and redox potential dynamics. Our results highlight the importance of joint spatially resolved hydrologic flow/transport and redox processes, the worth of contrasting experiments and computations for a sufficient understanding of the &lt;i>;E&lt;/i>; &lt;sub>; &lt;i>;h&lt;/i>; &lt;/sub>; dynamics, and the minimum amount of biogeochemistry needed to characterize the dynamics of electron donors/acceptors that are responsible for the patterns of &lt;i>;E&lt;/i>; &lt;sub>; &lt;i>;h&lt;/i>; &lt;/sub>; not directly explained by physical oxic/anoxic transitions. As an example, measured concentrations of sulfate, ammonium and iron II suggest coexistence of both oxic and anoxic conditions. We find that the local saturation velocity (a threshold value of the time derivative of soil saturation) exerts a significant hysteretic control on oxygen intrusion and on the cycling of redox potentials, in contrast with approaches using a single threshold saturation level as the determinant of anoxic conditions. Our findings improve our ability to target how and where hotspots of activity develop within soil microbial communities.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> Filippo Miele, Paolo Benettin, Simiao Wang, Ivan Retti, Mitra Asadollahi, Manon Frutschi, Binayak Mohanty, Rizlan Bernier‐Latmani, Andrea Rinaldo</dc:creator><category> Research Article</category><dc:title> Spatially explicit linkages between redox potential cycles and soil moisture fluctuations</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2022WR032328</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1029/2022WR032328</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR032328?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> Research Article</prism:section></item><item><link/> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033763?af=R<pubDate> Wed, 15 Feb 2023 18:43:51 -0800</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-02-15T06:43:51-08:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley: Water Resources Research: Table of Contents <prism:coverdate></prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate></prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR033763</guid><title> Potential evaporation and the complementary relationship</title><description> Water Resources Research, Accepted Article.</description><dc:description> Abstract The complementary relationship (CR) provides a framework for estimating land surface evaporation with basic meteorological observations by acknowledging the relationship between actual evaporation, apparent potential evaporation and potential evaporation (Epo). As a key variable in the CR, Epo estimates by conventional models have a long‐standing problem in practical applications.也就是说，常规 Epo 模型中采用的气象强迫（即辐射和温度）是在通常不饱和的实际条件下观测到的。 Hence conventional Epo models do not conform to the original definition of Epo (ie, the evaporation that would occur with an unlimited water supply). Here, we estimate Epo using the maximum evaporation approach (Epo_max) that does follow the original Epo definition. We find that adopting Epo_max considerably reduces the asymmetry of the complementary relationship compared to when the conventional Priestley‐Taylor Epo is used. We then employ Epo_max and develop a new physically‐based, calibration‐free CR model, which shows an overall good performance in estimating actual evaporation in 705 catchments at the mean annual scale and 64 flux sites at monthly and mean annual scales (R2 ranges from 0.73 to 0.75 and root‐mean‐squared error ranges from 9.8 to 18.8 W m‐2). More importantly, the use of Epo_max leads to a new physical interpretation of the CR. This article is protected by copyright.版权所有。</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;The complementary relationship (CR) provides a framework for estimating land surface evaporation with basic meteorological observations by acknowledging the relationship between actual evaporation, apparent potential evaporation and potential evaporation (&lt;i>;E&lt;/i>; &lt;sub>;po&lt;/sub>;). As a key variable in the CR, &lt;i>;E&lt;/i>; &lt;sub>;po&lt;/sub>; estimates by conventional models have a long-standing problem in practical applications. That is, the meteorological forcings (ie, radiation and temperature) employed in conventional &lt;i>;E&lt;/i>; &lt;sub>;po&lt;/sub>; models are observed under actual conditions that are generally not saturated. Hence conventional &lt;i>;E&lt;/i>; &lt;sub>;po&lt;/sub>; models do not conform to the original definition of &lt;i>;E&lt;/i>; &lt;sub>;po&lt;/sub>; (ie, the evaporation that would occur with an unlimited water supply). Here, we estimate &lt;i>;E&lt;/i>; &lt;sub>;po&lt;/sub>; using the maximum evaporation approach (&lt;i>;E&lt;/i>; &lt;sub>;po_max&lt;/sub>;) that does follow the original &lt;i>;E&lt;/i>; &lt;sub>;po&lt;/sub>; definition. We find that adopting &lt;i>;E&lt;/i>; &lt;sub>;po_max&lt;/sub>; considerably reduces the asymmetry of the complementary relationship compared to when the conventional Priestley-Taylor &lt;i>;E&lt;/i>; &lt;sub>;po&lt;/sub>; is used. We then employ &lt;i>;E&lt;/i>; &lt;sub>;po_max&lt;/sub>; and develop a new physically-based, calibration-free CR model, which shows an overall good performance in estimating actual evaporation in 705 catchments at the mean annual scale and 64 flux sites at monthly and mean annual scales (&lt;i>;R&lt;/i>; &lt;sup>;2&lt;/sup>; ranges from 0.73 to 0.75 and root-mean-squared error ranges from 9.8 to 18.8 W m&lt;sup>;-2&lt;/sup>;). More importantly, the use of &lt;i>;E&lt;/i>; &lt;sub>;po_max&lt;/sub>; leads to a new physical interpretation of the CR.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This article is protected by copyright. All rights reserved.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> Zhuoyi Tu、Yuting Yang、Michael L. Roderick、Tim R. McVicar</dc:creator><category> Research Article</category><dc:title> Potential evaporation and the complementary relationship</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2022WR033763</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1029/2022WR033763</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033763?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> Research Article</prism:section></item><item><link/> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033514?af=R<pubDate> Wed, 15 Feb 2023 17:13:38 -0800</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-02-15T05:13:38-08:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley: Water Resources Research: Table of Contents <prism:coverdate></prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate></prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR033514</guid><title> Towards Large Scale Soil Moisture Monitoring using Rail‐based Cosmic Ray Neutron Sensing</title><description> Water Resources Research, Accepted Article.</description><dc:description> Abstract Cosmic ray neutron sensing (CRNS) has become a promising method for soil water content (SWC) monitoring. Stationary CRNS offers hectare‐scale average SWC measurements at fixed locations maintenance‐free and continuous in time, while car‐borne CRNS roving can reveal spatial SWC patterns at medium scales, but only on certain survey days. The novel concept of a permanent mobile CRNS system on rails promises to combine the advantages of both methods, while its technical implementation, data processing and interpretation raised a new level of complexity. This study introduced a fully automatic CRNS rail‐borne system as the first of its kind, installed within the locomotion of a cargo train. Data recorded from Sep 2021 to July 2022 along an ∼ 9 km railway segment were analyzed, as repeatedly used by the train, supported by local SWC measurements (soil samples and dielectric methods), car‐borne and stationary CRNS. The results revealed at a daily resolution consistent spatial SWC patterns and temporary variation along the track. The observed variability was mostly related to surface features, seasonal dynamics and different responses of the railway segments to wetting and drying periods, while some variations were related to measurement uncertainties. The achieved medium scale of SWC mapping could support large scale hydrological modeling and detection of environmental risks, such as droughts and wildfires. Hence, rail‐borne CRNS has the chance to become a central tool of continuous SWC monitoring for scales at ≤ 10‐km resolution, with the additional benefit of providing root‐zone soil moisture, potentially even in sub‐daily resolution. This article is protected by copyright.版权所有。</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;Cosmic ray neutron sensing (CRNS) has become a promising method for soil water content (SWC) monitoring. Stationary CRNS offers hectare-scale average SWC measurements at fixed locations maintenance-free and continuous in time, while car-borne CRNS roving can reveal spatial SWC patterns at medium scales, but only on certain survey days. The novel concept of a permanent mobile CRNS system on rails promises to combine the advantages of both methods, while its technical implementation, data processing and interpretation raised a new level of complexity. This study introduced a fully automatic CRNS rail-borne system as the first of its kind, installed within the locomotion of a cargo train. Data recorded from Sep 2021 to July 2022 along an ∼ 9 km railway segment were analyzed, as repeatedly used by the train, supported by local SWC measurements (soil samples and dielectric methods), car-borne and stationary CRNS. The results revealed at a daily resolution consistent spatial SWC patterns and temporary variation along the track. The observed variability was mostly related to surface features, seasonal dynamics and different responses of the railway segments to wetting and drying periods, while some variations were related to measurement uncertainties. The achieved medium scale of SWC mapping could support large scale hydrological modeling and detection of environmental risks, such as droughts and wildfires. Hence, rail-borne CRNS has the chance to become a central tool of continuous SWC monitoring for scales at ≤ 10-km resolution, with the additional benefit of providing root-zone soil moisture, potentially even in sub-daily resolution.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This article is protected by copyright. All rights reserved.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> Daniel Altdorff, Sascha E. Oswald, Steffen Zacharias, Carmen Zengerle, Peter Dietrich, Hannes Mollenhauer, Sabine Attinger, Martin Schrön</dc:creator><category> Research Article</category><dc:title> Towards Large Scale Soil Moisture Monitoring using Rail‐based Cosmic Ray Neutron Sensing</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2022WR033514</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1029/2022WR033514</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033514?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> Research Article</prism:section></item><item><link/> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033613?af=R<pubDate> Wed, 15 Feb 2023 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-02-15T12:00:00-08:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley: Water Resources Research: Table of Contents<prism:coverdate> Wed, 01 Feb 2023 00:00:00 -0800</prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate> Wed, 01 Feb 2023 00:00:00 -0800</prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR033613</guid><title> Solute Trapping and the Mechanisms of Non‐Fickian Transport in Partially Saturated Porous Media</title><description> Water Resources Research, Volume 59, Issue 2, February 2023.</description><dc:description> Abstract We study the upscaling of pore‐scale solute transport in partially saturated porous media at different saturation degrees. The interaction between structural heterogeneity, phases distribution and small‐scale flow dynamics induces complex flow patterns and broad probability distributions of flow, which control key aspects of transport, such as residence and arrival times, dispersion, and spatial solute distributions, as well as chemical reactions. A continuous‐time random walk (CTRW) framework that integrates the processes of advection, diffusion, and trapping in immobile zones is used to upscale and evaluate the transport of diluted solutes. Results of this model were compared to direct numerical simulations solving the advection‐diffusion equation in experimental saturation patterns. The comparison between simulations results, with different Péclet numbers (Pe), and the physics‐based upscaled CTRW approach allows for a quantitative analysis of the governing factors of transport in partially saturated porous media. This analysis shows that the fluid phase saturation decreases the advective tortuosity, the media&#39;s characteristic length, the fraction of the immobile region, and the mean trapping time. At the same time, for a given saturation degree, the normalized mean trapping time is proportional to the Pe. This suggests that the characteristic trapping length is proportional to the media&#39;s characteristic (correlation) length. Moreover, the trapping frequency decreases with increasing Pe.</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;We study the upscaling of pore-scale solute transport in partially saturated porous media at different saturation degrees. The interaction between structural heterogeneity, phases distribution and small-scale flow dynamics induces complex flow patterns and broad probability distributions of flow, which control key aspects of transport, such as residence and arrival times, dispersion, and spatial solute distributions, as well as chemical reactions. A continuous-time random walk (CTRW) framework that integrates the processes of advection, diffusion, and trapping in immobile zones is used to upscale and evaluate the transport of diluted solutes. Results of this model were compared to direct numerical simulations solving the advection-diffusion equation in experimental saturation patterns. The comparison between simulations results, with different Péclet numbers (Pe), and the physics-based upscaled CTRW approach allows for a quantitative analysis of the governing factors of transport in partially saturated porous media. This analysis shows that the fluid phase saturation decreases the advective tortuosity, the media&#39;s characteristic length, the fraction of the immobile region, and the mean trapping time. At the same time, for a given saturation degree, the normalized mean trapping time is proportional to the Pe. This suggests that the characteristic trapping length is proportional to the media&#39;s characteristic (correlation) length. Moreover, the trapping frequency decreases with increasing Pe.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> Ilan Ben‐Noah, Juan J. Hidalgo, Joaquin Jimenez‐Martinez, Marco Dentz</dc:creator><category> Research Article</category><dc:title> Solute Trapping and the Mechanisms of Non‐Fickian Transport in Partially Saturated Porous Media</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2022WR033613</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1029/2022WR033613</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033613?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> Research Article</prism:section><prism:volume> 59</prism:volume><prism:number> 2个</prism:number></item><item><link/>https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR032967?af=R<pubDate> Tue, 14 Feb 2023 16:25:28 -0800</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-02-14T04:25:28-08:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley: Water Resources Research: Table of Contents <prism:coverdate></prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate></prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR032967</guid><title> Combining remotely sensed evapotranspiration and an agroecosystem model to estimate center‐pivot irrigation water use at high spatio‐temporal resolution</title><description> Water Resources Research, Accepted Article.</description><dc:description> Abstract Estimating irrigation water use accurately is critical for sustainable irrigation and studying terrestrial water cycle in irrigated croplands. However, irrigation is not monitored in most places, and current estimations of irrigation water use has coarse spatial and/or temporal resolutions. This study aims to estimate irrigation water use at the daily and field scale through the proposed model‐data fusion framework, which is achieved by particle filtering with two configurations (concurrent, CON, and sequential, SEQ) by assimilating satellite‐based evapotranspiration (ET) observations into an advanced agroecosystem model, ecosys. Two types of experiments using synthetic and real ET observations were conducted to study the efficacy of the proposed framework for estimating irrigation water use at the irrigated fields in eastern and western Nebraska, United States. The experiments using synthetic ET observations indicated that, for two major sources of uncertainties of ET difference between observations and model simulations, which are bias and noise, noise had larger impacts on degrading the estimation performance of irrigation water use than bias. For the experiments using real ET observations, monthly and annual estimations of irrigation water use matched well with farmer irrigation records, with Pearson correlation coefficient (r) around 0.80 and 0.50, respectively. Although detecting daily irrigation records was very challenging, our method still gave a good performance with RMSE, BIAS, and r around 2.90 mm/d, 0.03 mm/d, and 0.4, respectively. Our proposed model‐data fusion framework for estimating irrigation water use at high spatio‐temporal resolution could contribute to regional water management, sustainable irrigation, and better tracking terrestrial water cycle. This article is protected by copyright.版权所有。</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;Estimating irrigation water use accurately is critical for sustainable irrigation and studying terrestrial water cycle in irrigated croplands. However, irrigation is not monitored in most places, and current estimations of irrigation water use has coarse spatial and/or temporal resolutions. This study aims to estimate irrigation water use at the daily and field scale through the proposed model-data fusion framework, which is achieved by particle filtering with two configurations (concurrent, CON, and sequential, SEQ) by assimilating satellite-based evapotranspiration (ET) observations into an advanced agroecosystem model, &lt;i>;ecosys&lt;/i>;. Two types of experiments using synthetic and real ET observations were conducted to study the efficacy of the proposed framework for estimating irrigation water use at the irrigated fields in eastern and western Nebraska, United States. The experiments using synthetic ET observations indicated that, for two major sources of uncertainties of ET difference between observations and model simulations, which are bias and noise, noise had larger impacts on degrading the estimation performance of irrigation water use than bias. For the experiments using real ET observations, monthly and annual estimations of irrigation water use matched well with farmer irrigation records, with Pearson correlation coefficient (&lt;i>;r&lt;/i>;) around 0.80 and 0.50, respectively. Although detecting daily irrigation records was very challenging, our method still gave a good performance with RMSE, BIAS, and &lt;i>;r&lt;/i>; around 2.90 mm/d, 0.03 mm/d, and 0.4, respectively. Our proposed model-data fusion framework for estimating irrigation water use at high spatio-temporal resolution could contribute to regional water management, sustainable irrigation, and better tracking terrestrial water cycle.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This article is protected by copyright. All rights reserved.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> Jingwen Zhang, Kaiyu Guan, Wang Zhou, Chongya Jiang, Bin Peng, Ming Pan, Robert F. Grant, Trenton E. Franz, Andrew Suyker, Yi Yang, Xiaohong Chen, Kairong Lin, Zewei Ma</dc:creator><category> Research Article</category><dc:title> Combining remotely sensed evapotranspiration and an agroecosystem model to estimate center‐pivot irrigation water use at high spatio‐temporal resolution</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2022WR032967</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1029/2022WR032967</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR032967?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> Research Article</prism:section></item><item><link/> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033814?af=R<pubDate> Tue, 14 Feb 2023 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-02-14T12:00:00-08:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley: Water Resources Research: Table of Contents<prism:coverdate> Wed, 01 Feb 2023 00:00:00 -0800</prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate> Wed, 01 Feb 2023 00:00:00 -0800</prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR033814</guid><title> Remotely Sensed Soil Moisture Can Capture Dynamics Relevant to Plant Water Uptake</title><description> Water Resources Research, Volume 59, Issue 2, February 2023.</description><dc:description> Abstract A frequently expressed viewpoint across the Earth science community is that global soil moisture estimates from satellite L‐band (1.4 GHz) measurements represent moisture only in a shallow surface layer (0–5 cm) and consequently are of limited value for studying global terrestrial ecosystems because plants use water from deeper rootzones. Using this argumentation, many observation‐based land surface studies avoid satellite‐observed soil moisture. Here, based on peer‐reviewed literature across several fields, we argue that such a viewpoint is overly limiting for two reasons. First, microwave soil emission depth considerations and statistical considerations of vertically correlated soil moisture information together indicate that L‐band measurements carry information about soil moisture extending below the commonly referenced 5 cm in many conditions. However, spatial variations of effective depths of representation remain uncertain. Second, in reviewing isotopic tracer field studies of plant water uptake, we find a prevalence of vegetation that primarily draws moisture from these upper soil layers. This is especially true for grasslands and croplands covering more than a third of global vegetated surfaces. Even some deeper‐rooted species (ie, shrubs and trees) preferentially or seasonally draw water from the upper soil layers. Therefore, L‐band satellite soil moisture estimates are more relevant to global vegetation water uptake than commonly appreciated (ie, relevant beyond only shallow soil processes like soil evaporation). Our commentary encourages the application of satellite soil moisture across a broader range of terrestrial hydrosphere and biosphere studies while urging more rigorous estimates of its effective depth of representation.</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;A frequently expressed viewpoint across the Earth science community is that global soil moisture estimates from satellite L-band (1.4 GHz) measurements represent moisture only in a shallow surface layer (0–5 cm) and consequently are of limited value for studying global terrestrial ecosystems because plants use water from deeper rootzones. Using this argumentation, many observation-based land surface studies avoid satellite-observed soil moisture. Here, based on peer-reviewed literature across several fields, we argue that such a viewpoint is overly limiting for two reasons. First, microwave soil emission depth considerations and statistical considerations of vertically correlated soil moisture information together indicate that L-band measurements carry information about soil moisture extending below the commonly referenced 5 cm in many conditions. However, spatial variations of effective depths of representation remain uncertain. Second, in reviewing isotopic tracer field studies of plant water uptake, we find a prevalence of vegetation that primarily draws moisture from these upper soil layers. This is especially true for grasslands and croplands covering more than a third of global vegetated surfaces. Even some deeper-rooted species (ie, shrubs and trees) preferentially or seasonally draw water from the upper soil layers. Therefore, L-band satellite soil moisture estimates are more relevant to global vegetation water uptake than commonly appreciated (ie, relevant beyond only shallow soil processes like soil evaporation). Our commentary encourages the application of satellite soil moisture across a broader range of terrestrial hydrosphere and biosphere studies while urging more rigorous estimates of its effective depth of representation.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> Andrew F. Feldman, Daniel J. Short Gianotti, Jianzhi Dong, Ruzbeh Akbar, Wade T. Crow, Kaighin A. McColl, Alexandra G. Konings, Jesse B. Nippert, Shersingh Joseph Tumber‐Dávila, Noel M. Holbrook, Fulton E. Rockwell, Russell L. Scott, Rolf H. Reichle, Abhishek Chatterjee, Joanna Joiner, Benjamin Poulter, Dara Entekhabi</dc:creator><category> Commentary</category><dc:title> Remotely Sensed Soil Moisture Can Capture Dynamics Relevant to Plant Water Uptake</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2022WR033814</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1029/2022WR033814</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033814?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> Commentary</prism:section><prism:volume> 59</prism:volume><prism:number> 2个</prism:number></item><item><link/>https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2021WR031845?af=R<pubDate> Tue, 14 Feb 2023 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-02-14T12:00:00-08:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley: Water Resources Research: Table of Contents<prism:coverdate> Wed, 01 Feb 2023 00:00:00 -0800</prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate> Wed, 01 Feb 2023 00:00:00 -0800</prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2021WR031845</guid><title> Symptoms of Performance Degradation During Multi‐Annual Drought: A Large‐Sample, Multi‐Model Study</title><description> Water Resources Research, Volume 59, Issue 2, February 2023.</description><dc:description> Abstract Hydrologic models are essential tools to understand and plan for the effect of changing climates; however, they underperform in transitory climate conditions. Existing research identifies models&#39; inadequacy to perform during prolonged drought, but falls short on pinpointing which specific aspects of model performance are affected. We study five conceptual rainfall‐runoff models and their performance in 155 Australian catchments which recently experienced a 13‐year long drought. We use a wide range of performance metrics and a methodology based on ranked differences to a benchmark to fairly compare levels of degradation across metrics and periods. We show model performance degrading extensively during and after the drought, largely driven by overestimation of flow. Representation of shape and variability of hydrograph and flow‐duration curve are more resilient to the prolonged dry climate and rarely more degraded during the multi‐annual drought that on isolated dry years in the pre‐drought record. Conversely, volumetric error suffers from significant exacerbation over the multiple subsequent dry years. This indicates that catchment retention times and rates of storage depletion storage are significantly less affected by the drought than amounts of streamflow produced, pointing to a mismatch between reduction of influxes and out‐fluxes during the drought. We also identify a deficiency of models to delay and remove flow before it reaches the stream and keep track of moisture deficits over multiple dry seasons. By promoting rigorous investigation of models&#39; shortcomings, we hope to foster the development of more robust model structures and/or calibration frameworks to improve applicability within climate change scenarios.</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;Hydrologic models are essential tools to understand and plan for the effect of changing climates; however, they underperform in transitory climate conditions. Existing research identifies models&#39; inadequacy to perform during prolonged drought, but falls short on pinpointing which specific aspects of model performance are affected. We study five conceptual rainfall-runoff models and their performance in 155 Australian catchments which recently experienced a 13-year long drought. We use a wide range of performance metrics and a methodology based on ranked differences to a benchmark to fairly compare levels of degradation across metrics and periods. We show model performance degrading extensively during and after the drought, largely driven by overestimation of flow. Representation of shape and variability of hydrograph and flow-duration curve are more resilient to the prolonged dry climate and rarely more degraded during the multi-annual drought that on isolated dry years in the pre-drought record. Conversely, volumetric error suffers from significant exacerbation over the multiple subsequent dry years. This indicates that catchment retention times and rates of storage depletion storage are significantly less affected by the drought than amounts of streamflow produced, pointing to a mismatch between reduction of influxes and out-fluxes during the drought. We also identify a deficiency of models to delay and remove flow before it reaches the stream and keep track of moisture deficits over multiple dry seasons. By promoting rigorous investigation of models&#39; shortcomings, we hope to foster the development of more robust model structures and/or calibration frameworks to improve applicability within climate change scenarios.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> Luca Trotter, Margarita Saft, Murray C. Peel, Keirnan JA Fowler</dc:creator><category> Research Article</category><dc:title> Symptoms of Performance Degradation During Multi‐Annual Drought: A Large‐Sample, Multi‐Model Study</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2021WR031845</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1029/2021WR031845</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2021WR031845?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> Research Article</prism:section><prism:volume> 59</prism:volume><prism:number> 2个</prism:number></item><item><link/>https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033443?af=R<pubDate> Tue, 14 Feb 2023 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-02-14T12:00:00-08:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley: Water Resources Research: Table of Contents<prism:coverdate> Wed, 01 Feb 2023 00:00:00 -0800</prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate> Wed, 01 Feb 2023 00:00:00 -0800</prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR033443</guid><title> Self‐Regulation Mechanisms in Porous Media: The Origin of the Diversity of Fluid Displacement Patterns</title><description> Water Resources Research, Volume 59, Issue 2, February 2023.</description><dc:description> Abstract During two‐phase fluid displacement in a porous medium, self‐regulation mechanisms provide negative feedback to approach a state of minimum operating power. The versatility of these self‐regulation mechanisms results in a large diversity of fluid displacement patterns. For example, the introduction of a highly tortuous displacement channel, the appearance of the retention and development regions of the displaced phase, and the expansion of the displacement path area of the invading phase are the macroscopic responses of the two‐phase flow system to the self‐regulation mechanisms under different constraints. These new findings provide compelling physical explanations for the underlying mechanisms governing fluid displacement pattern transitions and the influence of inertial effects on the displacement patterns.</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;During two-phase fluid displacement in a porous medium, self-regulation mechanisms provide negative feedback to approach a state of minimum operating power. The versatility of these self-regulation mechanisms results in a large diversity of fluid displacement patterns. For example, the introduction of a highly tortuous displacement channel, the appearance of the retention and development regions of the displaced phase, and the expansion of the displacement path area of the invading phase are the macroscopic responses of the two-phase flow system to the self-regulation mechanisms under different constraints. These new findings provide compelling physical explanations for the underlying mechanisms governing fluid displacement pattern transitions and the influence of inertial effects on the displacement patterns.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> Xiaokang Guo, Runcong Liu, Xiaodong Wang</dc:creator><category> Research Article</category><dc:title> Self‐Regulation Mechanisms in Porous Media: The Origin of the Diversity of Fluid Displacement Patterns</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2022WR033443</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1029/2022WR033443</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033443?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> Research Article</prism:section><prism:volume> 59</prism:volume><prism:number> 2个</prism:number></item><item><link/>https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR032484?af=R<pubDate> Tue, 14 Feb 2023 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-02-14T12:00:00-08:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley: Water Resources Research: Table of Contents<prism:coverdate> Wed, 01 Feb 2023 00:00:00 -0800</prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate> Wed, 01 Feb 2023 00:00:00 -0800</prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR032484</guid><title> Hydrological Model Adaptability to Rainfall Inputs of Varied Quality</title><description> Water Resources Research, Volume 59, Issue 2, February 2023.</description><dc:description> Abstract Numerous studies have evaluated the reliability and hydrologic utility of various rainfall data sets through hydrological modeling. However, the calibration of hydrological models compensates for errors in rainfall inputs. The drivers, conditions, and factors affecting the calibration of hydrological models given the accuracy of rainfall inputs are not well understood. Here, we explore hydrological model adaptability to rainfall inputs of varied quality and its potential mechanisms. Twenty‐eight rainfall products from multiple sources are collected for a headwater catchment in the Southern United States. These rainfall data sets include measurements from rain gauges, weather radars, satellites, reanalysis products, and Weather Research and Forecasting model simulations. Such rainfall data sets with varied errors are used to independently calibrate a widely used conceptual Xin&#39;anjiang (XAJ) hydrological model. Results suggest that the hydrological model can often adapt well to two scenarios of inaccurate rainfall inputs producing high‐performance streamflow simulations. This adaptive ability is controlled by an adaptable threshold of the overall bias of the rainfall inputs. Moreover, hydrological model adaptability to rainfall inputs is further influenced by how event‐based rainfall bias shapes the overall rainfall bias, especially from those of heavy rainstorms. The hydrological model can adapt to those rainfall inputs that contain important information content for model calibration. Notably, the adaptability to rainfall inputs of the XAJ model is mainly controlled by a bias reduction through adjustment of evapotranspiration and soil moisture storage, yielding satisfactory effective rainfall. The study quantitatively sheds new light on hydrological model adaptability to rainfall input quality.</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;Numerous studies have evaluated the reliability and hydrologic utility of various rainfall data sets through hydrological modeling. However, the calibration of hydrological models compensates for errors in rainfall inputs. The drivers, conditions, and factors affecting the calibration of hydrological models given the accuracy of rainfall inputs are not well understood. Here, we explore hydrological model adaptability to rainfall inputs of varied quality and its potential mechanisms. Twenty-eight rainfall products from multiple sources are collected for a headwater catchment in the Southern United States. These rainfall data sets include measurements from rain gauges, weather radars, satellites, reanalysis products, and Weather Research and Forecasting model simulations. Such rainfall data sets with varied errors are used to independently calibrate a widely used conceptual Xin&#39;anjiang (XAJ) hydrological model. Results suggest that the hydrological model can often adapt well to two scenarios of inaccurate rainfall inputs producing high-performance streamflow simulations. This adaptive ability is controlled by an adaptable threshold of the overall bias of the rainfall inputs. Moreover, hydrological model adaptability to rainfall inputs is further influenced by how event-based rainfall bias shapes the overall rainfall bias, especially from those of heavy rainstorms. The hydrological model can adapt to those rainfall inputs that contain important information content for model calibration. Notably, the adaptability to rainfall inputs of the XAJ model is mainly controlled by a bias reduction through adjustment of evapotranspiration and soil moisture storage, yielding satisfactory effective rainfall. The study quantitatively sheds new light on hydrological model adaptability to rainfall input quality.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> Jiao Wang, Lu Zhuo, Dawei Han, Ying Liu, Miguel Angel Rico‐Ramirez</dc:creator><category> Research Article</category><dc:title> Hydrological Model Adaptability to Rainfall Inputs of Varied Quality</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2022WR032484</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1029/2022WR032484</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR032484?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> Research Article</prism:section><prism:volume> 59</prism:volume><prism:number> 2个</prism:number></item><item><link/>https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033895?af=R<pubDate> Mon, 13 Feb 2023 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-02-13T12:00:00-08:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley: Water Resources Research: Table of Contents<prism:coverdate> Wed, 01 Feb 2023 00:00:00 -0800</prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate> Wed, 01 Feb 2023 00:00:00 -0800</prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR033895</guid><title> Time Domain Reflectometry Waveform Interpretation With Convolutional Neural Networks</title><description> Water Resources Research, Volume 59, Issue 2, February 2023.</description><dc:description> Abstract Interpreting time domain reflectometry (TDR) waveforms obtained in soils with non‐uniform water content is an open question. We design a new TDR waveform interpretation model based on convolutional neural networks (CNNs) that can reveal the spatial variations of soil relative permittivity and water content along a TDR sensor. The proposed model, namely TDR‐CNN, is constructed with three modules. First, the geometrical features of the TDR waveforms are extracted with a simplified version of VGG16 network. Second, the reflection positions in a TDR waveform are traced using a 1D version of the region proposal network. Finally, the soil relative permittivity values are estimated via a CNN regression network. The three modules are developed in Python using Google TensorFlow and Keras API, and then stacked together to formulate the TDR‐CNN architecture. Each module is trained separately, and data transfer among the modules can be facilitated automatically. TDR‐CNN is evaluated using simulated TDR waveforms with varying relative permittivity but under a relatively stable soil electrical conductivity, and the accuracy and stability of the TDR‐CNN are shown. TDR measurements from a water infiltration study provide an application for TDR‐CNN and a comparison between TDR‐CNN and an inverse model. The proposed TDR‐CNN model is simple to implement, and modules in TDR‐CNN can be updated or fine‐tuned individually with new data sets. In conclusion, TDR‐CNN presents a model architecture that can be used to interpret TDR waveforms obtained in soil with a heterogeneous water content distribution.</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;Interpreting time domain reflectometry (TDR) waveforms obtained in soils with non-uniform water content is an open question. We design a new TDR waveform interpretation model based on convolutional neural networks (CNNs) that can reveal the spatial variations of soil relative permittivity and water content along a TDR sensor. The proposed model, namely TDR-CNN, is constructed with three modules. First, the geometrical features of the TDR waveforms are extracted with a simplified version of VGG16 network. Second, the reflection positions in a TDR waveform are traced using a 1D version of the region proposal network. Finally, the soil relative permittivity values are estimated via a CNN regression network. The three modules are developed in Python using Google TensorFlow and Keras API, and then stacked together to formulate the TDR-CNN architecture. Each module is trained separately, and data transfer among the modules can be facilitated automatically. TDR-CNN is evaluated using simulated TDR waveforms with varying relative permittivity but under a relatively stable soil electrical conductivity, and the accuracy and stability of the TDR-CNN are shown. TDR measurements from a water infiltration study provide an application for TDR-CNN and a comparison between TDR-CNN and an inverse model. The proposed TDR-CNN model is simple to implement, and modules in TDR-CNN can be updated or fine-tuned individually with new data sets. In conclusion, TDR-CNN presents a model architecture that can be used to interpret TDR waveforms obtained in soil with a heterogeneous water content distribution.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> Zhuangji Wang, Shan Hua, Dennis Timlin, Yuki Kojima, Songtao Lu, Wenguang Sun, David Fleisher, Robert Horton, Vangimalla R. Reddy, Katherine Tully</dc:creator><category> Research Article</category><dc:title> Time Domain Reflectometry Waveform Interpretation With Convolutional Neural Networks</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2022WR033895</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1029/2022WR033895</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033895?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> Research Article</prism:section><prism:volume> 59</prism:volume><prism:number> 2个</prism:number></item><item><link/>https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR032475?af=R<pubDate> Sat, 11 Feb 2023 02:10:15 -0800</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-02-11T02:10:15-08:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley: Water Resources Research: Table of Contents <prism:coverdate></prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate></prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR032475</guid><title> Improved calculation of hydraulic conductivity for small‐disk tension infiltrometers</title><description> Water Resources Research, Accepted Article.</description><dc:description> Abstract Because tension infiltrometers apply water through a disk of finite size, the infiltrated water moves laterally as well as downward. Only the vertical component of this flow is indicative of the hydraulic conductivity K, so the algorithm for computing K must include a way of isolating that component from the total flow. Some commonly used formulas correct for the multidimensional effects by subtracting an estimate of the laterally spreading flow. For disks smaller than about 200 mm in diameter, however, lateral spreading constitutes so much of the total flow that these subtractive formulas lose considerable accuracy, and sometimes overcorrect so severely as to produce a negative number for K. Other methods rely on empiricisms that are not completely consistent with unsaturated flow theory and that require prior knowledge of certain soil properties. We developed a new formula that uses a multiplicative factor instead of a subtracted term to achieve the needed correction. For testing we conducted numerical experiments with synthetic data produced by solving the Richardson‐Richards equation using the code VS2DRTI, for diverse media and a range of disk sizes, including the widely used 45‐mm diameter. We compared K values calculated from our formula to the actual K used to generate the simulated data, as well as to results from other published formulas. This comparison shows that our method provides an algorithm based in unsaturated‐flow theory that produces more reliable values for small disks without requiring prior knowledge of soil properties.</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;Because tension infiltrometers apply water through a disk of finite size, the infiltrated water moves laterally as well as downward. Only the vertical component of this flow is indicative of the hydraulic conductivity &lt;i>;K&lt;/i>;, so the algorithm for computing &lt;i>;K&lt;/i>; must include a way of isolating that component from the total flow. Some commonly used formulas correct for the multidimensional effects by subtracting an estimate of the laterally spreading flow. For disks smaller than about 200 mm in diameter, however, lateral spreading constitutes so much of the total flow that these subtractive formulas lose considerable accuracy, and sometimes overcorrect so severely as to produce a negative number for &lt;i>;K&lt;/i>;. Other methods rely on empiricisms that are not completely consistent with unsaturated flow theory and that require prior knowledge of certain soil properties. We developed a new formula that uses a multiplicative factor instead of a subtracted term to achieve the needed correction. For testing we conducted numerical experiments with synthetic data produced by solving the Richardson-Richards equation using the code VS2DRTI, for diverse media and a range of disk sizes, including the widely used 45-mm diameter. We compared &lt;i>;K&lt;/i>; values calculated from our formula to the actual &lt;i>;K&lt;/i>; used to generate the simulated data, as well as to results from other published formulas. This comparison shows that our method provides an algorithm based in unsaturated-flow theory that produces more reliable values for small disks without requiring prior knowledge of soil properties.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> John R. Nimmo, Paige R. Voss</dc:creator><category> Research Article</category><dc:title> Improved calculation of hydraulic conductivity for small‐disk tension infiltrometers</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2022WR032475</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1029/2022WR032475</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR032475?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> Research Article</prism:section></item></channel></rss>