<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:prism="http://prismstandard.org/namespaces/basic/2.0/"><channel><title> Wiley：水资源研究：目录</title><link/>https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R<description>水资源研究目录。最新期和 EarlyView 期的文章列表。</description><language> en-US</language><copyright></copyright><managingeditor> wileyonlinelibrary@wiley.com（AGU 出版物）</managingeditor><pubDate> Sat, 19 Aug 2023 08:14:04 +0000</pubDate><lastbuilddate> 2023 年 8 月 19 日星期六 08:14:04 +0000</lastbuilddate><generator> Atypon®文学™</generator><docs> https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs><ttl> 10080</ttl><dc:title> Wiley：水资源研究：目录</dc:title><dc:publisher>威利</dc:publisher><prism:publicationname>水资源研究</prism:publicationname><atom:link href="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"></atom:link><image/><title> Wiley：水资源研究：目录</title><url>https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/pb-assets/journal-banners/19447973.jpg</url><link/> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R<item><link/> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2023WR034686?af=R<pubDate> Fri, 18 Aug 2023 09:15:51 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-08-18T09:15:51-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley：水资源研究：目录<prism:coverdate>2023 年 8 月 1 日，星期二 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate> 2023 年 8 月 1 日，星期二 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2023WR034686</guid><title>多物理问题中状态相关磁导率的数值处理</title><description>《水资源研究》，第 59 卷，第 8 期，2023 年 8 月。</description><dc:description>摘要 以非线性方式关联流体势和通量的本构定律在多种多孔介质应用中很常见，包括生物和反应流、孔隙力学和裂缝变形。与标准的线性达西定律相比，这种增强的通量关系不仅增加了非线性程度，而且在多物理场模拟的情况下，还增加了过程之间的耦合强度。因此，虽然将非线性纳入仿真模型对于计算效率至关重要，但从实际角度来看，纳入牛顿方法所需的正确线性化具有挑战性。因此，标准方法是在线性化过程中忽略磁导率的非线性。对于多孔介质应用中流行的有限体积方法，完全线性化仅适用于最简单的通量离散化，即两点通量近似。我们引入了一种有限体积方法的近似线性化方案，该方案对于两点方案来说是精确的，并且可以应用于更先进和更精确的离散化，这里以多点通量模板为例。我们测试了非线性多孔介质流和多个多物理场模拟的新方法。我们的结果表明，新的线性化始终优于标准方法。此外，与标准方法获得的线性收敛相比，我们的方案实现了牛顿迭代的渐近二阶收敛。</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;摘要&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;以非线性方式关联流体势和通量的本构定律在多种多孔介质应用中很常见，包括生物和反应流、孔隙力学和裂缝变形。与标准的线性达西定律相比，这种增强的通量关系不仅增加了非线性程度，而且在多物理场模拟的情况下，还增加了过程之间的耦合强度。因此，虽然将非线性纳入仿真模型对于计算效率至关重要，但从实际角度来看，纳入牛顿方法所需的正确线性化具有挑战性。因此，标准方法是在线性化过程中忽略磁导率的非线性。对于多孔介质应用中流行的有限体积方法，完全线性化仅适用于最简单的通量离散化，即两点通量近似。我们引入了一种用于有限体积方法的近似线性化方案，该方案对于两点方案来说是精确的，并且可以应用于更先进和更精确的离散化，本文以多点通量模板为例。我们测试了非线性多孔介质流和多个多物理场模拟的新方法。我们的结果表明，新的线性化始终优于标准方法。此外，与标准方法获得的线性收敛相比，我们的方案实现了牛顿迭代的渐近二阶收敛。&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator>伊瓦尔·史蒂芬森、埃里克·凯勒加夫伦</dc:creator><category>研究文章</category><dc:title>多物理问题中状态相关磁导率的数值处理</dc:title><dc:identifier>10.1029/2023WR034686</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname>水资源研究</prism:publicationname><prism:doi>10.1029/2023WR034686</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2023WR034686?af=R</prism:url><prism:section>研究文章</prism:section><prism:volume>59</prism:volume><prism:number> 8</prism:number></item><item><link/> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR034399?af=R<pubDate> Fri, 18 Aug 2023 08:12:18 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-08-18T08:12:18-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley：水资源研究：目录<prism:coverdate>2023 年 8 月 1 日，星期二 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate> 2023 年 8 月 1 日，星期二 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR034399</guid><title>水文驱动下的漫滩湿地草食性水鸟栖息地时空演化</title><description>《水资源研究》，第 59 卷，第 8 期，2023 年 8 月。</description><dc:description>摘要 受自然气候变率和人类活动影响的漫滩湿地水文节律是影响草食雁栖息地分布的驱动因素。由于缺乏物种分布和广泛湿地观测的数据，确定其长期变化一直具有挑战性。本研究通过结合GPS跟踪数据和Landsat卫星数据，发现了适合草食鹅、大白额雁（GWG）和豆雁（BG）的关键归一化差异植被指数阈值范围。基于阈值范围提取1982-2020年GWG和BG的适宜栖息面积和分布变化特征。结果表明，2003年以后适宜栖息地面积呈下降趋势，分布向湖心方向移动，平均海拔降低了1 m左右，特别是在到达期。草食雁栖息地的变化是鄱阳湖持续干涸造成的。该研究可为湿地水鸟保护和流域水文管理提供合理的科学依据。</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;摘要&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;受自然气候变率和人类活动影响的漫滩湿地水文节律是影响草食雁栖息地分布的驱动因素。由于缺乏物种分布和广泛湿地观测的数据，确定其长期变化一直具有挑战性。本研究确定了适合草食鹅、大白额雁(&lt;i>;Anser albifrons&lt;/i>;, GWG)和豆雁(&lt;i>;Anser fabalis&lt;/i>;, BG)的关键归一化植被指数阈值范围），是通过将 GPS 跟踪数据与 Landsat 卫星数据相结合而发现的。基于阈值范围提取1982-2020年GWG和BG的适宜栖息面积和分布变化特征。结果表明，2003年以后适宜栖息地面积呈下降趋势，分布向湖心方向移动，平均海拔降低了1 m左右，特别是在到达期。草食雁栖息地的变化是鄱阳湖持续干涸造成的。该研究可为湿地水鸟保护和流域水文管理提供合理的科学依据。&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator>滕家琨、夏少霞、段厚朗、刘宇、余秀波、杨文娟</dc:creator><category>研究文章</category><dc:title>水文驱动下的漫滩湿地草食性水鸟栖息地时空演化</dc:title><dc:identifier>10.1029/2022WR034399</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname>水资源研究</prism:publicationname><prism:doi>10.1029/2022WR034399</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR034399?af=R</prism:url><prism:section>研究文章</prism:section><prism:volume>59</prism:volume><prism:number> 8</prism:number></item><item><link/> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR034166?af=R<pubDate> Fri, 18 Aug 2023 05:37:29 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-08-18T05:37:29-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley：水资源研究：目录<prism:coverdate></prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate></prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR034166</guid><title> CMIP6 HighResMIP 对爱荷华州年最大流量水文模型的评估</title><description>水资源研究，已接受文章。</description><dc:description>摘要 耦合模式比对第 6 阶段 (CMIP6) 的高分辨率模式比对项目 (HighResMIP) 实验代表了为提高气候模式的分辨率和性能所做的广泛努力。 HighResMIP 套件提供高空间分辨率（即 25 公里和 50 公里）强迫，已被证明可以改善气候过程的表示。然而，人们对其水文应用的适用性知之甚少。我们使用 HighResMIP 套件的输出，通过 Hillslope-Link 模型 (HLM) 模拟爱荷华州约 1000 个河流社区的年度最大流量。首先，我们评估气候模型的径流是否可以直接通过 HLM 中的河网模型来估计年度最大流量。基于径流的模拟可以捕获评估的十个模型/成员中的五个洪水峰值的经验分布。接下来，我们使用 HighResMIP 模型中的降水量、温度和潜在蒸散量强制 HLM 来模拟洪峰，发现所有模型/成员都产生与我们的参考类似的经验分布。然而，模型/构件强迫中存在显着偏差，因为正确的洪水响应是由于错误的原因而生成的。为了提高其对社区级评估的适用性，我们使用九种统计方法来校正偏差并将 HighResMIP 降水量缩小到 4 公里分辨率。气候模型降水的偏差校正和降尺度对于所有模型/成员都表现良好。此外，我们没有发现基于 HighResMIP 输出强制的 HLM 或基于路由径流的爱荷华州洪水峰值预测发生显着变化，但有迹象表明全州洪水峰值的变化预计会增加。本文受版权保护。版权所有。</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;摘要&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;耦合模型比对第 6 阶段 (CMIP6) 的高分辨率模型比对项目 (HighResMIP) 实验代表了为提高气候模型的分辨率和性能所做的广泛努力。 HighResMIP 套件提供高空间分辨率（即 25 公里和 50 公里）强迫，已被证明可以改善气候过程的表示。然而，人们对其水文应用的适用性知之甚少。我们使用 HighResMIP 套件的输出，通过 Hillslope-Link 模型 (HLM) 模拟爱荷华州约 1000 个河流社区的年度最大流量。首先，我们评估气候模型的径流是否可以直接通过 HLM 中的河网模型来估计年度最大流量。基于径流的模拟可以捕获所评估的十个模型/成员中的五个洪水峰值的经验分布。接下来，我们使用 HighResMIP 模型中的降水量、温度和潜在蒸散量强制 HLM 来模拟洪峰，发现所有模型/成员都产生与我们的参考类似的经验分布。然而，模型/构件强迫中存在显着偏差，因为正确的洪水响应是由于错误的原因而生成的。为了提高其对社区级评估的适用性，我们使用九种统计方法来校正偏差并将 HighResMIP 降水缩小到 4 公里分辨率。气候模型降水的偏差校正和降尺度对于所有模型/成员都表现良好。此外，我们没有发现基于 HighResMIP 输出强制的 HLM 或基于路由径流的爱荷华州洪水峰值预测发生显着变化，但有迹象表明全州洪水峰值的变异性预计会增加。&lt; /p>; &lt;p>;本文受版权保护。保留所有权利。&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> Alexander T. Michalek、Gabriele Villarini、Taereem Kim、Felipe Quintero、Witold F. Krajewski、Enrico Scoccimarro</dc:creator><category>研究文章</category><dc:title>CMIP6 HighResMIP 对爱荷华州年最大流量水文模型的评估</dc:title><dc:identifier>10.1029/2022WR034166</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname>水资源研究</prism:publicationname><prism:doi>10.1029/2022WR034166</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR034166?af=R</prism:url><prism:section>研究文章</prism:section></item><item><link/>https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2023WR034466?af=R<pubDate> Thu, 17 Aug 2023 04:17:04 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-08-17T04:17:04-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley：水资源研究：目录<prism:coverdate></prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate></prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2023WR034466</guid><title>评估城市洪水对气候变化响应的综合框架</title><description>水资源研究，已接受文章。</description><dc:description>摘要 近几十年来，极端降雨引发的灾难性城市洪水事件的频率不断增加，需要积极主动地评估洪水风险和脆弱性。在这里，我们开发了一个综合框架，用于对城市洪水对历史和未来预计的极端降水变化的响应进行精细时空尺度评估。该框架包括三个主要组成部分——历史极端降水的非平稳建模、未来降水建模和城市洪水模拟。它还通过统计模型、多种气候模型和随机不确定性提供了对设计降水不确定性的可靠估计，并使用机器学习技术进行估计。我们展示了美国德克萨斯州休斯顿白橡树河口流域的拟议框架。二维水文-水力互联河道和池塘选线（ICPR）模型用于模拟三个（SSP1-2.5）历史时期（1986-2020）和两个未来时期（2021-2050和2071-2100）设计降水量的洪水响应、SSP2-4.5 和 SSP5-8.5）未来气候情景。结果表明，历史降水量的非平稳设计估计值比 1 小时至 24 小时持续时间的 100 年事件的平稳估计值高 14-25%。与全球总体趋势相反，我们发现在所有三种排放情景中，未来设计降水量均显着减少。此外，未来设计降水的随机不确定性大于历史估计中的建模不确定性和未来估计中的气候模型不确定性。洪水峰值和总洪水量方面的洪水响应表明，固定与非固定历史和未来设计降水量之间的差异很大，会导致模拟洪水发生相当大的变化。</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;近几十年来，极端降雨引发的灾难性城市洪水事件的频率不断增加，需要积极主动地评估洪水风险和脆弱性。在这里，我们开发了一个综合框架，用于对城市洪水对历史和未来预计的极端降水变化的响应进行精细时空尺度评估。该框架包括三个主要组成部分——历史极端降水的非平稳建模、未来降水建模和城市洪水模拟。它还通过统计模型、多种气候模型和随机不确定性提供了对设计降水不确定性的可靠估计，并使用机器学习技术进行估计。我们展示了美国德克萨斯州休斯顿白橡树河口流域的拟议框架。二维水文-水力互联河道和池塘选线 (ICPR) 模型用于模拟三个 (SSP1-2.5) 历史时期 (1986-2020) 和未来两个时期 (2021-2050 和 2071-2100) 设计降水量的洪水响应、SSP2-4.5 和 SSP5-8.5）未来气候情景。结果表明，历史降水量的非平稳设计估计值比持续时间为 1 小时至 24 小时的 100 年事件的平稳估计值高 14-25%。与全球总体趋势相反，我们发现在所有三种排放情景中，未来设计降水量均显着减少。此外，未来设计降水的随机不确定性大于历史估计中的建模不确定性和未来估计中的气候模型不确定性。洪峰和总洪水量方面的洪水响应表明，稳态与非稳态历史和未来设计降水量之间的差异很大，会导致模拟洪水发生相当大的变化。&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator>拉利特·帕尔、Siddharth Saksena、Sayan Dey、Venkatesh Merwade、Chandra Shekhar Prasad Ojha</dc:creator><category>研究文章</category><dc:title>评估城市洪水对气候变化响应的综合框架</dc:title><dc:identifier>10.1029/2023WR034466</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname>水资源研究</prism:publicationname><prism:doi>10.1029/2023WR034466</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2023WR034466?af=R</prism:url><prism:section>研究文章</prism:section></item><item><link/>https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR034169?af=R<pubDate> Wed, 16 Aug 2023 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-08-16T12:00:00-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley：水资源研究：目录<prism:coverdate></prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate></prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR034169</guid><title>利用多光谱卫星图像绘制地表水存在情况和源头水流网络的潜流特性</title><description>水资源研究，已接受文章。</description><dc:description>摘要 源头河流网络的增长和收缩决定了栖息地的范围，并打开了通往潜流带的窗口。一个基本的挑战是对过程本身的观察：湿润河道的范围在空间和时间上是动态的，在源头集水区的单个风暴事件过程中，湿润河道的长度会发生数量级的变化。迄今为止，观测数据集是通过实地活动、无人机成像或流量存在传感器生成的，这些数据通常很费力，并且在空间和时间范围上受到限制。在这里，我们评估卫星图像作为一种通过对湿河道范围进行局部调查训练的机器学习方法来检测湿河道范围的手段。即使通道特征小于图像的空间分辨率，地表水的存在也可能会被印在单个像素的光谱特征上。对于加利福尼亚州北部两个流域，河岸冠层覆盖度最小且湿河道范围高度动态，我们在与现有调查同时捕获的 RapidEye 图像上训练随机森林模型，以预测湿河道范围（准确度 >; 91%）。该模型用于产生长度-流量（L-Q）关系并计算渠道潜流流量和交换的空间分布估计。从主干通道到低阶支流，潜流流量急剧中断，导致传统使用的幂律模型无法捕获阶梯式 L-Q 关系。遥感图像是以高空间分辨率绘制湿河道地图的强大工具。</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;摘要&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;源头河流网络的增长和收缩决定了栖息地范围，并打开了通往潜流带的窗口。一个基本的挑战是对过程本身的观察：湿润河道的范围在空间和时间上是动态的，在源头集水区的单个风暴事件过程中，湿润河道的长度会发生数量级的变化。迄今为止，观测数据集是通过实地活动、无人机成像或流量存在传感器生成的，这些数据通常很费力，并且在空间和时间范围上受到限制。在这里，我们评估卫星图像作为一种通过对湿河道范围进行局部调查训练的机器学习方法来检测湿河道范围的手段。即使通道特征小于图像的空间分辨率，地表水的存在也可能会被印在单个像素的光谱特征上。对于加利福尼亚州北部两个流域，河岸冠层覆盖度最小，湿河道范围高度动态，我们在与现有调查同时捕获的 RapidEye 图像上训练随机森林模型，以预测湿河道范围（准确度 >; 91%）。该模型用于产生长度-流量 (LQ) 关系并计算渠道潜流流量和交换的空间分布估计。从主干道到低阶支流，潜流流量急剧中断，导致传统使用的幂律模型无法捕获阶梯式 LQ 关系。遥感影像是以高空间分辨率绘制湿河道地图的强大工具。&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> DN Dralle、DA Lapides、DM Rempe、WJ Hahm</dc:creator><category>研究文章</category><dc:title>利用多光谱卫星图像绘制地表水存在情况和源头水流网络的潜流特性</dc:title><dc:identifier>10.1029/2022WR034169</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname>水资源研究</prism:publicationname><prism:doi>10.1029/2022WR034169</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR034169?af=R</prism:url><prism:section>研究文章</prism:section></item><item><link/>https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2023WR034831?af=R<pubDate> Tue, 15 Aug 2023 23:04:12 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-08-15T11:04:12-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley：水资源研究：目录<prism:coverdate></prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate></prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2023WR034831</guid><title>使用视频监控摄像头改进实时降雨强度估算</title><description>水资源研究，已接受文章。</description><dc:description>摘要 全球气候变化背景下，城市内涝频繁发生，造成巨大的经济损失和人员伤亡。极端降雨是城市内涝的直接关键原因之一，高时空分辨率的准确降雨量估算对于城市洪水实时预报具有重要意义。使用现有的降雨强度测量技术，包括地面雨量计、地面雷达和卫星遥感，很难获得所需质量和分辨率的估计。然而，通过机器学习算法处理分布式监控摄像头网络图像来估计降雨强度的方法显示出相当大的前景。在这里，我们提出了一种新颖的方法，首先从监控摄像头图像中提取雨滴信息（而不是直接使用原始图像），然后使用卷积神经网络（CNN）从所得雨滴信息中估计降雨强度。对白天和夜间条件下的 12 个降雨事件的评估表明，该方法的泛化能力，特别是夜间预测性能显着提高。这代表着以相对较低的成本实现实时、高时空分辨率的城市降雨量测量的重要一步。本文受版权保护。版权所有。</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;全球气候变化背景下，城市内涝频繁发生，造成巨大的经济损失和人员伤亡。极端降雨是引发城市内涝的直接关键原因之一，高时空分辨率的准确降雨量估算对于城市洪水实时预报具有重要意义。使用现有的降雨强度测量技术，包括地面雨量计、地面雷达和卫星遥感，很难获得所需质量和分辨率的估计。然而，通过机器学习算法处理分布式监控摄像头网络图像来估计降雨强度的方法显示出相当大的前景。在这里，我们提出了一种新颖的方法，首先从监控摄像头图像中提取雨滴信息（而不是直接使用原始图像），然后使用卷积神经网络（CNN）从所得雨滴信息中估计降雨强度。对白天和夜间条件下的 12 个降雨事件的评估表明，该方法的泛化能力，特别是夜间预测性能显着提高。这代表着以相对较低的成本实现实时、高时空分辨率的城市降雨量测量的重要一步。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;本文受版权保护。保留所有权利。&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator>郑菲菲、尹航、马依依、段焕峰、Hoshin Gupta、Dragan Savic、Zoran Kapelan</dc:creator><category>研究文章</category><dc:title>使用视频监控摄像头改进实时降雨强度估算</dc:title><dc:identifier>10.1029/2023WR034831</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname>水资源研究</prism:publicationname><prism:doi>10.1029/2023WR034831</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2023WR034831?af=R</prism:url><prism:section>研究文章</prism:section></item><item><link/>https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR034059?af=R<pubDate> Tue, 15 Aug 2023 20:56:22 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-08-15T08:56:22-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley：水资源研究：目录<prism:coverdate></prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate></prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR034059</guid><title>河岸带非垂直流热传输的二维闭式解析解</title><description>水资源研究，已接受文章。</description><dc:description>摘要 近几十年来，热作为示踪剂受到越来越多的关注，并已成为一种流行且广泛使用的工具，用于量化河床通量以及许多其他应用。非垂直流分量是河岸带传热的重要参数。然而，以前使用热量作为示踪剂来定量河床通量的研究经常忽视或简化非垂直流分量并做出错误的假设。在这项研究中，首次使用格林函数方法提出了一种新颖的二维闭式解析解，用于具有垂直和非垂直流动分量以及损失条件下的任意初始和边界条件的热传输。新模型通过有限元求解和随机建模进行了测试。新分析解决方案的功能通过现场数据得到证明。结果表明，非垂直流分量对河床传热有显着影响。河床与地表水的温差随着非垂直流分量的增大而增大，且受非垂直流的影响，同一深度的温度曲线的幅度随着距河中心水平距离的增加而减小。随机建模表明，不断增加的不均匀水流会导致高估河岸附近的垂直和非垂直水流分量，并且当河床导水率的自然对数方差小于 0.10 时，新的分析模型在非均匀河床​​中效果良好()。垂直和非垂直流动分量对温度-时间数据比其他参数更敏感。新的分析模型是之前仅考虑垂直流的一维分析模型的重大进步。本文受版权保护。版权所有。</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;摘要&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;近几十年来，热量作为示踪剂受到越来越多的关注，并已成为一种流行且广泛使用的工具，用于量化河床通量以及许多其他应用。非垂直流分量是河岸带传热的重要参数。然而，以前使用热量作为示踪剂来定量河床通量的研究经常忽视或简化非垂直流分量并做出错误的假设。在这项研究中，首次使用格林函数方法提出了一种新颖的二维闭式解析解，用于具有垂直和非垂直流动分量以及损失条件下的任意初始和边界条件的热传输。新模型通过有限元求解和随机建模进行了测试。新分析解决方案的功能通过现场数据得到证明。结果表明，非垂直流分量对河床传热有显着影响。河床与地表水的温差随着非垂直流分量的增大而增大，且受非垂直流的影响，同一深度的温度曲线的幅度随着距河中心水平距离的增加而减小。随机建模表明，不断增加的不均匀水流会导致高估河岸附近的垂直和非垂直水流分量，并且当河床导水率的自然对数方差小于 0.10 时，新的分析模型在非均匀河床​​中效果良好()。垂直和非垂直流分量对温度-时间数据比其他参数更敏感。新的分析模型是对之前仅考虑垂直流的一维分析模型的重大改进。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;本文受版权保护。保留所有权利。&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator>史文光、詹宏斌、王全荣、谢先军</dc:creator><category>研究文章</category><dc:title>河岸带非垂直流热传输的二维闭式解析解</dc:title><dc:identifier>10.1029/2022WR034059</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname>水资源研究</prism:publicationname><prism:doi>10.1029/2022WR034059</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR034059?af=R</prism:url><prism:section>研究文章</prism:section></item><item><link/>https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR032194?af=R<pubDate> Tue, 15 Aug 2023 07:50:05 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-08-15T07:50:05-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley：水资源研究：目录<prism:coverdate>2023 年 8 月 1 日，星期二 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate> 2023 年 8 月 1 日，星期二 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR032194</guid><title>决策相关因素固定框架：在高维水质模型不确定性分析中的应用</title><description>《水资源研究》，第 59 卷，第 8 期，2023 年 8 月。</description><dc:description>摘要 因子固定（FF）是减少模型参数数量以降低计算成本的常用方法。 FF 通常从区分不敏感参数和敏感参数开始，并对所得降阶模型进行不确定性量化 (UQ)，将每个不敏感参数固定为固定值。然而，有必要扩展这种通用方法来考虑 FF-UQ 过程中决策选择对感兴趣指标的影响。因此，为了指导FF的使用并增加对所得降维模型的信心，我们提出了一个新的自适应框架，该框架由四个原则组成：（a）首先重新参数化模型以减少明显的不可识别参数组合，（b） ) 重点关注决策相关性，尤其是与感兴趣数量 (QoI) 错误相关的决策相关性，(c) 随着样本量的增加，对 FF 选择中的 QoI 错误进行适应性评估和鲁棒性评估，以及 (d) 重新考虑是否需要修正。该框架在空间分布的水质模型上进行了论证。由 FF 引起的 QoI 估计误差可以使用多项式混沌展开 (PCE) 代理模型来估计。该替代模型通过 70 次模型运行构建，评估所需的计算成本低廉，并且可以免费提供全局敏感性指数。对于选定的流域，只需两个因素就可以对总悬浮固体（TSS）平均年负荷的模型不确定性提供可接受的准确估计，这表明在采取进一步的正式不确定性之前，减少这两个参数的不确定性是未来工作的优先事项量化。</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;因子固定（FF）是减少模型参数数量以降低计算成本的常用方法。 FF 通常从区分不敏感参数和敏感参数开始，并对所得降阶模型进行不确定性量化 (UQ)，将每个不敏感参数固定为固定值。 There is a need, however, to expand such a common approach to consider the effects of decision choices in the FF-UQ procedure on metrics of interest. Therefore, to guide the use of FF and increase confidence in the resulting dimension-reduced model, we propose a new adaptive framework consisting of four principles: (a) re-parameterize the model first to reduce obvious non-identifiable parameter combinations, (b) focus on decision relevance especially with respect to errors in quantities of interest (QoI), (c) conduct adaptive evaluation and robustness assessment of errors in the QoI across FF choices as sample size increases, and (d) reconsider whether fixing is warranted. The framework is demonstrated on a spatially-distributed water quality model. The error in estimates of QoI caused by FF can be estimated using a Polynomial Chaos Expansion (PCE) surrogate model. Built with 70 model runs, the surrogate is computationally inexpensive to evaluate and can provide global sensitivity indices for free. For the selected catchment, just two factors may provide an acceptably accurate estimate of model uncertainty in the average annual load of Total Suspended Solids (TSS), suggesting that reducing the uncertainty in these two parameters is a priority for future work before undertaking further formal uncertainty quantification.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> Qian Wang, Joseph HA Guillaume, John D. Jakeman, Frederick R. Bennett, Barry FW Croke, Baihua Fu, Tao Yang, Anthony J. Jakeman</dc:creator><category> Research Article</category><dc:title> A Decision‐Relevant Factor‐Fixing Framework: Application to Uncertainty Analysis of a High‐Dimensional Water Quality Model</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2022WR032194</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1029/2022WR032194</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR032194?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> Research Article</prism:section><prism:volume> 59</prism:volume><prism:number> 8</prism:number></item><item><link/> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR034024?af=R<pubDate> Tue, 15 Aug 2023 04:29:10 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-08-15T04:29:10-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley: Water Resources Research: Table of Contents <prism:coverdate></prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate></prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR034024</guid><title> Size distributions reveal regime transition of lake systems under different dominant driving forces</title><description> Water Resources Research, Accepted Article.</description><dc:description> Abstract Power law size distribution is found to associate with fractal, self‐organized behaviors and patterns of complex systems. Such distribution also emerges from natural lakes, with potentially important links to the dynamics of lake systems. But the driving mechanism that generates and shapes this feature in lake systems remains unclear. Moreover, the power law itself was found inadequate for fully describing the size distribution of lakes, due to deviations at the two ends of size range. Based on observed and simulated lakes in China&#39;s 11 hydro‐climatic zones, we established a conceptual model for lake systems, which covers the whole size range of lake size distribution and reveals the underlying driving mechanism. The full lake size distribution is composed of three components, with three phases featured by exponential, stretched‐exponential and power law distribution. The three phases represent system states with successively increasing degrees of heterogeneity and orderliness, and more importantly, indicate the dominance of exogenic and endogenic forces, respectively. As the dominant driving force changes from endogenic to exogenic, a phase transition occurs with lake size distribution shifted from power law to stretched‐exponential and further to exponential distribution. Apart from compressing the power law phase, exogenic force also increases its scaling exponent, driving the corresponding lake size power spectrum into the regime of “blue noise”. During this process, the autocorrelation function of the lake system diverges with a possibility of going to infinity, indicating the loss of system resilience.</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;Power law size distribution is found to associate with fractal, self-organized behaviors and patterns of complex systems. Such distribution also emerges from natural lakes, with potentially important links to the dynamics of lake systems. But the driving mechanism that generates and shapes this feature in lake systems remains unclear. Moreover, the power law itself was found inadequate for fully describing the size distribution of lakes, due to deviations at the two ends of size range. Based on observed and simulated lakes in China&#39;s 11 hydro-climatic zones, we established a conceptual model for lake systems, which covers the whole size range of lake size distribution and reveals the underlying driving mechanism. The full lake size distribution is composed of three components, with three phases featured by exponential, stretched-exponential and power law distribution. The three phases represent system states with successively increasing degrees of heterogeneity and orderliness, and more importantly, indicate the dominance of exogenic and endogenic forces, respectively. As the dominant driving force changes from endogenic to exogenic, a phase transition occurs with lake size distribution shifted from power law to stretched-exponential and further to exponential distribution. Apart from compressing the power law phase, exogenic force also increases its scaling exponent, driving the corresponding lake size power spectrum into the regime of “blue noise”. During this process, the autocorrelation function of the lake system diverges with a possibility of going to infinity, indicating the loss of system resilience.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> Shengjie Hu, Zhenlei Yang, Sergio Torres, Zipeng Wang, Ling Li</dc:creator><category> Research Article</category><dc:title> Size distributions reveal regime transition of lake systems under different dominant driving forces</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2022WR034024</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1029/2022WR034024</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR034024?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> Research Article</prism:section></item><item><link/> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2023WR034431?af=R<pubDate> Mon, 14 Aug 2023 20:24:19 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-08-14T08:24:19-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley: Water Resources Research: Table of Contents <prism:coverdate></prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate></prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2023WR034431</guid><title> Toward improved regional hydrological model performance using state‐of‐the‐science data‐informed soil parameters</title><description> Water Resources Research, Accepted Article.</description><dc:description> Abstract Accurate soil moisture and streamflow data are an aspirational need of many hydrologically‐relevant fields. Model simulated soil moisture and streamflow hold promise but models require validation prior to application. Calibration methods are commonly used to improve model fidelity but misrepresentation of the true dynamics remains a challenge. In this study, we leverage soil parameter estimates from the Soil Survey Geographic (SSURGO) database and the probability mapping of SSURGO (POLARIS) to improve the representation of hydrologic processes in the Weather Research and Forecasting Hydrological modeling system (WRF‐Hydro) over a central California domain. Our results show WRF‐Hydro soil moisture exhibits increased correlation coefficients (r), reduced biases, and increased Kling‐Gupta Efficiencies (KGEs) across seven in‐situ soil moisture observing stations after updating the model&#39;s soil parameters according to POLARIS. Compared to four well‐established soil moisture datasets including Soil Moisture Active Passive data and three Phase 2 North American Land Data Assimilation System land surface models, our POLARIS‐adjusted WRF‐Hydro simulations produce the highest mean KGE (0.69) across the seven stations. More importantly, WRF‐Hydro streamflow fidelity also increases, especially in the case where the model domain is set up with SSURGO‐informed total soil thickness. The magnitude and timing of peak flow events are better captured, r increases across nine United States Geological Survey stream gages, and the mean KGE across seven of the nine gages increases from 0.12 to 0.66. Our pre‐calibration parameter estimate approach, which is transferable to other spatially‐distributed hydrological models, can substantially improve a model&#39;s performance, helping reduce calibration efforts and computational costs.</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;Accurate soil moisture and streamflow data are an aspirational need of many hydrologically-relevant fields. Model simulated soil moisture and streamflow hold promise but models require validation prior to application. Calibration methods are commonly used to improve model fidelity but misrepresentation of the true dynamics remains a challenge. In this study, we leverage soil parameter estimates from the Soil Survey Geographic (SSURGO) database and the probability mapping of SSURGO (POLARIS) to improve the representation of hydrologic processes in the Weather Research and Forecasting Hydrological modeling system (WRF-Hydro) over a central California domain. Our results show WRF-Hydro soil moisture exhibits increased correlation coefficients (&lt;i>;r&lt;/i>;), reduced biases, and increased Kling-Gupta Efficiencies (KGEs) across seven in-situ soil moisture observing stations after updating the model&#39;s soil parameters according to POLARIS. Compared to four well-established soil moisture datasets including Soil Moisture Active Passive data and three Phase 2 North American Land Data Assimilation System land surface models, our POLARIS-adjusted WRF-Hydro simulations produce the highest mean KGE (0.69) across the seven stations. More importantly, WRF-Hydro streamflow fidelity also increases, especially in the case where the model domain is set up with SSURGO-informed total soil thickness. The magnitude and timing of peak flow events are better captured, &lt;i>;r&lt;/i>; increases across nine United States Geological Survey stream gages, and the mean KGE across seven of the nine gages increases from 0.12 to 0.66. Our pre-calibration parameter estimate approach, which is transferable to other spatially-distributed hydrological models, can substantially improve a model&#39;s performance, helping reduce calibration efforts and computational costs.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> Chuxuan Li, Guo Yu, Jiali Wang, Daniel E. Horton</dc:creator><category> Research Article</category><dc:title> Toward improved regional hydrological model performance using state‐of‐the‐science data‐informed soil parameters</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2023WR034431</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1029/2023WR034431</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2023WR034431?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> Research Article</prism:section></item><item><link/> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033970?af=R<pubDate> Mon, 14 Aug 2023 09:05:40 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-08-14T09:05:40-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley: Water Resources Research: Table of Contents<prism:coverdate> Tue, 01 Aug 2023 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate> Tue, 01 Aug 2023 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR033970</guid><title> Evidence and Controls of the Acceleration of the Hydrological Cycle Over Land</title><description> Water Resources Research, Volume 59, Issue 8, August 2023.</description><dc:description> Abstract Investigating modifications in the hydrological cycle is essential to understand the impacts of climate change on ecosystems. This study assesses the change in the velocity of the water cycle over land at the global scale, whereas previous studies have mostly focused on changes in the atmospheric water cycle. The hydrological acceleration is quantified by a decrease in average residence time (RT) of water in the first meter of soil. The soil water RT is shown to be sensitive to the soil texture and seasonality of hydroclimatic variables. Despite substantial local variability, most of the RTs are in the range of 50–300 days. The global mean soil water RT declined at a rate of −2.30 and −0.36 days decade−1 (−1.6 to 1.0 days decade−1 the range of nine models) from 2001 to 2020 as measured by reanalysis and CMIP6 simulations for the historical scenario, respectively, which corresponds to −6.8 and −1.1 days °C−1 when expressed per degree of global warming over land. This acceleration is projected to continue at a rate of −1.35 days decade−1 (−3.4 to 0.0 days decade−1 the range of nine models) or −2.2 days °C−1 during the period 2015–2100 under the most extreme emission scenario: SSP 585. Changes in precipitation dominantly drive the acceleration of the terrestrial water cycle compared to changes in evapotranspiration. Rising temperatures and increasing carbon dioxide have opposite effects on the speed of the terrestrial water cycle with compensatory roles keeping RT relatively unchanged in the absence of PR trends.</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;Investigating modifications in the hydrological cycle is essential to understand the impacts of climate change on ecosystems. This study assesses the change in the velocity of the water cycle over land at the global scale, whereas previous studies have mostly focused on changes in the atmospheric water cycle. The hydrological acceleration is quantified by a decrease in average residence time (RT) of water in the first meter of soil. The soil water RT is shown to be sensitive to the soil texture and seasonality of hydroclimatic variables. Despite substantial local variability, most of the RTs are in the range of 50–300 days. The global mean soil water RT declined at a rate of −2.30 and −0.36 days decade&lt;sup>;−1&lt;/sup>; (−1.6 to 1.0 days decade&lt;sup>;−1&lt;/sup>; the range of nine models) from 2001 to 2020 as measured by reanalysis and CMIP6 simulations for the historical scenario, respectively, which corresponds to −6.8 and −1.1 days °C&lt;sup>;−1&lt;/sup>; when expressed per degree of global warming over land. This acceleration is projected to continue at a rate of −1.35 days decade&lt;sup>;−1&lt;/sup>; (−3.4 to 0.0 days decade&lt;sup>;−1&lt;/sup>; the range of nine models) or −2.2 days °C&lt;sup>;−1&lt;/sup>; during the period 2015–2100 under the most extreme emission scenario: SSP 585. Changes in precipitation dominantly drive the acceleration of the terrestrial water cycle compared to changes in evapotranspiration. Rising temperatures and increasing carbon dioxide have opposite effects on the speed of the terrestrial water cycle with compensatory roles keeping RT relatively unchanged in the absence of PR trends.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> Y. Wang, N. Meili, S. Fatichi</dc:creator><category> Research Article</category><dc:title> Evidence and Controls of the Acceleration of the Hydrological Cycle Over Land</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2022WR033970</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1029/2022WR033970</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033970?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> Research Article</prism:section><prism:volume> 59</prism:volume><prism:number> 8</prism:number></item><item><link/> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2023WR034664?af=R<pubDate> Sun, 13 Aug 2023 01:38:19 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-08-13T01:38:19-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley: Water Resources Research: Table of Contents <prism:coverdate></prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate></prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2023WR034664</guid><title> Pore‐scale modeling of PFAS transport in water‐unsaturated porous media: Air–water interfacial adsorption and mass‐transfer processes in thin water films</title><description> Water Resources Research, Accepted Article.</description><dc:description> Abstract Air–water interfacial adsorption complicates PFAS transport in vadose zones. Air–water interfaces can arise from pendular rings between soil grains and thin water films on grain surfaces, the latter of which account for over 90% of the total air–water interfaces for most field‐relevant conditions. However, whether all thin‐water‐film air–water interfaces are accessible by PFAS and how mass‐transfer limitations in thin water films control PFAS transport in soils remain unknown. We develop a pore‐scale model that represents both PFAS adsorption at bulk capillary and thin‐water‐film air–water interfaces and the mass‐transfer processes between bulk capillary water and thin water films (including advection, aqueous diffusion, and surface diffusion along air–water interfaces). We apply the pore‐scale model to a series of numerical experiments—constrained by experimentally‐determined hydraulic parameters and air–water interfacial area data sets—to examine the impact of thin‐water‐film mass‐transfer limitations in a sand medium. Our analyses suggest: (1) The mass‐transfer limitations between bulk capillary water and thin water films inside a pore are negligible due to surface diffusion. (2) However, strong mass‐transfer limitations arise in thin water films of pore clusters where pendular rings disconnect. The mass‐transfer limitations lead to early arrival and long tailing behaviors even if surface diffusion is present. (3) Despite the mass‐transfer limitations, all air–water interfaces in the thin water films were accessed by PFAS under the simulated conditions. These findings highlight the importance of incorporating the thin‐water‐film mass‐transfer limitations and surface diffusion for modeling PFAS transport in vadose zones. This article is protected by copyright.版权所有。</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;Air–water interfacial adsorption complicates PFAS transport in vadose zones. Air–water interfaces can arise from pendular rings between soil grains and thin water films on grain surfaces, the latter of which account for over 90% of the total air–water interfaces for most field-relevant conditions. However, whether all thin-water-film air–water interfaces are accessible by PFAS and how mass-transfer limitations in thin water films control PFAS transport in soils remain unknown. We develop a pore-scale model that represents both PFAS adsorption at bulk capillary and thin-water-film air–water interfaces and the mass-transfer processes between bulk capillary water and thin water films (including advection, aqueous diffusion, and surface diffusion along air–water interfaces). We apply the pore-scale model to a series of numerical experiments—constrained by experimentally-determined hydraulic parameters and air–water interfacial area data sets—to examine the impact of thin-water-film mass-transfer limitations in a sand medium. Our analyses suggest: (1) The mass-transfer limitations between bulk capillary water and thin water films inside a pore are negligible due to surface diffusion. (2) However, strong mass-transfer limitations arise in thin water films of pore clusters where pendular rings disconnect. The mass-transfer limitations lead to early arrival and long tailing behaviors even if surface diffusion is present. (3) Despite the mass-transfer limitations, all air–water interfaces in the thin water films were accessed by PFAS under the simulated conditions. These findings highlight the importance of incorporating the thin-water-film mass-transfer limitations and surface diffusion for modeling PFAS transport in vadose zones.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This article is protected by copyright. All rights reserved.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> Sidian Chen, Bo Guo</dc:creator><category> Research Article</category><dc:title> Pore‐scale modeling of PFAS transport in water‐unsaturated porous media: Air–water interfacial adsorption and mass‐transfer processes in thin water films</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2023WR034664</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1029/2023WR034664</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2023WR034664?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> Research Article</prism:section></item><item><link/> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033858?af=R<pubDate> Sun, 13 Aug 2023 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-08-13T12:00:00-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley: Water Resources Research: Table of Contents <prism:coverdate></prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate></prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR033858</guid><title> Analysis of Aquifer‐System Deformation in the Doñana Natural Space (Spain) using Unsupervised Cloud‐Computed InSAR Data and Wavelet Analysis</title><description> Water Resources Research, Accepted Article.</description><dc:description> Abstract This work is focused on the Almonte‐Marismas aquifer located within Doñana Natural Space (SW Spain); this aquifer is threatened by droughts, irrigation‐driven groundwater overexploitation, urban use, and the potential reactivation of gas extraction and storage projects. We present ground deformation measurements from Sentinel‐1 Interferometric Synthetic Aperture Radar (InSAR) data ranging from 1‐2.5 cm, covering ∼2,500 km2 from 2014‐2020. Detecting spatially distributed ground deformation over this agricultural area is challenging due to the low‐coherence radar signals; consequently, the ground movement results are on the same order of magnitude as the errors associated with InSAR data. We have approached this issue by considering auxiliary information such as groundwater levels, climatic time series, and pumping rates and analyzing their spatio‐temporal connections to ground displacements. We correlate InSAR and hydrogeological information through wavelet analysis, developing a Python package that allows applying the same methodology in other similar study areas. For the first time in the Doñana area, a significant relationship between distances to pumping wells and the displacement extent is detected. Moreover, other subsidence‐related triggering factors are identified, such as the soil moisture balance, clay shrinking‐swelling processes, and creep of geological formations. These results are highly valuable to support aquifer management decisions in the Doñana Natural Space; in this border region, three groundwater bodies were officially declared overexploited in 2020. Our findings provide a ground motion baseline assessment to help differentiate historical variations from any future anthropogenic effect in this complex marsh land ecosystem.</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;This work is focused on the Almonte-Marismas aquifer located within Doñana Natural Space (SW Spain); this aquifer is threatened by droughts, irrigation-driven groundwater overexploitation, urban use, and the potential reactivation of gas extraction and storage projects. We present ground deformation measurements from Sentinel-1 Interferometric Synthetic Aperture Radar (InSAR) data ranging from 1-2.5 cm, covering ∼2,500 km&lt;sup>;2&lt;/sup>; from 2014-2020. Detecting spatially distributed ground deformation over this agricultural area is challenging due to the low-coherence radar signals; consequently, the ground movement results are on the same order of magnitude as the errors associated with InSAR data. We have approached this issue by considering auxiliary information such as groundwater levels, climatic time series, and pumping rates and analyzing their spatio-temporal connections to ground displacements. We correlate InSAR and hydrogeological information through wavelet analysis, developing a Python package that allows applying the same methodology in other similar study areas. For the first time in the Doñana area, a significant relationship between distances to pumping wells and the displacement extent is detected. Moreover, other subsidence-related triggering factors are identified, such as the soil moisture balance, clay shrinking-swelling processes, and creep of geological formations. These results are highly valuable to support aquifer management decisions in the Doñana Natural Space; in this border region, three groundwater bodies were officially declared overexploited in 2020. Our findings provide a ground motion baseline assessment to help differentiate historical variations from any future anthropogenic effect in this complex marsh land ecosystem.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> M. González‐Jiménez, C. Guardiola‐Albert, P. Ezquerro, H. Aguilera, M. Béjar‐Pizarro, N. Naranjo‐Fernández, G. Bru, G. Herrera</dc:creator><category> Research Article</category><dc:title> Analysis of Aquifer‐System Deformation in the Doñana Natural Space (Spain) using Unsupervised Cloud‐Computed InSAR Data and Wavelet Analysis</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2022WR033858</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1029/2022WR033858</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033858?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> Research Article</prism:section></item><item><link/> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR034023?af=R<pubDate> Fri, 11 Aug 2023 14:53:25 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-08-11T02:53:25-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley: Water Resources Research: Table of Contents <prism:coverdate></prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate></prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR034023</guid><title> The Impact of Soil Tension on Isotope Fractionation, Transport, and Interpretations of the Root Water Uptake Origin</title><description> Water Resources Research, Accepted Article.</description><dc:description> Abstract The new isotope module in HYDRUS‐1D can be used to infer the origin of root water uptake (RWU), a suitable dynamic indicator for agriculture and forest water management. However, evidence shows that the equilibrium fractionation between liquid water and water vapor within the soil is affected not only by soil temperature but also by soil tension. How soil tension affects isotope transport modeling and interpretations of the RWU origin is still unknown. In this study, we evaluated three fractionation scenarios on model performance for a field dataset from Langeoog Island: i) no fractionation (Non_Frac), ii) the soil temperature control on equilibrium fractionation as described by the standard Craig‐Gordon equation (CG_Frac), and iii) CG_Frac plus the soil tension control on equilibrium fractionation (CGT_Frac). The model simulations showed that CGT_Frac led to more depleted surface isotopic compositions than CG_Frac. The vertical origin of RWU was estimated using the water balance calculations (WB) and the Bayesian mixing model (SIAR). While the former directly used water flow outputs, the latter used as input simulated isotopic compositions (using different fractionation scenarios) of RWU and soil water. Both methods provided similar variation trends with time and depth in different soil layers&#39; contributions to RWU. The contributions of all soil layers interpreted by the CGT_Frac scenario were always between Non_Frac and CG_Frac. The temporal origin of RWU was deduced from particle tracking (PT, releasing one hypothetical particle for individual precipitation event and tracking its movement based on the water balance between particles) and a virtual tracer experiment (VTE, assigning a known isotope composition to individual precipitation event and tracking its movement based on the cumulative isotope flux). Both methods revealed similar variation trends with time in drainage and root zone (RZ) travel times. The interpreted drainage and RZ travel times were generally ranked as Non_Frac >; CGT_Frac >; CG_Frac. Overall, the factors considered in the standard CG equation dominated isotope fractionation, transport, and interpretations of the RWU origin. Isotope transport‐based methods (SIAR, VTE) were more computationally demanding than water flow‐based methods (WB, PT). This article is protected by copyright.版权所有。</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;The new isotope module in HYDRUS-1D can be used to infer the origin of root water uptake (RWU), a suitable dynamic indicator for agriculture and forest water management. However, evidence shows that the equilibrium fractionation between liquid water and water vapor within the soil is affected not only by soil temperature but also by soil tension. How soil tension affects isotope transport modeling and interpretations of the RWU origin is still unknown. In this study, we evaluated three fractionation scenarios on model performance for a field dataset from Langeoog Island: &lt;i>;i&lt;/i>;) no fractionation (Non_Frac), &lt;i>;ii&lt;/i>;) the soil temperature control on equilibrium fractionation as described by the standard Craig-Gordon equation (CG_Frac), and &lt;i>;iii&lt;/i>;) CG_Frac plus the soil tension control on equilibrium fractionation (CGT_Frac). The model simulations showed that CGT_Frac led to more depleted surface isotopic compositions than CG_Frac.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The vertical origin of RWU was estimated using the water balance calculations (WB) and the Bayesian mixing model (SIAR). While the former directly used water flow outputs, the latter used as input simulated isotopic compositions (using different fractionation scenarios) of RWU and soil water. Both methods provided similar variation trends with time and depth in different soil layers&#39; contributions to RWU. The contributions of all soil layers interpreted by the CGT_Frac scenario were always between Non_Frac and CG_Frac. The temporal origin of RWU was deduced from particle tracking (PT, releasing one hypothetical particle for individual precipitation event and tracking its movement based on the water balance between particles) and a virtual tracer experiment (VTE, assigning a known isotope composition to individual precipitation event and tracking its movement based on the cumulative isotope flux). Both methods revealed similar variation trends with time in drainage and root zone (RZ) travel times. The interpreted drainage and RZ travel times were generally ranked as Non_Frac &amp;gt; CGT_Frac &amp;gt; CG_Frac. Overall, the factors considered in the standard CG equation dominated isotope fractionation, transport, and interpretations of the RWU origin. Isotope transport-based methods (SIAR, VTE) were more computationally demanding than water flow-based methods (WB, PT).&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This article is protected by copyright. All rights reserved.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> Tiantian Zhou, Jiří Šimůnek, Paolo Nasta, Giuseppe Brunetti, Marcel Gaj, Christoph Neukum, Vincent Post</dc:creator><category> Research Article</category><dc:title> The Impact of Soil Tension on Isotope Fractionation, Transport, and Interpretations of the Root Water Uptake Origin</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2022WR034023</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1029/2022WR034023</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR034023?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> Research Article</prism:section></item><item><link/> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033617?af=R<pubDate> Fri, 11 Aug 2023 10:19:29 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-08-11T10:19:29-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley: Water Resources Research: Table of Contents <prism:coverdate></prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate></prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR033617</guid><title> Multidirectional shifts in hydrological connectivityresult from hydraulic barriers</title><description> Water Resources Research, Accepted Article.</description><dc:description> Abstract The weakening of hydrological connectivity caused by hydraulic barriers and its impact on the ecological environment has gained worldwide attention. ​Previous studies have primarily focused on the obstructive effect of barriers, often overlooking its influence on the internal connectivity of regulated water systems. The study employed a new conceptual framework of hydrological connectivity and utilized the connectivity assessment tool (CAST) to assess the impact of the proposed Poyang Lake Hydraulic Project (PLHP) on the lake&#39;s internal connectivity. The estimated impacts were based on various factors, including the connectivity function (CF), spatial distribution of the connected object (CONNOB), as well as duration and timing of connection. Key findings indicate that the PLHP will enhance the total connectivity (TC) and general connectivity involving inundation depth (GCD) of the lake. This enhancement will result in increased CF values, expanded CONNOBs and prolonged connection durations. Conversely, the PLHP will weaken the general connectivity involving flow velocity (GCV) and effective connectivity (EC). As a result, CF values will decrease, CONNOBs will shrink, and connection durations will be shorter. It&#39;s important to note that the impact of hydraulic barriers varies depending on evaluation metrics, duration, timing, direction, distance, location, hydrological year, and regulation stage. Therefore, it is not appropriate to simply categorize the barrier impact as “weakening” or “enhancing”. This study innovates the knowledge of hydraulic barriers from the perspective of internal connectivity and is expected to provide more comprehensive theoretical guidance for water resource regulation and eco‐environmental protection.</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;The weakening of hydrological connectivity caused by hydraulic barriers and its impact on the ecological environment has gained worldwide attention. ​Previous studies have primarily focused on the obstructive effect of barriers, often overlooking its influence on the internal connectivity of regulated water systems. The study employed a new conceptual framework of hydrological connectivity and utilized the connectivity assessment tool (CAST) to assess the impact of the proposed Poyang Lake Hydraulic Project (PLHP) on the lake&#39;s internal connectivity. The estimated impacts were based on various factors, including the connectivity function (CF), spatial distribution of the connected object (CONNOB), as well as duration and timing of connection. Key findings indicate that the PLHP will enhance the total connectivity (TC) and general connectivity involving inundation depth (GCD) of the lake. This enhancement will result in increased CF values, expanded CONNOBs and prolonged connection durations. Conversely, the PLHP will weaken the general connectivity involving flow velocity (GCV) and effective connectivity (EC). As a result, CF values will decrease, CONNOBs will shrink, and connection durations will be shorter. It&#39;s important to note that the impact of hydraulic barriers varies depending on evaluation metrics, duration, timing, direction, distance, location, hydrological year, and regulation stage. Therefore, it is not appropriate to simply categorize the barrier impact as “weakening” or “enhancing”. This study innovates the knowledge of hydraulic barriers from the perspective of internal connectivity and is expected to provide more comprehensive theoretical guidance for water resource regulation and eco-environmental protection.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> ZQ Tan, J. Yao, LQ Gong, YL Li, Q. Zhang, XL Wang, RR Wan, B. Li</dc:creator><category> Research Article</category><dc:title> Multidirectional shifts in hydrological connectivityresult from hydraulic barriers</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2022WR033617</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1029/2022WR033617</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033617?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> Research Article</prism:section></item><item><link/> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2023WR034974?af=R<pubDate> Fri, 11 Aug 2023 09:11:08 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-08-11T09:11:08-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley: Water Resources Research: Table of Contents<prism:coverdate> Tue, 01 Aug 2023 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate> Tue, 01 Aug 2023 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2023WR034974</guid><title> Improved Prediction of Local Significant Wave Height by Considering the Memory of Past Winds</title><description> Water Resources Research, Volume 59, Issue 8, August 2023.</description><dc:description> Abstract Wave and water depth were measured with an instrumented tripod in the Yellow River Delta from 9 December 2014 to 29 April 2015. Concurrent wind data were also collected from a nearby wind station. A high‐precision model for predicting local significant wave height (Hs) with wind speed (vw) is constructed using an improved data‐driven approach. The proposed model realized high accuracy as it solves the problem that the Hs falls too fast during the wind‐decreasing periods. It was tackled by considering the remaining influence of historical vw on the present Hs via incorporating a memory curve of the past wind effect. This innovative approach significantly improves the prediction (R2 from 0.60 to 0.83). The winds in the past 24 hr still left an influence on the waves at the observation site although the influence decreases with time. Physically, it is an implicit but simpler consideration of wind fetch/duration. Further data modeling experiments indicated that the decisive factor for the Hs at the site is the wind speed. Wind directions slightly improve the prediction, indicating that waves are slightly affected by the underwater seabed slope along different wind directions, and northwest winds cause the strongest waves at the site. Adding atmospheric pressure or water depth even reduces the accuracy, which indicated that storm surges and wave deformations under different tide levels have a weak impact on Hs. The proposed local wave model can be easily constructed with available wind and wave data, making it expandable to other regions dominated by wind waves.</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;Wave and water depth were measured with an instrumented tripod in the Yellow River Delta from 9 December 2014 to 29 April 2015. Concurrent wind data were also collected from a nearby wind station. A high-precision model for predicting local significant wave height (&lt;i>;H&lt;/i>; &lt;sub>; &lt;i>;s&lt;/i>; &lt;/sub>;) with wind speed (&lt;i>;v&lt;/i>; &lt;sub>; &lt;i>;w&lt;/i>; &lt;/sub>;) is constructed using an improved data-driven approach. The proposed model realized high accuracy as it solves the problem that the &lt;i>;H&lt;/i>; &lt;sub>; &lt;i>;s&lt;/i>; &lt;/sub>; falls too fast during the wind-decreasing periods. It was tackled by considering the remaining influence of historical &lt;i>;v&lt;/i>; &lt;sub>; &lt;i>;w&lt;/i>; &lt;/sub>; on the present &lt;i>;H&lt;/i>; &lt;sub>; &lt;i>;s&lt;/i>; &lt;/sub>; via incorporating a memory curve of the past wind effect. This innovative approach significantly improves the prediction (&lt;i>;R&lt;/i>; &lt;sup>;2&lt;/sup>; from 0.60 to 0.83). The winds in the past 24 hr still left an influence on the waves at the observation site although the influence decreases with time. Physically, it is an implicit but simpler consideration of wind fetch/duration. Further data modeling experiments indicated that the decisive factor for the &lt;i>;H&lt;/i>; &lt;sub>; &lt;i>;s&lt;/i>; &lt;/sub>; at the site is the wind speed. Wind directions slightly improve the prediction, indicating that waves are slightly affected by the underwater seabed slope along different wind directions, and northwest winds cause the strongest waves at the site. Adding atmospheric pressure or water depth even reduces the accuracy, which indicated that storm surges and wave deformations under different tide levels have a weak impact on &lt;i>;H&lt;/i>; &lt;sub>; &lt;i>;s&lt;/i>; &lt;/sub>;. The proposed local wave model can be easily constructed with available wind and wave data, making it expandable to other regions dominated by wind waves.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> Shaotong Zhang, Zhen Yang, Yaqi Zhang, Shangrui Zhao, Jinran Wu, Chenghao Wang, You‐Gan Wang, Dong‐Sheng Jeng, Peter Nielsen, Guangxue Li, Sanzhong Li</dc:creator><category> Research Article</category><dc:title> Improved Prediction of Local Significant Wave Height by Considering the Memory of Past Winds</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2023WR034974</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1029/2023WR034974</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2023WR034974?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> Research Article</prism:section><prism:volume> 59</prism:volume><prism:number> 8</prism:number></item><item><link/> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033216?af=R<pubDate> Fri, 11 Aug 2023 09:05:28 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-08-11T09:05:28-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley: Water Resources Research: Table of Contents<prism:coverdate> Tue, 01 Aug 2023 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate> Tue, 01 Aug 2023 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR033216</guid><title> Application of the Observation‐Oriented CNOP‐P Sensitivity Analysis Method in Evapotranspiration Simulation and Prediction Over the Tibetan Plateau</title><description> Water Resources Research, Volume 59, Issue 8, August 2023.</description><dc:description> Abstract To improve the ability to accurately simulate and predict evapotranspiration (ET) over the Tibetan Plateau (TP), an observation‐oriented sensitivity analysis (SA) method based on a conditional nonlinear optimal parameter perturbation (CNOP‐P) method is employed. With the observation‐oriented CNOP‐P SA method, a sensitive parameter subset among all parameters is first determined through comparison with observations of ET across the TP. Then, the sensitive parameter combination is optimized to evaluate the ET simulation ability and prediction skill over the TP. A traditional one‐at‐a‐time (OAT) method is also employed, and the results are compared with the numerical results obtained with the observation‐oriented CNOP‐P SA method. The results show that the identified parameter combination using the observation‐oriented CNOP‐P SA method is more sensitive than that using the OAT method for the estimation of ET at 13 sites on the TP. The above results demonstrate that it is important to determine the sensitive parameter combination using the observation‐oriented SA method to improve the ET simulation ability and prediction skill over the TP.</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;To improve the ability to accurately simulate and predict evapotranspiration (ET) over the Tibetan Plateau (TP), an observation-oriented sensitivity analysis (SA) method based on a conditional nonlinear optimal parameter perturbation (CNOP-P) method is employed. With the observation-oriented CNOP-P SA method, a sensitive parameter subset among all parameters is first determined through comparison with observations of ET across the TP. Then, the sensitive parameter combination is optimized to evaluate the ET simulation ability and prediction skill over the TP. A traditional one-at-a-time (OAT) method is also employed, and the results are compared with the numerical results obtained with the observation-oriented CNOP-P SA method. The results show that the identified parameter combination using the observation-oriented CNOP-P SA method is more sensitive than that using the OAT method for the estimation of ET at 13 sites on the TP. The above results demonstrate that it is important to determine the sensitive parameter combination using the observation-oriented SA method to improve the ET simulation ability and prediction skill over the TP.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> Guodong Sun, Mu Mu, Qiyu Zhang, Qiujie Ren, Qinglong You</dc:creator><category> Research Article</category><dc:title> Application of the Observation‐Oriented CNOP‐P Sensitivity Analysis Method in Evapotranspiration Simulation and Prediction Over the Tibetan Plateau</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2022WR033216</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1029/2022WR033216</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033216?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> Research Article</prism:section><prism:volume> 59</prism:volume><prism:number> 8</prism:number></item><item><link/> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR034036?af=R<pubDate> Thu, 10 Aug 2023 10:23:10 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-08-10T10:23:10-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley: Water Resources Research: Table of Contents<prism:coverdate> Tue, 01 Aug 2023 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate> Tue, 01 Aug 2023 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR034036</guid><title> An Algorithm‐Independent Definition of Effective Contour Length and Its Impacts on Pixel‐Scale Specific Catchment Area</title><description> Water Resources Research, Volume 59, Issue 8, August 2023.</description><dc:description> Abstract Specific catchment area (SCA) is crucial terrain attribute extensively‐adopted in topographically‐driven modelings, which is function of total contributing area (TCA) and effective contour length (EL). Despite of numerous studies about SCA and TCA, none has focused on the investigation of existing EL definitions and adaption of point‐scale SCA concept to two‐dimensional pixel of digital elevation model (DEM). This work conducts a systematic research on rationality of existing EL definitions, proposal of new EL definition and concept of pixel‐scale SCA on gridded DEM. To overcome the defects of existing EL definitions, a new EL definition based on Triangular Discretization and Spatial Geometry (TDSG) is proposed in this work. SCA concept is extended from point scale to pixel scale for adapting to context of gridded DEM. The solutions of true pixel‐scale SCA, TCA, and EL in integral forms are deduced based on the solutions of point‐scale SCAs obtained by method of Zhou and Liu (2002, https://doi.org/10.1080/13658810210149425) or Gallant and Hutchinson (2011, https://doi.org/10.1029/2009WR008540). Besides, true pixel‐scale SCA, TCA, and EL are solved analytically for several synthetic surfaces. Numerical experiments indicate that (a) TDSG definition is superior to all existing EL definitions in physical mechanism, spatial characteristics, and computational precisions on synthetic surfaces and a real‐world DEM. (b) Spatial characteristics of SCA are controlled mainly by TCA and tuned slightly by EL, while overall precision of SCA is affected seriously by both TCA and EL. (c) TDSG definition is the only EL definition of responding accurately and sensitively to convergent and dispersive characteristics of local terrains.</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;Specific catchment area (SCA) is crucial terrain attribute extensively-adopted in topographically-driven modelings, which is function of total contributing area (TCA) and effective contour length (EL). Despite of numerous studies about SCA and TCA, none has focused on the investigation of existing EL definitions and adaption of point-scale SCA concept to two-dimensional pixel of digital elevation model (DEM). This work conducts a systematic research on rationality of existing EL definitions, proposal of new EL definition and concept of pixel-scale SCA on gridded DEM. To overcome the defects of existing EL definitions, a new EL definition based on Triangular Discretization and Spatial Geometry (TDSG) is proposed in this work. SCA concept is extended from point scale to pixel scale for adapting to context of gridded DEM. The solutions of true pixel-scale SCA, TCA, and EL in integral forms are deduced based on the solutions of point-scale SCAs obtained by method of Zhou and Liu (2002, &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;Link to external resource&quot; href=&quot;https://doi.org/10.1080/13658810210149425&quot;>;https://doi.org/10.1080/13658810210149425&lt;/a>;) or Gallant and Hutchinson (2011, &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;Link to external resource&quot; href=&quot;https://doi.org/10.1029/2009WR008540&quot;>;https://doi.org/10.1029/2009WR008540&lt;/a>;). Besides, true pixel-scale SCA, TCA, and EL are solved analytically for several synthetic surfaces. Numerical experiments indicate that (a) TDSG definition is superior to all existing EL definitions in physical mechanism, spatial characteristics, and computational precisions on synthetic surfaces and a real-world DEM. (b) Spatial characteristics of SCA are controlled mainly by TCA and tuned slightly by EL, while overall precision of SCA is affected seriously by both TCA and EL. (c) TDSG definition is the only EL definition of responding accurately and sensitively to convergent and dispersive characteristics of local terrains.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> Zhenya Li, Xijun Lai, Pengfei Shi, Tao Yang</dc:creator><category> Research Article</category><dc:title> An Algorithm‐Independent Definition of Effective Contour Length and Its Impacts on Pixel‐Scale Specific Catchment Area</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2022WR034036</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1029/2022WR034036</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR034036?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> Research Article</prism:section><prism:volume> 59</prism:volume><prism:number> 8</prism:number></item><item><link/> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2023WR034554?af=R<pubDate> Thu, 10 Aug 2023 10:19:16 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-08-10T10:19:16-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley: Water Resources Research: Table of Contents<prism:coverdate> Tue, 01 Aug 2023 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate> Tue, 01 Aug 2023 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2023WR034554</guid><title> Whitewater Sound Dependence on Discharge and Wave Configuration at an Adjustable Wave Feature</title><description> Water Resources Research, Volume 59, Issue 8, August 2023.</description><dc:description> Abstract Stream acoustics has been proposed as a means of monitoring discharge and wave hazards from outside the stream channel. To better understand the dependence of sound on discharge and wave characteristics, this study analyzes discharge and infrasound data from an artificial wave feature which is adjusted to accommodate daily changes in recreational use and seasonal changes in irrigation demand. Monitorable sound is only observed when discharge exceeds ∼35 m3/s, and even above that threshold the sound‐discharge relationship is non‐linear and inconsistent. When sound is observed, it shows consistent dependence on wave type within a given year, but the direction of this dependence varies among the 3 years studied (2016, 2021, and 2022). These findings support previous research that establishes discharge and stream morphology as relevant controls on stream acoustics and highlights the complex, combined effects of these variables.</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;Stream acoustics has been proposed as a means of monitoring discharge and wave hazards from outside the stream channel. To better understand the dependence of sound on discharge and wave characteristics, this study analyzes discharge and infrasound data from an artificial wave feature which is adjusted to accommodate daily changes in recreational use and seasonal changes in irrigation demand. Monitorable sound is only observed when discharge exceeds ∼35 m&lt;sup>;3&lt;/sup>;/s, and even above that threshold the sound-discharge relationship is non-linear and inconsistent. When sound is observed, it shows consistent dependence on wave type within a given year, but the direction of this dependence varies among the 3 years studied (2016, 2021, and 2022). These findings support previous research that establishes discharge and stream morphology as relevant controls on stream acoustics and highlights the complex, combined effects of these variables.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> Taylor A. Tatum, Jacob F. Anderson, Timothy J. Ronan</dc:creator><category> Research Article</category><dc:title> Whitewater Sound Dependence on Discharge and Wave Configuration at an Adjustable Wave Feature</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2023WR034554</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1029/2023WR034554</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2023WR034554?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> Research Article</prism:section><prism:volume> 59</prism:volume><prism:number> 8</prism:number></item><item><link/> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033453?af=R<pubDate> Thu, 10 Aug 2023 10:15:18 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-08-10T10:15:18-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley: Water Resources Research: Table of Contents<prism:coverdate> Tue, 01 Aug 2023 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate> Tue, 01 Aug 2023 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR033453</guid><title> Cycles‐L: A Coupled, 3‐D, Land Surface, Hydrologic, and Agroecosystem Landscape Model</title><description> Water Resources Research, Volume 59, Issue 8, August 2023.</description><dc:description> Abstract Managing landscapes to increase agricultural productivity and environmental stewardship can be informed by spatially‐distributed models that operate at spatial and temporal scales that are intervention‐relevant. This paper presents Cycles‐L, a landscape‐scale agroecosystem and hydrologic modeling system, using as a test case a watershed in Pennsylvania. Cycles‐L emerges from melding the landscape and hydrology structure of Flux‐PIHM, a 3‐D land surface hydrologic model, with the agroecosystem processes in the Cycles model. Consequently, Cycles‐L can simulate processes affected by topography, soil heterogeneity, and management practices, owing to its physically‐based hydrology that can simulate horizontal and vertical transport of solutes with water. The model was tested at a 730‐ha experimental watershed within the Mahantango Creek watershed. Cycles‐L simulated well stream water and mineral nitrogen discharge (Nash‐Sutcliffe coefficient 0.55 and 0.60, respectively) and grain yield (root mean square error 1.2 Mg ha−1). Cycles‐L outputs are as good or better than those obtained with the uncoupled Flux‐PIHM (water discharge) and Cycles (grain yield) models. Modeled spatial patterns of nitrogen fluxes like denitrification illustrate the combined control of crop management and topography. For example, denitrification is almost twice as high when simulated with Cycles‐L than when simulated with Cycles 1‐D. Due to its spatial and temporal resolution, Cycles‐L fills a gap in the availability of models that operate at a scale relevant to evaluate interventions in the landscape. Cycles‐L can become a central component in tools for climate change scenario analysis, precision agriculture, precision conservation, and artificial intelligence‐based decision support systems.</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;Managing landscapes to increase agricultural productivity and environmental stewardship can be informed by spatially-distributed models that operate at spatial and temporal scales that are intervention-relevant. This paper presents Cycles-L, a landscape-scale agroecosystem and hydrologic modeling system, using as a test case a watershed in Pennsylvania. Cycles-L emerges from melding the landscape and hydrology structure of Flux-PIHM, a 3-D land surface hydrologic model, with the agroecosystem processes in the Cycles model. Consequently, Cycles-L can simulate processes affected by topography, soil heterogeneity, and management practices, owing to its physically-based hydrology that can simulate horizontal and vertical transport of solutes with water. The model was tested at a 730-ha experimental watershed within the Mahantango Creek watershed. Cycles-L simulated well stream water and mineral nitrogen discharge (Nash-Sutcliffe coefficient 0.55 and 0.60, respectively) and grain yield (root mean square error 1.2 Mg ha&lt;sup>;−1&lt;/sup>;). Cycles-L outputs are as good or better than those obtained with the uncoupled Flux-PIHM (water discharge) and Cycles (grain yield) models. Modeled spatial patterns of nitrogen fluxes like denitrification illustrate the combined control of crop management and topography. For example, denitrification is almost twice as high when simulated with Cycles-L than when simulated with Cycles 1-D. Due to its spatial and temporal resolution, Cycles-L fills a gap in the availability of models that operate at a scale relevant to evaluate interventions in the landscape. Cycles-L can become a central component in tools for climate change scenario analysis, precision agriculture, precision conservation, and artificial intelligence-based decision support systems.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> Yuning Shi, Felipe Montes, Armen R. Kemanian</dc:creator><category> Research Article</category><dc:title> Cycles‐L: A Coupled, 3‐D, Land Surface, Hydrologic, and Agroecosystem Landscape Model</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2022WR033453</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1029/2022WR033453</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033453?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> Research Article</prism:section><prism:volume> 59</prism:volume><prism:number> 8</prism:number></item><item><link/> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2023WR034920?af=R<pubDate> Thu, 10 Aug 2023 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-08-10T12:00:00-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley: Water Resources Research: Table of Contents <prism:coverdate></prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate></prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2023WR034920</guid><title> On groundwater recharge in variably‐saturated subsurface flow models</title><description> Water Resources Research, Accepted Article.</description><dc:description> Abstract Groundwater models that simulate only saturated flow use groundwater recharge as an input parameter. In contrast, variably‐saturated subsurface flow models, including integrated surface and subsurface hydrologic models, can jointly simulate the movement of water in the saturated and unsaturated zones. Instead of recharge, they require climate data such as precipitation and potential evapotranspiration. Given that the latter models represent hydrological processes operating throughout the unsaturated zone and at the water table, one might expect that recharge can be readily extracted from them. In this paper, we demonstrate that it is not the case. When the commonly used definitions of groundwater recharge are implemented in variably‐saturated subsurface flow models, they do not yield meaningful results. Above all, the problems occur because of the storage dynamics in the capillary fringe above the water table. Despite this difficulty, variably‐saturated subsurface flow models can provide the information required for water resources management directly. This article is protected by copyright.版权所有。</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;Groundwater models that simulate only saturated flow use groundwater recharge as an input parameter. In contrast, variably-saturated subsurface flow models, including integrated surface and subsurface hydrologic models, can jointly simulate the movement of water in the saturated and unsaturated zones. Instead of recharge, they require climate data such as precipitation and potential evapotranspiration. Given that the latter models represent hydrological processes operating throughout the unsaturated zone and at the water table, one might expect that recharge can be readily extracted from them. In this paper, we demonstrate that it is not the case. When the commonly used definitions of groundwater recharge are implemented in variably-saturated subsurface flow models, they do not yield meaningful results. Above all, the problems occur because of the storage dynamics in the capillary fringe above the water table. Despite this difficulty, variably-saturated subsurface flow models can provide the information required for water resources management directly.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This article is protected by copyright. All rights reserved.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> Chengcheng Gong, Peter G. Cook, René Therrien, Wenke Wang, Philip Brunner</dc:creator><category> Research Article</category><dc:title> On groundwater recharge in variably‐saturated subsurface flow models</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2023WR034920</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1029/2023WR034920</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2023WR034920?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> Research Article</prism:section></item></channel></rss>