<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:prism="http://prismstandard.org/namespaces/basic/2.0/"><channel><title> Wiley：水资源研究：目录</title><link/>https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R<description>水资源研究目录。最新期和 EarlyView 期的文章列表。</description><language> en-US</language><copyright></copyright><managingeditor> wileyonlinelibrary@wiley.com（AGU 出版物）</managingeditor><pubDate> Wed, 19 Jul 2023 07:45:40 +0000</pubDate><lastbuilddate> 2023 年 7 月 19 日星期三 07:45:40 +0000</lastbuilddate><generator> Atypon®文学™</generator><docs> https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs><ttl> 10080</ttl><dc:title> Wiley：水资源研究：目录</dc:title><dc:publisher>威利</dc:publisher><prism:publicationname>水资源研究</prism:publicationname><atom:link href="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"></atom:link><image/><title> Wiley：水资源研究：目录</title><url>https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/pb-assets/journal-banners/19447973.jpg</url><link/> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R<item><link/> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2023WR034484?af=R<pubDate> Tue, 18 Jul 2023 12:27:36 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-07-18T12:27:36-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley：水资源研究：目录<prism:coverdate>2023 年 7 月 1 日，星期六 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate> 2023 年 7 月 1 日，星期六 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2023WR034484</guid><title>河流的音乐：波浪数学揭示了水流机制的全球结构和驱动因素</title><description>《水资源研究》，第 59 卷，第 7 期，2023 年 7 月。</description><dc:description>摘要 河流流量的变化时间尺度从几分钟到几千年不等。这些流量振动受到全球多种因素的调节，例如水坝抑制多日变化或植被减弱某些生态系统中的洪峰。影响流动的物理、生物和人为因素的相对重要性是一个活跃的研究领域，寻找描述整体流动状态的通用语言的相关问题也是如此。在这里，我们使用 1988 年至 2016 年全球 3,000 多个站点的每日河流流量数据集来讨论这两个主题。我们首先研究了常见流态量化方法之间的相似性，包括传统流量度量、小波和傅里叶分析。在所有这些方法中，流动数据显示出低维结构（即简单且一致的模式），表明基本机制正在限制流动状态。其中一种模式是每日变异性与每年变异性呈负相关。此外，河流流量数据中的低维结构仅与少数流域特征密切相关，包括流域面积、降水和温度，但与生物群落、大坝表面积或大坝数量无关。我们在一个框架中讨论这些发现，旨在让从事河流研究和管理的许多社区都能接触到，同时强调让数据结构指导机械推理和跨学科讨论的重要性。</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;摘要&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;河流流量的变化时间尺度从几分钟到几千年不等。这些流量振动受到全球多种因素的调节，例如，水坝抑制了多日变化，或者植被减弱了某些生态系统中的洪峰。影响流动的物理、生物和人为因素的相对重要性是一个活跃的研究领域，寻找描述整体流动状态的通用语言的相关问题也是如此。在这里，我们使用 1988 年至 2016 年全球 3,000 多个站点的每日河流流量数据集来讨论这两个主题。我们首先研究了常见流态量化方法之间的相似性，包括传统流量度量、小波和傅里叶分析。在所有这些方法中，流动数据显示出低维结构（即简单且一致的模式），表明基本机制正在限制流动状态。其中一种模式是每日变异性与每年变异性呈负相关。此外，河流流量数据的低维结构仅与少数流域特征密切相关，包括流域面积、降水和温度，但与生物群落、大坝表面积或大坝数量无关。我们在一个旨在让从事河流研究和管理的许多社区都能访问的框架中讨论这些发现，同时强调让数据结构指导机械推理和跨学科讨论的重要性。&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> Brian C. Brown、Aimee H. Fulerton、Darin Kopp、Flavia Tromboni、Arial J. Shogren、J. Angus Webb、Claire Ruffing、Matthew Heaton、Lenka Kuglerová、Daniel C. Allen、Lillian McGill、Jay P. Zarnetske、Matt R . 威尔斯，杰里米·B·琼斯，本杰明·W·阿博特</dc:creator><category>研究文章</category><dc:title>河流的音乐：波浪数学揭示了水流机制的全球结构和驱动因素</dc:title><dc:identifier>10.1029/2023WR034484</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname>水资源研究</prism:publicationname><prism:doi>10.1029/2023WR034484</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2023WR034484?af=R</prism:url><prism:section>研究文章</prism:section><prism:volume>59</prism:volume><prism:number> 7</prism:number></item><item><link/> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2023WR034493?af=R<pubDate> Tue, 18 Jul 2023 12:19:40 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-07-18T12:19:40-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley：水资源研究：目录<prism:coverdate>2023 年 7 月 1 日，星期六 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate> 2023 年 7 月 1 日，星期六 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2023WR034493</guid><title>临界区建筑和积雪对径流生成过程的影响：地中海气候下的山地草甸水源系统</title><description>《水资源研究》，第 59 卷，第 7 期，2023 年 7 月。</description><dc:description>摘要：对地中海气候下花岗岩流域的观测揭示了加利福尼亚州内华达山脉草甸系统内常年溪流源头及其上升贡献区的水文和关键区域功能。化学分析（混合模型的诊断工具、端元混合分析、氚等）和物理数据（水位、渗压计、土壤水、积雪等）表明，有两种主要的水输入源头水流的途径来自高山草甸。一个输入是一条较浅、较年轻的地下通道，其中含有类似于积雪化学的水，另一个输入是一条更深、更古老的地下通道，其中含有水，反映了来自山坡的地下水的化学成分。多年的观察表明，无论积雪量如何，在山坡渗透高峰期，山坡上的浅层和深层路径的行为与源头溪流的启动相似。然而，在夏季干旱期间，高积雪年和低积雪年之间草甸中心内活动路径的相似性不保持。由于降雪减少，草甸中心内的常年地下水排放被消除，成为草甸出口处的季节性水源。在草甸边缘，地球物理观察到的下坡腐泥土厚度变薄，通过增强上坡水的地下水排放，减少了横向透射率和源头水流的起始点。综合起来，这些发现表明积雪和关键区域结构的损失如何共同调节地中海气候湿草甸系统的水文功能。对气候变化下源头湿草甸系统水力功能的稳定性产生新的认识。</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;摘要&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;对地中海气候下花岗岩流域的观测揭示了加利福尼亚州内华达山脉草甸系统内常年溪流源头及其上升贡献区的水文和关键区域功能。化学分析（混合模型的诊断工具、端元混合分析、氚等）和物理数据（水位、渗压计、土壤水、积雪等）表明，有两种主要的水输入源头水流的途径来自高山草甸。一个输入是一条较浅、较年轻的地下通道，其中含有类似于积雪化学的水，另一个输入是一条更深、更古老的地下通道，其中含有水，反映了来自山坡的地下水的化学成分。多年的观察表明，无论积雪量如何，在山坡渗透峰值期间，山坡上的浅层和深层路径的行为与源头溪流的启动相似。然而，在夏季干旱期间，高积雪年和低积雪年之间草甸中心内活动路径的相似性不保持。由于降雪减少，草甸中心内的常年地下水排放被消除，成为草甸出口处的季节性水源。在草甸边缘，地球物理观察到的下坡腐泥土厚度变薄，通过增强上坡水的地下水排放，减少了横向透射率和源头水流的起始点。综合起来，这些发现表明积雪和关键区域结构的损失如何共同调节地中海气候湿草甸系统的水文功能。对气候变化下源头湿草甸系统水力功能的稳定性有了新的认识。&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> PZ Klos、RG 卢卡斯、MH 康克林</dc:creator><category>研究文章</category><dc:title>临界区建筑和积雪对径流生成过程的影响：地中海气候下的山地草甸水源系统</dc:title><dc:identifier>10.1029/2023WR034493</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname>水资源研究</prism:publicationname><prism:doi>10.1029/2023WR034493</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2023WR034493?af=R</prism:url><prism:section>研究文章</prism:section><prism:volume>59</prism:volume><prism:number> 7</prism:number></item><item><link/> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2023WR034910?af=R<pubDate> Tue, 18 Jul 2023 07:18:56 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-07-18T07:18:56-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley：水资源研究：目录<prism:coverdate></prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate></prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2023WR034910</guid><title>重新审视用于评估浓度-排放关系的幂律分析的起源</title><description>水资源研究，已接受文章。</description><dc:description>摘要 浓度-排放（C-Q）关系经常用于理解流域物质输出的控制。这些分析通常使用对数幂律函数 (C=aQb) 来确定 C 和 Q 之间的关系。C-Q 分析中幂律的使用可以追溯到 Francis Hall 的两篇开创性论文（1970 年、1971 年）他比较了六个日益复杂的水文模型，得出幂律具有最大解释力的结论。然而，霍尔的分析和结论是基于有限的数据集，并假设了水量和储存量，并使用了简单的模型选择标准。虽然幂律应用广泛，但 50 多年来一直没有经过严格的测试和评估。我们使用八年的高频和每周比电导数据重新检查了霍尔在时间尺度上的原始模型，并使用更复杂的模型选择标准评估了模型性能。虽然我们发现幂律分析仍然是性能最好的模型之一，但其他模型的性能也同样好，包括对数线性函数形式。模型性能在次日到每周尺度上相似，但随采样方法的不同而变化。相对于更简单的模型，更复杂的模型表现较差，并且由于模型参数与观测数据拟合的限制，往往会低估流量极值时的浓度。虽然我们根据此处分析的数据得出结论，幂律仍然是 C-Q 分析的合适模型，但仍有机会根据数据分布、衰退分析和预测的基本假设来完善和区分 C-Q 模型。将模型应用于反应性溶质。</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;摘要&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;浓度-排放 (CQ) 关系经常用于了解流域物质输出的控制。这些分析通常使用对数幂律函数 (C=aQ&lt;sup>;b&lt;/sup>;) 来确定 C 和 Q 之间的关系。在 CQ 分析中使用幂律可以追溯到 Francis 的两篇开创性论文Hall（1970，1971）比较了六种日益复杂的水文模型，得出幂律具有最大解释力的结论。然而，霍尔的分析和结论是基于有限的数据集，并假设了水量和储存量，并使用了简单的模型选择标准。虽然幂律应用广泛，但 50 多年来并未经过严格的测试和评估。我们使用八年的高频和每周比电导数据重新检查了霍尔在时间尺度上的原始模型，并使用更复杂的模型选择标准评估了模型性能。虽然我们发现幂律分析仍然是性能最好的模型之一，但其他模型的性能也同样好，包括对数线性函数形式。模型性能在次日到每周尺度上相似，但随采样方法的不同而变化。相对于更简单的模型，更复杂的模型表现较差，并且由于模型参数与观测数据拟合的限制，往往会低估流量极值时的浓度。虽然我们根据此处分析的数据得出结论，幂律仍然是 CQ 分析的合适模型，但仍有机会根据数据分布、衰退分析的基本假设来完善和区分 CQ 模型，并将模型应用于反应性分析。溶质。&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> Adam S. Wymore、William Larsen、Dustin W. Kincaid、Kristen L. Underwood、Hannah M. Fazekas、William H. McDowell、Desneiges S. Murray、Arial J. Shogren、Shannon L. Speir、Alex J. Webster</dc:creator><category>研究文章</category><dc:title>重新审视用于评估浓度-排放关系的幂律分析的起源</dc:title><dc:identifier>10.1029/2023WR034910</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname>水资源研究</prism:publicationname><prism:doi>10.1029/2023WR034910</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2023WR034910?af=R</prism:url><prism:section>研究文章</prism:section></item><item><link/>https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR034315?af=R<pubDate> Tue, 18 Jul 2023 07:18:55 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-07-18T07:18:55-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley：水资源研究：目录<prism:coverdate></prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate></prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR034315</guid><title>南阿巴拉契亚山脉大型传感器网络土壤湿度的地形驱动因素（美国）</title><description>水资源研究，已接受文章。</description><dc:description>摘要：在地形复杂的地区，了解土壤湿度的分布非常困难，这些地区既受到大尺度气候梯度的影响，又受到地形、植被和土壤结构的细尺度影响。遥感方法可以捕获大规模的湿度模式，但空间和时间分辨率有限，而商业现场传感器仍然过于昂贵，无法在大空间范围内集中部署。在这里，我们演示了如何使用低成本（&lt;20 美元）定制传感器创建大烟山国家公园（北卡罗来纳州、田纳西州、美国）。在实验室测试中，温度校准的 VMC 值接近商业探头的精度。我们在多个流域、地形位置和 1800 米海拔梯度上部署了 80 多个传感器，并创建了分层模型来了解 VMC 与与供水和需求相关的空间（30 米分辨率）和时间（每日）变量的关联。海拔与 VMC 的相关性最强，梯度增加 5 倍，反映出降水（增加）和蒸散量（减少）1.5 倍的变化；坡度角度是一个强有力的中介因素。包括地形收敛指数 (TCI) 在内的常见湿度指标与 VMC 无关，这可能是由于地表排水对当地水平衡的贡献有限。我们的模型预测一组验证传感器的每日 VMC，均方根误差为 4.8%，这可以通过特定地点的现场校准来改进。我们的研究表明，空间广泛、基于现场的土壤湿度网络实用、准确，是区域环境监测的重要组成部分。</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;在地形复杂的地区，了解土壤水分的分布非常困难，这些地区既受到大尺度气候梯度的影响，又受到地形、植被和土壤结构的细尺度影响。遥感方法可以捕获大规模的湿度模式，但空间和时间分辨率有限，而商业现场传感器仍然过于昂贵，无法在大空间范围内集中部署。在这里，我们演示了如何使用低成本（&lt;20 美元）定制传感器创建大烟山国家公园（北卡罗来纳州、田纳西州）地表（0-15 厘米深）体积土壤水分含量 (VMC) 的大型监测网络， 美国）。在实验室测试中，温度校准的 VMC 值接近商业探头的精度。我们在多个流域、地形位置和 1800 米海拔梯度上部署了 80 多个传感器，并创建了分层模型来了解 VMC 与与供水和需求相关的空间（30 米分辨率）和时间（每日）变量的关联。海拔与 VMC 的相关性最强，梯度增加 5 倍，反映出降水量（增加）和蒸散量（减少）变化 1.5 倍；坡度角度是一个强有力的中介因素。包括地形收敛指数 (TCI) 在内的常见湿度指标与 VMC 无关，这可能是由于地表排水对当地水平衡的贡献有限。我们的模型预测一组验证传感器的每日 VMC，均方根误差为 4.8%，这可以通过特定地点的现场校准来改进。我们的研究表明，空间广泛、基于现场的土壤湿度网络实用、准确，是区域环境监测的重要组成部分。&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator>乔丹·R·斯塔克、杰森·D·弗里德利</dc:creator><category>研究文章</category><dc:title>南阿巴拉契亚山脉大型传感器网络土壤湿度的地形驱动因素（美国）</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2022WR034315</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname>水资源研究</prism:publicationname><prism:doi>10.1029/2022WR034315</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR034315?af=R</prism:url><prism:section>研究文章</prism:section></item><item><link/>https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2023WR034867?af=R<pubDate> Mon, 17 Jul 2023 08:09:52 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-07-17T08:09:52-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley：水资源研究：目录<prism:coverdate>2023 年 7 月 1 日，星期六 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate> 2023 年 7 月 1 日，星期六 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2023WR034867</guid><title>通过探索基于场景的方法来设计配水管网的多目标优化模型</title><description>《水资源研究》，第 59 卷，第 7 期，2023 年 7 月。</description><dc:description>摘要 由于用水者的行为不可预测，配水管网（WDN）的需求是一个偶然变量。因此，这是该基础设施设计存在不确定性的主要原因之一。不断增加的需水数据集为通过结合统计和优化方法来改进 WDN 的传统确定性设计方法提供了机会。鲁棒优化 (RO) 通过研究在任何可能的需求场景（即 WDN 生命周期内此变量的任何可能实现）下表现良好的解决方案来考虑需求不确定性。因此，正确选择场景对于确保设计网络的可靠性至关重要。本文提出了一种生成场景的统计方法，用于解决稳健的设计优化问题。它涉及三个步骤：(a) 对历史数据进行描述性分析，以得出 WDN 每个节点高峰时段需求的边际分布，(b) 通过从节点的相关边际分布进行分层采样来生成大量快照峰值需求，(c) 通过减少快照数量生成峰值需求场景。提出了两种启发式技术来减少快照的数量，并且对于每种技术，派生出两种不同数量的场景。解决了两个多目标 RO 模型：第一个模型包括成本最小化和均值方差广义弹性和故障指数最大化目标，第二个模型还考虑最大未交付需求的最小化，使用后悔函数进行形式化。</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;由于用水者的行为不可预测，配水管网 (WDN) 的需求是一个偶然变量。因此，这是该基础设施设计存在不确定性的主要原因之一。不断增加的需水数据集为通过结合统计和优化方法来改进 WDN 的传统确定性设计方法提供了机会。鲁棒优化 (RO) 通过研究在任何可能的需求场景（即 WDN 生命周期内此变量的任何可能实现）下表现良好的解决方案来考虑需求不确定性。因此，正确选择场景对于确保设计网络的可靠性至关重要。本文提出了一种生成场景的统计方法，用于解决稳健的设计优化问题。它涉及三个步骤：(a) 对历史数据进行描述性分析，以得出 WDN 每个节点高峰时段需求的边际分布，(b) 通过从节点的相关边际分布进行分层采样来生成大量快照峰值需求，(c) 通过减少快照数量生成峰值需求场景。提出了两种启发式技术来减少快照的数量，并且对于每种技术，派生出两种不同数量的场景。解决了两个多目标 RO 模型：第一个模型包括成本最小化和均值方差广义弹性和故障指数最大化目标，第二个模型还考虑最大未交付需求的最小化，使用后悔函数进行形式化。&lt;/ p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> MC Cunha、R. Magini、J. Marques</dc:creator><category>研究文章</category><dc:title>通过探索基于场景的方法来设计配水管网的多目标优化模型</dc:title><dc:identifier>10.1029/2023WR034867</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname>水资源研究</prism:publicationname><prism:doi>10.1029/2023WR034867</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2023WR034867?af=R</prism:url><prism:section>研究文章</prism:section><prism:volume>59</prism:volume><prism:number> 7</prism:number></item><item><link/> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2023WR034718?af=R<pubDate> Mon, 17 Jul 2023 08:06:49 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-07-17T08:06:49-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley：水资源研究：目录<prism:coverdate></prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate></prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2023WR034718</guid><title>复合洪水事件相关性建模与评价系统框架</title><description>水资源研究，已接受文章。</description><dc:description>摘要 不同河流、不同地区的洪水过程的重合和叠加往往会形成复合洪水事件，这是由不同洪水过程之间的空间关系决定的，现有的相关性分析方法无法准确描述和评估。开发了一个集成多维 vine copula 模型和依赖性评估系统的框架，并以面向测试的应用程序来探索从已识别的复合洪水事件中提取的两种极端径流序列（峰值流量和洪水量）之间的潜在依赖性。长江上游。建立多维规则藤蔓（R-vine）系词模型来描述复杂多样的依赖关系，并通过藤结构阵列指定相应的藤结构，该藤结构阵列可以反映支流流入干流的顺序和空间位置。不同的水文测站。根据最优R-vine copula模型和信息论计算并比较依赖程度和关联状态。与现有方法的比较表明，相关性评价体系能够反映非线性和局部相关性特征，消除其他水文站极端径流序列对相关性的影响。考虑到支流洪水来流的影响，长江上游不同极端径流序列与其支流之间的关联状况呈现出多样性。该框架可以作为复合洪水依赖性建模和评估的有效方法，从而为水资源系统的风险分析提供科学参考。本文受版权保护。版权所有。</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;不同河流、不同地区的洪水过程的重合和叠加往往会形成复合洪水事件，这是由不同洪水过程之间的空间关系决定的，现有的依赖分析方法无法准确描述和评估。开发了一个集成多维 vine copula 模型和相关性评估系统的框架，并以面向测试的应用程序来探索从已识别的复合洪水事件中提取的两种极端径流序列（峰值流量和洪水量）之间的潜在相关性。长江上游。建立多维规则藤蔓（R-vine）系词模型来描述复杂多样的依赖关系，并通过藤结构阵列指定相应的藤结构，该藤结构阵列可以反映支流流入干流的顺序和空间位置。不同的水文测站。根据最优R-vine copula模型和信息论计算并比较依赖程度和关联状态。与现有方法的比较表明，相关性评价体系能够反映非线性和局部相关性特征，消除其他水文站极端径流序列对相关性的影响。考虑到支流洪水来流的影响，长江上游不同极端径流序列与其支流之间的关联状况呈现出多样性。该框架可以作为复合洪水依赖性建模和评估的有效方法，从而为水资源系统的风险分析提供科学参考。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;本文受版权保护。保留所有权利。&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator>王旭、沉永明</dc:creator><category>研究文章</category><dc:title>复合洪水事件相关性建模与评价系统框架</dc:title><dc:identifier>10.1029/2023WR034718</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname>水资源研究</prism:publicationname><prism:doi>10.1029/2023WR034718</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2023WR034718?af=R</prism:url><prism:section>研究文章</prism:section></item><item><link/>https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033854?af=R<pubDate> Mon, 17 Jul 2023 08:05:47 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-07-17T08:05:47-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley：水资源研究：目录<prism:coverdate></prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate></prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR033854</guid><title>乐于控制：控制大型城市排水系统的启发式和预测性策略</title><description>水资源研究，已接受的文章。</description><dc:description>摘要 城市排水系统（UDS）的模型预测控制（MPC）已被建立为一种经济有效的减少污染的方法。然而，大型UDS（包含超过20个执行器）的运行只能通过过度简化UDS动力学来优化，可能导致性能下降和用户信任度降低，从而抑制MPC程序的广泛实施。建立了启发式和预测策略（HAPPy），依赖于对 UDS 功能影响最大的执行器的动态选择，并实时优化这些执行器。其余执行器遵循预设的启发式程序。 HAPPy 程序应用于鹿特丹的两个独立的 UDS，控制目标是最大限度地减少两个案例中的溢出量。获得的结果表明，执行器对 UDS 功能的影响程度在事件期间发生变化，并且可以使用随机森林算法进行预测。这些预测可用于提供近乎全局的最佳执行器设置，从而使 HAPPy 程序的性能可与全 MPC 控制相媲美，并优于启发式控制程序。为获得接近全局最优设置而选择的执行器数量取决于 UDS 和降雨特性，随着执行器数量的增加，显示出渐近 RTC 性能。 HAPPy 程序对于中型和大型降雨事件表现出不同的 RTC 动态，前者比后者表现出更高水平的可控性。对于中等事件，相对少量的执行器就足以实现潜在的性能改进。本文受版权保护。版权所有。</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;摘要&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;城市排水系统 (UDS) 的模型预测控制 (MPC) 已被建立为一种经济有效的减少污染的方法。然而，大型UDS（包含超过20个执行器）的运行只能通过过度简化UDS动力学来优化，可能导致性能下降和用户信任度降低，从而抑制MPC程序的广泛实施。建立了启发式和预测策略（HAPPy），依赖于对 UDS 功能影响最大的执行器的动态选择，并实时优化这些执行器。其余执行器遵循预设的启发式程序。 HAPPy 程序应用于鹿特丹的两个独立的 UDS，控制目标是最大限度地减少两个案例中的溢出量。获得的结果表明，执行器对 UDS 功能的影响程度在事件期间发生变化，并且可以使用随机森林算法进行预测。这些预测可用于提供近乎全局的最佳执行器设置，从而使 HAPPy 程序的性能可与全 MPC 控制相媲美，并优于启发式控制程序。为获得接近全局最佳设置而选择的执行器数量取决于 UDS 和降雨特性，随着执行器数量的增加，显示出渐近 RTC 性能。 HAPPy 程序对于中型和大型降雨事件表现出不同的 RTC 动态，前者比后者表现出更高水平的可控性。对于中等事件，相对较少数量的执行器足以实现潜在的性能改进。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;本文受版权保护。保留所有权利。&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> JA Werf、Z. Kapelan、JG Langeveld</dc:creator><category>研究文章</category><dc:title>乐于控制：控制大型城市排水系统的启发式和预测性策略</dc:title><dc:identifier>10.1029/2022WR033854</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname>水资源研究</prism:publicationname><prism:doi>10.1029/2022WR033854</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033854?af=R</prism:url><prism:section>研究文章</prism:section></item><item><link/>https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR034271?af=R<pubDate> Mon, 17 Jul 2023 08:05:35 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-07-17T08:05:35-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley：水资源研究：目录<prism:coverdate></prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate></prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR034271</guid><title>土壤异质性、佩克莱特数和不饱和输运空间变扩散的控制</title><description>水资源研究，已接受的文章。</description><dc:description>摘要 土壤的物理性质普遍存在异质性。这种空间变异性对保守交通具有深远但仍部分被理解的影响。此外，分子扩散通常是一个被忽视的过程，它可能对运输产生重要的反直觉影响：扩散可以通过动员否则被困在低速区域的质量来防止非菲克拖尾。在这里，我们关注呈现小尺度异质性的宏观均质土壤，如米勒-米勒理论所描述的。 We then analyze the dynamic control of soil heterogeneity, advection and diffusion on conservative transport. We focus especially on the importance of diffusion and of its tortuosity‐dependent spatial variability on the overall transport. Our results confirm previous finding that relatively high Péclet number systems are highly sensitive to the degree of heterogeneity, which promotes non‐Fickian transport. Also, diffusion appears to have a profound impact on transport, depending on both the degree of heterogeneity and the Péclet number. For a high Péclet number and a very heterogeneous system, diffusion leads to the counter‐intuitive decrease of non‐Fickian spreading described previously. This is not observed for a low Péclet number due to the impact of the spatial variability in the diffusion coefficient, which appears to be a significant controlling factor of transport by promoting or preventing the accumulation of mass in low velocity zones. Globally, this work (1) highlights the complex, synergistic effect of soil heterogeneity, advective fluxes and diffusion on transport and (2), alerts on potential upscaling challenges when the spatial variability of such key processes cannot be properly described. This article is protected by copyright.版权所有。</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;Physical properties of soils are ubiquitously heterogeneous. This spatial variability has a profound, yet still partially understood, impact on conservative transport. Moreover, molecular diffusion is often a disregarded process that can have an important counter-intuitive effect on transport: diffusion can prevent non-Fickian tailing by mobilizing mass otherwise trapped in low velocity zones. Here, we focus on macroscopically homogeneous soils presenting small scale heterogeneity, as described by the Miller-Miller theory. We then analyze the dynamic control of soil heterogeneity, advection and diffusion on conservative transport. We focus especially on the importance of diffusion and of its tortuosity-dependent spatial variability on the overall transport. Our results confirm previous finding that relatively high Péclet number systems are highly sensitive to the degree of heterogeneity, which promotes non-Fickian transport. Also, diffusion appears to have a profound impact on transport, depending on both the degree of heterogeneity and the Péclet number. For a high Péclet number and a very heterogeneous system, diffusion leads to the counter-intuitive decrease of non-Fickian spreading described previously. This is not observed for a low Péclet number due to the impact of the spatial variability in the diffusion coefficient, which appears to be a significant controlling factor of transport by promoting or preventing the accumulation of mass in low velocity zones. Globally, this work (1) highlights the complex, synergistic effect of soil heterogeneity, advective fluxes and diffusion on transport and (2), alerts on potential upscaling challenges when the spatial variability of such key processes cannot be properly described.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This article is protected by copyright. All rights reserved.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> Christopher V. Henri, Efstathios Diamantopoulos</dc:creator><category> Research Article</category><dc:title> On the Control of Soil Heterogeneity, Péclet number and Spatially Variable Diffusion over Unsaturated Transport</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2022WR034271</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1029/2022WR034271</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR034271?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> Research Article</prism:section></item><item><link/> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2023WR034593?af=R<pubDate> Mon, 17 Jul 2023 08:05:11 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-07-17T08:05:11-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley: Water Resources Research: Table of Contents <prism:coverdate></prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate></prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2023WR034593</guid><title> Effects of multiple drivers of environmental change on native and invasive macroalgae in nearshore groundwater dependent ecosystems</title><description> Water Resources Research, Accepted Article.</description><dc:description> Abstract Groundwater dependent ecosystems (GDE) are increasingly recognized as critical components of sustainable groundwater management, but are threatened by multiple drivers of environmental change. Despite this importance, data that link drivers of hydrologic change to GDEs are scarce. This study adapts a land‐sea modeling framework by calibrating marine models with macroalgal experiments to quantitatively assess impacts of climate and land use change on submarine groundwater discharge (SGD) and subsequent habitat suitability for a native (Ulva lactuca) and an invasive (Hypnea musciformis) macroalgae in nearshore GDEs in Kona, Hawai&#39;i. Lab analyses demonstrate that while U. lactuca grows optimally in low‐salinity, high‐nutrient waters, H. musciformis appears constrained to a salinity threshold and exhibits low growth in low salinity despite high nutrient concentrations. Land‐sea model results predict that while a dry future climate (Representative Concentration Pathway 8.5 mid‐century) coupled with increased urban development will likely reduce SGD, protecting native forests may prevent further loss of SGD quantity. This prevention thus partially mitigates the decline in habitat suitability of U. lactuca due to the combined effects of climate and land use change. Findings also suggest that, in contrast to the native U. lactuca, reductions in SGD may favor H. musciformis growth if introduced to Kona. Collectively, this study demonstrates the importance of considering multiple drivers of environmental change on GDEs. This study bridges experiments with models to spatially map changes in species abundance beyond their current habitat conditions, and thus informs management actions that can explicitly incorporate future human and climate‐related impacts. This article is protected by copyright.版权所有。</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;Groundwater dependent ecosystems (GDE) are increasingly recognized as critical components of sustainable groundwater management, but are threatened by multiple drivers of environmental change. Despite this importance, data that link drivers of hydrologic change to GDEs are scarce. This study adapts a land-sea modeling framework by calibrating marine models with macroalgal experiments to quantitatively assess impacts of climate and land use change on submarine groundwater discharge (SGD) and subsequent habitat suitability for a native (&lt;i>;Ulva lactuca&lt;/i>;) and an invasive (&lt;i>;Hypnea musciformis&lt;/i>;) macroalgae in nearshore GDEs in Kona, Hawai&#39;i. Lab analyses demonstrate that while &lt;i>;U. lactuca&lt;/i>; grows optimally in low-salinity, high-nutrient waters, &lt;i>;H. musciformis&lt;/i>; appears constrained to a salinity threshold and exhibits low growth in low salinity despite high nutrient concentrations. Land-sea model results predict that while a dry future climate (Representative Concentration Pathway 8.5 mid-century) coupled with increased urban development will likely reduce SGD, protecting native forests may prevent further loss of SGD quantity. This prevention thus partially mitigates the decline in habitat suitability of &lt;i>;U. lactuca&lt;/i>; due to the combined effects of climate and land use change. Findings also suggest that, in contrast to the native &lt;i>;U. lactuca&lt;/i>;, reductions in SGD may favor &lt;i>;H. musciformis&lt;/i>; growth if introduced to Kona. Collectively, this study demonstrates the importance of considering multiple drivers of environmental change on GDEs. This study bridges experiments with models to spatially map changes in species abundance beyond their current habitat conditions, and thus informs management actions that can explicitly incorporate future human and climate-related impacts.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This article is protected by copyright. All rights reserved.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> BK Okuhata, JMS Delevaux, A. Richards Donà, CM Smith, VL Gibson, H. Dulai, AI El‐Kadi, K. Stamoulis, KM Burnett, CA Wada, LL Bremer</dc:creator><category> Research Article</category><dc:title> Effects of multiple drivers of environmental change on native and invasive macroalgae in nearshore groundwater dependent ecosystems</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2023WR034593</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1029/2023WR034593</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2023WR034593?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> Research Article</prism:section></item><item><link/> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2023WR034446?af=R<pubDate> Mon, 17 Jul 2023 08:05:09 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-07-17T08:05:09-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley: Water Resources Research: Table of Contents <prism:coverdate></prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate></prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2023WR034446</guid><title> Definition of spatial copula based dependence using a family of non‐Gaussian spatial random fields</title><description> Water Resources Research, Accepted Article.</description><dc:description> Abstract Spatial structures of natural variables are often very complex due to the different physical chemical or biological processes which contributed to the emergence of the fields. These structures often show non‐Gaussian spatial dependence. Unfortunately, there are only a limited number of approaches that can explicitly consider non‐Gaussian behavior. In this contribution, a very flexible way of defining non‐Gaussian spatial dependence is presented. The approach is based on a kind of continuous deformation of fields with different Gaussian spatial dependence. Theoretical examples illustrate the methodology for a wide variety of non‐Gaussian structures. A real‐life example of groundwater quality parameters shows the practical applicability of the geostatistical model. This article is protected by copyright.版权所有。</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;Spatial structures of natural variables are often very complex due to the different physical chemical or biological processes which contributed to the emergence of the fields. These structures often show non-Gaussian spatial dependence. Unfortunately, there are only a limited number of approaches that can explicitly consider non-Gaussian behavior. In this contribution, a very flexible way of defining non-Gaussian spatial dependence is presented. The approach is based on a kind of continuous deformation of fields with different Gaussian spatial dependence. Theoretical examples illustrate the methodology for a wide variety of non-Gaussian structures. A real-life example of groundwater quality parameters shows the practical applicability of the geostatistical model.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This article is protected by copyright. All rights reserved.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> András Bárdossy, Sebastian Hörning</dc:creator><category> Research Article</category><dc:title> Definition of spatial copula based dependence using a family of non‐Gaussian spatial random fields</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2023WR034446</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1029/2023WR034446</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2023WR034446?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> Research Article</prism:section></item><item><link/> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2023WR034912?af=R<pubDate> Fri, 14 Jul 2023 08:59:35 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-07-14T08:59:35-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley: Water Resources Research: Table of Contents<prism:coverdate> Sat, 01 Jul 2023 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate> Sat, 01 Jul 2023 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2023WR034912</guid><title> Contribution of Fresh Submarine Groundwater Discharge to the Gulf of Alaska</title><description> Water Resources Research, Volume 59, Issue 7, July 2023.</description><dc:description> Abstract High latitude mountain environments are experiencing disproportionately adverse effects from climate change. The Gulf of Alaska (GoA) region is an embodiment of this change, particularly concerning a shifting hydrologic balance. Even so, the magnitude and contribution of fresh submarine groundwater discharge (fresh SGD) remains virtually unexplored within the region, though it has gained increasing attention globally due to its chemical significance and influence on coastal ecosystems. Here we provide the first regional estimates of fresh SGD to the GoA using two established water balance approaches. This is an effective way to distinguish the contribution of terrestrially derived fresh SGD, rather than the more commonly quantified total SGD which includes discharge that is driven by marine forces such as sea‐level oscillations and density gradients. We compare the approaches and assess their capabilities in computing the magnitude of fresh SGD over a large regional scale. Mean annual fresh SGD flux ranges between 26.5 and 86.8 km3 yr−1 to the GoA, equivalent to 3.5%–11.4% of the total freshwater discharge. Contributions are highest in the Southeastern panhandle and lowest in the Cook Inlet basin, with the highest area normalized contribution occurring in the Prince William Sound. Fresh SGD exhibits high spatial and temporal variability throughout the region. Although freshwater discharge to the GoA is investigated considerably, the importance of fresh SGD has, thus far, been overlooked.</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;High latitude mountain environments are experiencing disproportionately adverse effects from climate change. The Gulf of Alaska (GoA) region is an embodiment of this change, particularly concerning a shifting hydrologic balance. Even so, the magnitude and contribution of fresh submarine groundwater discharge (fresh SGD) remains virtually unexplored within the region, though it has gained increasing attention globally due to its chemical significance and influence on coastal ecosystems. Here we provide the first regional estimates of fresh SGD to the GoA using two established water balance approaches. This is an effective way to distinguish the contribution of terrestrially derived fresh SGD, rather than the more commonly quantified total SGD which includes discharge that is driven by marine forces such as sea-level oscillations and density gradients. We compare the approaches and assess their capabilities in computing the magnitude of fresh SGD over a large regional scale. Mean annual fresh SGD flux ranges between 26.5 and 86.8 km&lt;sup>;3&lt;/sup>; yr&lt;sup>;−1&lt;/sup>; to the GoA, equivalent to 3.5%–11.4% of the total freshwater discharge. Contributions are highest in the Southeastern panhandle and lowest in the Cook Inlet basin, with the highest area normalized contribution occurring in the Prince William Sound. Fresh SGD exhibits high spatial and temporal variability throughout the region. Although freshwater discharge to the GoA is investigated considerably, the importance of fresh SGD has, thus far, been overlooked.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> AA Russo, DF Boutt, LA Munk, J. Jenckes</dc:creator><category> Research Article</category><dc:title> Contribution of Fresh Submarine Groundwater Discharge to the Gulf of Alaska</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2023WR034912</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1029/2023WR034912</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2023WR034912?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> Research Article</prism:section><prism:volume> 59</prism:volume><prism:number> 7</prism:number></item><item><link/> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR034011?af=R<pubDate> Fri, 14 Jul 2023 08:56:52 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-07-14T08:56:52-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley: Water Resources Research: Table of Contents<prism:coverdate> Sat, 01 Jul 2023 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate> Sat, 01 Jul 2023 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR034011</guid><title> Sampling‐Based Methods for Uncertainty Propagation in Flood Modeling Under Multiple Uncertain Inputs: Finding Out the Most Efficient Choice</title><description> Water Resources Research, Volume 59, Issue 7, July 2023.</description><dc:description> Abstract In probabilistic flood modeling, uncertainty manifests in frequency of occurrence, or histograms, for quantities of interest, including the Flood Extent and hazard rating (HR). Such modeling at the field‐scale requires the identification of a more efficient alternative to the Standard Monte Carlo (SMC) method that can reproduce comparable output probability distributions with a relatively reduced sample size, including detailed histograms of quantities of interest. Latin hypercube sampling (LHS) is the most evaluated alternative for fluvial floods but yields no considerable sample size reduction. Potentially better alternatives include adaptive stratified sampling (ASS), Quasi Monte Carlo (QMC) and Haar‐wavelet expansion (HWE), which are yet unevaluated for probabilistic flood modeling. To fulfill this gap, LHS, ASS, QMC, and HWE are compared to quantify sample size reduction to reproduce output detailed histograms—for Flood Extent, and average and maximum HR—while keeping the difference below 10% to the reference SMC prediction. The comparison is done for two test cases with two (ie, inflow discharge and Manning&#39;s coefficient) and three (ie, further including the ground elevation) input random variables, and a real case with five input random variables. With two input random variables, all four alternatives yield sample size reductions, with QMC and HWE considerably outperforming the others; with three and more input random variables, HWE becomes inflexible and LHS underperforms. Still, QMC is a better choice than ASS to boost sample size reduction for the real case and shall be preferred in probabilistic flood modeling. Accompanying research codes are openly available online.</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;In probabilistic flood modeling, uncertainty manifests in frequency of occurrence, or histograms, for quantities of interest, including the Flood Extent and hazard rating (HR). Such modeling at the field-scale requires the identification of a more efficient alternative to the Standard Monte Carlo (SMC) method that can reproduce comparable output probability distributions with a relatively reduced sample size, including detailed histograms of quantities of interest. Latin hypercube sampling (LHS) is the most evaluated alternative for fluvial floods but yields no considerable sample size reduction. Potentially better alternatives include adaptive stratified sampling (ASS), Quasi Monte Carlo (QMC) and Haar-wavelet expansion (HWE), which are yet unevaluated for probabilistic flood modeling. To fulfill this gap, LHS, ASS, QMC, and HWE are compared to quantify sample size reduction to reproduce output detailed histograms—for Flood Extent, and average and maximum HR—while keeping the difference below 10% to the reference SMC prediction. The comparison is done for two test cases with two (ie, inflow discharge and Manning&#39;s coefficient) and three (ie, further including the ground elevation) input random variables, and a real case with five input random variables. With two input random variables, all four alternatives yield sample size reductions, with QMC and HWE considerably outperforming the others; with three and more input random variables, HWE becomes inflexible and LHS underperforms. Still, QMC is a better choice than ASS to boost sample size reduction for the real case and shall be preferred in probabilistic flood modeling. Accompanying research codes are openly available online.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> Mahya Hajihassanpour, Georges Kesserwani, Per Pettersson, Vasilis Bellos</dc:creator><category> Research Article</category><dc:title> Sampling‐Based Methods for Uncertainty Propagation in Flood Modeling Under Multiple Uncertain Inputs: Finding Out the Most Efficient Choice</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2022WR034011</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1029/2022WR034011</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR034011?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> Research Article</prism:section><prism:volume> 59</prism:volume><prism:number> 7</prism:number></item><item><link/> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR032630?af=R<pubDate> Fri, 14 Jul 2023 08:55:42 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-07-14T08:55:42-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley: Water Resources Research: Table of Contents<prism:coverdate> Sat, 01 Jul 2023 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate> Sat, 01 Jul 2023 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR032630</guid><title> Large Scale Crop Water Footprint Evaluation Based on Remote Sensing Methods: A Case Study of Maize</title><description> Water Resources Research, Volume 59, Issue 7, July 2023.</description><dc:description> Abstract Agriculture is the world&#39;s largest consumer of water resources, and accurate measurement of crop water footprint (CWF) can provide a scientific basis for evaluating the water use characteristics of agricultural production and guiding water management. The measurement of regional CWF requires large amounts of ground data, and remote sensing provides an effective means to scientifically measure the CWF on a large scale. In this study, we developed an effective means to estimate regional maize CWF based on global evapotranspiration (MOD16 and Global Land Data Assimilation System (GLDAS)‐Noah) products in China. And we also calculated the CWF based on the FAO Penman‐Monteith equation (FAO‐PM) on the site scale in China. We assessed the accuracy of these methods by comparing them against eight eddy‐covariance based flux tower measurements. Links and differences behind the results of the three water footprint calculations were analyzed in terms of the basic principles and characteristics of the calculations. The results showed that the CWF had a similar distribution based on the MOD16 and GLDAS‐Noah, reflecting the influence of regional soil moisture on the CWF. Computational rationale analysis of the three quantitative methods showed that the ETc‐based method from the FAO‐PM model was similar to the MOD16‐ and GLDAS‐Noah‐based CWF in the wetter areas, two remote sensing‐based methods considered the water constraints during soil evaporation and water dissipation during dry and wet canopy conditions, and were closer to reality than the ETc‐based methods in measuring the CWF in arid and semi‐arid regions.</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;Agriculture is the world&#39;s largest consumer of water resources, and accurate measurement of crop water footprint (CWF) can provide a scientific basis for evaluating the water use characteristics of agricultural production and guiding water management. The measurement of regional CWF requires large amounts of ground data, and remote sensing provides an effective means to scientifically measure the CWF on a large scale. In this study, we developed an effective means to estimate regional maize CWF based on global evapotranspiration (MOD16 and Global Land Data Assimilation System (GLDAS)-Noah) products in China. And we also calculated the CWF based on the FAO Penman-Monteith equation (FAO-PM) on the site scale in China. We assessed the accuracy of these methods by comparing them against eight eddy-covariance based flux tower measurements. Links and differences behind the results of the three water footprint calculations were analyzed in terms of the basic principles and characteristics of the calculations. The results showed that the CWF had a similar distribution based on the MOD16 and GLDAS-Noah, reflecting the influence of regional soil moisture on the CWF. Computational rationale analysis of the three quantitative methods showed that the ET&lt;sub>;c&lt;/sub>;-based method from the FAO-PM model was similar to the MOD16- and GLDAS-Noah-based CWF in the wetter areas, two remote sensing-based methods considered the water constraints during soil evaporation and water dissipation during dry and wet canopy conditions, and were closer to reality than the ET&lt;sub>;c&lt;/sub>;-based methods in measuring the CWF in arid and semi-arid regions.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> Zheng Li, Shikun Sun, Jinfeng Zhao, Chong Li, Zihan Gao, Yali Yin, Yubao Wang, Pute Wu</dc:creator><category> Research Article</category><dc:title> Large Scale Crop Water Footprint Evaluation Based on Remote Sensing Methods: A Case Study of Maize</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2022WR032630</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1029/2022WR032630</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR032630?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> Research Article</prism:section><prism:volume> 59</prism:volume><prism:number> 7</prism:number></item><item><link/> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033644?af=R<pubDate> Fri, 14 Jul 2023 08:49:50 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-07-14T08:49:50-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley: Water Resources Research: Table of Contents<prism:coverdate> Sat, 01 Jul 2023 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate> Sat, 01 Jul 2023 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR033644</guid><title> Inverse Modeling for Subsurface Flow Based on Deep Learning Surrogates and Active Learning Strategies</title><description> Water Resources Research, Volume 59, Issue 7, July 2023.</description><dc:description> Abstract Inverse modeling is usually necessary for prediction of subsurface flows, which is beneficial to characterize underground geologic properties and reduce prediction uncertainty. Considering the intensive computational effort required for repeated simulation runs when solving inverse problems, surrogate models can be built to substitute for the simulator and improve inversion efficiency. Deep learning models have been widely used for surrogate modeling of subsurface flow. However, a large amount of training data is usually needed to train the models, especially for constructing globally accurate surrogate models, which would bring large computational burden. In fact, the local accuracy of surrogate models in regions around the true solution of the inverse problem and the potential searching path of the solution is more important for the inversion processes. The local accuracy of surrogate models can be enhanced with active learning. In this work, active learning strategies based on likelihood or posterior information are proposed for inverse modeling, including both offline and online learning strategies. In the offline strategy, a pre‐trained model is utilized to select samples with higher likelihood, which can produce model responses closer to the observations, and then the selected samples can be used to retrain the surrogate. The retrained surrogate is further integrated with the iterative ensemble smoother (IES) algorithm for inversion. In the online strategy, the pre‐trained model is adaptively updated and refined with the selected posterior samples in each iteration of IES to continuously adapt to the solution searching path. Several subsurface flow problems, including both single‐phase groundwater flow and two‐phase (oil‐water) flow problems, are introduced to evaluate the performance of the proposed active learning strategies. The results show that the proposed strategies achieve better inversion performance than the original surrogate‐based inversion method without active learning, and the number of required simulation runs can also be reduced.</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;Inverse modeling is usually necessary for prediction of subsurface flows, which is beneficial to characterize underground geologic properties and reduce prediction uncertainty. Considering the intensive computational effort required for repeated simulation runs when solving inverse problems, surrogate models can be built to substitute for the simulator and improve inversion efficiency. Deep learning models have been widely used for surrogate modeling of subsurface flow. However, a large amount of training data is usually needed to train the models, especially for constructing globally accurate surrogate models, which would bring large computational burden. In fact, the local accuracy of surrogate models in regions around the true solution of the inverse problem and the potential searching path of the solution is more important for the inversion processes. The local accuracy of surrogate models can be enhanced with active learning. In this work, active learning strategies based on likelihood or posterior information are proposed for inverse modeling, including both offline and online learning strategies. In the offline strategy, a pre-trained model is utilized to select samples with higher likelihood, which can produce model responses closer to the observations, and then the selected samples can be used to retrain the surrogate. The retrained surrogate is further integrated with the iterative ensemble smoother (IES) algorithm for inversion. In the online strategy, the pre-trained model is adaptively updated and refined with the selected posterior samples in each iteration of IES to continuously adapt to the solution searching path. Several subsurface flow problems, including both single-phase groundwater flow and two-phase (oil-water) flow problems, are introduced to evaluate the performance of the proposed active learning strategies. The results show that the proposed strategies achieve better inversion performance than the original surrogate-based inversion method without active learning, and the number of required simulation runs can also be reduced.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> Nanzhe Wang, Haibin Chang, Dongxiao Zhang</dc:creator><category> Research Article</category><dc:title> Inverse Modeling for Subsurface Flow Based on Deep Learning Surrogates and Active Learning Strategies</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2022WR033644</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1029/2022WR033644</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033644?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> Research Article</prism:section><prism:volume> 59</prism:volume><prism:number> 7</prism:number></item><item><link/> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR034253?af=R<pubDate> Thu, 13 Jul 2023 11:36:47 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-07-13T11:36:47-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley: Water Resources Research: Table of Contents<prism:coverdate> Sat, 01 Jul 2023 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate> Sat, 01 Jul 2023 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR034253</guid><title> Effect of Particulate Organic Carbon Deposition on Nitrate Reduction in the Hyporheic Zone</title><description> Water Resources Research, Volume 59, Issue 7, July 2023.</description><dc:description> Abstract The hyporheic zone (HZ), where surface water and groundwater interact in sediments beneath streams, presents unique conditions for nutrient dynamics, such as carbon and nitrogen (N) cycling. Organic carbon (OC) in aquatic systems has two distinct forms: dissolved organic carbon and particulate organic carbon (POC). OC affects N reduction and controls the occurrence of denitrification, a primary process by which nitrate (NO3−) is removed as gas (N2 or N2O) to the atmosphere. When POC is the predominant form of OC in streams, how POC influences NO3− reduction within a HZ remains unclear. We established a new reactive transport model incorporating POC transport and filtration processes to assess how POC deposition affects NO3− removal. Sediment permeability decreases as POC is filtrated in the streambed. Nitrate influx is reduced due to POC‐induced sediment clogging. The deposited POC in the shallow streambed serves as an OC source and supports higher biogeochemical reaction kinetics because OC is an important substrate promoting microbial activities. The filtrated POC pool enhances denitrification, thus causing a higher NO3− removal efficiency. In contrast, the POC pool is typically assumed to be distributed homogeneously in sediments, potentially causing a significant underestimation of stream‐borne NO3− removal. A lower hydraulic conductivity, a smaller POC grain size, and a larger POC filtration efficiency and in‐stream POC concentration allow for extensive POC deposition within the shallow streambed that favors nitrate removal. This study provides a better understanding of N processing and an accurate estimation of NO3− removal potential in HZs.</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;The hyporheic zone (HZ), where surface water and groundwater interact in sediments beneath streams, presents unique conditions for nutrient dynamics, such as carbon and nitrogen (N) cycling. Organic carbon (OC) in aquatic systems has two distinct forms: dissolved organic carbon and particulate organic carbon (POC). OC affects N reduction and controls the occurrence of denitrification, a primary process by which nitrate (NO&lt;sub>;3&lt;/sub>; &lt;sup>;−&lt;/sup>;) is removed as gas (N&lt;sub>;2&lt;/sub>; or N&lt;sub>;2&lt;/sub>;O) to the atmosphere. When POC is the predominant form of OC in streams, how POC influences NO&lt;sub>;3&lt;/sub>; &lt;sup>;−&lt;/sup>; reduction within a HZ remains unclear. We established a new reactive transport model incorporating POC transport and filtration processes to assess how POC deposition affects NO&lt;sub>;3&lt;/sub>; &lt;sup>;−&lt;/sup>; removal. Sediment permeability decreases as POC is filtrated in the streambed. Nitrate influx is reduced due to POC-induced sediment clogging. The deposited POC in the shallow streambed serves as an OC source and supports higher biogeochemical reaction kinetics because OC is an important substrate promoting microbial activities. The filtrated POC pool enhances denitrification, thus causing a higher NO&lt;sub>;3&lt;/sub>; &lt;sup>;−&lt;/sup>; removal efficiency. In contrast, the POC pool is typically assumed to be distributed homogeneously in sediments, potentially causing a significant underestimation of stream-borne NO&lt;sub>;3&lt;/sub>; &lt;sup>;−&lt;/sup>; removal. A lower hydraulic conductivity, a smaller POC grain size, and a larger POC filtration efficiency and in-stream POC concentration allow for extensive POC deposition within the shallow streambed that favors nitrate removal. This study provides a better understanding of N processing and an accurate estimation of NO&lt;sub>;3&lt;/sub>; &lt;sup>;−&lt;/sup>; removal potential in HZs.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> Xue Ping, Yang Xian, Menggui Jin</dc:creator><category> Research Article</category><dc:title> Effect of Particulate Organic Carbon Deposition on Nitrate Reduction in the Hyporheic Zone</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2022WR034253</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1029/2022WR034253</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR034253?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> Research Article</prism:section><prism:volume> 59</prism:volume><prism:number> 7</prism:number></item><item><link/> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033662?af=R<pubDate> Thu, 13 Jul 2023 11:34:27 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-07-13T11:34:27-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley: Water Resources Research: Table of Contents <prism:coverdate></prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate></prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR033662</guid><title> River geomorphology affects biogeochemical responses to hydrologic events in a large river ecosystem</title><description> Water Resources Research, Accepted Article.</description><dc:description> Abstract Shifts in the frequency and intensity of high discharge events due to climate change may have important consequences for the hydrology and biogeochemistry of rivers. However, our understanding of event‐scale biogeochemical dynamics in large rivers lags that of small streams. To fill this gap, we used high‐frequency sensor data collected during four consecutive summers from a main channel and backwater site of the Upper Mississippi River. We identified high discharge events and calculated event concentration‐discharge responses for both physical‐chemical (nitrate, turbidity, and fluorescent dissolved organic matter) and biological (chlorophyll‐a and cyanobacteria) constituents using metrics of hysteresis and slope. We found a range of responses across events, particularly for nitrate. Although fluorescent dissolved organic matter (FDOM) and turbidity exhibited more consistent responses across events, contrasting hysteresis metrics indicated that FDOM was flushed to the river from more distant sources than turbidity. Biological responses (chlorophyll a and cyanobacteria) differed more between sites than among physical and chemical constituents. Lastly, we found that the event characteristics best explaining concentration responses differed between sites, with event magnitude more frequently related to responses in the main channel, and antecedent wetness conditions associated with response variation in the backwater. Our results indicate that event responses in large rivers are distinct across the diverse habitats and biogeochemical components of a large floodplain river, which has implications for local and downstream ecosystems as the climate shifts.</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;Shifts in the frequency and intensity of high discharge events due to climate change may have important consequences for the hydrology and biogeochemistry of rivers. However, our understanding of event-scale biogeochemical dynamics in large rivers lags that of small streams. To fill this gap, we used high-frequency sensor data collected during four consecutive summers from a main channel and backwater site of the Upper Mississippi River. We identified high discharge events and calculated event concentration-discharge responses for both physical-chemical (nitrate, turbidity, and fluorescent dissolved organic matter) and biological (chlorophyll-a and cyanobacteria) constituents using metrics of hysteresis and slope. We found a range of responses across events, particularly for nitrate. Although fluorescent dissolved organic matter (FDOM) and turbidity exhibited more consistent responses across events, contrasting hysteresis metrics indicated that FDOM was flushed to the river from more distant sources than turbidity. Biological responses (chlorophyll a and cyanobacteria) differed more between sites than among physical and chemical constituents. Lastly, we found that the event characteristics best explaining concentration responses differed between sites, with event magnitude more frequently related to responses in the main channel, and antecedent wetness conditions associated with response variation in the backwater. Our results indicate that event responses in large rivers are distinct across the diverse habitats and biogeochemical components of a large floodplain river, which has implications for local and downstream ecosystems as the climate shifts.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> Taryn Waite, KJ Jankowski, DA Bruesewitz, M. Appledorn, M. Johnston, JN Houser, DA Baumann, B. Bennie</dc:creator><category> Research Article</category><dc:title> River geomorphology affects biogeochemical responses to hydrologic events in a large river ecosystem</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2022WR033662</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1029/2022WR033662</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033662?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> Research Article</prism:section></item><item><link/> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033600?af=R<pubDate> Thu, 13 Jul 2023 11:05:33 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-07-13T11:05:33-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley: Water Resources Research: Table of Contents<prism:coverdate> Sat, 01 Jul 2023 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate> Sat, 01 Jul 2023 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR033600</guid><title> Automated Symbolic Upscaling: 1. Model Generation for Extended Applicability Regimes</title><description> Water Resources Research, Volume 59, Issue 7, July 2023.</description><dc:description> Abstract In porous media theory, upscaling techniques are fundamental to deriving rigorous Darcy‐scale models for flow and reactive transport in subsurface systems. Due to limitations in classical techniques, a number of ad hoc approaches have been proposed to address physical regimes in which reactive time scales are similar to, or faster than, diffusive time scales. In Part 1 of this two part series, we present a strategy for expanding the applicability of classical homogenization theory by generalizing the assumed closure form. We detail the implementation of this strategy on two reactive mass transport problems with moderately reactive physics. The strategy produces nontrivial homogenized models with emergent terms and effective parameters that couple reactive, diffusive, and advective transport. The differences in equation forms between the macroscopic and pore‐scale descriptions advise caution to further studies where the forms of macroscopic equations are assumed, as opposed to rigorously derived. Numerical validation is provided for each problem to show that the error estimates of homogenization theory are satisfied, and to justify the implemented strategy. In Part 2, the presented strategy is automated using symbolic computing to expedite its implementation.</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;In porous media theory, upscaling techniques are fundamental to deriving rigorous Darcy-scale models for flow and reactive transport in subsurface systems. Due to limitations in classical techniques, a number of &lt;i>;ad hoc&lt;/i>; approaches have been proposed to address physical regimes in which reactive time scales are similar to, or faster than, diffusive time scales. In Part 1 of this two part series, we present a strategy for expanding the applicability of classical homogenization theory by generalizing the assumed closure form. We detail the implementation of this strategy on two reactive mass transport problems with moderately reactive physics. The strategy produces nontrivial homogenized models with emergent terms and effective parameters that couple reactive, diffusive, and advective transport. The differences in equation forms between the macroscopic and pore-scale descriptions advise caution to further studies where the forms of macroscopic equations are assumed, as opposed to rigorously derived. Numerical validation is provided for each problem to show that the error estimates of homogenization theory are satisfied, and to justify the implemented strategy. In Part 2, the presented strategy is automated using symbolic computing to expedite its implementation.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> Kyle Pietrzyk, Ilenia Battiato</dc:creator><category> Research Article</category><dc:title> Automated Symbolic Upscaling: 1. Model Generation for Extended Applicability Regimes</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2022WR033600</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1029/2022WR033600</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033600?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> Research Article</prism:section><prism:volume> 59</prism:volume><prism:number> 7</prism:number></item><item><link/> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2023WR034454?af=R<pubDate> Thu, 13 Jul 2023 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-07-13T12:00:00-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley: Water Resources Research: Table of Contents <prism:coverdate></prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate></prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2023WR034454</guid><title> Explaining the statistical properties of salt intrusion in estuaries using a stochastic dynamical modelling approach</title><description> Water Resources Research, Accepted Article.</description><dc:description> Abstract Determining the statistical properties of salt intrusion in estuaries on sub‐tidal timescales is a substantial challenge in environmental modelling. To study these properties, we here extend an idealized deterministic salt intrusion model to a stochastic one by including a stochastic model of the river discharge. In the river discharge model, two types of stochastic forcing are used: one independent (additive noise) and one dependent (multiplicative noise) on the river discharge state. Each type of forcing results in a non‐Gaussian response in the salt intrusion length, which we consider here as the distance of the 2 psu isohaline contour to the estuary mouth. The salt intrusion model including both types of stochastic forcing in the river discharge provides a satisfactory explanation of the multi‐year statistics of observed salt intrusion lengths in the San Francisco Bay estuary, in particular for the skewness of its probability density function. This article is protected by copyright.版权所有。</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;Determining the statistical properties of salt intrusion in estuaries on sub-tidal timescales is a substantial challenge in environmental modelling. To study these properties, we here extend an idealized deterministic salt intrusion model to a stochastic one by including a stochastic model of the river discharge. In the river discharge model, two types of stochastic forcing are used: one independent (additive noise) and one dependent (multiplicative noise) on the river discharge state. Each type of forcing results in a non-Gaussian response in the salt intrusion length, which we consider here as the distance of the 2 psu isohaline contour to the estuary mouth. The salt intrusion model including both types of stochastic forcing in the river discharge provides a satisfactory explanation of the multi-year statistics of observed salt intrusion lengths in the San Francisco Bay estuary, in particular for the skewness of its probability density function.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This article is protected by copyright. All rights reserved.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> Henk Dijkstra, Bouke Biemond, Jiyong Lee, Huib Swart</dc:creator><category> Research Article</category><dc:title> Explaining the statistical properties of salt intrusion in estuaries using a stochastic dynamical modelling approach</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2023WR034454</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1029/2023WR034454</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2023WR034454?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> Research Article</prism:section></item><item><link/> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033711?af=R<pubDate> Thu, 13 Jul 2023 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-07-13T12:00:00-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley: Water Resources Research: Table of Contents <prism:coverdate></prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate></prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR033711</guid><title> Information‐Theoretic Scores for Bayesian Model Selection and Similarity Analysis: Concept and Application to a Groundwater Problem</title><description> Water Resources Research, Accepted Article.</description><dc:description> Abstract Bayesian model selection (BMS) and Bayesian model justifiability analysis (BMJ) provide a statistically rigorous framework for comparing competing models through the use of Bayesian model evidence (BME). However, a BME‐based analysis has two main limitations: (1) it does not account for a model&#39;s posterior predictive performance after using the data for calibration and (2) it leads to biased results when comparing models that use different subsets of the observations for calibration. To address these limitations, we propose augmenting BMS and BMJ analyses with additional information‐theoretic measures: expected log‐predictive density (ELPD), relative entropy (RE) and information entropy (IE). Exploring the connection between Bayesian inference and information theory, we explicitly link BME and ELPD together with RE and IE to highlight the information flow in BMS and BMJ analyses. We show how to compute and interpret these scores alongside BME, and apply the framework to a controlled 2D groundwater setup featuring five models, one of which uses a subset of the data for calibration. Our results show how the information‐theoretic scores complement BME by providing a more complete picture concerning the Bayesian updating process. Additionally, we demonstrate how both RE and IE can be used to objectively compare models that feature different data sets for calibration. Overall, the introduced Bayesian information‐theoretic framework can lead to a better‐informed decision by incorporating a model&#39;s post‐calibration predictive performance, by allowing to work with different subsets of the data and by considering the usefulness of the data in the Bayesian updating process. This article is protected by copyright.版权所有。</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;Bayesian model selection (BMS) and Bayesian model justifiability analysis (BMJ) provide a statistically rigorous framework for comparing competing models through the use of Bayesian model evidence (BME). However, a BME-based analysis has two main limitations: (1) it does not account for a model&#39;s posterior predictive performance after using the data for calibration and (2) it leads to biased results when comparing models that use different subsets of the observations for calibration. To address these limitations, we propose augmenting BMS and BMJ analyses with additional information-theoretic measures: expected log-predictive density (ELPD), relative entropy (RE) and information entropy (IE). Exploring the connection between Bayesian inference and information theory, we explicitly link BME and ELPD together with RE and IE to highlight the information flow in BMS and BMJ analyses. We show how to compute and interpret these scores alongside BME, and apply the framework to a controlled 2D groundwater setup featuring five models, one of which uses a subset of the data for calibration. Our results show how the information-theoretic scores complement BME by providing a more complete picture concerning the Bayesian updating process. Additionally, we demonstrate how both RE and IE can be used to objectively compare models that feature different data sets for calibration. Overall, the introduced Bayesian information-theoretic framework can lead to a better-informed decision by incorporating a model&#39;s post-calibration predictive performance, by allowing to work with different subsets of the data and by considering the usefulness of the data in the Bayesian updating process.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This article is protected by copyright. All rights reserved.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> Maria Fernanda Morales Oreamuno, Sergey Oladyshkin, Wolfgang Nowak</dc:creator><category> Research Article</category><dc:title> Information‐Theoretic Scores for Bayesian Model Selection and Similarity Analysis: Concept and Application to a Groundwater Problem</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2022WR033711</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1029/2022WR033711</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033711?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> Research Article</prism:section></item><item><link/> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2023WR034992?af=R<pubDate> Wed, 12 Jul 2023 09:02:20 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-07-12T09:02:20-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley: Water Resources Research: Table of Contents<prism:coverdate> Sat, 01 Jul 2023 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate> Sat, 01 Jul 2023 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2023WR034992</guid><title> A Novel Methodology for the Stochastic Integration of Geophysical and Hydrogeological Data in Geologically Consistent Models</title><description> Water Resources Research, Volume 59, Issue 7, July 2023.</description><dc:description> Abstract To address groundwater issues, it is often necessary to develop geological and hydrogeological models. Combining geological, geophysical and hydrogeological data available on a site to build such models is often a challenge. This paper presents a methodology to integrate such data within a geologically consistent model with robust error estimation. The methodology combines the Ensemble Smoother with Multiple Data Assimilation (ESMDA) algorithm with a hierarchical geological modeling approach (ArchPy). Geophysical and hydrogeological field data are jointly assimilated in a stochastic ESMDA framework. To speed up the inversion process, forward responses are computed in lower‐dimensional spaces relevant to each physical problem. By doing so, the final models take into account multiple data sources and regional conceptual geological knowledge. This study illustrates the applicability of this novel approach using actual data from the upper Aare Valley, Switzerland. The results of cross‐validation show that the combination of different data types, each sensitive to different spatial dimensions, enhances the quality of the model within a reasonable computing time. The proposed methodology allows the automatic generation of groundwater models with robust uncertainty estimation and could be applied to a wide variety of hydrogeological issues.</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;To address groundwater issues, it is often necessary to develop geological and hydrogeological models. Combining geological, geophysical and hydrogeological data available on a site to build such models is often a challenge. This paper presents a methodology to integrate such data within a geologically consistent model with robust error estimation. The methodology combines the Ensemble Smoother with Multiple Data Assimilation (ESMDA) algorithm with a hierarchical geological modeling approach (ArchPy). Geophysical and hydrogeological field data are jointly assimilated in a stochastic ESMDA framework. To speed up the inversion process, forward responses are computed in lower-dimensional spaces relevant to each physical problem. By doing so, the final models take into account multiple data sources and regional conceptual geological knowledge. This study illustrates the applicability of this novel approach using actual data from the upper Aare Valley, Switzerland. The results of cross-validation show that the combination of different data types, each sensitive to different spatial dimensions, enhances the quality of the model within a reasonable computing time. The proposed methodology allows the automatic generation of groundwater models with robust uncertainty estimation and could be applied to a wide variety of hydrogeological issues.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> Alexis Neven, Philippe Renard</dc:creator><category> Research Article</category><dc:title> A Novel Methodology for the Stochastic Integration of Geophysical and Hydrogeological Data in Geologically Consistent Models</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2023WR034992</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1029/2023WR034992</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2023WR034992?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> Research Article</prism:section><prism:volume> 59</prism:volume><prism:number> 7</prism:number></item><item><link/> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR034352?af=R<pubDate> Wed, 12 Jul 2023 09:01:06 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-07-12T09:01:06-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley: Water Resources Research: Table of Contents<prism:coverdate> Sat, 01 Jul 2023 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate> Sat, 01 Jul 2023 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR034352</guid><title> Optimal Postprocessing Strategies With LSTM for Global Streamflow Prediction in Ungauged Basins</title><description> Water Resources Research, Volume 59, Issue 7, July 2023.</description><dc:description> Abstract Streamflow prediction in ungauged basins (PUB) is challenging, and Long Short‐Term Memory (LSTM) is widely used to for such predictions, owing to its excellent migration performance. Traditional LSTM forced by meteorological data and catchment attribute data barely highlight the optimum data integration strategy for LSTM and its migration from data‐rich basins to ungauged ones. In this study, we experimented with 1,897 global catchments and found that LSTM‐corrected Global Hydrological Models (GHMs) outperformed uncorrected GHMs, improving the median Nash‐Sutcliff efficiency (NSE) from 0.03 to 0.66. Notably, there was a large gap between traditional LSTM modeling in ungauged basins and autoregressive modeling in data‐rich basins, and GHM‐forced LSTM were an effective way to close this gap in ungauged basins. The spatial heterogeneity of the performance of GHM‐forced LSTM was mainly influenced by three metrics (dryness, the leaf area index and latitude), which described the hydrological similarity among catchments. Weaker hydrological similarity among continental catchments results in larger variability in GHM‐forced LSTM, with the best performance in Siberia (NSE, 0.54) and the worst in North America (NSE, 0.10). However, the migration performance of GHM‐forced LSTM was significantly improved (NSE, 0.63) in ungauged basins when hydrological similarity was considered. This study stressed the advantages of GHM‐forced LSTM and due significance should be attached to hydrological similarities among catchments to improve hydrological prediction in ungauged catchments.</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;Streamflow prediction in ungauged basins (PUB) is challenging, and Long Short-Term Memory (LSTM) is widely used to for such predictions, owing to its excellent migration performance. Traditional LSTM forced by meteorological data and catchment attribute data barely highlight the optimum data integration strategy for LSTM and its migration from data-rich basins to ungauged ones. In this study, we experimented with 1,897 global catchments and found that LSTM-corrected Global Hydrological Models (GHMs) outperformed uncorrected GHMs, improving the median Nash-Sutcliff efficiency (NSE) from 0.03 to 0.66. Notably, there was a large gap between traditional LSTM modeling in ungauged basins and autoregressive modeling in data-rich basins, and GHM-forced LSTM were an effective way to close this gap in ungauged basins. The spatial heterogeneity of the performance of GHM-forced LSTM was mainly influenced by three metrics (dryness, the leaf area index and latitude), which described the hydrological similarity among catchments. Weaker hydrological similarity among continental catchments results in larger variability in GHM-forced LSTM, with the best performance in Siberia (NSE, 0.54) and the worst in North America (NSE, 0.10). However, the migration performance of GHM-forced LSTM was significantly improved (NSE, 0.63) in ungauged basins when hydrological similarity was considered. This study stressed the advantages of GHM-forced LSTM and due significance should be attached to hydrological similarities among catchments to improve hydrological prediction in ungauged catchments.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> Senlin Tang, Fubao Sun, Wenbin Liu, Hong Wang, Yao Feng, Ziwei Li</dc:creator><category> Research Article</category><dc:title> Optimal Postprocessing Strategies With LSTM for Global Streamflow Prediction in Ungauged Basins</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2022WR034352</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1029/2022WR034352</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR034352?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> Research Article</prism:section><prism:volume> 59</prism:volume><prism:number> 7</prism:number></item></channel></rss>