<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:prism="http://prismstandard.org/namespaces/basic/2.0/"><channel><title> Wiley：水资源研究：目录</title><link/>https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R<description>水资源研究目录。最新期和 EarlyView 期的文章列表。</description><language> en-US</language><copyright></copyright><managingeditor> wileyonlinelibrary@wiley.com（AGU 出版物）</managingeditor><pubDate> Sun, 27 Aug 2023 07:37:32 +0000</pubDate><lastbuilddate> 2023 年 8 月 27 日星期日 07:37:32 +0000</lastbuilddate><generator> Atypon®文学™</generator><docs> https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs><ttl> 10080</ttl><dc:title> Wiley：水资源研究：目录</dc:title><dc:publisher>威利</dc:publisher><prism:publicationname>水资源研究</prism:publicationname><atom:link href="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"></atom:link><image/><title> Wiley：水资源研究：目录</title><url>https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/pb-assets/journal-banners/19447973.jpg</url><link/> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R<item><link/> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR034297?af=R<pubDate> Sat, 26 Aug 2023 09:20:34 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-08-26T09:20:34-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley：水资源研究：目录<prism:coverdate></prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate></prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR034297</guid><title>水平含水层的非线性衰退模型</title><description>水资源研究，已接受文章。</description><dc:description>摘要 衰退分析是确定河岸含水层水力特征的有力工具。该方法的基础依赖于非线性 Boussinesq 方程的两个解析解：一个适用于半无限含水层中的均匀地下水位剖面，另一个适用于有限含水层中的假设初始剖面。两种解决方案都假设相邻河流的水深可以忽略不计。在目前的工作中，使用行波近似导出一维 Boussinesq 方程的非线性解。该解更好地代表了现场条件，因为它涉及与非零水位的河流相邻的有限含水层中的均匀地下水位剖面。它可以导出地下水位下降、流量和相关排水量的简单代数表达式。还获得了将流量与流出量相关的近似值，用于含水层水力参数估计的实际实施。所提出的参数估计方法与衰退分析的标准方法的比较表明，本方法是优越的，因为它避免了与经典方法相关的陷阱，特别是当使用具有固有观测误差的日流量值时。衰退模型在实际案例中的应用证明了其在估计流域规模导水率和可排水孔隙度方面的有效性。</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;摘要&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;衰退分析是确定河岸含水层水力特征的有力工具。该方法的基础依赖于非线性 Boussinesq 方程的两个解析解：一个适用于半无限含水层中的均匀地下水位剖面，而另一个适用于有限含水层中的假设初始剖面。两种解决方案都假设相邻河流的水深可以忽略不计。在目前的工作中，使用行波近似导出一维 Boussinesq 方程的非线性解。该解更好地代表了现场条件，因为它涉及与非零水位的溪流相邻的有限含水层中的均匀地下水位剖面。它可以导出地下水位下降、流量和相关排水量的简单代数表达式。还获得了将流量与流出量相关的近似值，用于含水层水力参数估计的实际实施。所提出的参数估计方法与衰退分析的标准方法的比较表明，本方法是优越的，因为它避免了与经典方法相关的陷阱，特别是当使用具有固有观测误差的日流量值时。衰退模型在实际案例中的应用证明了其在流域尺度导水率和可排水孔隙度估算中的有效性。&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator>哈岜沙</dc:creator><category>研究文章</category><dc:title>水平含水层的非线性衰退模型</dc:title><dc:identifier>10.1029/2022WR034297</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname>水资源研究</prism:publicationname><prism:doi>10.1029/2022WR034297</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR034297?af=R</prism:url><prism:section>研究文章</prism:section></item><item><link/>https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2023WR034460?af=R<pubDate> Fri, 25 Aug 2023 23:34:03 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-08-25T11:34:03-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley：水资源研究：目录<prism:coverdate></prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate></prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2023WR034460</guid><title>结合日常传感器观测和空间激光雷达数据绘制亚高山森林中的雪水当量图</title><description>水资源研究，已接受文章。</description><dc:description>摘要 雪以多种方式与其环境相互作用，因此具有高度异质的空间和时间变化。因此，对雪的变化进行建模很困难，尤其是在森林环境中。为了加深对雪时空变化的理解并验证雪模型，需要类似时空尺度的可靠观测数据。为此，通常使用机载激光雷达调查或从地面雪传感器导出的时间序列。然而，这些都仅限于空间或时间上的一个点。提出了瑞士阿尔普塔尔山谷亚高山森林每日积雪变化的新的、广泛的数据集。核心数据集由密集的传感器网络、使用固定翼无人机获取的重复高分辨率激光雷达数据以及手动雪深和雪密度测量组成。使用机器学习算法，确定了具有相似雪深动态的四个不同空间集群。通过将这些空间聚类与观测到的雪深时间序列相结合，得出雪深和雪水当量（SWE）的每日高分辨率地图。据我们所知，这些产品是第一个几乎完全基于现场数据提供时空连续雪深和 SWE 的产品。所提出的工作流程可转移到不同的地区、气候和规模。此外，这些结果使未来的现场活动能够找到有代表性的传感器位置，并以激光雷达调查为目标，以更少的工作量获得类似的连续产品。</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;雪以多种方式与其环境相互作用，因此具有高度异质的空间和时间变化。因此，对雪的变化进行建模很困难，尤其是在森林环境中。为了加深对雪时空变化的理解并验证雪模型，需要类似时空尺度的可靠观测数据。为此，通常使用机载激光雷达调查或从地面雪传感器得出的时间序列。然而，这些都仅限于空间或时间上的一个点。提出了瑞士阿尔普塔尔山谷亚高山森林每日积雪变化的新的、广泛的数据集。核心数据集由密集的传感器网络、使用固定翼无人机获取的重复高分辨率激光雷达数据以及手动雪深和雪密度测量组成。使用机器学习算法，确定了具有相似雪深动态的四个不同空间集群。通过将这些空间聚类与观测到的雪深时间序列相结合，得出雪深和雪水当量（SWE）的每日高分辨率地图。据我们所知，这些产品是第一个几乎完全基于现场数据提供时空连续积雪深度和 SWE 的产品。所提出的工作流程可转移到不同的地区、气候和规模。此外，这些结果使未来的现场活动能够找到具有代表性的传感器位置，并针对其 LiDAR 调查进行定位，以更少的工作量获得类似的连续产品。&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator>约施卡·盖斯勒、拉斯·拉斯曼、马库斯·韦勒</dc:creator><category>研究文章</category><dc:title>结合日常传感器观测和空间激光雷达数据绘制亚高山森林中的雪水当量图</dc:title><dc:identifier>10.1029/2023WR034460</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname>水资源研究</prism:publicationname><prism:doi>10.1029/2023WR034460</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2023WR034460?af=R</prism:url><prism:section>研究文章</prism:section></item><item><link/>https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR034166?af=R<pubDate> Fri, 25 Aug 2023 10:09:56 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-08-25T10:09:56-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley：水资源研究：目录<prism:coverdate>2023 年 8 月 1 日，星期二 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate> 2023 年 8 月 1 日，星期二 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR034166</guid><title> CMIP6 HighResMIP 对爱荷华州年度最大流量水文模型的评估</title><description>《水资源研究》，第 59 卷，第 8 期，2023 年 8 月。</description><dc:description>摘要 耦合模型比较第 6 阶段的高分辨率模型比较项目 (HighResMIP) 实验代表了为提高气候模型的分辨率和性能所做的广泛努力。 HighResMIP 套件提供高空间分辨率（即 25 公里和 50 公里）强迫，已被证明可以改善气候过程的表示。然而，人们对其水文应用的适用性知之甚少。我们使用 HighResMIP 套件的输出，通过 Hillslope-Link 模型 (HLM) 模拟爱荷华州约 1,000 个河流社区的年度最大流量。首先，我们评估气候模型的径流是否可以直接通过 HLM 中的河网模型来估计年度最大流量。基于径流的模拟可以捕获评估的 10 个模型/成员中的 5 个洪水峰值的经验分布。接下来，我们使用 HighResMIP 模型中的降水量、温度和潜在蒸散量强制 HLM 来模拟洪峰，发现所有模型/成员都产生与我们的参考类似的经验分布。然而，模型/构件强迫中存在显着偏差，因为正确的洪水响应是由于错误的原因而生成的。为了提高其对社区级评估的适用性，我们使用九种统计方法来校正偏差并将 HighResMIP 降水量缩小到 4 公里分辨率。气候模型降水的偏差校正和降尺度对于所有模型/成员都表现良好。此外，我们没有发现基于 HighResMIP 输出强制的 HLM 或基于路由径流的爱荷华州洪水峰值预测发生显着变化，但有迹象表明全州洪水峰值的变化预计会增加。</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;摘要&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;耦合模型比对第 6 阶段的高分辨率模型比对项目 (HighResMIP) 实验代表了为提高气候模型的分辨率和性能所做的广泛努力。 HighResMIP 套件提供高空间分辨率（即 25 公里和 50 公里）强迫，已被证明可以改善气候过程的表示。然而，人们对其水文应用的适用性知之甚少。我们使用 HighResMIP 套件的输出，通过 Hillslope-Link 模型 (HLM) 模拟爱荷华州约 1,000 个河流社区的年度最大流量。首先，我们评估气候模型的径流是否可以直接通过 HLM 中的河网模型来估计年度最大流量。基于径流的模拟可以捕获所评估的 10 个模型/成员中的 5 个洪水峰值的经验分布。接下来，我们使用 HighResMIP 模型中的降水量、温度和潜在蒸散量强制 HLM 来模拟洪峰，发现所有模型/成员都产生与我们的参考类似的经验分布。然而，模型/构件强迫中存在显着偏差，因为正确的洪水响应是由于错误的原因而生成的。为了提高其对社区级评估的适用性，我们使用九种统计方法来校正偏差并将 HighResMIP 降水缩小到 4 公里分辨率。气候模型降水的偏差校正和降尺度对于所有模型/成员都表现良好。此外，我们没有发现基于 HighResMIP 输出强制的 HLM 或基于路由径流的爱荷华州洪水峰值预测发生显着变化，但有迹象表明全州洪水峰值的变异性预计会增加。&lt; /p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> Alexander T. Michalek、Gabriele Villarini、Taereem Kim、Felipe Quintero、Witold F. Krajewski、Enrico Scoccimarro</dc:creator><category>研究文章</category><dc:title>CMIP6 HighResMIP 对爱荷华州年度最大流量水文模型的评估</dc:title><dc:identifier>10.1029/2022WR034166</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname>水资源研究</prism:publicationname><prism:doi>10.1029/2022WR034166</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR034166?af=R</prism:url><prism:section>研究文章</prism:section><prism:volume>59</prism:volume><prism:number> 8</prism:number></item><item><link/> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2023WR034664?af=R<pubDate> Fri, 25 Aug 2023 09:54:08 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-08-25T09:54:08-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley：水资源研究：目录<prism:coverdate>2023 年 8 月 1 日，星期二 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate> 2023 年 8 月 1 日，星期二 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2023WR034664</guid><title>水不饱和多孔介质中 PFAS 传输的孔隙尺度模拟：薄水膜中的空气-水界面吸附和传质过程</title><description>《水资源研究》，第 59 卷，第 8 期，2023 年 8 月。</description><dc:description>摘要 空气-水界面吸附使全氟烷基物质和多氟烷基物质（PFAS）在包气区的传输变得复杂。空气-水界面可由土壤颗粒之间的摆环和颗粒表面的薄水膜产生，在大多数现场相关条件下，后者占总空气-水界面的 90% 以上。然而，PFAS 是否可以进入所有薄水膜空气-水界面以及薄水膜中的传质限制如何控制 PFAS 在土壤中的传输仍然未知。我们开发了一个孔隙尺度模型，该模型代表了整体毛细管和薄水膜空气-水界面上的 PFAS 吸附，以及整体毛细管水和薄水膜之间的传质过程（包括平流、水扩散和表面扩散）。空气-水界面）。我们将孔隙尺度模型应用于一系列数值实验（受实验确定的水力参数和空气-水界面面积数据集的约束），以检查砂介质中薄水膜传质限制的影响。我们的分析表明：（a）由于表面扩散，孔隙内的大量毛细管水和薄水膜之间的传质限制可以忽略不计。 （b）然而，在摆环断开的孔隙簇的薄水膜中出现强烈的传质限制。即使存在表面扩散，传质限制也会导致提前到达和长拖尾行为。 (c) 尽管存在传质限制，PFAS 在模拟条件下仍可访问薄水膜中的所有空气-水界面。这些发现强调了结合薄水膜传质限制和表面扩散来模拟渗流区 PFAS 传输的重要性。</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;摘要&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;空气-水界面吸附使包气区的全氟烷基物质和多氟烷基物质 (PFAS) 传输变得复杂。空气-水界面可由土壤颗粒之间的摆环和颗粒表面的薄水膜产生，在大多数现场相关条件下，后者占总空气-水界面的 90% 以上。然而，PFAS 是否可以进入所有薄水膜空气-水界面，以及薄水膜中的传质限制如何控制 PFAS 在土壤中的传输仍然未知。我们开发了一个孔隙尺度模型，该模型代表了整体毛细管和薄水膜空气-水界面上的 PFAS 吸附，以及整体毛细管水和薄水膜之间的传质过程（包括平流、水扩散和表面扩散）。空气-水界面）。我们将孔隙尺度模型应用于一系列数值实验（受实验确定的水力参数和空气-水界面面积数据集的约束），以研究砂介质中薄水膜传质限制的影响。我们的分析表明：（a）由于表面扩散，孔隙内的大量毛细管水和薄水膜之间的传质限制可以忽略不计。 （b）然而，在摆环断开的孔隙簇的薄水膜中出现强烈的传质限制。即使存在表面扩散，传质限制也会导致提前到达和长拖尾行为。 (c) 尽管存在传质限制，PFAS 在模拟条件下仍能访问薄水膜中的所有空气-水界面。这些发现强调了结合薄水膜传质限制和表面扩散对于包气区 PFAS 传输建模的重要性。&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator>陈思典、郭博</dc:creator><category>研究文章</category><dc:title>水不饱和多孔介质中 PFAS 传输的孔隙尺度模拟：薄水膜中的空气-水界面吸附和传质过程</dc:title><dc:identifier>10.1029/2023WR034664</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname>水资源研究</prism:publicationname><prism:doi>10.1029/2023WR034664</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2023WR034664?af=R</prism:url><prism:section>研究文章</prism:section><prism:volume>59</prism:volume><prism:number> 8</prism:number></item><item><link/> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2023WR035026?af=R<pubDate> Thu, 24 Aug 2023 17:10:18 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-08-24T05:10:18-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley：水资源研究：目录<prism:coverdate></prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate></prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2023WR035026</guid><title>河口缺氧 - 识别现在和未来气候情景下的高风险流域</title><description>水资源研究，已接受文章。</description><dc:description>摘要 缺氧黑水事件在世界范围内发生，影响内陆和沿海水域。人造洪泛区排水加剧了这些事件，导致大规模鱼类死亡和生态退化。本文提出了一种新方法来识别最有可能产生缺氧条件的河口流域区域。该方法使用已确定的风险因素，包括植被类型、淹没范围和持续时间，在澳大利亚东部经过实地验证。如果 (i) 位于洪水高和/或排水受阻的地方，(ii) 场地地形包括广阔的低洼洪泛区，则流域产生缺氧黑水的风险较高；和/或 (iii) 土地利用和环境特征具有高脱氧潜力。对河口的后续影响取决于河漫滩与河口的连通性以及流域排水系统的流量特征。在多个邻近的流域具有相似的排水条件的情况下，混合的低氧黑水羽流可能会压倒河口的同化能力。由于海平面上升、气温升高以及更强烈和零星的降雨事件导致排水量减少，气候变化可能会显着增加河口环境中黑水事件的数量和频率。建议采取管理措施，减轻气候变化的影响，避免进一步广泛的缺氧黑水事件。本文受版权保护。版权所有。</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;缺氧黑水事件在世界范围内发生，影响内陆和沿海水域。人为洪泛区排水加剧了这些事件，导致大规模鱼类死亡和生态退化。本文提出了一种新方法来识别最有可能产生缺氧条件的河口流域区域。该方法使用在澳大利亚东部经过实地验证的既定风险因素，包括植被类型、淹没范围和持续时间。如果 (i) 位于洪水高涨和/或排水受阻的地方，(ii) 场地地形包括广阔的低洼洪泛区，则流域产生缺氧黑水的风险较高；和/或 (iii) 土地利用和环境特征具有高脱氧潜力。对河口的后续影响取决于河漫滩与河口的连通性以及流域排水系统的流量特征。在多个邻近的流域具有相似的排水条件的情况下，混合的低氧黑水羽流可能会压倒河口的同化能力。由于海平面上升、气温升高以及更强烈和零星的降雨事件导致排水量减少，气候变化可能会显着增加河口环境中黑水事件的数量和频率。建议采取管理措施，减轻气候变化的影响，避免进一步大范围的缺氧黑水事件。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;本文受版权保护。保留所有权利。&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> K.沃丁顿、A.哈里森、D.雷纳、T.塔克、W.格拉莫尔</dc:creator><category>研究文章</category><dc:title>河口缺氧 - 识别现在和未来气候情景下的高风险流域</dc:title><dc:identifier>10.1029/2023WR035026</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname>水资源研究</prism:publicationname><prism:doi>10.1029/2023WR035026</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2023WR035026?af=R</prism:url><prism:section>研究文章</prism:section></item><item><link/>https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033671?af=R<pubDate> Thu, 24 Aug 2023 14:00:41 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-08-24T02:00:41-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley：水资源研究：目录<prism:coverdate></prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate></prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR033671</guid><title>推进公平、稳健、适应性和合作稳定的区域供水管理和基础设施投资路径</title><description>水资源研究，已接受文章。</description><dc:description>摘要 区域化方法（地理上邻近的公用事业公司合作管理干旱风险并共同投资新基础设施）越来越成为利用规模经济满足不断增长的需求和应对金融风险的必要战略。然而，区域化也给供水规划带来了新的挑战。成功的区域化政策必须公平地平衡多个合作伙伴的利益，同时处理区域参与者之间的权力关系。在长期基础设施规划背景下，不断发展的系统状态动态加剧了这一挑战，而基础设施投资可能从根本上重塑系统状态动态。这项工作介绍了公平、稳健、自适应和稳定的深度不确定路径 (DU PathwaysERAS)，这是一个用于开发区域供水管理和基础设施投资路径的探索性建模框架。 DU PathwaysERAS 为利益相关者提供了一个综合框架，以评估合作伙伴之间政策结果的公平性，并探索合作基础设施政策中的区域权力关系。为了捕捉基础设施路径随时间演变的动态，DU PathwaysERAS 采用了新工具来衡量路径政策的适应能力并评估随时间演变的脆弱性。我们展示了六家公用事业供水伙伴关系的框架，寻求在北卡罗来纳州研究三角区开发合作基础设施投资途径。我们的结果表明，常用的稳健性框架可能会对区域伙伴关系产生巨大且意想不到的不利后果。结果进一步表明，区域和个体脆弱性是高度相互依存的，并强调需要通过精心设计的合作协议来限制交易对手风险。除了研究三角之外，这些结果广泛适用于全球合作供水基础设施投资和管理。本文受版权保护。版权所有。</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;区域化方法（地理上邻近的公用事业公司合作管理干旱风险并共同投资新基础设施）日益成为利用规模经济满足不断增长的需求和应对金融风险的必要战略。然而，区域化也给供水规划带来了新的挑战。成功的区域化政策必须公平地平衡多个合作伙伴的利益，同时处理区域参与者之间的权力关系。在长期基础设施规划背景下，不断发展的系统状态动态加剧了这一挑战，而基础设施投资可能从根本上重塑系统状态动态。这项工作介绍了公平、稳健、适应性和稳定的深度不确定路径（DU Pathways&lt;sub>; &lt;i>;ERAS&lt;/i>; &lt;/sub>;），这是一个用于开发区域供水管理和基础设施投资路径的探索性建模框架。 DU Pathways&lt;sub>; &lt;i>;ERAS&lt;/i>; &lt;/sub>; 为利益相关者提供了一个综合框架，以评估合作伙伴之间政策成果的公平性，并探索合作基础设施政策中的区域权力关系。为了捕捉基础设施路径随时间演变的动态，DU Pathways&lt;sub>; &lt;i>;ERAS&lt;/i>; &lt;/sub>; 采用了新工具来衡量路径政策的适应能力并评估随时间演变的脆弱性。我们展示了六家公用事业供水伙伴关系的框架，寻求在北卡罗来纳州研究三角区开发合作基础设施投资途径。我们的结果表明，常用的稳健性框架可能会对区域伙伴关系产生巨大且意想不到的不利后果。结果进一步表明，区域和个体脆弱性是高度相互依存的，并强调需要通过精心设计的合作协议来限制交易对手风险。除了研究三角之外，这些结果广泛适用于全球合作供水基础设施投资和管理。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;本文受版权保护。保留所有权利。&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator>大卫·F·戈尔德、帕特里克·M·里德、大卫·E·戈尔利克、格雷戈里·W·查拉克利斯</dc:creator><category>研究文章</category><dc:title>推进公平、稳健、适应性和合作稳定的区域供水管理和基础设施投资路径</dc:title><dc:identifier>10.1029/2022WR033671</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname>水资源研究</prism:publicationname><prism:doi>10.1029/2022WR033671</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033671?af=R</prism:url><prism:section>研究文章</prism:section></item><item><link/>https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2023WR034715?af=R<pubDate> Thu, 24 Aug 2023 08:49:42 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-08-24T08:49:42-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley：水资源研究：目录<prism:coverdate></prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate></prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2023WR034715</guid><title>裂缝基质系统中的热扩散及其在地热能提取中的应用</title><description>水资源研究，已接受文章。</description><dc:description>摘要：我们研究了由多孔且可渗透的岩石基质围成的裂缝中的热分散，其中流体流动和热传输在这些介质之间的界面上耦合。裂缝基体系统中平流弥散传热的降阶模型是由雷诺分解得出的。该模型允许计算放大的色散和平流项。开发了一种简单的比例关系来估计地热裂缝矩阵系统的热量提取。结果表明，提取的热量与矩阵高度的平方成反比。我们的发现还表明，无量纲提取的热量弱依赖于断裂佩克莱特数和基体达西数，并且是基体无量纲热扩散时间的三倍。在所提出的分析中，我们假设一个同质系统。由裂缝和岩石基质特性（例如孔隙度、渗透率、厚度和孔径）变化引起的非均质性增加了更多的复杂性。使用耦合断裂矩阵方法确定热分散时需要进一步研究这些复杂性。然而，所开发的模型以及本研究的结果为从裂缝性地热储层提取热能的物理学提供了宝贵的见解，并且可用于测试实际应用中的基本假设。</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;摘要&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;我们研究了由多孔且可渗透的岩石基质围成的裂缝中的热分散，其中流体流动和热传输在这些介质之间的界面上耦合。裂隙-基体系统中平流-弥散传热的降阶模型是由雷诺分解得出的。该模型允许计算放大的色散和平流项。开发了一种简单的比例关系来估计地热裂缝基质系统的热量提取。结果表明，提取的热量与矩阵高度的平方成反比。我们的发现还表明，无量纲提取的热量弱依赖于断裂佩克莱特数和基体达西数，并且是基体无量纲热扩散时间的三倍。在所提出的分析中，我们假设一个同质系统。由裂缝和岩石基质特性（例如孔隙度、渗透率、厚度和孔径）变化引起的非均质性增加了更多的复杂性。使用耦合断裂矩阵方法确定热分散时需要进一步研究这些复杂性。然而，开发的模型以及本研究的结果为从裂缝性地热储层提取热能的物理过程提供了有价值的见解，并可用于测试实际应用中的基本假设。&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator>莫特扎·德贾姆、哈桑·哈桑扎德</dc:creator><category>研究文章</category><dc:title>裂缝基质系统中的热扩散及其在地热能提取中的应用</dc:title><dc:identifier>10.1029/2023WR034715</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname>水资源研究</prism:publicationname><prism:doi>10.1029/2023WR034715</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2023WR034715?af=R</prism:url><prism:section>研究文章</prism:section></item><item><link/>https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2023WR035383?af=R<pubDate> Thu, 24 Aug 2023 07:59:32 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-08-24T07:59:32-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley：水资源研究：目录<prism:coverdate></prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate></prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2023WR035383</guid><title>具有灵活初始条件的层状介质线性化Richards方程的精确解</title><description>水资源研究，已接受文章。</description><dc:description>摘要 Srivastava 和 Yeh (1991, https://doi.org/10.1029/90WR02772) 使用具有特定初始条件的拉普拉斯变换 (LT) 方法导出了双层介质渗透的线性化 Richards 方程 (LRE) 的精确解假定，为层状介质 LRE（即 ES-LMLRE）精确解的推导做出了最具开创性的贡献。然而，LT 方法不适合推导考虑任意初始条件或任意层数或两者的 ES-LMLRE，从而阻碍了 ES-LMLRE 开发的进一步进展。采用一种新的解决策略，即变量分离法和转移矩阵法的结合使用，我们开发了一种新型的精确分层介质LRE渗透解决方案，克服了上述困难。首先，所提出的解决方案已成功针对 Srivastava-Yeh 解决方案进行了验证。作为特征演示示例，模拟了层状介质吸水过程，我们的解决方案很好地捕捉了水力参数的异质性如何影响该过程的动态。此外，所提出的解决方案是相关数值模型的有价值的基准。本文受版权保护。版权所有。</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;摘要&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;Srivastava 和 Yeh（1991，https://doi.org/10.1029/90WR02772）使用拉普拉斯导出了两层介质渗透的线性化 Richards 方程 (LRE) 的精确解transform (LT) method with a particular initial condition assumed, making the most pioneering contribution to the derivation of exact solutions to the layered-medium LRE (ie, ES-LMLREs). However, the LT method is unsuitable for deriving an ES-LMLRE that considers either an arbitrary initial condition or an arbitrary number of layers, or both, preventing further progress in developing ES-LMLREs. Adopting a new solution strategy, namely a conjunctive use of the variable separation method and the transfer matrix method, we develop a novel exact layered-medium-LRE infiltration solution, overcoming the above difficulties.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;First, the proposed solution is successfully validated against the Srivastava-Yeh solution. As a feature-demonstration example, a layered-medium water absorption process is simulated, and our solution well captures how the heterogeneity of hydraulic parameters affects the dynamics of this process. Moreover, the proposed solution is a valuable benchmark for related numerical models.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This article is protected by copyright. All rights reserved.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> Zhang‐Long Chen, Yiyi Huang, Hongwei Fang, Tian‐Chyi Jim Yeh, Yuanyuan Zha</dc:creator><category>方法</category><dc:title>An exact solution to the linearized Richards equation for layered media with flexible initial condition</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2023WR035383</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1029/2023WR035383</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2023WR035383?af=R</prism:url><prism:section>方法</prism:section></item><item><link/>https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR034132?af=R<pubDate> Thu, 24 Aug 2023 06:19:32 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-08-24T06:19:32-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley: Water Resources Research: Table of Contents<prism:coverdate> Tue, 01 Aug 2023 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate> Tue, 01 Aug 2023 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR034132</guid><title> Evaluating European ECOSTRESS Hub Evapotranspiration Products Across a Range of Soil‐Atmospheric Aridity and Biomes Over Europe</title><description> Water Resources Research, Volume 59, Issue 8, August 2023.</description><dc:description> Abstract The ECOsystem Spaceborne Thermal Radiometer Experiment on Space Station (ECOSTRESS) is a scientific mission that collects high spatio‐temporal resolution (∼70 m, 1–5 days average revisit time) thermal images since its launch on 29 June 2018. As a predecessor of future missions, one of the main objectives of ECOSTRESS is to retrieve and understand the spatio‐temporal variations in terrestrial evapotranspiration (ET) and its responses to soil water availability and atmospheric aridity. In the European ECOSTRESS Hub (EEH), by taking advantage of land surface temperature (LST) retrievals, we generated ECOSTRESS ET products over Europe and Africa using three models with different structures and parameterization schemes, namely Surface Energy Balance System (SEBS) and Two Source Energy Balance (TSEB) parametric models, as well as the non‐parametric Surface Temperature Initiated Closure (STIC) model. A comprehensive evaluation of the EEH ET products was conducted with respect to flux measurements from 19 eddy covariance sites in Europe over six different biomes with diverse aridity levels. Results revealed comparable performances of STIC and SEBS (RMSE of ∼70 W m−2). However, the relatively complex TSEB model produced a higher RMSE of ∼90 W m−2. Comparison between STIC ET estimates and the operational ECOSTRESS ET product from NASA PT‐JPL model showed a larger RMSE (around 50 W m−2 higher) for the PT‐JPL ET estimates. Substantial overestimation (>;80 W m−2) in PT‐JPL ET estimates was evident over shrublands and savannas, presumably due to weak constraint of LST in the model. Overall, the EEH supports ET retrieval for the future high‐resolution thermal missions.</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;The ECOsystem Spaceborne Thermal Radiometer Experiment on Space Station (ECOSTRESS) is a scientific mission that collects high spatio-temporal resolution (∼70 m, 1–5 days average revisit time) thermal images since its launch on 29 June 2018. As a predecessor of future missions, one of the main objectives of ECOSTRESS is to retrieve and understand the spatio-temporal variations in terrestrial evapotranspiration (ET) and its responses to soil water availability and atmospheric aridity. In the European ECOSTRESS Hub (EEH), by taking advantage of land surface temperature (LST) retrievals, we generated ECOSTRESS ET products over Europe and Africa using three models with different structures and parameterization schemes, namely Surface Energy Balance System (SEBS) and Two Source Energy Balance (TSEB) parametric models, as well as the non-parametric Surface Temperature Initiated Closure (STIC) model. A comprehensive evaluation of the EEH ET products was conducted with respect to flux measurements from 19 eddy covariance sites in Europe over six different biomes with diverse aridity levels. Results revealed comparable performances of STIC and SEBS (RMSE of ∼70 W m&lt;sup>;−2&lt;/sup>;). However, the relatively complex TSEB model produced a higher RMSE of ∼90 W m&lt;sup>;−2&lt;/sup>;. Comparison between STIC ET estimates and the operational ECOSTRESS ET product from NASA PT-JPL model showed a larger RMSE (around 50 W m&lt;sup>;−2&lt;/sup>; higher) for the PT-JPL ET estimates. Substantial overestimation (&amp;gt;80 W m&lt;sup>;−2&lt;/sup>;) in PT-JPL ET estimates was evident over shrublands and savannas, presumably due to weak constraint of LST in the model. Overall, the EEH supports ET retrieval for the future high-resolution thermal missions.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> Tian Hu, Kaniska Mallick, Patrik Hitzelberger, Yoanne Didry, Gilles Boulet, Zoltan Szantoi, Benjamin Koetz, Itziar Alonso, Madeleine Pascolini‐Campbell, Gregory Halverson, Kerry Cawse‐Nicholson, Glynn C. Hulley, Simon Hook, Nishan Bhattarai, Albert Olioso, Jean‐Louis Roujean, Philippe Gamet, Bob Su</dc:creator><category> Research Article</category><dc:title> Evaluating European ECOSTRESS Hub Evapotranspiration Products Across a Range of Soil‐Atmospheric Aridity and Biomes Over Europe</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2022WR034132</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1029/2022WR034132</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR034132?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> Research Article</prism:section><prism:volume> 59</prism:volume><prism:number> 8</prism:number></item><item><link/> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR034024?af=R<pubDate> Wed, 23 Aug 2023 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-08-23T10:00:00-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley: Water Resources Research: Table of Contents<prism:coverdate> Tue, 01 Aug 2023 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate> Tue, 01 Aug 2023 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR034024</guid><title> Size Distributions Reveal Regime Transition of Lake Systems Under Different Dominant Driving Forces</title><description> Water Resources Research, Volume 59, Issue 8, August 2023.</description><dc:description> Abstract Power law size distribution is found to associate with fractal, self‐organized behaviors and patterns of complex systems. Such distribution also emerges from natural lakes, with potentially important links to the dynamics of lake systems. But the driving mechanism that generates and shapes this feature in lake systems remains unclear. Moreover, the power law itself was found inadequate for fully describing the size distribution of lakes, due to deviations at the two ends of size range. Based on observed and simulated lakes in China&#39;s 11 hydro‐climatic zones, we established a conceptual model for lake systems, which covers the whole size range of lake size distribution and reveals the underlying driving mechanism. The full lake size distribution is composed of three components, with three phases featured by exponential, stretched‐exponential and power law distribution. The three phases represent system states with successively increasing degrees of heterogeneity and orderliness, and more importantly, indicate the dominance of exogenic and endogenic forces, respectively. As the dominant driving force changes from endogenic to exogenic, a phase transition occurs with lake size distribution shifted from power law to stretched‐exponential and further to exponential distribution. Apart from compressing the power law phase, exogenic force also increases its scaling exponent, driving the corresponding lake size power spectrum into the regime of “blue noise.” During this process, the autocorrelation function of the lake system diverges with a possibility of going to infinity, indicating the loss of system resilience.</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;Power law size distribution is found to associate with fractal, self-organized behaviors and patterns of complex systems. Such distribution also emerges from natural lakes, with potentially important links to the dynamics of lake systems. But the driving mechanism that generates and shapes this feature in lake systems remains unclear. Moreover, the power law itself was found inadequate for fully describing the size distribution of lakes, due to deviations at the two ends of size range. Based on observed and simulated lakes in China&#39;s 11 hydro-climatic zones, we established a conceptual model for lake systems, which covers the whole size range of lake size distribution and reveals the underlying driving mechanism. The full lake size distribution is composed of three components, with three phases featured by exponential, stretched-exponential and power law distribution. The three phases represent system states with successively increasing degrees of heterogeneity and orderliness, and more importantly, indicate the dominance of exogenic and endogenic forces, respectively. As the dominant driving force changes from endogenic to exogenic, a phase transition occurs with lake size distribution shifted from power law to stretched-exponential and further to exponential distribution. Apart from compressing the power law phase, exogenic force also increases its scaling exponent, driving the corresponding lake size power spectrum into the regime of “blue noise.” During this process, the autocorrelation function of the lake system diverges with a possibility of going to infinity, indicating the loss of system resilience.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> Shengjie Hu, Zhenlei Yang, Sergio Torres, Zipeng Wang, Ling Li</dc:creator><category> Research Article</category><dc:title> Size Distributions Reveal Regime Transition of Lake Systems Under Different Dominant Driving Forces</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2022WR034024</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1029/2022WR034024</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR034024?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> Research Article</prism:section><prism:volume> 59</prism:volume><prism:number> 8</prism:number></item><item><link/> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2023WR034831?af=R<pubDate> Wed, 23 Aug 2023 09:45:56 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-08-23T09:45:56-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley: Water Resources Research: Table of Contents<prism:coverdate> Tue, 01 Aug 2023 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate> Tue, 01 Aug 2023 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2023WR034831</guid><title> Toward Improved Real‐Time Rainfall Intensity Estimation Using Video Surveillance Cameras</title><description> Water Resources Research, Volume 59, Issue 8, August 2023.</description><dc:description> Abstract Under global climate change, urban flooding occurs frequently, leading to huge economic losses and human casualties. Extreme rainfall is one of the direct and key causes of urban flooding, and accurate rainfall estimates at high spatiotemporal resolution are of great significance for real‐time urban flood forecasting. Using existing rainfall intensity measurement technologies, including ground rainfall gauges, ground‐based radar, and satellite remote sensing, it is challenging to obtain estimates of the desired quality and resolution. However, an approach based on processing distributed surveillance camera network imagery through machine learning algorithms to estimate rainfall intensities shows considerable promise. Here, we present a novel approach that first extracts raindrop information from the surveillance camera images (rather than using the raw imagery directly), followed by the use of convolutional neural networks to estimate rainfall intensity from the resulting raindrop information. Evaluation of the approach on 12 rainfall events under both daytime and nighttime conditions shows that generalization ability, and especially nighttime predictive performance, is significantly improved. This represents an important step toward achieving real‐time, high spatiotemporal resolution, measurement of urban rainfall at relatively low cost.</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;Under global climate change, urban flooding occurs frequently, leading to huge economic losses and human casualties. Extreme rainfall is one of the direct and key causes of urban flooding, and accurate rainfall estimates at high spatiotemporal resolution are of great significance for real-time urban flood forecasting. Using existing rainfall intensity measurement technologies, including ground rainfall gauges, ground-based radar, and satellite remote sensing, it is challenging to obtain estimates of the desired quality and resolution. However, an approach based on processing distributed surveillance camera network imagery through machine learning algorithms to estimate rainfall intensities shows considerable promise. Here, we present a novel approach that first extracts raindrop information from the surveillance camera images (rather than using the raw imagery directly), followed by the use of convolutional neural networks to estimate rainfall intensity from the resulting raindrop information. Evaluation of the approach on 12 rainfall events under both daytime and nighttime conditions shows that generalization ability, and especially nighttime predictive performance, is significantly improved. This represents an important step toward achieving real-time, high spatiotemporal resolution, measurement of urban rainfall at relatively low cost.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> Feifei Zheng, Hang Yin, Yiyi Ma, Huan‐Feng Duan, Hoshin Gupta, Dragan Savic, Zoran Kapelan</dc:creator><category> Research Article</category><dc:title> Toward Improved Real‐Time Rainfall Intensity Estimation Using Video Surveillance Cameras</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2023WR034831</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1029/2023WR034831</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2023WR034831?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> Research Article</prism:section><prism:volume> 59</prism:volume><prism:number> 8</prism:number></item><item><link/> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2023WR034466?af=R<pubDate> Wed, 23 Aug 2023 09:34:10 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-08-23T09:34:10-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley: Water Resources Research: Table of Contents<prism:coverdate> Tue, 01 Aug 2023 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate> Tue, 01 Aug 2023 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2023WR034466</guid><title> An Integrative Framework for Assessment of Urban Flood Response to Changing Climate</title><description> Water Resources Research, Volume 59, Issue 8, August 2023.</description><dc:description> Abstract Increasing frequency of extreme rainfall induced catastrophic urban flood events in recent decades demands proactive efforts to assess flood risk and vulnerability. Here, we develop an integrative framework for fine spatiotemporal scale assessment of urban flood response to historical and future projected changes in extreme precipitation. The framework includes three main components—nonstationary modeling of historical extreme precipitation, modeling of future precipitation, and urban flood simulations. It also provides robust estimates of uncertainty in design precipitation from statistical modeling, multiple climate models and stochastic uncertainty, estimated using machine learning techniques. We demonstrate the proposed framework for White Oak Bayou watershed in Houston, Texas, US. Two‐dimensional hydrologic‐hydraulic Interconnected Channel and Pond Routing model is used to simulate flood response from design precipitation for historical (1986–2020) and two future (2021–2050 and 2071–2100) periods in three (SSP1‐2.5, SSP2‐4.5, and SSP5‐8.5) future climate scenarios. Results show that nonstationary design estimates for historical precipitation are 14%–25% higher than the stationary estimates for 100‐year event of 1‐ to 24‐hr duration. Contrary to general global trends, we found a significant reduction in future design precipitation in all three emission scenarios. Additionally, stochastic uncertainty in future design precipitations is found to be larger than the modeling uncertainty in historical estimates and climate model uncertainty in future estimates. Flood response in terms of peak flood and total flood volume suggests that the difference in stationary versus nonstationary historical and future design precipitation are substantial to cause considerable change in simulated flood.</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;Increasing frequency of extreme rainfall induced catastrophic urban flood events in recent decades demands proactive efforts to assess flood risk and vulnerability. Here, we develop an integrative framework for fine spatiotemporal scale assessment of urban flood response to historical and future projected changes in extreme precipitation. The framework includes three main components—nonstationary modeling of historical extreme precipitation, modeling of future precipitation, and urban flood simulations. It also provides robust estimates of uncertainty in design precipitation from statistical modeling, multiple climate models and stochastic uncertainty, estimated using machine learning techniques. We demonstrate the proposed framework for White Oak Bayou watershed in Houston, Texas, US. Two-dimensional hydrologic-hydraulic Interconnected Channel and Pond Routing model is used to simulate flood response from design precipitation for historical (1986–2020) and two future (2021–2050 and 2071–2100) periods in three (SSP1-2.5, SSP2-4.5, and SSP5-8.5) future climate scenarios. Results show that nonstationary design estimates for historical precipitation are 14%–25% higher than the stationary estimates for 100-year event of 1- to 24-hr duration. Contrary to general global trends, we found a significant reduction in future design precipitation in all three emission scenarios. Additionally, stochastic uncertainty in future design precipitations is found to be larger than the modeling uncertainty in historical estimates and climate model uncertainty in future estimates. Flood response in terms of peak flood and total flood volume suggests that the difference in stationary versus nonstationary historical and future design precipitation are substantial to cause considerable change in simulated flood.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> Lalit Pal, Siddharth Saksena, Sayan Dey, Venkatesh Merwade, Chandra Shekhar Prasad Ojha</dc:creator><category> Research Article</category><dc:title> An Integrative Framework for Assessment of Urban Flood Response to Changing Climate</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2023WR034466</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1029/2023WR034466</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2023WR034466?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> Research Article</prism:section><prism:volume> 59</prism:volume><prism:number> 8</prism:number></item><item><link/> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR032831?af=R<pubDate> Tue, 22 Aug 2023 15:59:33 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-08-22T03:59:33-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley: Water Resources Research: Table of Contents <prism:coverdate></prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate></prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR032831</guid><title> Defining renewable groundwater use and its relevance to sustainable groundwater management</title><description> Water Resources Research, Accepted Article.</description><dc:description> Abstract Groundwater systems are commonly defined as renewable or non‐renewable based on natural fluxes of recharge or on estimates of aquifer storage and groundwater residence time. However, we show here that the principle of capture (ie how recharge and discharge change due to pumping) challenges simple definitions so that a groundwater system cannot be renewable or non‐renewable in and of itself, but only with reference to how the groundwater is being used. We develop and propose more hydraulically informed definitions for flux‐renewable and storage‐renewable groundwater use, and a combined definition that encompasses both the flux‐based and storage‐based perspectives such that: renewable groundwater use allows for dynamically stable re‐equilibrium of groundwater levels and quality on human timescales. Further, we show how a matrix of combinations of (1) the ratio of pumping rate to the maximum rate of capture along with (2) the response or recovery timescales implicit in this definition, leads to a useful four‐quadrant framework for characterising groundwater use, illustrated using case studies from aquifers around the world. Renewable groundwater use may inform pathways to groundwater sustainability, which encompasses a broader set of dimensions (eg socio‐political, economic, ecological and cultural) beyond the scope of groundwater science. We propose that separating physically robust definitions of renewable groundwater use from the inherently value‐based language of sustainability, can help bring much needed clarity to wider discussions about sustainable groundwater management strategies, and the role of groundwater science and scientists in such endeavours.本文受版权保护。版权所有。</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;Groundwater systems are commonly defined as renewable or non-renewable based on natural fluxes of recharge or on estimates of aquifer storage and groundwater residence time. However, we show here that the principle of capture (ie how recharge and discharge change due to pumping) challenges simple definitions so that a groundwater system cannot be renewable or non-renewable in and of itself, but only with reference to how the groundwater is being used. We develop and propose more hydraulically informed definitions for flux-renewable and storage-renewable groundwater use, and a combined definition that encompasses both the flux-based and storage-based perspectives such that: &lt;i>;renewable groundwater use allows for dynamically stable re-equilibrium of groundwater levels and quality on human timescales&lt;/i>;. Further, we show how a matrix of combinations of (1) the ratio of pumping rate to the maximum rate of capture along with (2) the response or recovery timescales implicit in this definition, leads to a useful four-quadrant framework for characterising groundwater use, illustrated using case studies from aquifers around the world. Renewable groundwater use may inform pathways to groundwater sustainability, which encompasses a broader set of dimensions (eg socio-political, economic, ecological and cultural) beyond the scope of groundwater science. We propose that separating physically robust definitions of renewable groundwater use from the inherently value-based language of sustainability, can help bring much needed clarity to wider discussions about sustainable groundwater management strategies, and the role of groundwater science and scientists in such endeavours.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This article is protected by copyright. All rights reserved.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> MO Cuthbert, T. Gleeson, MFP Bierkens, G. Ferguson, RG Taylor</dc:creator><category>评论</category><dc:title>Defining renewable groundwater use and its relevance to sustainable groundwater management</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2022WR032831</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1029/2022WR032831</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR032831?af=R</prism:url><prism:section>评论</prism:section></item><item><link/>https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR034224?af=R<pubDate> Tue, 22 Aug 2023 10:49:21 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-08-22T10:49:21-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley: Water Resources Research: Table of Contents <prism:coverdate></prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate></prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR034224</guid><title> Biogeochemical processes are altered by non‐conservative mixing at stream confluences</title><description> Water Resources Research, Accepted Article.</description><dc:description> Abstract Stream confluences are ubiquitous interfaces in freshwater networks and serve as junctions of previously independent landscapes. However, few studies have investigated how confluences influence transport, mixing, and fate of organic matter and inorganic nutrients at the scale of river networks. To understand how network biogeochemical fluxes may be altered by confluences, we conducted two sampling campaigns at five confluences in summer and fall 2021 spanning the extent of a mixed land use stream network. We sampled the confluence mainstem and tributary reaches as well as throughout the mixing zone downstream. We predicted that biologically reactive solutes would mix non‐conservatively downstream of confluences and that alterations to downstream biogeochemistry would be driven by differences in chemistry and size of the tributary and upstream reaches. In our study, confluences were geomorphically distinct (eg, wider, deeper, unique erosional and depositional features) downstream compared to reaches upstream of the confluence. Dissolved organic matter and nutrients mixed non‐conservatively downstream of the five confluences. Biogeochemical patterns downstream of confluences were only partially explained by contributing reach chemistry and drainage area. We found that the relationship between geomorphic variability, water residence time, and microbial respiration differed between reaches upstream and downstream of confluences. The lack of explanatory power from network‐scale drivers suggests that non‐conservative mixing downstream of confluences may be driven by biogeochemical processes within the confluence mixing zone. The unique geomorphology, non‐conservative biogeochemistry, and ubiquity of confluences highlights a need to account for the distinct functional role of confluences in water resource management in freshwater networks.</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;Stream confluences are ubiquitous interfaces in freshwater networks and serve as junctions of previously independent landscapes. However, few studies have investigated how confluences influence transport, mixing, and fate of organic matter and inorganic nutrients at the scale of river networks. To understand how network biogeochemical fluxes may be altered by confluences, we conducted two sampling campaigns at five confluences in summer and fall 2021 spanning the extent of a mixed land use stream network. We sampled the confluence mainstem and tributary reaches as well as throughout the mixing zone downstream. We predicted that biologically reactive solutes would mix non-conservatively downstream of confluences and that alterations to downstream biogeochemistry would be driven by differences in chemistry and size of the tributary and upstream reaches. In our study, confluences were geomorphically distinct (eg, wider, deeper, unique erosional and depositional features) downstream compared to reaches upstream of the confluence. Dissolved organic matter and nutrients mixed non-conservatively downstream of the five confluences. Biogeochemical patterns downstream of confluences were only partially explained by contributing reach chemistry and drainage area. We found that the relationship between geomorphic variability, water residence time, and microbial respiration differed between reaches upstream and downstream of confluences. The lack of explanatory power from network-scale drivers suggests that non-conservative mixing downstream of confluences may be driven by biogeochemical processes within the confluence mixing zone. The unique geomorphology, non-conservative biogeochemistry, and ubiquity of confluences highlights a need to account for the distinct functional role of confluences in water resource management in freshwater networks.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> Stephen Plont, Durelle T. Scott, Erin R. Hotchkiss</dc:creator><category> Research Article</category><dc:title> Biogeochemical processes are altered by non‐conservative mixing at stream confluences</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2022WR034224</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1029/2022WR034224</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR034224?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> Research Article</prism:section></item><item><link/> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR034289?af=R<pubDate> Tue, 22 Aug 2023 09:49:32 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-08-22T09:49:32-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley: Water Resources Research: Table of Contents<prism:coverdate> Tue, 01 Aug 2023 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate> Tue, 01 Aug 2023 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR034289</guid><title> Exploratory Analysis of Surrogate Metrics to Assess the Resilience of Water Distribution Networks</title><description> Water Resources Research, Volume 59, Issue 8, August 2023.</description><dc:description> Abstract This study compares and discusses the adequacy of surrogate resilience metrics proposed in the literature for resilience assessment of drinking water systems concerning demand increase and network redundancy. A sensitivity analysis is carried out for increasing flow rates using a conceptual case study with different layouts and demand scenarios, selecting several metrics to assess the resilience of two real network areas. Resilience metrics based on surplus energy are sensitive to network layout and demand scenarios. The network resilience index considers hydraulic reliability and network diameter uniformity. In contrast, the weighted resilience index also considers the network topology and gives importance to pipes with higher flow rates. Entropy‐based resilience metrics mainly rely on the network flows&#39; uniformity and are sensitive to pipe redundancy. The entropy metric most adequate to assess the hydraulic capacity is the diameter‐sensitive flow entropy, since it is sensitive to the velocity inside the pipes. Topology metrics cannot assess the hydraulic capacity though evaluate the system redundancy (meshed‐ness coefficient), robustness (central‐point dominance) and water transportation efficiency (average‐path length). Surrogate resilience metrics do not assess the system performance during a failure. They indicate systems which are better prepared to overcome failure events and increased demand events, providing vital information to drinking water systems management.</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;This study compares and discusses the adequacy of surrogate resilience metrics proposed in the literature for resilience assessment of drinking water systems concerning demand increase and network redundancy. A sensitivity analysis is carried out for increasing flow rates using a conceptual case study with different layouts and demand scenarios, selecting several metrics to assess the resilience of two real network areas. Resilience metrics based on surplus energy are sensitive to network layout and demand scenarios. The network resilience index considers hydraulic reliability and network diameter uniformity. In contrast, the weighted resilience index also considers the network topology and gives importance to pipes with higher flow rates. Entropy-based resilience metrics mainly rely on the network flows&#39; uniformity and are sensitive to pipe redundancy. The entropy metric most adequate to assess the hydraulic capacity is the diameter-sensitive flow entropy, since it is sensitive to the velocity inside the pipes. Topology metrics cannot assess the hydraulic capacity though evaluate the system redundancy (meshed-ness coefficient), robustness (central-point dominance) and water transportation efficiency (average-path length). Surrogate resilience metrics do not assess the system performance during a failure. They indicate systems which are better prepared to overcome failure events and increased demand events, providing vital information to drinking water systems management.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> Joana Carneiro, Dália Loureiro, Dídia Covas</dc:creator><category> Research Article</category><dc:title> Exploratory Analysis of Surrogate Metrics to Assess the Resilience of Water Distribution Networks</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2022WR034289</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1029/2022WR034289</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR034289?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> Research Article</prism:section><prism:volume> 59</prism:volume><prism:number> 8</prism:number></item><item><link/> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR034360?af=R<pubDate> Tue, 22 Aug 2023 01:59:11 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-08-22T01:59:11-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley: Water Resources Research: Table of Contents<prism:coverdate> Tue, 01 Aug 2023 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate> Tue, 01 Aug 2023 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR034360</guid><title> Assessing Contaminant Mass Discharge Uncertainty With Application of Hydraulic Conductivities Derived From Geoelectrical Cross‐Borehole Induced Polarization and Other Methods</title><description> Water Resources Research, Volume 59, Issue 8, August 2023.</description><dc:description> Abstract A new methodology was developed to support contaminant mass discharge (CMD)‐based risk assessment of groundwater contamination downgradient of point source zones. Geoelectrical cross‐borehole induced polarization (IP) data were collected at a site undergoing in situ remediation of chlorinated solvents for determining 2D hydraulic conductivity (K) distributions with an inversion model resolution of 0.15 m (vertically) x 0.50 m (horizontally) in three control planes from 10 to 20 m depth. Additionally, 18 slug tests and 31 grain size distribution analyses (GSA) from the control planes, were used for K‐estimation. The geometric means and variance of the IP, slug test, and GSA derived K‐estimates were consistent with previously studied sandy aquifers. Furthermore, the vertical variation in K between two geological settings, a sandy till and a meltwater sand formation, was clearly identified by the IP K‐estimates. The vertical variation was backed up by hydraulic profiling tool (HPT) measurements. Random realizations of CMD were simulated based on the cross‐borehole IP derived K‐values. For comparison, the CMD was also estimated with a geostatistical conditional simulation approach, using the data from slug tests and GSAs. The high IP resolution captured the small scale variations in K across the transects and led to CMD predictions with a narrow uncertainty interval, whereas slug test and GSA either under‐ or overestimated the magnitude of the areas with the highest CMD. Applying the geophysical cross‐borehole method for estimating K‐distributions in addition to traditional methods would improve CMD‐based risk assessment and evaluation of remediation performance at contaminated sites.</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;A new methodology was developed to support contaminant mass discharge (CMD)-based risk assessment of groundwater contamination downgradient of point source zones. Geoelectrical cross-borehole induced polarization (IP) data were collected at a site undergoing in situ remediation of chlorinated solvents for determining 2D hydraulic conductivity (K) distributions with an inversion model resolution of 0.15 m (vertically) &lt;i>;x&lt;/i>; 0.50 m (horizontally) in three control planes from 10 to 20 m depth. Additionally, 18 slug tests and 31 grain size distribution analyses (GSA) from the control planes, were used for K-estimation. The geometric means and variance of the IP, slug test, and GSA derived K-estimates were consistent with previously studied sandy aquifers. Furthermore, the vertical variation in K between two geological settings, a sandy till and a meltwater sand formation, was clearly identified by the IP K-estimates. The vertical variation was backed up by hydraulic profiling tool (HPT) measurements. Random realizations of CMD were simulated based on the cross-borehole IP derived K-values. For comparison, the CMD was also estimated with a geostatistical conditional simulation approach, using the data from slug tests and GSAs. The high IP resolution captured the small scale variations in K across the transects and led to CMD predictions with a narrow uncertainty interval, whereas slug test and GSA either under- or overestimated the magnitude of the areas with the highest CMD. Applying the geophysical cross-borehole method for estimating K-distributions in addition to traditional methods would improve CMD-based risk assessment and evaluation of remediation performance at contaminated sites.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> Rasmus Thalund‐Hansen, Mads Troldborg, Léa Levy, Anders Vest Christiansen, Thue S. Bording, Poul L. Bjerg</dc:creator><category> Research Article</category><dc:title> Assessing Contaminant Mass Discharge Uncertainty With Application of Hydraulic Conductivities Derived From Geoelectrical Cross‐Borehole Induced Polarization and Other Methods</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2022WR034360</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1029/2022WR034360</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR034360?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> Research Article</prism:section><prism:volume> 59</prism:volume><prism:number> 8</prism:number></item><item><link/> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR034059?af=R<pubDate> Mon, 21 Aug 2023 11:25:36 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-08-21T11:25:36-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley: Water Resources Research: Table of Contents<prism:coverdate> Tue, 01 Aug 2023 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate> Tue, 01 Aug 2023 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR034059</guid><title> A Two‐Dimensional Closed‐Form Analytical Solution for Heat Transport With Nonvertical Flow in Riparian Zones</title><description> Water Resources Research, Volume 59, Issue 8, August 2023.</description><dc:description> Abstract Heat as a tracer has received increasing attention in recent decades and has become a popular and widely used tool for quantifying streambed fluxes, among many other applications. Nonvertical flow component is an important parameter for heat transport in riparian zones. However, previous investigations using heat as a tracer in the quantification of streambed fluxes frequently overlooked or simplified nonvertical flow component with erroneous presumptions. In this study, a novelty two‐dimensional closed‐form analytical solution for heat transport with vertical and nonvertical flow components and arbitrary initial and boundary conditions under losing conditions is presented for the first time using Green&#39;s function method. The new model is tested by finite‐element solution and stochastic modeling. The capabilities of the new analytical solution are demonstrated using field data. Results show that the nonvertical flow component has a significant impact on heat transport in streambed. The temperature difference between the streambed and the surface water increases as the nonvertical flow component increases, and the amplitude of the temperature curves decreases with increasing horizontal distance from the center of stream at the same depth due to the influences of nonvertical flow. Stochastic modeling shows that an increasing nonuniform flow can result in overestimation of vertical and nonvertical flow components near the bank of stream, and the new analytical model works well in a heterogeneous streambed when the variance of natural logarithm of the streambed hydraulic conductivity is less than 0.10 (). The vertical and nonvertical flow components are more sensitive to temperature‐time data than the other parameters. The new analytical model is a significant advancement of the previous one‐dimensional analytical models which only considered vertical flow.</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;Heat as a tracer has received increasing attention in recent decades and has become a popular and widely used tool for quantifying streambed fluxes, among many other applications. Nonvertical flow component is an important parameter for heat transport in riparian zones. However, previous investigations using heat as a tracer in the quantification of streambed fluxes frequently overlooked or simplified nonvertical flow component with erroneous presumptions. In this study, a novelty two-dimensional closed-form analytical solution for heat transport with vertical and nonvertical flow components and arbitrary initial and boundary conditions under losing conditions is presented for the first time using Green&#39;s function method. The new model is tested by finite-element solution and stochastic modeling. The capabilities of the new analytical solution are demonstrated using field data. Results show that the nonvertical flow component has a significant impact on heat transport in streambed. The temperature difference between the streambed and the surface water increases as the nonvertical flow component increases, and the amplitude of the temperature curves decreases with increasing horizontal distance from the center of stream at the same depth due to the influences of nonvertical flow. Stochastic modeling shows that an increasing nonuniform flow can result in overestimation of vertical and nonvertical flow components near the bank of stream, and the new analytical model works well in a heterogeneous streambed when the variance of natural logarithm of the streambed hydraulic conductivity is less than 0.10 (). The vertical and nonvertical flow components are more sensitive to temperature-time data than the other parameters. The new analytical model is a significant advancement of the previous one-dimensional analytical models which only considered vertical flow.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> Wenguang Shi, Hongbin Zhan, Quanrong Wang, Xianjun Xie</dc:creator><category> Research Article</category><dc:title> A Two‐Dimensional Closed‐Form Analytical Solution for Heat Transport With Nonvertical Flow in Riparian Zones</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2022WR034059</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1029/2022WR034059</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR034059?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> Research Article</prism:section><prism:volume> 59</prism:volume><prism:number> 8</prism:number></item><item><link/> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033617?af=R<pubDate> Mon, 21 Aug 2023 11:23:37 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-08-21T11:23:37-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley: Water Resources Research: Table of Contents<prism:coverdate> Tue, 01 Aug 2023 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate> Tue, 01 Aug 2023 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR033617</guid><title> Multidirectional Shifts in Hydrological Connectivity Result From Hydraulic Barriers</title><description> Water Resources Research, Volume 59, Issue 8, August 2023.</description><dc:description> Abstract The weakening of hydrological connectivity caused by hydraulic barriers and its impact on the ecological environment has gained worldwide attention. Previous studies have primarily focused on the obstructive effect of barriers, often overlooking its influence on the internal connectivity of regulated water systems. The study employed a new conceptual framework of hydrological connectivity and utilized the connectivity assessment tool to assess the impact of the proposed Poyang Lake Hydraulic Project (PLHP) on the lake&#39;s internal connectivity. The estimated impacts were based on various factors, including the connectivity function (CF), the spatial distribution of the connected object (CONNOB), as well as duration and timing of connection. Key findings indicate that the PLHP will enhance the total connectivity and general connectivity involving inundation depth of the lake. This enhancement will result in increased CF values, expanded CONNOBs and prolonged connection durations. Conversely, the PLHP will weaken the general connectivity involving flow velocity and effective connectivity. As a result, CF values will decrease, CONNOBs will shrink, and connection durations will be shorter. It is important to note that the impact of hydraulic barriers varies depending on evaluation metrics, duration, timing, direction, distance, location, hydrological year, and regulation stage. Therefore, it is not appropriate to simply categorize the barrier impact as “weakening” or “enhancing.” This study innovates the knowledge of hydraulic barriers from the perspective of internal connectivity and is expected to provide more comprehensive theoretical guidance for water resource regulation and eco‐environmental protection.</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;img src=&quot;https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/cms/asset/4b67ca85-92e8-4558-9668-72108c0d9412/wrcr26766-toc-0001-m.png&quot; alt=&quot;Multidirectional Shifts in Hydrological Connectivity Result From Hydraulic Barriers&quot;/>; &lt;p>; &lt;/p>; &lt;br/>; &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;The weakening of hydrological connectivity caused by hydraulic barriers and its impact on the ecological environment has gained worldwide attention. Previous studies have primarily focused on the obstructive effect of barriers, often overlooking its influence on the internal connectivity of regulated water systems. The study employed a new conceptual framework of hydrological connectivity and utilized the connectivity assessment tool to assess the impact of the proposed Poyang Lake Hydraulic Project (PLHP) on the lake&#39;s internal connectivity. The estimated impacts were based on various factors, including the connectivity function (CF), the spatial distribution of the connected object (CONNOB), as well as duration and timing of connection. Key findings indicate that the PLHP will enhance the total connectivity and general connectivity involving inundation depth of the lake. This enhancement will result in increased CF values, expanded CONNOBs and prolonged connection durations. Conversely, the PLHP will weaken the general connectivity involving flow velocity and effective connectivity. As a result, CF values will decrease, CONNOBs will shrink, and connection durations will be shorter. It is important to note that the impact of hydraulic barriers varies depending on evaluation metrics, duration, timing, direction, distance, location, hydrological year, and regulation stage. Therefore, it is not appropriate to simply categorize the barrier impact as “weakening” or “enhancing.” This study innovates the knowledge of hydraulic barriers from the perspective of internal connectivity and is expected to provide more comprehensive theoretical guidance for water resource regulation and eco-environmental protection.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> ZQ Tan, J. Yao, LQ Gong, YL Li, Q. Zhang, XL Wang, RR Wan, B. Li</dc:creator><category> Research Article</category><dc:title> Multidirectional Shifts in Hydrological Connectivity Result From Hydraulic Barriers</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2022WR033617</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1029/2022WR033617</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033617?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> Research Article</prism:section><prism:volume> 59</prism:volume><prism:number> 8</prism:number></item><item><link/> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2023WR035162?af=R<pubDate> Mon, 21 Aug 2023 11:15:39 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-08-21T11:15:39-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley: Water Resources Research: Table of Contents<prism:coverdate> Tue, 01 Aug 2023 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate> Tue, 01 Aug 2023 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2023WR035162</guid><title> Beyond the Case Study: Characterizing Natural Floodplain Heterogeneity in the United States</title><description> Water Resources Research, Volume 59, Issue 8, August 2023.</description><dc:description> Abstract We use the five landscape ecology metrics of aggregation index, percentage of like adjacencies, interspersion and juxtaposition index, patch density, and Shannon&#39;s evenness index to assess spatial heterogeneity at 15 floodplains in the continental United States. Assessments are based on floodplain classes and patches delineated remotely using topography and vegetation. Floodplain reaches examined here represent diverse drainage areas, flow regimes, valley geometries, channel planforms, and biomes. We selected sites with minimal direct human alteration. Our objectives are to quantify floodplain spatial heterogeneity; evaluate whether statistically significant patterns are present; and interpret the statistical analyses with respect to the influence of lateral channel mobility and valley‐floor space available. We develop a conceptual model of the influences on lateral mobility and space available, and then test specific hypotheses derived from this conceptual model. These natural floodplains have a median aggregation index of 58.8%, median percentage of like adjacencies of 58.5%, median interspersion and juxtaposition index of 74.9%, median density of 1,241 patches/ha, and median Shannon&#39;s evenness index of 0.934 (n = 15). In other words, natural floodplains have moderate aggregation of classes, high evenness and intermixing of classes, and a wide range of patch densities. Drainage area, the ratio of floodplain/channel width, elevation, precipitation, total sinuosity, large wood volume, planform, and flow regime emerge as important variables to floodplain heterogeneity. These results highlight the influence of biotic‐abiotic interactions in shaping floodplain heterogeneity across diverse river corridors.</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;We use the five landscape ecology metrics of aggregation index, percentage of like adjacencies, interspersion and juxtaposition index, patch density, and Shannon&#39;s evenness index to assess spatial heterogeneity at 15 floodplains in the continental United States. Assessments are based on floodplain classes and patches delineated remotely using topography and vegetation. Floodplain reaches examined here represent diverse drainage areas, flow regimes, valley geometries, channel planforms, and biomes. We selected sites with minimal direct human alteration. Our objectives are to quantify floodplain spatial heterogeneity; evaluate whether statistically significant patterns are present; and interpret the statistical analyses with respect to the influence of lateral channel mobility and valley-floor space available. We develop a conceptual model of the influences on lateral mobility and space available, and then test specific hypotheses derived from this conceptual model. These natural floodplains have a median aggregation index of 58.8%, median percentage of like adjacencies of 58.5%, median interspersion and juxtaposition index of 74.9%, median density of 1,241 patches/ha, and median Shannon&#39;s evenness index of 0.934 (&lt;i>;n&lt;/i>; = 15). In other words, natural floodplains have moderate aggregation of classes, high evenness and intermixing of classes, and a wide range of patch densities. Drainage area, the ratio of floodplain/channel width, elevation, precipitation, total sinuosity, large wood volume, planform, and flow regime emerge as important variables to floodplain heterogeneity. These results highlight the influence of biotic-abiotic interactions in shaping floodplain heterogeneity across diverse river corridors.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> Emily P. Iskin, Ellen Wohl</dc:creator><category> Research Article</category><dc:title> Beyond the Case Study: Characterizing Natural Floodplain Heterogeneity in the United States</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2023WR035162</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1029/2023WR035162</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2023WR035162?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> Research Article</prism:section><prism:volume> 59</prism:volume><prism:number> 8</prism:number></item><item><link/> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2023WR034725?af=R<pubDate> Mon, 21 Aug 2023 11:02:48 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-08-21T11:02:48-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley: Water Resources Research: Table of Contents <prism:coverdate></prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate></prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2023WR034725</guid><title> One‐parameter analytical derivation in modified Budyko framework for unsteady‐state streamflow elasticity in humid catchments</title><description> Water Resources Research, Accepted Article.</description><dc:description> Abstract The changes in climate and catchment properties have altered the hydrological processes significantly at different spatiotemporal scales around the world. In particular for finer time scales, changes in water storage, which has been commonly neglected for long‐term temporal scales, may play an important role on hydrological processes. Nevertheless, few studies addressed this question in modifying the Budyko framework, with most of them remaining a steady‐state assumption on catchment characteristics. Here we derive new analytical formulas of unsteady‐state streamflow elasticity in a modified Budyko framework, incorporating both storage change and one specific parameter for catchment properties. We study 78 humid catchments in the USA with simulation data of daily hydrological processes from a probability‐distribution‐based hydrological model (the modified HyMOD). As indicated by results, the annual storage change ratio is linearly correlated with the annual aridity index, and this relationship can be used to estimate elasticity coefficients with our formulas. The estimated elasticity coefficients perform well in simulating the annual streamflow with the power‐law model. For different catchments, variability of the unsteady‐state elasticity is higher than that of the steady‐state elasticity. Unsteady‐state streamflow coefficients show significant linear correlation with catchment properties, such as the average slope, average elevation and catchment area. This study provides a new analytical approach to investigate the inter‐annual stability of catchments with varying climate and catchment properties.</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;The changes in climate and catchment properties have altered the hydrological processes significantly at different spatiotemporal scales around the world. In particular for finer time scales, changes in water storage, which has been commonly neglected for long-term temporal scales, may play an important role on hydrological processes. Nevertheless, few studies addressed this question in modifying the Budyko framework, with most of them remaining a steady-state assumption on catchment characteristics. Here we derive new analytical formulas of unsteady-state streamflow elasticity in a modified Budyko framework, incorporating both storage change and one specific parameter for catchment properties. We study 78 humid catchments in the USA with simulation data of daily hydrological processes from a probability-distribution-based hydrological model (the modified HyMOD). As indicated by results, the annual storage change ratio is linearly correlated with the annual aridity index, and this relationship can be used to estimate elasticity coefficients with our formulas. The estimated elasticity coefficients perform well in simulating the annual streamflow with the power-law model. For different catchments, variability of the unsteady-state elasticity is higher than that of the steady-state elasticity. Unsteady-state streamflow coefficients show significant linear correlation with catchment properties, such as the average slope, average elevation and catchment area. This study provides a new analytical approach to investigate the inter-annual stability of catchments with varying climate and catchment properties.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> Peng‐Fei Han, A. Sankarasubramanian, Xu‐Sheng Wang, Li Wan, Lili Yao</dc:creator><category> Research Article</category><dc:title> One‐parameter analytical derivation in modified Budyko framework for unsteady‐state streamflow elasticity in humid catchments</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2023WR034725</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1029/2023WR034725</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2023WR034725?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> Research Article</prism:section></item><item><link/> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033719?af=R<pubDate> Mon, 21 Aug 2023 07:57:05 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-08-21T07:57:05-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley: Water Resources Research: Table of Contents <prism:coverdate></prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate></prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR033719</guid><title> Improving CINRAD Radar QPE through GPM‐DPR Reflectivity Bias Correction</title><description> Water Resources Research, Accepted Article.</description><dc:description> Abstract Reflectivity bias of ground‐based weather radar (GR) is a common error source that can lead to biases in quantitative precipitation estimation (QPE). In this study, the Dual‐frequency Precipitation Radar onboard the Global Precipitation Measurement Mission Core Observatory (GPM‐DPR) is used to correct GR reflectivity bias. The reflectivity bias correction comprehensively considers variations in GR–DPR reflectivity difference associated with radar frequency difference, data matching approach, precipitation type, GR orographic beam blockage, attenuation, and sample size. The criteria to perform a robust GR–DPR comparison are presented. Disdrometer validation, based on 8 typical rain events from April to August 2019, demonstrates that GPM‐DPR can effectively reduce GR reflectivity bias to ±1 dB. For the period from June to August 2021, the reflectivity correction method is applied to 17 operational GRs. The multi‐radar QPE shows a significant increase in correlation coefficient (from 0.62 to 0.71), and decreases in relative mean bias (from ‐0.28 to ‐0.19) and root mean square error (from 3.96 mm to 3.54 mm) compared to rain gauges. These results confirm that GPM‐DPR can effectively correct the reflectivity biases of a GR network and improve multi‐radar QPE accuracy and consistency.本文受版权保护。版权所有。</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;Reflectivity bias of ground-based weather radar (GR) is a common error source that can lead to biases in quantitative precipitation estimation (QPE). In this study, the Dual-frequency Precipitation Radar onboard the Global Precipitation Measurement Mission Core Observatory (GPM-DPR) is used to correct GR reflectivity bias. The reflectivity bias correction comprehensively considers variations in GR–DPR reflectivity difference associated with radar frequency difference, data matching approach, precipitation type, GR orographic beam blockage, attenuation, and sample size. The criteria to perform a robust GR–DPR comparison are presented. Disdrometer validation, based on 8 typical rain events from April to August 2019, demonstrates that GPM-DPR can effectively reduce GR reflectivity bias to ±1 dB. For the period from June to August 2021, the reflectivity correction method is applied to 17 operational GRs. The multi-radar QPE shows a significant increase in correlation coefficient (from 0.62 to 0.71), and decreases in relative mean bias (from -0.28 to -0.19) and root mean square error (from 3.96 mm to 3.54 mm) compared to rain gauges. These results confirm that GPM-DPR can effectively correct the reflectivity biases of a GR network and improve multi-radar QPE accuracy and consistency.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This article is protected by copyright. All rights reserved.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> Ziwei Zhu, Youcun Qi, Donghuan Li</dc:creator><category> Research Article</category><dc:title> Improving CINRAD Radar QPE through GPM‐DPR Reflectivity Bias Correction</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2022WR033719</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1029/2022WR033719</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033719?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> Research Article</prism:section></item></channel></rss>