<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:prism="http://prismstandard.org/namespaces/basic/2.0/"><channel><title> Wiley：水资源研究：目录</title><link/>https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R<description>水资源研究目录。最新和 EarlyView 问题的文章列表。</description><language>英文</language><copyright></copyright><managingeditor>wileyonlinelibrary@wiley.com（AGU 出版物）</managingeditor><pubDate> Sun, 07 May 2023 08:12:06 +0000</pubDate><lastbuilddate> 2023 年 5 月 7 日星期日 08:12:06 +0000</lastbuilddate><generator> Atypon®文学™</generator><docs> https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs><ttl> 10080</ttl><dc:title> Wiley：水资源研究：目录</dc:title><dc:publisher>威利</dc:publisher><prism:publicationname>水资源研究</prism:publicationname><atom:link href="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"></atom:link><image/><title> Wiley：水资源研究：目录</title><url>https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/pb-assets/journal-banners/19447973.jpg</url><link/> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R<item><link/> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033387?af=R<pubDate> Sat, 06 May 2023 07:19:20 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-05-06T07:19:20-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley：水资源研究：目录<prism:coverdate></prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate></prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR033387</guid><title>两相流场景中分区示踪试验时域随机游动模型参数的后验评估</title><description>水资源研究，接受的文章。</description><dc:description>摘要 我们为解释不确定条件下的实验室规模划分示踪剂测试数据提供了可靠且有效的方法框架。所提出的方法基于时域随机游走 (TDRW) 粒子跟踪方法。后者的适用范围扩展到包括考虑延迟和捕获机制的分区示踪剂的传输。考虑到 Dwarakanath 等人的大量实验观察结果，应用了经典的最大似然法 (ML) 方法。 (1999)。这产生了模型参数的最佳估计，包括残留固定相饱和度、分配系数和用于模拟溶质捕获影响的记忆函数的参数。根据正则化项，分配系数的实验观察结果包含在目标函数中。我们表明，考虑通常通过批量实验获得的这些类型的信息对于获得分配系数和残余固定相饱和度的联合估计很重要。然后通过随机逆建模方法评估以可用数据为条件的模型参数的样本概率分布。此步骤在计算工作方面提出了重大挑战，并通过降阶代理模型执行。我们的结果表明，基于 TDRW 的方法可以有效地捕捉所分析的各种分配示踪剂的观察到的突破曲线的关键特征，并提供令人满意的残留固定相饱和度估计。本文受版权保护。版权所有。</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;我们为解释不确定条件下的实验室规模分配示踪剂测试数据提供了可靠且有效的方法框架。所提出的方法基于时域随机游走 (TDRW) 粒子跟踪方法。后者的适用范围扩展到包括考虑延迟和捕获机制的分区示踪剂的传输。考虑到 Dwarakanath 等人的大量实验观察结果，应用了经典的最大似然法 (ML) 方法。 (1999)。这产生了模型参数的最佳估计，包括残留固定相饱和度、分配系数和用于模拟溶质捕获影响的记忆函数的参数。根据正则化项，分配系数的实验观察结果包含在目标函数中。我们表明，考虑通常通过批量实验获得的这些类型的信息对于获得分配系数和残余固定相饱和度的联合估计很重要。然后通过随机逆建模方法评估以可用数据为条件的模型参数的样本概率分布。此步骤在计算工作方面提出了重大挑战，并通过降阶代理模型执行。我们的结果表明，基于 TDRW 的方法可以有效地捕捉所分析的各种分配示踪剂的观察到的突破曲线的关键特征，并提供令人满意的残留固定相饱和度估计。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;本文受版权保护。保留所有权利。&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator>伊曼纽拉·比安奇·珍妮特、阿尔贝托·瓜达尼尼、莫妮卡·里瓦</dc:creator><category>研究文章</category><dc:title>两相流场景中分区示踪试验时域随机游动模型参数的后验评估</dc:title><dc:identifier>10.1029/2022WR033387</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname>水资源研究</prism:publicationname><prism:doi>10.1029/2022WR033387</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033387?af=R</prism:url><prism:section>研究文章</prism:section></item><item><link/>https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033235?af=R<pubDate> Sat, 06 May 2023 07:15:24 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-05-06T07:15:24-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley：水资源研究：目录<prism:coverdate></prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate></prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR033235</guid><title>基于帕累托的灵敏度分析和多目标校准方法，用于整合流量和蒸发数据</title><description>水资源研究，接受的文章。</description><dc:description>摘要 蒸发作为水文研究中的校准和评估变量越来越受到关注，水文研究旨在提高水文模型的物理真实性，并超越长期建立的仅流量校准。然而，这种趋势尚未反映在旨在确定要校准的相关参数的敏感性分析中，传统上流量在其中起着主导作用。在帕累托优化方法的基础上，我们提出了一个框架，将流量和蒸发的时间动态整合到水文建模练习的敏感性分析和校准阶段，这里称为“基于帕累托的敏感性分析”和“多-客观校准”。该框架已成功应用于在西班牙三个流域使用可变渗透能力 (VIC) 模型的案例研究，作为伊比利亚半岛内不同水文气候条件的代表。几个 VIC 植被参数被确定为在敏感性分析期间对蒸发性能估计很重要，因此是改进蒸发通量模型表示的合适候选者。反过来，水流性能的敏感性主要由土壤和路线参数驱动，植被参数的贡献很小。在对流量和蒸发的性能增益和损失进行比较分析后，对最简约的参数化进行了多目标校准实验，并同时对两个水文变量进行了优化调整。这项研究的结果将有助于更好地理解将流量和蒸发数据联合整合到建模框架中所产生的权衡。本文受版权保护。版权所有。</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;摘要&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;蒸发作为水文研究中的校准和评估变量越来越受到关注，这些研究旨在提高水文模型的物理真实性，并超越长期以来仅采用径流校准的方法。然而，这种趋势尚未反映在旨在确定要校准的相关参数的敏感性分析中，传统上流量在其中起着主导作用。在帕累托优化方法的基础上，我们提出了一个框架，将流量和蒸发的时间动态整合到水文建模练习的敏感性分析和校准阶段，这里称为“基于帕累托的敏感性分析”和“多-客观校准”。该框架已成功应用于在西班牙三个流域使用可变渗透能力 (VIC) 模型的案例研究，作为伊比利亚半岛内不同水文气候条件的代表。几个 VIC 植被参数被确定为在敏感性分析期间对蒸发性能估计很重要，因此是改进蒸发通量模型表示的合适候选者。反过来，水流性能的敏感性主要由土壤和路线参数驱动，植被参数的贡献很小。在对流量和蒸发的性能增益和损失进行比较分析后，对最简约的参数化进行了多目标校准实验，并同时对两个水文变量进行了优化调整。这项研究的结果将有助于更好地理解将流量和蒸发数据联合集成到建模框架中所产生的权衡。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;本文受版权保护。保留所有权利。&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> Patricio Yeste、Lieke A. Melsen、Matilde García-Valdecas Ojeda、Sonia R. Gámiz-Fortis、Yolanda Castro-Díez、María Jesús Esteban-Parra</dc:creator><category>研究文章</category><dc:title>基于帕累托的灵敏度分析和多目标校准方法，用于整合流量和蒸发数据</dc:title><dc:identifier>10.1029/2022WR033235</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname>水资源研究</prism:publicationname><prism:doi>10.1029/2022WR033235</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033235?af=R</prism:url><prism:section>研究文章</prism:section></item><item><link/>https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2021WR031774?af=R<pubDate> Sat, 06 May 2023 03:34:20 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-05-06T03:34:20-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley：水资源研究：目录<prism:coverdate></prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate></prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2021WR031774</guid><title>耦合多组分反应传输建模的组合全局隐式方法</title><description>水资源研究，接受的文章。</description><dc:description>摘要 反应性输运模型已被广泛用于帮助提高对从孔隙尺度到流域尺度的水文地球化学过程的理解。近年来，反应式传输应用程序的范围已朝着更高级别的复杂性和过程耦合方向发展。例如，水的生产和消耗，以及与水合矿物的溶解和沉淀相关的孔隙度演化都会影响系统演化。废石风化、碳封存或放射性废物储存库中工程屏障的退化都构成了地球化学和流体动力学可以相互强烈影响的应用。出于这些目的，将地下水流和反应性传输过程分离的反应性传输模拟器的传统公式是有限的。我们提出了一种全局隐式组合方法，该方法将流动过程直接集成到反应传输和地球化学框架中。该方法通过反应输运方程隐式求解流场，同时考虑地球化学反应引起的耗水量和产量。应用表明，该模型可以解决复杂的反应传输问题，同时考虑水内反应、氧化还原反应以及涉及气相和固相传质的反应。所呈现的模拟还表明，对于反应性相对较低的复杂地球化学系统，成分方法和传统方法产生了相似的结果。本文受版权保护。版权所有。</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;摘要&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;反应输运模型已被广泛用于帮助提高对从孔隙尺度到流域尺度的水文地球化学过程的理解。近年来，反应式传输应用程序的范围已朝着更高级别的复杂性和过程耦合方向发展。例如，水的生产和消耗，以及与水合矿物的溶解和沉淀相关的孔隙度演化都会影响系统演化。废石风化、碳封存或放射性废物储存库中工程屏障的退化都构成了地球化学和流体动力学可以相互强烈影响的应用。出于这些目的，将地下水流和反应性传输过程分离的反应性传输模拟器的传统公式是有限的。我们提出了一种全局隐式组合方法，该方法将流动过程直接集成到反应传输和地球化学框架中。该方法通过反应输运方程隐式求解流场，同时考虑地球化学反应引起的耗水量和产量。应用表明，该模型允许解决复杂的反应传输问题，同时考虑水内反应、氧化还原反应以及涉及气相和固相传质的反应。所呈现的模拟还表明，对于反应性相对较低的复杂地球化学系统，成分方法和传统方法产生了相似的结果。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;本文受版权保护。保留所有权利。&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> Nicolas Seigneur、Adrien Socié、K. Ulrich Mayer</dc:creator><category>研究文章</category><dc:title>耦合多组分反应传输建模的组合全局隐式方法</dc:title><dc:identifier>10.1029/2021WR031774</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname>水资源研究</prism:publicationname><prism:doi>10.1029/2021WR031774</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2021WR031774?af=R</prism:url><prism:section>研究文章</prism:section></item><item><link/>https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033402?af=R<pubDate> Sat, 06 May 2023 01:09:45 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-05-06T01:09:45-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley：水资源研究：目录<prism:coverdate></prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate></prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR033402</guid><title>植物水力学改进了对 ET 和 GPP 对干旱响应的预测</title><description>水资源研究，接受的文章。</description><dc:description>摘要 陆地表面模型通常忽略植物水力学过程，并使用经验土壤水分胁迫函数来限制蒸腾和光合作用。植物水力学如何影响碳和水通量的预测及其对干旱的反应仍不清楚。在这里，我们开发了一种植物水力学分析方案，其中考虑了叶级和茎级的水力容量，并将其纳入植被界面过程模型 (VIP-PHS)。然后，我们使用马尔可夫链蒙特卡罗 (MCMC) 方法校准了 VIP-PHS 参数，并对 30 个 FLUXNET 站点的 VIP-PHS 进行了生态系统规模评估。结果表明，VIP-PHS 改进了研究地点的蒸散量 (ET) 和总初级生产量 (GPP) 模拟，将均方根误差 (RMSE) 降低了 0.02-0.27 mm day-1 和 0.04-0.52 g C m-与经验土壤水力学方案（以下简称 VIP-SHS）相关的第 2 天-1。 VIP-PHS 在常绿针叶林中将 ET 和 GPP 的 RMSE 降低了 45% 和 55%。与 VIP-SHS 相比，VIP-PHS 降低了 ET 和 GPP 对土壤水分胁迫的敏感性，显着改善了低土壤水分条件下 ET 和 GPP 的预测。敏感性分析表明，较大的茎干水力电容可以更好地缓解木质部水分胁迫，从而导致更高的蒸腾作用和 GPP，以及更小的负日最小茎水势。这些发现强调了在未来干旱条件下将植物水力学纳入下一代地球系统模型的必要性。本文受版权保护。版权所有。</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;摘要&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;地表模型通常忽略植物水力过程，并使用经验土壤水分胁迫函数来限制蒸腾和光合作用。植物水力学如何影响碳和水通量的预测及其对干旱的反应仍不清楚。在这里，我们开发了一种植物水力学分析方案，其中考虑了叶级和茎级的水力容量，并将其纳入植被界面过程模型 (VIP-PHS)。然后，我们使用马尔可夫链蒙特卡罗 (MCMC) 方法校准了 VIP-PHS 参数，并对 30 个 FLUXNET 站点的 VIP-PHS 进行了生态系统规模评估。结果表明，VIP-PHS 改进了研究地点的蒸散量 (ET) 和总初级生产量 (GPP) 模拟，将均方根误差 (RMSE) 降低了 0.02–0.27 mm day&lt;sup>;-1&lt;/sup>; 和0.04–0.52 g C m&lt;sup>;-2&lt;/sup>; day&lt;sup>;-1&lt;/sup>; 与经验土壤水力学方案（以下简称 VIP-SHS）相关。 VIP-PHS 在常绿针叶林中将 ET 和 GPP 的 RMSE 降低了 45% 和 55%。与VIP-SHS相比，VIP-PHS降低了ET和GPP对土壤水分胁迫的敏感性，显着改善了低土壤水分条件下ET和GPP的预测。敏感性分析表明，较大的茎干水力电容可以更好地缓解木质部水分胁迫，从而提高蒸腾作用和 GPP，并减少负日最小茎水势。这些发现强调了在未来干旱条件下将植物水力学纳入下一代地球系统模型的必要性。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;本文受版权保护。保留所有权利。&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator>谢树迪、莫兴国、刘素霞、胡石</dc:creator><category>研究文章</category><dc:title>植物水力学改进了对 ET 和 GPP 对干旱响应的预测</dc:title><dc:identifier>10.1029/2022WR033402</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname>水资源研究</prism:publicationname><prism:doi>10.1029/2022WR033402</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033402?af=R</prism:url><prism:section>研究文章</prism:section></item><item><link/>https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR034222?af=R<pubDate> Fri, 05 May 2023 09:44:24 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-05-05T09:44:24-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley：水资源研究：目录<prism:coverdate></prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate></prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR034222</guid><title>未监测盆地蒸发互补关系模型的空间和时间精度之间的权衡</title><description>水资源研究，接受的文章。</description><dc:description>摘要 实际蒸发量和潜在蒸发量之间的互补关系 (CR) 在过去几十年中得到了快速发展。通常，CR 模型的评估并不全面涵盖模型性能的空间和时间方面；因此，不同 CR 模型的时空精度和参数敏感性仍然相对未知，尤其是在未监测的盆地中。我们在中国黄河源区的月尺度上检查了四个固定参数的 CR 模型的时空性能和参数敏感性。此外，还选择了两个具有分布式参数的 CR 模型作为比较。由于缺乏蒸发时空“真实”值，修正后的水分平衡衍生蒸发被用作时间参考，多个蒸发产物的集合平均值被用作空间参考。我们发现在应用中应考虑流域蒸发的固定参数 CR 模型的空间和时间精度之间的权衡。尽管四个具有固定参数的 CR 模型表现出不同的空间和时间性能，但它们的整体性能大致相似。 CR模型的参数具有一致的时空敏感性，参数αe的敏感性强于其他参数。本研究表明，具有分布式参数的 CR 模型在估算流域或区域蒸发方面具有广阔的前景。集成的时空评估框架可以更好地区分 CR 模型的性能。这些方法可用作评估和校准符合应用需求的 CR 模型的指南。本文受版权保护。版权所有。</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;摘要&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;实际蒸发量和潜在蒸发量之间的互补关系（CR）在过去几十年中得到了快速发展。通常，CR 模型的评估并不全面涵盖模型性能的空间和时间方面；因此，不同 CR 模型的时空精度和参数敏感性仍然相对未知，尤其是在未监测的盆地中。我们在中国黄河源区的月尺度上检查了四个固定参数的 CR 模型的时空性能和参数敏感性。此外，还选择了两个具有分布式参数的 CR 模型作为比较。由于缺乏蒸发时空“真实”值，修正后的水平衡衍生蒸发被用作时间参考，多个蒸发产物的集合平均值被用作空间参考。我们发现在应用中应考虑具有固定盆地蒸发参数的 CR 模型的空间和时间精度之间的权衡。尽管四个具有固定参数的 CR 模型表现出不同的空间和时间性能，但它们的整体性能大致相似。 CR模型的参数具有一致的时空敏感性，参数&lt;i>;α&lt;/i>; &lt;sub>; &lt;i>;e&lt;/i>; &lt;/sub>;的敏感性强于其他参数。本研究表明，具有分布式参数的 CR 模型在估算流域或区域蒸发方面具有广阔的前景。集成的时空评估框架可以更好地区分 CR 模型的性能。这些方法可用作评估和校准符合应用程序需求的 CR 模型的指南。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;本文受版权保护。保留所有权利。&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> Xiaolong Zhang，Songjun Han，Yan Wang，Xiaole Kong，Ying Guo，Yanjun Shen，Yinsheng Zhang，Yan-Jun Shen</dc:creator><category>研究文章</category><dc:title>未监测盆地蒸发互补关系模型的空间和时间精度之间的权衡</dc:title><dc:identifier>10.1029/2022WR034222</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname>水资源研究</prism:publicationname><prism:doi>10.1029/2022WR034222</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR034222?af=R</prism:url><prism:section>研究文章</prism:section></item><item><link/>https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR032650?af=R<pubDate> Fri, 05 May 2023 08:34:18 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-05-05T08:34:18-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley：水资源研究：目录<prism:coverdate></prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate></prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR032650</guid><title>东亚六个不同规模水体的蒸发：规模依赖性分析</title><description>水资源研究，接受的文章。</description><dc:description>摘要 对东亚面积从 0.05 km2 到 3000 km2 的一个池塘和五个湖泊进行了比较调查，以揭示蒸发的大小依赖性及其辐射和空气动力学贡献。年蒸发量的可用能量控制与六个水体的大小无关，但蒸发量与 Penman 开阔水域蒸发量的比率随着面积的减少而从小池塘的几乎统一到两个大湖的 0.8 左右。三个组合方程的气动相关参数可以很好地用幂律的水体面积表示，这归因于传质系数随着水体的提取而减小。随尺寸增加的风速抵消了传质系数的影响，使能量分配和蒸发速率独立于尺寸。结果表明，基于能量的方程可用于蒸发，而无需考虑研究区域的水体大小。需要用更多的湖泊进一步研究组合方程的大小相关参数。本文受版权保护。版权所有。</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;摘要&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;对东亚0.05 km&lt;sup>;2&lt;/sup>;至3000 km&lt;sup>;2&lt;/sup>;面积的一塘五湖进行了比较调查，揭示了其大小-蒸发及其辐射和空气动力学贡献的依赖性。年蒸发量的可用能量控制与六个水体的大小无关，但蒸发量与 Penman 开阔水域蒸发量的比率随着面积的减少而从小池塘的几乎统一到两个大湖的 0.8 左右。三个组合方程的气动相关参数可以很好地用幂律的水体面积表示，这归因于传质系数随着水体的提取而减小。随尺寸增加的风速抵消了传质系数的影响，使能量分配和蒸发速率独立于尺寸。结果表明，基于能量的方程可用于蒸发而不考虑研究区域的水体大小。组合方程的大小相关参数需要用更多的湖泊进一步研究。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;本文受版权保护。保留所有权利。&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator>韩松军、郭方举</dc:creator><category>研究文章</category><dc:title>东亚六个不同规模水体的蒸发：规模依赖性分析</dc:title><dc:identifier>10.1029/2022WR032650</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname>水资源研究</prism:publicationname><prism:doi>10.1029/2022WR032650</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR032650?af=R</prism:url><prism:section>研究文章</prism:section></item><item><link/>https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033893?af=R<pubDate> Fri, 05 May 2023 06:03:34 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-05-05T06:03:34-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley：水资源研究：目录<prism:coverdate></prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate></prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR033893</guid><title>通过水文特征检测水库影响的全国范围</title><description>水资源研究，接受的文章。</description><dc:description>摘要 水库在水资源的供应和管理中起着至关重要的作用，其运行可以显着改变下游流量。尽管如此，水库在大规模水文模型中经常被排除在外或表现不佳，这在一定程度上可归因于缺乏描述水库运行、流入和存储的开放获取数据。为了帮助制定水库运行方案，我们整理了一套水文特征，旨在仅从下游流量记录中检测水库对大尺度流态的影响。通过消除对水库前后流量时间序列的需求（许多现有技术的要求），这些特征有助于评估更广泛的集水区的流量变化。为了证明它们的应用，我们计算了英国 111 个基准（即近自然）集水区和 186 个水库集水区（至少存在一个上游水库）的特征。我们发现，从水资源水库取水会导致水平衡出现赤字，并且预先定义的流量释放（例如补偿流量）会减少下游流量持续时间曲线和年内低流量的可变性。通过比较基准流域和水库流域的特征，我们定义了阈值，高于该阈值可以将水库的影响与自然变化区分开来，并确定了 40 个受水库存在显着影响的流域。这些签名还提供了对当地水库运营的见解，这可以为量身定制的水库运营方案的开发提供信息，并确定当前建模实践（缺乏水库代表性）不足的位置。</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;摘要&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;水库在水资源的供应和管理中起着至关重要的作用，水库的运行可以显着改变下游流量。尽管如此，水库在大规模水文模型中经常被排除在外或表现不佳，这在一定程度上可归因于缺乏描述水库运行、流入和存储的开放获取数据。为了帮助制定水库运行方案，我们整理了一套水文特征，旨在仅从下游流量记录中检测水库对大尺度流态的影响。通过消除对水库前后流量时间序列的需求（许多现有技术的要求），这些特征有助于评估更广泛的集水区的流量变化。为了证明它们的应用，我们计算了英国 111 个基准（即近自然）集水区和 186 个水库集水区（至少存在一个上游水库）的特征。我们发现，从水资源水库取水会导致水平衡出现赤字，并且预先定义的流量释放（例如补偿流量）会减少下游流量持续时间曲线和年内低流量的可变性。通过比较基准流域和水库流域的特征，我们定义了阈值，高于该阈值可以将水库的影响与自然变化区分开来，并确定了 40 个受水库存在显着影响的流域。这些签名还提供了对当地水库运营的见解，这可以为量身定制的水库运营方案的开发提供信息，并确定当前建模实践（缺乏水库代表性）不足的位置。&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> S. Salwey、G. Coxon、F. Pianosi、MB Singer、C. Hutton</dc:creator><category>研究文章</category><dc:title>通过水文特征检测水库影响的全国范围</dc:title><dc:identifier>10.1029/2022WR033893</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname>水资源研究</prism:publicationname><prism:doi>10.1029/2022WR033893</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033893?af=R</prism:url><prism:section>研究文章</prism:section></item><item><link/>https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR032039?af=R<pubDate> Thu, 04 May 2023 13:49:39 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-05-04T01:49:39-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley：水资源研究：目录<prism:coverdate>2023 年 5 月 1 日星期一 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate> 2023 年 5 月 1 日星期一 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR032039</guid><title>在美国国家水模型的洪水泛滥制图应用中，将高度延伸到最近的排水系统上方以模拟多个河流源</title><description>水资源研究，第 59 卷，第 5 期，2023 年 5 月。</description><dc:description> Abstract Height Above Nearest Drainage (HAND) 是一种排水归一化地形指数，是一种能够使用平均合成评级曲线从国家水模型 (NWM) 以大比例和高分辨率生成洪水淹没图 (FIM) 的方法。我们在此强调，HAND 仅限于从最近的流道产生洪水时产生洪水，因此缺乏从多个河流来源产生洪水的能力。提出了一种称为广义主干 (GMS) 的 HAND 版本，它将目标流网络离散化为称为水平路径 (LP) 的单位 Horton-Strahler 流顺序段。然后将与每个独立 LP 关联的 FIM 拼接在一起，通过消除相邻支流的影响，有效地将流网络转变为离散的同质单位流序组。当将淹没范围与基准的 FIM 进行比较时，通过显着减少河流交汇处的漏报，可以观察到制图技能的提高。由于通过增加集水区的大小引入阶段流量关系的转变，还观察到误报率有更多的边际降低。我们观察到，将此方法应用于整个河流网络的 4%–5% 到 100% 的网络的改进与从不减少排水订单到网络的 4%–5% 的改进幅度大致相同。 This novel contribution is framed in a new open‐source implementation that utilizes the latest combination of hydro‐conditioning techniques to enforce drainage and counter limitations in the input data.</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;Height Above Nearest Drainage (HAND), a drainage normalizing terrain index, is a means able of producing flood inundation maps (FIMs) from the National Water Model (NWM) at large scales and high resolutions using reach-averaged synthetic rating curves. We highlight here that HAND is limited to producing inundation only when sourced from its nearest flowpath, thus lacks the ability to source inundation from multiple fluvial sources. A version of HAND, known as Generalized Mainstems (GMS), is proposed that discretizes a target stream network into segments of unit Horton-Strahler stream order known as level paths (LPs). The FIMs associated with each independent LP are then mosaiced together, effectively turning the stream network into discrete groups of homogeneous unit stream order by removing the influence of neighboring tributaries. Improvement in mapping skill is observed by significantly reducing false negatives at river junctions when the inundation extents are compared to FIMs from that of benchmarks. A more marginal reduction in the false alarm rate is also observed due to a shift introduced in the stage-discharge relationship by increasing the size of the catchments. We observe that the improvement of this method applied at 4%–5% of the entire stream network to 100% of the network is about the same magnitude improvement as going from no drainage order reduction to 4%–5% of the network. This novel contribution is framed in a new open-source implementation that utilizes the latest combination of hydro-conditioning techniques to enforce drainage and counter limitations in the input data.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> Fernando Aristizabal, Fernando Salas, Gregory Petrochenkov, Trevor Grout, Brian Avant, Bradford Bates, Ryan Spies, Nick Chadwick, Zachary Wills, Jasmeet Judge</dc:creator><category> Research Article</category><dc:title> Extending Height Above Nearest Drainage to Model Multiple Fluvial Sources in Flood Inundation Mapping Applications for the US National Water Model</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2022WR032039</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1029/2022WR032039</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR032039?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> Research Article</prism:section><prism:volume> 59</prism:volume><prism:number> 5</prism:number></item><item><link/> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2023WR034653?af=R<pubDate> Thu, 04 May 2023 08:34:45 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-05-04T08:34:45-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley: Water Resources Research: Table of Contents <prism:coverdate></prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate></prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2023WR034653</guid><title> Modelling microplastic and solute transport in vegetated flows Dispersion of polyethylene in submerged model canopies</title><description> Water Resources Research, Accepted Article.</description><dc:description> Abstract Physical interactions of microplastics within vegetation and turbulent flows of freshwater systems are poorly understood. An experimental study was conducted to investigate the underlying physical transport mechanisms of microplastics over submerged canopies across a range of flow conditions common in the natural environment. The effects of changing canopy heights were investigated by testing two model canopies of varying stem heights, simulating seasonal variation. This study determined and compared the mixing and dispersion processes for microplastics and solutes utilizing fluorometric tracing techniques. A hydrodynamic model was developed based on the advection‐dispersion equation for quantifying microplastic mixing in submerged canopies. Longitudinal dispersion coefficients for neutrally buoyant microplastics (polyethylene) and solutes were significantly correlated within submerged model vegetation irrespective of the complexity of the flow regime. Hydrodynamic and solute transport models were shown to be capable of robust predictions of mixing for neutrally buoyant microplastics in environmental flows over a canopy, facilitating a new approach to quantify microplastic transport and fate.</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;Physical interactions of microplastics within vegetation and turbulent flows of freshwater systems are poorly understood. An experimental study was conducted to investigate the underlying physical transport mechanisms of microplastics over submerged canopies across a range of flow conditions common in the natural environment. The effects of changing canopy heights were investigated by testing two model canopies of varying stem heights, simulating seasonal variation. This study determined and compared the mixing and dispersion processes for microplastics and solutes utilizing fluorometric tracing techniques. A hydrodynamic model was developed based on the advection-dispersion equation for quantifying microplastic mixing in submerged canopies. Longitudinal dispersion coefficients for neutrally buoyant microplastics (polyethylene) and solutes were significantly correlated within submerged model vegetation irrespective of the complexity of the flow regime. Hydrodynamic and solute transport models were shown to be capable of robust predictions of mixing for neutrally buoyant microplastics in environmental flows over a canopy, facilitating a new approach to quantify microplastic transport and fate.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> Ben Stride, Soroush Abolfathi, MGN Odara, Gary D. Bending, Jonathan Pearson</dc:creator><category> Research Article</category><dc:title> Modelling microplastic and solute transport in vegetated flows Dispersion of polyethylene in submerged model canopies</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2023WR034653</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1029/2023WR034653</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2023WR034653?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> Research Article</prism:section></item><item><link/> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR032716?af=R<pubDate> Thu, 04 May 2023 06:51:53 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-05-04T06:51:53-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley: Water Resources Research: Table of Contents<prism:coverdate> Mon, 01 May 2023 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate> Mon, 01 May 2023 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR032716</guid><title> A Physically Based Model for the Sequential Evolution Analysis of Rainfall‐Induced Shallow Landslides in a Catchment</title><description> Water Resources Research, Volume 59, Issue 5, May 2023.</description><dc:description> Abstract Predicting the occurrence time, volume, distribution and run‐out length of shallow landslides is critical for assessing the volume of debris flow in a catchment. Recent studies suggest that the landslides hydro‐mechanical triggering (LHT) model based on threshold‐based mechanical interactions can adequately predict rainfall‐induced landslides. However, this model assumes that the soil‐rock interface is the only sliding surface and cannot dynamically determine a sliding surface above the soil‐rock interface. Therefore, by calculating the wetting front depth in the shallow soil layer and using the limit analysis method, the most likely sliding surface can be dynamically calculated to improve the model. Through linking the Soil and Water Assessment Tool (SWAT, USDA) model and the depth‐resolved LHT model (D‐LHT), a framework for predicting shallow landslides in a catchment was proposed in this work. This framework considers the effects of antecedent rainfall, the mechanical reinforcement of roots, and the spatial distribution of soil properties on slopes. The D‐LHT model was applied to the Jiangjia gully in Yunnan, China, to adequately predicted the occurrence time, scale and spatial distribution of shallow landslides. In addition, the present and antecedent rainfall effects on the shallow landslide volume were analyzed. The results showed that the average soil moisture content threshold was determined by antecedent and same‐day rainfall, which affect the timing and volume of the shallow landslides. This study provides a new method for predicting shallow landslides. The stability and simplicity of the model make it suitable for early warning systems.</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;Predicting the occurrence time, volume, distribution and run-out length of shallow landslides is critical for assessing the volume of debris flow in a catchment. Recent studies suggest that the landslides hydro-mechanical triggering (LHT) model based on threshold-based mechanical interactions can adequately predict rainfall-induced landslides. However, this model assumes that the soil-rock interface is the only sliding surface and cannot dynamically determine a sliding surface above the soil-rock interface. Therefore, by calculating the wetting front depth in the shallow soil layer and using the limit analysis method, the most likely sliding surface can be dynamically calculated to improve the model. Through linking the Soil and Water Assessment Tool (SWAT, USDA) model and the depth-resolved LHT model (D-LHT), a framework for predicting shallow landslides in a catchment was proposed in this work. This framework considers the effects of antecedent rainfall, the mechanical reinforcement of roots, and the spatial distribution of soil properties on slopes. The D-LHT model was applied to the Jiangjia gully in Yunnan, China, to adequately predicted the occurrence time, scale and spatial distribution of shallow landslides. In addition, the present and antecedent rainfall effects on the shallow landslide volume were analyzed. The results showed that the average soil moisture content threshold was determined by antecedent and same-day rainfall, which affect the timing and volume of the shallow landslides. This study provides a new method for predicting shallow landslides. The stability and simplicity of the model make it suitable for early warning systems.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> Yuanjun Jiang, Xiaobo Hu, Heng Liang, Po Ning, Xiaoyi Fan</dc:creator><category> Research Article</category><dc:title> A Physically Based Model for the Sequential Evolution Analysis of Rainfall‐Induced Shallow Landslides in a Catchment</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2022WR032716</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1029/2022WR032716</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR032716?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> Research Article</prism:section><prism:volume> 59</prism:volume><prism:number> 5</prism:number></item><item><link/> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033445?af=R<pubDate> Thu, 04 May 2023 06:51:26 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-05-04T06:51:26-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley: Water Resources Research: Table of Contents<prism:coverdate> Mon, 01 May 2023 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate> Mon, 01 May 2023 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR033445</guid><title> Linking Stream Chemistry to Subsurface Redox Architecture</title><description> Water Resources Research, Volume 59, Issue 5, May 2023.</description><dc:description> Abstract As drinking‐water scarcity grows worldwide, we need to improve predictions of the quantity and quality of our water resources. An overarching problem for model improvement is that we do not know the geological structure of aquifers in sufficient detail. In this work, we demonstrate that mineral‐water reactions imprint structure in the subsurface that impacts the flow and transport of some chemical species. Specifically, pyrite, a ubiquitous mineral, commonly oxidizes and depletes in the upper layers of the weathering profile in most humid watersheds, only remaining at depths of meters. We hypothesize that variations in concentrations (C) of pyrite‐derived sulfate released into rivers as a function of discharge (q) reflect the rate‐limiting step and depth of pyrite‐oxidizing layers. We found that log C − log q behaviors thus differ in small and large watersheds in the Susquehanna River Basin as well as in selected watersheds in the Western United States. Although coal mining changes pyrite oxidation from closed to open system with respect to O2, patterns in stream chemistry as a function of discharge are consistent with deep and shallow pyrite oxidation zones in small and large watersheds respectively. Therefore, understanding the subsurface patterns of mineral reactions and how they affect the architecture of aquifers will elucidate patterns of changing river chemistry and our ability to manage water resources in the future under accelerated land use and climate change.</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;As drinking-water scarcity grows worldwide, we need to improve predictions of the quantity and quality of our water resources. An overarching problem for model improvement is that we do not know the geological structure of aquifers in sufficient detail. In this work, we demonstrate that mineral-water reactions imprint structure in the subsurface that impacts the flow and transport of some chemical species. Specifically, pyrite, a ubiquitous mineral, commonly oxidizes and depletes in the upper layers of the weathering profile in most humid watersheds, only remaining at depths of meters. We hypothesize that variations in concentrations (&lt;i>;C&lt;/i>;) of pyrite-derived sulfate released into rivers as a function of discharge (&lt;i>;q&lt;/i>;) reflect the rate-limiting step and depth of pyrite-oxidizing layers. We found that log &lt;i>;C&lt;/i>; − log &lt;i>;q&lt;/i>; behaviors thus differ in small and large watersheds in the Susquehanna River Basin as well as in selected watersheds in the Western United States. Although coal mining changes pyrite oxidation from closed to open system with respect to O&lt;sub>;2&lt;/sub>;, patterns in stream chemistry as a function of discharge are consistent with deep and shallow pyrite oxidation zones in small and large watersheds respectively. Therefore, understanding the subsurface patterns of mineral reactions and how they affect the architecture of aquifers will elucidate patterns of changing river chemistry and our ability to manage water resources in the future under accelerated land use and climate change.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> Andrew R. Shaughnessy, Michael J. Forgeng, Tao Wen, Xin Gu, Jordon D. Hemingway, Susan L. Brantley</dc:creator><category> Research Article</category><dc:title> Linking Stream Chemistry to Subsurface Redox Architecture</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2022WR033445</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1029/2022WR033445</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033445?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> Research Article</prism:section><prism:volume> 59</prism:volume><prism:number> 5</prism:number></item><item><link/> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR032690?af=R<pubDate> Wed, 03 May 2023 13:19:29 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-05-03T01:19:29-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley: Water Resources Research: Table of Contents <prism:coverdate></prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate></prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR032690</guid><title> Time‐variability of flow recession dynamics: Application of machine learning and learning from the machine</title><description> Water Resources Research, Accepted Article.</description><dc:description> Abstract Flow recession analysis, relating discharge Q and its time rate of change −dQ/dt, has been widely used to understand catchment scale flow dynamics. However, data points in the recession plot, the plot of −dQ/dt versus Q, typically form a wide point cloud due to noise and hysteresis in the storage‐discharge relationship, and it is still unclear what information we can extract from the plot and how to understand the information. There seem to be two contrasting approaches to interpret the plot. One emphasizes the importance of the ensemble characteristics of many recessions (ie, the lower envelope or a measure of central tendency), and the other highlights the importance of the event scale analysis and questions the meaning of the ensemble characteristics. We examine if those approaches can be reconciled. We utilize a machine learning tool to capture the point cloud using the past trajectory of daily discharge. Our model results for a catchment show that most of the data points can be captured using 5 days of past discharge. We show that we can learn the catchment scale flow recession dynamics from what the machine learned. We analyze patterns learned by the machine and explain and hypothesize why the machine learned those characteristics. The hysteresis in the plot mainly occurs during the early time dynamics, and the flow recession dynamics eventually converge to an attractor in the plot, which represents the master recession curve. We also illustrate that a hysteretic storage‐discharge relationship can be estimated based on the attractor. This article is protected by copyright. All rights reserved.</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;Flow recession analysis, relating discharge &lt;i>;Q&lt;/i>; and its time rate of change −&lt;i>;dQ&lt;/i>;/&lt;i>;dt&lt;/i>;, has been widely used to understand catchment scale flow dynamics. However, data points in the recession plot, the plot of −&lt;i>;dQ&lt;/i>;/&lt;i>;dt&lt;/i>; versus &lt;i>;Q&lt;/i>;, typically form a wide point cloud due to noise and hysteresis in the storage-discharge relationship, and it is still unclear what information we can extract from the plot and how to understand the information. There seem to be two contrasting approaches to interpret the plot. One emphasizes the importance of the ensemble characteristics of many recessions (ie, the lower envelope or a measure of central tendency), and the other highlights the importance of the event scale analysis and questions the meaning of the ensemble characteristics. We examine if those approaches can be reconciled. We utilize a machine learning tool to capture the point cloud using the past trajectory of daily discharge. Our model results for a catchment show that most of the data points can be captured using 5 days of past discharge. We show that we can learn the catchment scale flow recession dynamics from what the machine learned. We analyze patterns learned by the machine and explain and hypothesize why the machine learned those characteristics. The hysteresis in the plot mainly occurs during the early time dynamics, and the flow recession dynamics eventually converge to an attractor in the plot, which represents the master recession curve. We also illustrate that a hysteretic storage-discharge relationship can be estimated based on the attractor.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This article is protected by copyright. All rights reserved.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> Minseok Kim, Hannes H. Bauser, Keith Beven, Peter A. Troch</dc:creator><category> Research Article</category><dc:title> Time‐variability of flow recession dynamics: Application of machine learning and learning from the machine</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2022WR032690</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1029/2022WR032690</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR032690?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> Research Article</prism:section></item><item><link/> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033625?af=R<pubDate> Wed, 03 May 2023 12:19:14 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-05-03T12:19:14-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley: Water Resources Research: Table of Contents <prism:coverdate></prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate></prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR033625</guid><title> Stormflow Response and &#39;Effective&#39; Hydraulic Conductivity of a Degraded Tropical Imperata Grassland Catchment as Evaluated with Two Infiltration Models</title><description> Water Resources Research, Accepted Article.</description><dc:description> Abstract Predicting catchment stormflow responses after tropical deforestation remains difficult. We used five‐minute rainfall and storm runoff data for 30 events to calibrate the Green–Ampt (GA) and the Spatially Variable Infiltration (SVI) models and predict runoff responses for a small, degraded grassland catchment on Leyte Island (the Philippines), where infiltration‐excess overland flow is considered the dominant runoff process. SVI replicated individual stormflow hydrographs better than GA, particularly for events with small runoff responses or multiple peaks. Calibrated parameter values of the SVI model (ie, spatially averaged maximum infiltration capacity, Im and initial abstraction, F0) varied markedly between events, but were statistically significant and negatively correlated with (mid‐slope) soil moisture content at 10 cm (SWC10) – as did the &#39;catchment‐wide effective&#39; hydraulic conductivity (Ke) of the GA model. Using SWC10‐based estimates of F0 and Im in SVI yielded satisfactory to good simulations for 11 out of 17 events with runoff coefficients ≥15%, but failed to reproduce the hydrographs for events with very small runoff amounts (0.25–1 mm) and low runoff coefficients (3–6%). The median field‐measured near‐surface Ksat (2 mm h‐1) was distinctly lower than the median Im (32 mm h‐1) and, to a lesser extent, Ke (∼8 mm h‐1), suggesting an underestimation of the spatially averaged Ksat by the field measurements.</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;Predicting catchment stormflow responses after tropical deforestation remains difficult. We used five-minute rainfall and storm runoff data for 30 events to calibrate the Green–Ampt (GA) and the Spatially Variable Infiltration (SVI) models and predict runoff responses for a small, degraded grassland catchment on Leyte Island (the Philippines), where infiltration-excess overland flow is considered the dominant runoff process. SVI replicated individual stormflow hydrographs better than GA, particularly for events with small runoff responses or multiple peaks. Calibrated parameter values of the SVI model (&lt;i>;ie&lt;/i>;., spatially averaged maximum infiltration capacity, &lt;i>;I&lt;/i>; &lt;sub>;m&lt;/sub>; and initial abstraction, &lt;i>;F&lt;/i>; &lt;sub>;0&lt;/sub>;) varied markedly between events, but were statistically significant and negatively correlated with (mid-slope) soil moisture content at 10 cm (SWC&lt;sub>;10&lt;/sub>;) – as did the &#39;catchment-wide effective&#39; hydraulic conductivity (&lt;i>;K&lt;/i>; &lt;sub>;e&lt;/sub>;) of the GA model. Using SWC&lt;sub>;10&lt;/sub>;-based estimates of &lt;i>;F&lt;/i>; &lt;sub>;0&lt;/sub>; and &lt;i>;I&lt;/i>; &lt;sub>;m&lt;/sub>; in SVI yielded satisfactory to good simulations for 11 out of 17 events with runoff coefficients ≥15%, but failed to reproduce the hydrographs for events with very small runoff amounts (0.25–1 mm) and low runoff coefficients (3–6%). The median field-measured near-surface &lt;i>;K&lt;/i>; &lt;sub>;sat&lt;/sub>; (2 mm h&lt;sup>;-1&lt;/sup>;) was distinctly lower than the median &lt;i>;I&lt;/i>; &lt;sub>;m&lt;/sub>; (32 mm h&lt;sup>;-1&lt;/sup>;) and, to a lesser extent, &lt;i>;K&lt;/i>; &lt;sub>;e&lt;/sub>; (∼8 mm h&lt;sup>;-1&lt;/sup>;), suggesting an underestimation of the spatially averaged &lt;i>;K&lt;/i>; &lt;sub>;sat&lt;/sub>; by the field measurements.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> Zhuo Cheng, Jun Zhang, Bofu Yu, Nick A. Chappell, HJ (Ilja) van Meerveld, L. Adrian Bruijnzeel</dc:creator><category> Research Article</category><dc:title> Stormflow Response and &#39;Effective&#39; Hydraulic Conductivity of a Degraded Tropical Imperata Grassland Catchment as Evaluated with Two Infiltration Models</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2022WR033625</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1029/2022WR033625</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033625?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> Research Article</prism:section></item><item><link/> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR032875?af=R<pubDate> Wed, 03 May 2023 12:13:25 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-05-03T12:13:25-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley: Water Resources Research: Table of Contents <prism:coverdate></prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate></prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR032875</guid><title> The severity of the 2014‐2015 snow drought in the Oregon Cascades in a multicentury context</title><description> Water Resources Research, Accepted Article.</description><dc:description> Abstract The western United States (US) is a hotspot for snow drought. The Oregon Cascade Range is highly sensitive to warming and as a result has experienced the largest mountain snowpack losses in the western US since the mid‐20th century, including a record‐breaking snow drought in 2014‐2015 that culminated in a state of emergency. While Oregon Cascade snowpacks serve as the state&#39;s primary water supply, short instrumental records limit water managers&#39; ability to fully constrain long‐term natural snowpack variability prior to the influence of ongoing and projected anthropogenic climate change. Here, we use annually‐resolved tree‐ring records to develop the first multi‐century reconstruction of Oregon Cascade April 1st Snow Water Equivalent (SWE). The model explains 58% of observed snowpack variability and extends back to 1688 AD, nearly quintupling the length of the existing snowpack record. Our reconstruction suggests that only one other multiyear event in the last three centuries was as severe as the 2014‐2015 snow drought. The 2015 event alone was more severe than nearly any other year in over three centuries. Extreme low‐to‐high snowpack &#39;whiplash&#39; transitions are a consistent feature throughout the reconstructed record. Multi‐decadal intervals of persistent below‐the‐mean peak SWE are prominent features of pre‐instrumental snowpack variability, but are generally absent from the instrumental period and likely not fully accounted for in modern water management. In the face of projected snow drought intensification and warming, our findings motivate adaptive management strategies that address declining snowpack and increasingly variable precipitation regimes. This article is protected by copyright. All rights reserved.</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;The western United States (US) is a hotspot for snow drought. The Oregon Cascade Range is highly sensitive to warming and as a result has experienced the largest mountain snowpack losses in the western US since the mid-20th century, including a record-breaking snow drought in 2014-2015 that culminated in a state of emergency. While Oregon Cascade snowpacks serve as the state&#39;s primary water supply, short instrumental records limit water managers&#39; ability to fully constrain long-term natural snowpack variability prior to the influence of ongoing and projected anthropogenic climate change. Here, we use annually-resolved tree-ring records to develop the first multi-century reconstruction of Oregon Cascade April 1st Snow Water Equivalent (SWE). The model explains 58% of observed snowpack variability and extends back to 1688 AD, nearly quintupling the length of the existing snowpack record. Our reconstruction suggests that only one other multiyear event in the last three centuries was as severe as the 2014-2015 snow drought. The 2015 event alone was more severe than nearly any other year in over three centuries. Extreme low-to-high snowpack &#39;whiplash&#39; transitions are a consistent feature throughout the reconstructed record. Multi-decadal intervals of persistent below-the-mean peak SWE are prominent features of pre-instrumental snowpack variability, but are generally absent from the instrumental period and likely not fully accounted for in modern water management. In the face of projected snow drought intensification and warming, our findings motivate adaptive management strategies that address declining snowpack and increasingly variable precipitation regimes.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This article is protected by copyright. All rights reserved.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> Laura A. Dye, Bethany L. Coulthard, Benjamin Hatchett, Inga K. Homfeld, Taylor N. Salazar, Jeremy S. Littell, Kevin J. Anchukaitis</dc:creator><category> Research Article</category><dc:title> The severity of the 2014‐2015 snow drought in the Oregon Cascades in a multicentury context</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2022WR032875</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1029/2022WR032875</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR032875?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> Research Article</prism:section></item><item><link/> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033991?af=R<pubDate> Wed, 03 May 2023 08:41:29 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-05-03T08:41:29-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley: Water Resources Research: Table of Contents <prism:coverdate></prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate></prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR033991</guid><title> Effect of combined subsurface structures and steps on hyporheic exchange</title><description> Water Resources Research, Accepted Article.</description><dc:description> Abstract The deployment of artificial structures in streambeds has been proposed as a way to enhance 21 hyporheic exchange, and numerical models can be used to quantify their effects. In this study, combinations of different structures – ie, boxes, steps and a new type of subsurface structure (L‐shaped structure) – were considered to evaluate their potential applicability on river restoration. Flow‐3D and COMSOL were applied to simulate surface and subsurface flow, respectively. The performance of the structures was evaluated on the basis of hyporheic flow and residence time distributions. For the structure sizes here considered, results showed for steps (single step, combination of two steps) and L‐shaped structures (single L‐shaped structure, combination of two L‐shaped structures) most hyporheic flowpaths return to the stream after 5 hours and 2.5 hours, respectively. Instead, shorter residence times (&lt;0.25 hours) were found for boxes (single box, combination of two boxes). For combinations of steps and permeable boxes, the values of hyporheic flow per unit width are higher (0.35 and 0.3 m2/h, respectively) than for the combination of L‐shaped (0.06 m2/h). As a result, the combinations of steps and boxes are more effective in increasing hyporheic flow. However, when subsurface structures are combined with steps the resulting hyporheic exchange is dominated by the steps. Therefore, the combined use of in‐stream and subsurface structures separately may increase their benefits for hyporheic exchange, but when steps are the other subsurface structures provide minor advantages. This article is protected by copyright. All rights reserved.</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;The deployment of artificial structures in streambeds has been proposed as a way to enhance 21 hyporheic exchange, and numerical models can be used to quantify their effects. In this study, combinations of different structures – ie, boxes, steps and a new type of subsurface structure (L-shaped structure) – were considered to evaluate their potential applicability on river restoration. Flow-3D and COMSOL were applied to simulate surface and subsurface flow, respectively. The performance of the structures was evaluated on the basis of hyporheic flow and residence time distributions. For the structure sizes here considered, results showed for steps (single step, combination of two steps) and L-shaped structures (single L-shaped structure, combination of two L-shaped structures) most hyporheic flowpaths return to the stream after 5 hours and 2.5 hours, respectively. Instead, shorter residence times (&amp;lt;0.25 hours) were found for boxes (single box, combination of two boxes). For combinations of steps and permeable boxes, the values of hyporheic flow per unit width are higher (0.35 and 0.3 m&lt;sup>;2&lt;/sup>;/h, respectively) than for the combination of L-shaped (0.06 m&lt;sup>;2&lt;/sup>;/h). As a result, the combinations of steps and boxes are more effective in increasing hyporheic flow. However, when subsurface structures are combined with steps the resulting hyporheic exchange is dominated by the steps. Therefore, the combined use of in-stream and subsurface structures separately may increase their benefits for hyporheic exchange, but when steps are the other subsurface structures provide minor advantages.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This article is protected by copyright. All rights reserved.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> M. Tajari, MH Omid, AA Dehghani, AN Ghameshlou, F. Boano</dc:creator><category> Research Article</category><dc:title> Effect of combined subsurface structures and steps on hyporheic exchange</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2022WR033991</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1029/2022WR033991</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033991?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> Research Article</prism:section></item><item><link/> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR034122?af=R<pubDate> Wed, 03 May 2023 08:40:04 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-05-03T08:40:04-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley: Water Resources Research: Table of Contents <prism:coverdate></prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate></prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR034122</guid><title> Reconstructing the Unsaturated Flow Equation from Sparse and Noisy Data: Leveraging the Synergy of Group Sparsity and Physics‐Informed Deep Learning</title><description> Water Resources Research, Accepted Article.</description><dc:description> Abstract Data‐driven scientific discovery methods have been developed and applied to discover governing equations from data, involving the attempt to discover the unsaturated flow equation in soils from data. However, an important but unresolved problem is how to reconstruct the unsaturated flow equation from highly noisy and scarce discrete data. In this study, we present a new deep‐learning framework: DeepGS (Deep‐learning‐based Group Sparsity framework), that leverages the synergy of group sparsity and physics‐informed deep learning to the latent governing equation for unsaturated flow. In particular, we design a strategy that decomposes the identification of the unsaturated flow equation into two tasks: the determination of the PDE structure and the reconstruction of the nonlinear coefficients. The tasks can be seamlessly handled by group sparse regression and the physics‐informed deep learning approach. Through the training, it realizes the simultaneous reconstruction of soil moisture dynamics and unsaturated flow governing equation. A series of comprehensive numerical experiments are conducted to determine the optimal architecture and test its performance. The results show the efficacy and robustness of DeepGS, which significantly outperform previous methods. We also conclude that accurately reconstructing soil moisture dynamics and spatiotemporal derivatives from noisy and scarce data play a critical role in governing equation discovery. This study further demonstrates the potential of discovering the governing equation for unsaturated flow from data in more complex scenarios, where rich and accurate soil moisture observations are generally intractable to access.</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;Data-driven scientific discovery methods have been developed and applied to discover governing equations from data, involving the attempt to discover the unsaturated flow equation in soils from data. However, an important but unresolved problem is how to reconstruct the unsaturated flow equation from highly noisy and scarce discrete data. In this study, we present a new deep-learning framework: DeepGS (Deep-learning-based Group Sparsity framework), that leverages the synergy of group sparsity and physics-informed deep learning to the latent governing equation for unsaturated flow. In particular, we design a strategy that decomposes the identification of the unsaturated flow equation into two tasks: the determination of the PDE structure and the reconstruction of the nonlinear coefficients. The tasks can be seamlessly handled by group sparse regression and the physics-informed deep learning approach. Through the training, it realizes the simultaneous reconstruction of soil moisture dynamics and unsaturated flow governing equation. A series of comprehensive numerical experiments are conducted to determine the optimal architecture and test its performance. The results show the efficacy and robustness of DeepGS, which significantly outperform previous methods. We also conclude that accurately reconstructing soil moisture dynamics and spatiotemporal derivatives from noisy and scarce data play a critical role in governing equation discovery. This study further demonstrates the potential of discovering the governing equation for unsaturated flow from data in more complex scenarios, where rich and accurate soil moisture observations are generally intractable to access.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> Wenxiang Song, Liangsheng Shi, Xiaolong Hu, Yanling Wang, Lijun Wang</dc:creator><category> Research Article</category><dc:title> Reconstructing the Unsaturated Flow Equation from Sparse and Noisy Data: Leveraging the Synergy of Group Sparsity and Physics‐Informed Deep Learning</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2022WR034122</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1029/2022WR034122</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR034122?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> Research Article</prism:section></item><item><link/> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033669?af=R<pubDate> Wed, 03 May 2023 08:39:53 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-05-03T08:39:53-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley: Water Resources Research: Table of Contents <prism:coverdate></prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate></prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR033669</guid><title> Reduction of Multi‐Port Water Distribution Networks using the Generalized Thevenin Theorem</title><description> Water Resources Research, Accepted Article.</description><dc:description> Abstract Expansion and reorganization of water distribution networks by connecting sub‐networks via single or multiple pipes are common practices in developing cities to serve newly developed areas. In that context, the existing large network is often replaced with its equivalent simplified network for the optimal design of the upcoming sub‐networks to avoid the computational burden. The reservoir‐pump model is frequently used by practicing hydraulic engineers to replace an existing one; however, such a model should be applied only when the networks are connected through a single pipe. In this study, a new network reduction methodology is developed for multi‐port connections utilizing the analogy between electrical circuits and hydraulic networks. The equivalent simple network is obtained by suitably applying the generalized Thevenin theorem for electrical circuits. The number of network elements in the equivalent network is significantly reduced compared to the ones obtained by the existing WDN reduction methods. Therefore, it is possible to reorganize and expand a large existing network system from a prior knowledge of its most sensitive parts. The accuracy and robustness of the proposed methodology are investigated on realistic WDNs by comparing the results with EPANET, for both Demand Driven Analysis and Pressure Driven Analysis. However, as of now, an electrical simulator is required to implement the proposed methodology due to the absence of current dependent voltage source model in hydraulic simulators. The proposed network reduction method can be of enormous utility for hydraulic engineers and opens up an opportunity to implement new elements in hydraulic simulators.</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;Expansion and reorganization of water distribution networks by connecting sub-networks via single or multiple pipes are common practices in developing cities to serve newly developed areas. In that context, the existing large network is often replaced with its equivalent simplified network for the optimal design of the upcoming sub-networks to avoid the computational burden. The reservoir-pump model is frequently used by practicing hydraulic engineers to replace an existing one; however, such a model should be applied only when the networks are connected through a single pipe. In this study, a new network reduction methodology is developed for multi-port connections utilizing the analogy between electrical circuits and hydraulic networks. The equivalent simple network is obtained by suitably applying the generalized Thevenin theorem for electrical circuits. The number of network elements in the equivalent network is significantly reduced compared to the ones obtained by the existing WDN reduction methods. Therefore, it is possible to reorganize and expand a large existing network system from a prior knowledge of its most sensitive parts. The accuracy and robustness of the proposed methodology are investigated on realistic WDNs by comparing the results with EPANET, for both Demand Driven Analysis and Pressure Driven Analysis. However, as of now, an electrical simulator is required to implement the proposed methodology due to the absence of current dependent voltage source model in hydraulic simulators. The proposed network reduction method can be of enormous utility for hydraulic engineers and opens up an opportunity to implement new elements in hydraulic simulators.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> Raman Balireddy, Anjan Chakravorty, S. Murty Bhallamudi, Soumendra Nath Kuiry</dc:creator><category> Research Article</category><dc:title> Reduction of Multi‐Port Water Distribution Networks using the Generalized Thevenin Theorem</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2022WR033669</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1029/2022WR033669</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033669?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> Research Article</prism:section></item><item><link/> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033816?af=R<pubDate> Wed, 03 May 2023 08:39:49 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-05-03T08:39:49-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley: Water Resources Research: Table of Contents <prism:coverdate></prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate></prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR033816</guid><title> Channel network modeling of flow and transport in fractured rock at the Äspö HRL: Data‐worth analysis for model development, calibration and prediction</title><description> Water Resources Research, Accepted Article.</description><dc:description> Abstract Performance assessment of nuclear waste disposal in deep crystalline bedrock demands a thorough understanding of the related flow and transport processes. Uncertainties may arise both from the selection of the conceptual model as well as the estimation of the related model parameters. Discrete fracture network (DFN) models are widely used for such modeling while channel network models (CNM) provide an alternative representation, the latter focusing on the fact that flow and transport in deep fractured media often are dominated by a small number of long preferential flow paths. This study applies the principle of channel networks, implemented in the Pychan3d simulator, to analyze the hydraulic and tracer transport behavior in a 450‐m‐deep fractured granite system at the Äspö Hard Rock Laboratory in Sweden, where extensive site characterization data, including hydraulic and tracer test data are available. Semi‐automated calibration of channel conductances to field characterization data (flow rates, drawdowns, and tracer recoveries) is performed using PEST algorithm. It was observed that an optimal CNM connectivity map for channel conductance calibration can only be developed by jointly fitting flow rates, drawdowns and tracer mass recovery values. Results from data‐calibrated channel network model when compared to a corresponding calibrated DFN model shows that the CNM calibrates and adapts better than a DFN model with uniform fracture surfaces. This comparative study shows the differences and uncertainties between two models as well as examines the implications of using them for long term model predictions. This article is protected by copyright. All rights reserved.</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;Performance assessment of nuclear waste disposal in deep crystalline bedrock demands a thorough understanding of the related flow and transport processes. Uncertainties may arise both from the selection of the conceptual model as well as the estimation of the related model parameters. Discrete fracture network (DFN) models are widely used for such modeling while channel network models (CNM) provide an alternative representation, the latter focusing on the fact that flow and transport in deep fractured media often are dominated by a small number of long preferential flow paths. This study applies the principle of channel networks, implemented in the Pychan3d simulator, to analyze the hydraulic and tracer transport behavior in a 450-m-deep fractured granite system at the Äspö Hard Rock Laboratory in Sweden, where extensive site characterization data, including hydraulic and tracer test data are available. Semi-automated calibration of channel conductances to field characterization data (flow rates, drawdowns, and tracer recoveries) is performed using PEST algorithm. It was observed that an optimal CNM connectivity map for channel conductance calibration can only be developed by jointly fitting flow rates, drawdowns and tracer mass recovery values. Results from data-calibrated channel network model when compared to a corresponding calibrated DFN model shows that the CNM calibrates and adapts better than a DFN model with uniform fracture surfaces. This comparative study shows the differences and uncertainties between two models as well as examines the implications of using them for long term model predictions.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This article is protected by copyright. All rights reserved.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> Benoit Dessirier, Kunwar Mrityunjai Sharma, Jonas Pedersen, Chin‐Fu Tsang, Auli Niemi</dc:creator><category> Research Article</category><dc:title> Channel network modeling of flow and transport in fractured rock at the Äspö HRL: Data‐worth analysis for model development, calibration and prediction</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2022WR033816</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1029/2022WR033816</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033816?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> Research Article</prism:section></item><item><link/> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033114?af=R<pubDate> Wed, 03 May 2023 08:39:20 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-05-03T08:39:20-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley: Water Resources Research: Table of Contents <prism:coverdate></prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate></prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR033114</guid><title> Experimental observations of bedload tracer movement: Effects of mixed particle sizes and bedforms</title><description> Water Resources Research, Accepted Article.</description><dc:description> Abstract Predicting the transport of bedload tracer particles is a problem of significant theoretical and practical interest. Yet, little understanding exists for transport in rivers in the presence of bedforms, which may trap grains and thereby influence travel distance. In a series of flume experiments with a sandy gravel bed in a large experimental flume, bed elevation and tracer travel distances were measured at high resolution for a range of discharges. As discharge increased, bedform height increased and bedform length decreased, increasing bedform steepness. For all tracer sizes and flow conditions, bedforms act as primary controls on the tracer travel distances. Bedform trapping increases linearly with the ratio of bedform height to tracer grain size, with 50% trapping efficiency for a ratio of two and 90% trapping efficiency for a ratio of four. A theoretical model based on the extended active layer formulation for sediment transport is able to capture much of the distribution of measured travel distances for all tracer sizes and discharges, providing a first connection between tracer transport theory and bedform trapping and indicating normal diffusion of tracers at relatively small timescales. Variable bedform geometry can influence trap efficiency for individual bedforms and the theoretical model can help identify “preferential trapping” conditions. The distribution of tracer travel distances for a mixture of grain sizes and variable discharge, as expected in natural rivers, displays heavy tail characteristics. This article is protected by copyright. All rights reserved.</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;Predicting the transport of bedload tracer particles is a problem of significant theoretical and practical interest. Yet, little understanding exists for transport in rivers in the presence of bedforms, which may trap grains and thereby influence travel distance. In a series of flume experiments with a sandy gravel bed in a large experimental flume, bed elevation and tracer travel distances were measured at high resolution for a range of discharges. As discharge increased, bedform height increased and bedform length decreased, increasing bedform steepness. For all tracer sizes and flow conditions, bedforms act as primary controls on the tracer travel distances. Bedform trapping increases linearly with the ratio of bedform height to tracer grain size, with 50% trapping efficiency for a ratio of two and 90% trapping efficiency for a ratio of four. A theoretical model based on the extended active layer formulation for sediment transport is able to capture much of the distribution of measured travel distances for all tracer sizes and discharges, providing a first connection between tracer transport theory and bedform trapping and indicating normal diffusion of tracers at relatively small timescales. Variable bedform geometry can influence trap efficiency for individual bedforms and the theoretical model can help identify “preferential trapping” conditions. The distribution of tracer travel distances for a mixture of grain sizes and variable discharge, as expected in natural rivers, displays heavy tail characteristics.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This article is protected by copyright. All rights reserved.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> Arvind Singh, Zi Wu, Peter Wilcock, Efi Foufoula‐Georgiou</dc:creator><category> Research Article</category><dc:title> Experimental observations of bedload tracer movement: Effects of mixed particle sizes and bedforms</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2022WR033114</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1029/2022WR033114</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033114?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> Research Article</prism:section></item><item><link/> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033447?af=R<pubDate> Wed, 03 May 2023 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-05-03T12:00:00-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley: Water Resources Research: Table of Contents <prism:coverdate></prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate></prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR033447</guid><title> Which Potential Evapotranspiration Formula to Use in Hydrological Modelling World‐wide?</title><description> Water Resources Research, Accepted Article.</description><dc:description> Abstract Although many potential evapotranspiration (PET) formulas are available, there is still a lack of knowledge on when and where to use them in catchment modelling world‐wide. Here we experimented with three different formulas in a global hydrological model (the World‐wide HYPE), using 15 years of observations from 5,338 streamflow gauges and global evapotranspiration from Earth‐observations (MOD16). We tested model performance in a multi‐process approach to select the best formula for catchments covering the global landmass. From comparing the results with land‐cover, climate classification, water‐energy limitations, we found that climate is the main driver behind the spatial patterns in model performance. Hargreaves was the best PET formula in 50% of the catchments, most of them located in the Amazonas, central Europe, and Oceania; Jensen‐Haise was better for catchments in northern latitudes (36%). Finally, Priestley‐Taylor was the best formula for India and latitudes above 65⁰ North. The selection of a PET formula seems to be more critical in tropical regions close to the equator, where the differences in performance are above 50%. This is also where PET is highest. We found a strong connection between the five main Köppen regions and the PET formulas, further supported by landcover analysis. Hence, the PET formulas differed in their capacity to provide useful input to the water balance modelling, with complex formulas only giving improved predictions in temperate and polar regions; however, for the rest of the globe simpler formulas were better. We thus recommend to apply different PET formulas based on climatic regions world‐wide. This article is protected by copyright. All rights reserved.</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;Although many potential evapotranspiration (PET) formulas are available, there is still a lack of knowledge on when and where to use them in catchment modelling world-wide. Here we experimented with three different formulas in a global hydrological model (the World-wide HYPE), using 15 years of observations from 5,338 streamflow gauges and global evapotranspiration from Earth-observations (MOD16). We tested model performance in a multi-process approach to select the best formula for catchments covering the global landmass. From comparing the results with land-cover, climate classification, water-energy limitations, we found that climate is the main driver behind the spatial patterns in model performance. Hargreaves was the best PET formula in 50% of the catchments, most of them located in the Amazonas, central Europe, and Oceania; Jensen-Haise was better for catchments in northern latitudes (36%). Finally, Priestley-Taylor was the best formula for India and latitudes above 65⁰ North. The selection of a PET formula seems to be more critical in tropical regions close to the equator, where the differences in performance are above 50%. This is also where PET is highest. We found a strong connection between the five main Köppen regions and the PET formulas, further supported by landcover analysis. Hence, the PET formulas differed in their capacity to provide useful input to the water balance modelling, with complex formulas only giving improved predictions in temperate and polar regions; however, for the rest of the globe simpler formulas were better. We thus recommend to apply different PET formulas based on climatic regions world-wide.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This article is protected by copyright. All rights reserved.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> R. Pimentel, B. Arheimer, L. Crochemore, JCM Andersson, IG Pechlivanidis, D. Gustafsson</dc:creator><category> Research Article</category><dc:title> Which Potential Evapotranspiration Formula to Use in Hydrological Modelling World‐wide?</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2022WR033447</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1029/2022WR033447</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033447?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> Research Article</prism:section></item><item><link/> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033494?af=R<pubDate> Wed, 03 May 2023 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-05-03T12:00:00-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley: Water Resources Research: Table of Contents <prism:coverdate></prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate></prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR033494</guid><title> An upscaled model of fill‐and‐spill hydrological response</title><description> Water Resources Research, Accepted Article.</description><dc:description> Abstract The hydrology of wetland‐dominated landscapes is often controlled by a fill‐and‐spill mechanism, whereby surface depressions retain water and release it once a deficit is filled. The response of these systems to precipitation/snowmelt events is influenced by the local storage deficit and connectivity between storage features. To estimate runoff generated from a heterogeneous wetland complex, a closed‐form analytical upscaled probabilistic model is developed. The mathematical solution requires information on the distribution of initial deficits and wetland local contributing areas, which may be estimated via a combination of spatial analysis and field observation. The model is used to explore the influence of spatial heterogeneity of wetland properties including deficit depth, local contributing area, and cascade depth (the number of wetlands in‐series within a cascade) on runoff response. It is also used to clarify “gatekeeper” storage features role at large scales and for systems with shallow wetland cascade depths. The proposed solution is shown to be a generalization of the well‐known Probability Distributed Model and Xinanjiang runoff models, augmented to include information about local contributing areas and wetlands connectivity. The closed form probabilistic mathematical solution is verified by comparing results with Monte Carlo simulations. The proposed runoff model has been implemented in Raven, a hydrologic model, to test the method performance in lumped runoff simulation of wetland‐dominated basins influenced by fill‐and‐spill hydrology. This study can contribute to our understanding of wetland characteristics distribution on landscape hydrology, and compensate for insufficiently resolved elevation data in flat terrains where threshold criteria are hard to estimate. This article is protected by copyright. All rights reserved.</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;The hydrology of wetland-dominated landscapes is often controlled by a fill-and-spill mechanism, whereby surface depressions retain water and release it once a deficit is filled. The response of these systems to precipitation/snowmelt events is influenced by the local storage deficit and connectivity between storage features. To estimate runoff generated from a heterogeneous wetland complex, a closed-form analytical upscaled probabilistic model is developed. The mathematical solution requires information on the distribution of initial deficits and wetland local contributing areas, which may be estimated via a combination of spatial analysis and field observation. The model is used to explore the influence of spatial heterogeneity of wetland properties including deficit depth, local contributing area, and cascade depth (the number of wetlands in-series within a cascade) on runoff response. It is also used to clarify “gatekeeper” storage features role at large scales and for systems with shallow wetland cascade depths. The proposed solution is shown to be a generalization of the well-known Probability Distributed Model and Xinanjiang runoff models, augmented to include information about local contributing areas and wetlands connectivity. The closed form probabilistic mathematical solution is verified by comparing results with Monte Carlo simulations. The proposed runoff model has been implemented in Raven, a hydrologic model, to test the method performance in lumped runoff simulation of wetland-dominated basins influenced by fill-and-spill hydrology. This study can contribute to our understanding of wetland characteristics distribution on landscape hydrology, and compensate for insufficiently resolved elevation data in flat terrains where threshold criteria are hard to estimate.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This article is protected by copyright. All rights reserved.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> Mahkameh Taheri, Mark Ranjram, James R. Craig</dc:creator><category> Research Article</category><dc:title> An upscaled model of fill‐and‐spill hydrological response</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2022WR033494</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1029/2022WR033494</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033494?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> Research Article</prism:section></item></channel></rss>