<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:prism="http://prismstandard.org/namespaces/basic/2.0/"><channel><title> Wiley：水资源研究：目录</title><link/>https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R<description>水资源研究目录。最新期和 EarlyView 期的文章列表。</description><language> en-US</language><copyright></copyright><managingeditor> wileyonlinelibrary@wiley.com（AGU 出版物）</managingeditor><pubDate> Wed, 12 Jul 2023 07:40:04 +0000</pubDate><lastbuilddate> 2023 年 7 月 12 日星期三 07:40:04 +0000</lastbuilddate><generator> Atypon®文学™</generator><docs> https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs><ttl> 10080</ttl><dc:title> Wiley：水资源研究：目录</dc:title><dc:publisher>威利</dc:publisher><prism:publicationname>水资源研究</prism:publicationname><atom:link href="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"></atom:link><image/><title> Wiley：水资源研究：目录</title><url>https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/pb-assets/journal-banners/19447973.jpg</url><link/> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R<item><link/> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR032630?af=R<pubDate> Tue, 11 Jul 2023 08:06:00 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-07-11T08:06:00-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley：水资源研究：目录<prism:coverdate></prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate></prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR032630</guid><title>基于遥感方法的大面积农作物水足迹评价：以玉米为例</title><description>水资源研究，已接受文章。</description><dc:description>摘要 农业是全球最大的水资源消耗国，准确测量农作物水足迹（CWF）可以为评价农业生产用水特征、指导水资源管理提供科学依据。区域水力测量需要大量地面数据，遥感为大范围科学测量水力提供了有效手段。在本研究中，我们开发了一种基于中国全球蒸散量（MOD16 和 GLDAS-Noah）产品来估算区域玉米作物水足迹的有效方法。我们还根据FAO Penman-Monteith方程（FAO-PM）计算了中国场地尺度的CWF。我们通过将这些方法与八个基于涡流协方差的通量塔测量进行比较来评估这些方法的准确性。从计算的基本原理和特点出发，分析了三种水足迹计算结果背后的联系和差异。结果表明，基于MOD16和GLDAS-Noah，CWF具有相似的分布，反映了区域土壤湿度对CWF的影响。三种定量方法的计算原理分析表明，FAO-PM 模型中基于 ETc 的方法与潮湿地区基于 MOD16 和 GLDAS-Noah 的作物水足迹相似，两种基于遥感的方法都考虑了水干旱和半干旱地区 CWF 的测量比基于 ETc 的方法更接近现实。本文受版权保护。版权所有。</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;农业是全球最大的水资源消耗者，农作物水足迹（CWF）的准确测量可以为评价农业生产用水特征、指导水资源管理提供科学依据。区域水力测量需要大量地面数据，遥感为大范围科学测量水力提供了有效手段。在本研究中，我们开发了一种基于中国全球蒸散量（MOD16 和 GLDAS-Noah）产品来估算区域玉米作物水足迹的有效方法。我们还根据FAO Penman-Monteith方程（FAO-PM）计算了中国场地尺度的CWF。我们通过将这些方法与八个基于涡流协方差的通量塔测量进行比较来评估这些方法的准确性。从计算的基本原理和特点出发，分析了三种水足迹计算结果背后的联系和差异。结果表明，基于MOD16和GLDAS-Noah的CWF具有相似的分布，反映了区域土壤湿度对CWF的影响。对三种定量方法的计算原理分析表明，FAO-PM 模型中基于 ET&lt;sub>;c&lt;/sub>; 的方法与潮湿地区基于 MOD16 和 GLDAS-Noah 的作物水足迹相似，两个基于遥感的方法考虑了干湿冠层条件下土壤蒸发和水耗散过程中的水分约束，在干旱半干旱地区的CWF测量中比基于ET&lt;sub>;c&lt;/sub>;的方法更接近实际情况。干旱地区。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;本文受版权保护。保留所有权利。&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator>李峥、孙世坤、赵金峰、李冲、高子涵、尹亚丽、王玉宝、吴普特</dc:creator><category>研究文章</category><dc:title>基于遥感方法的大面积农作物水足迹评价：以玉米为例</dc:title><dc:identifier>10.1029/2022WR032630</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname>水资源研究</prism:publicationname><prism:doi>10.1029/2022WR032630</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR032630?af=R</prism:url><prism:section>研究文章</prism:section></item><item><link/>https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR034053?af=R<pubDate> Mon, 10 Jul 2023 09:27:10 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-07-10T09:27:10-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley：水资源研究：目录<prism:coverdate>2023 年 7 月 1 日，星期六 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate> 2023 年 7 月 1 日，星期六 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR034053</guid><title>流量、地下水梯度和河床微地形控制源头暂时蓄水的时间动态</title><description>《水资源研究》，第 59 卷，第 7 期，2023 年 7 月。</description><dc:description>摘要 过去研究对瞬态储存模型（TSM）结果的相互矛盾的解释阻碍了对水文条件如何控制河流中溶质输送的理解。为了解决这个问题，我们在卢森堡的韦尔巴赫溪流中进行了 30 次瞬时示踪剂实验。使用迭代建模方法，我们校准 TSM 参数并评估它们在各种水文条件下的可识别性。近河地下水监测井和河床激光雷达扫描用于评估每次实验的潜流带和水下沉积物的面积。我们的研究结果表明，增加放电会增强参数相互作用，需要更多 TSM 参数样本才能获得可识别的结果。我们的结果还表明，研究地点的瞬时储存受到低流量期间河内和潜流交换过程的影响，这可能是由于潜流区范围较大，且与河床上板岩碎片的大小相比，水位相对较低。然而，随着流量的增加，河道内蓄水区成为平流河道的一部分，并且流向邻近地下水的局部河流水损失较低，表明暂时蓄水的潜流交换减少。获得的结果用于为研究地点生成水文过程线，说明不同流量下的河内和潜流储存的动态演化，从而深入了解示踪剂实验之前不同瞬态储存过程的预期影响。总体而言，我们的研究增强了对潜流区和河内蓄水区在暂态蓄水中作用的理解，并有助于更准确地估计 TSM 参数。</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;摘要&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;过去研究对瞬态储存模型 (TSM) 结果的矛盾解释阻碍了对水文条件如何控制溪流中溶质迁移的理解。为了解决这个问题，我们在卢森堡的韦尔巴赫溪流中进行了 30 次瞬时示踪剂实验。使用迭代建模方法，我们校准 TSM 参数并评估它们在各种水文条件下的可识别性。近河地下水监测井和河床激光雷达扫描用于评估每次实验的潜流带和水下沉积物的面积。我们的研究结果表明，增加放电会增强参数相互作用，需要更多 TSM 参数样本才能获得可识别的结果。我们的结果还表明，研究地点的瞬时储存受到低流量期间河内和潜流交换过程的影响，这可能是由于潜流区范围较大，且与河床上板岩碎片的大小相比，水位相对较低。然而，随着流量的增加，河内蓄水区成为平流河道的一部分，并且流向邻近地下水的局部河流水损失较低，表明暂时蓄水的潜流交换减少。获得的结果用于生成研究地点的水文过程线，说明随流量变化的河内和潜流蓄水的动态演变，从而深入了解示踪剂实验之前不同瞬态蓄水过程的预期影响。总体而言，我们的研究增强了对潜流区和河内蓄水区在暂态蓄水中作用的理解，并有助于更准确地估计TSM参数。&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator>恩里科·博南诺、君特·布洛施尔、朱利安·克劳斯</dc:creator><category>研究文章</category><dc:title>流量、地下水梯度和河床微地形控制源头暂时蓄水的时间动态</dc:title><dc:identifier>10.1029/2022WR034053</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname>水资源研究</prism:publicationname><prism:doi>10.1029/2022WR034053</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR034053?af=R</prism:url><prism:section>研究文章</prism:section><prism:volume>59</prism:volume><prism:number> 7</prism:number></item><item><link/> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR031929?af=R<pubDate> Mon, 10 Jul 2023 09:25:25 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-07-10T09:25:25-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley：水资源研究：目录<prism:coverdate>2023 年 7 月 1 日，星期六 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate> 2023 年 7 月 1 日，星期六 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR031929</guid><title>探索基于特征的模型校准，用于未计量盆地的水流预测</title><description>《水资源研究》，第 59 卷，第 7 期，2023 年 7 月。</description><dc:description>摘要：将降水-径流模型校准为径流特征是未计量流域（PUB）径流预测的一种有前景的方法。在这种情况下，参数和预测不确定性的估计并非微不足道，因为：（a）校准发生在特征域中，而预测需要在时域中进行，以及（b）估计水流特征（例如，来自捐助者集水区）而不是“观察到的”（根据目标流域中观察到的水流计算得出），因此特别不确定。本研究研究了在近似贝叶斯计算框架中使用估计签名的模型校准。首先，我们基于季节性流量持续时间曲线构建随机签名传输模型。其次，我们根据估计的特征校准降水-径流模型，并考虑到它们的不确定性。所提出的方法在瑞士图尔盆地的六个流域进行了测试。考虑三种数据可用性场景：(a) 伴随场景，其中“观察到”签名；(b) 非伴随场景，其中签名从不同时间段传输；(c) 区域化场景，其中签名从不同时间段传输（邻近）捐助集水区。在这项研究中，从观察到的区域化特征的转变将预测水流的不确定性增加了 38%，并使与观测的（确定性）拟合恶化了 17%（就纳什-萨特克利夫效率而言）。尽管出现这种恶化，后验预测不确定性仍然低于使用代表性参数范围内的统一先验生成的先验预测不确定性（“未校准”模型），这证明了所提出的基于签名的校准的有效性。更重要的是，在未测量的流域处可靠地估计了不确定性，这代表了随机水流 PUB 的关键进步。</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;将降水-径流模型校准为径流特征是在未计量流域 (PUB) 中进行径流预测的一种很有前途的方法。在这种情况下，参数和预测不确定性的估计并非微不足道，因为：（a）校准发生在特征域中，而预测需要在时域中进行，以及（b）估计水流特征（例如，来自捐助者集水区）而不是“观察到的”（根据目标流域中观察到的水流计算得出），因此特别不确定。本研究研究了在近似贝叶斯计算框架中使用估计签名的模型校准。首先，我们基于季节性流量持续时间曲线构建随机签名传输模型。其次，我们根据估计的特征校准降水-径流模型，并考虑到它们的不确定性。所提出的方法在瑞士图尔盆地的六个流域进行了测试。考虑三种数据可用性场景：(a) 伴随场景，其中“观察到”签名；(b) 非伴随场景，其中签名从不同时间段传输；(c) 区域化场景，其中签名从不同时间段传输（邻近）捐助集水区。在这项研究中，从观察到的区域化特征的转变将预测水流的不确定性增加了 38%，并使与观测的（确定性）拟合恶化了 17%（就 Nash-Sutcliffe 效率而言）。尽管这种恶化，后验预测不确定性仍然低于使用代表性参数范围内的统一先验生成的先验预测不确定性（“未校准”模型），这证明了所提出的基于签名的校准的有效性。更重要的是，在未测量的流域处可靠地估计了不确定性，这代表了随机水流 PUB 的关键进步。&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator>马可·达尔·莫林、德米特里·卡维茨基、卡洛·艾伯特、法布里齐奥·费尼西亚</dc:creator><category>研究文章</category><dc:title>探索基于特征的模型校准，用于未计量盆地的水流预测</dc:title><dc:identifier>10.1029/2022WR031929</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname>水资源研究</prism:publicationname><prism:doi>10.1029/2022WR031929</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR031929?af=R</prism:url><prism:section>研究文章</prism:section><prism:volume>59</prism:volume><prism:number> 7</prism:number></item><item><link/> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2023WR034662?af=R<pubDate> Mon, 10 Jul 2023 09:20:20 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-07-10T09:20:20-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley：水资源研究：目录<prism:coverdate>2023 年 7 月 1 日，星期六 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate> 2023 年 7 月 1 日，星期六 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2023WR034662</guid><title>考虑吸附水和毛管水冻结的土壤冻结特性曲线理论模型</title><description>《水资源研究》，第 59 卷，第 7 期，2023 年 7 月。</description><dc:description>摘要 土壤冻结特征曲线（SFCC）代表了零下温度与土壤未冻水含量之间的本构关系。它控制与冻结土壤相关的水文和机械行为。许多研究调查了土壤水结冰的机制，并尝试使用土壤水特征曲线（SWCC）和克拉佩龙方程来预测SFCC。然而，人们对冻结过程中吸附水和毛细管水之间的物理差异的关注有限，包括压力和水-冰界面的变化。在这项研究中，我们提出了一种预测 SFCC 的新颖理论模型。该模型通过计算土壤水和冰的化学势及其各自的压力来确定冰点，从而捕捉吸附水和毛细水之间冻结行为的区别。所有模型参数都具有明确的物理解释，并且模型仅依赖于 SWCC 作为输入。通过涉及沙质、粉质和粘土的水相图、SWCC 和相应的 SFCC 的实验测量，证实了所提出模型的有效性。无论土壤类型如何，该模型都表现出强大的 SFCC 预测能力，并且在预测高吸附水含量土壤的 SFCC 方面优于传统方法。通过模型分析研究了单个孔径、土壤类型和初始含水量对冻结过程的影响，揭示了吸附和毛细管作用在土壤水冻结中的独特贡献。该研究阐明了土壤水冻结的机制，为冻土行为的分析和预测提供了理论框架。</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;摘要&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;土壤冻结特征曲线（SFCC）代表零下温度与土壤未冻水含量之间的本构关系。它控制与冻结土壤相关的水文和机械行为。许多研究调查了土壤水结冰的机制，并尝试使用土壤水特征曲线（SWCC）和克拉佩龙方程来预测SFCC。然而，人们对冻结过程中吸附水和毛细管水之间的物理差异（包括压力和水-冰界面的变化）的关注有限。在这项研究中，我们提出了一种预测 SFCC 的新颖理论模型。该模型通过计算土壤水和冰的化学势及其各自的压力来确定冰点，从而捕捉吸附水和毛细水之间冻结行为的区别。所有模型参数都具有明确的物理解释，并且模型仅依赖于 SWCC 作为输入。通过涉及沙质、粉质和粘土的水相图、SWCC 和相应的 SFCC 的实验测量，证实了所提出模型的有效性。无论土壤类型如何，该模型都表现出强大的 SFCC 预测能力，并且在预测高吸附水含量土壤的 SFCC 方面优于传统方法。通过模型分析研究了单个孔径、土壤类型和初始含水量对冻结过程的影响，揭示了吸附和毛细管作用在土壤水冻结中的独特贡献。本研究阐明了土壤水冻结的机制，为冻土行为分析和预测提供了理论框架。&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator>王逸杰、胡黎明</dc:creator><category>研究文章</category><dc:title>考虑吸附水和毛管水冻结的土壤冻结特性曲线理论模型</dc:title><dc:identifier>10.1029/2023WR034662</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname>水资源研究</prism:publicationname><prism:doi>10.1029/2023WR034662</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2023WR034662?af=R</prism:url><prism:section>研究文章</prism:section><prism:volume>59</prism:volume><prism:number> 7</prism:number></item><item><link/> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033681?af=R<pubDate> Mon, 10 Jul 2023 09:20:12 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-07-10T09:20:12-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley：水资源研究：目录<prism:coverdate>2023 年 7 月 1 日，星期六 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate> 2023 年 7 月 1 日，星期六 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR033681</guid><title>基于水文对象的湖流拓扑系统流向模型构建</title><description>《水资源研究》，第 59 卷，第 7 期，2023 年 7 月。</description><dc:description>摘要 湖泊和溪流的拓扑系统是衍生多种水文学、地貌学和生态学模式和过程的基础。流向是构建湖流拓扑系统的关键。然而，湖泊和溪流是重要的水文对象，应予以考虑，因为它们在物质和能量运输过程中是相互联系的。因此，本文提出了一种能够清晰表达湖泊和溪流拓扑关系的流向算法。将湖泊和溪流作为河流网络中的水文对象并耦合到流向算法中。基于所提出的算法建立了拓扑系统。选择青藏高原6个地区作为样本区，以MERIT数字高程模型（DEM）作为DEM数据源。将来自 HydroSHEDS 数据集 (HYDROSTREAMS) 和 MERIT Hydro 数据集 (MERITSTREAMS) 中流向数据的水流，以及来自 D-infinity 算法和优先洪水算法流向结果的水流与来自提出的算法。该算法清楚地表达了河流和湖泊之间的拓扑关系。在湖泊地区，所提出的算法表现出更好的性能，并且没有发现并行流。在非湖泊地区，由这些算法得出的河流网络是稳定的。所提出的算法提供了在模拟过程中以不同方式处理湖泊和溪流的机会，从而增加了模拟的真实性。</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;摘要&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;湖泊和溪流的拓扑系统是衍生水文学、地貌学和生态学中多种模式和过程的基础。流向是构建湖溪拓扑系统的关键。然而，湖泊和溪流是重要的水文对象，应予以考虑，因为它们在物质和能量运输过程中是相互联系的。因此，本文提出了一种能够清晰表达湖泊和溪流拓扑关系的流向算法。将湖泊和溪流作为河流网络中的水文对象并耦合到流向算法中。基于所提出的算法建立了拓扑系统。选择青藏高原6个地区作为样本区，以MERIT数字高程模型（DEM）作为DEM数据源。将来自 HydroSHEDS 数据集 (HYDROSTREAMS) 和 MERIT Hydro 数据集 (MERITSTREAMS) 中的流向数据的水流，以及来自 D-infinity 算法和优先洪水算法的流向结果的水流与来自提出的算法。该算法清楚地表达了河流和湖泊之间的拓扑关系。在湖泊地区，所提出的算法表现出更好的性能，并且没有发现并行流。在非湖泊地区，由这些算法得出的河流网络是稳定的。所提出的算法提供了在模拟过程中以不同方式处理湖泊和溪流的机会，从而增加了模拟的真实性。&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator>赵飞、熊立洋、张楚之、魏洪、刘凯、唐国安</dc:creator><category>研究文章</category><dc:title>基于水文对象的湖流拓扑系统流向模型构建</dc:title><dc:identifier>10.1029/2022WR033681</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname>水资源研究</prism:publicationname><prism:doi>10.1029/2022WR033681</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033681?af=R</prism:url><prism:section>研究文章</prism:section><prism:volume>59</prism:volume><prism:number> 7</prism:number></item><item><link/> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR034011?af=R<pubDate> Mon, 10 Jul 2023 09:16:45 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-07-10T09:16:45-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley：水资源研究：目录<prism:coverdate></prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate></prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR034011</guid><title>多个不确定输入下洪水建模中基于采样的不确定性传播方法：找出最有效的选择</title><description>水资源研究，已接受文章。</description><dc:description>摘要 在概率洪水建模中，不确定性表现在感兴趣的数量（包括洪水范围和危险等级）的发生频率或直方图中。这种现场规模的建模需要找到一种比标准蒙特卡罗（SMC）方法更有效的替代方法，该方法可以用相对较小的样本量重现可比的输出概率分布，包括感兴趣数量的详细直方图。拉丁超立方采样 (LHS) 是评估最多的河流洪水替代方案，但样本量并没有大幅减少。潜在更好的替代方案包括自适应分层采样（ASS）、准蒙特卡罗（QMC）和哈尔小波扩展（HWE），这些方法尚未针对概率洪水建模进行评估。为了弥补这一差距，对 LHS、ASS、QMC 和 HWE 进行比较，以量化样本量的减少，以重现输出详细的直方图（洪水范围、平均和最大危险等级），同时将与参考 SMC 预测的差异保持在 10% 以下。比较是针对具有两个（即流入流量和曼宁系数）和三个（即进一步包括地面高程）输入随机变量的两个测试案例以及具有五个输入随机变量的真实案例进行的。使用两个输入随机变量，所有四种替代方案都会减少样本量，其中 QMC 和 HWE 的表现明显优于其他方案；当输入三个或更多随机变量时，HWE 变得不灵活，而 LHS 表现不佳。尽管如此，QMC 仍然是比 ASS 更好的选择，可以减少实际情况的样本量，并且在概率洪水建模中应该是首选。随附的研究代码可在线公开获取。本文受版权保护。版权所有。</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;摘要&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;在概率洪水建模中，不确定性表现为感兴趣数量（包括洪水范围和危险等级）的发生频率或直方图。这种现场规模的建模需要确定标准蒙特卡罗（SMC）方法的更有效替代方法，该方法可以用相对较小的样本量重现可比较的输出概率分布，包括感兴趣数量的详细直方图。拉丁超立方采样 (LHS) 是评估最多的河流洪水替代方案，但样本量并没有大幅减少。可能更好的替代方案包括自适应分层采样 (ASS)、准蒙特卡罗 (QMC) 和哈尔小波扩展 (HWE)，这些方法尚未针对概率洪水建模进行评估。为了弥补这一差距，对 LHS、ASS、QMC 和 HWE 进行比较，以量化样本量的减少，以重现输出详细的直方图（洪水范围、平均和最大危险等级），同时将与参考 SMC 预测的差异保持在 10% 以下。比较是针对具有两个（即流入流量和曼宁系数）和三个（即进一步包括地面高程）输入随机变量的两个测试案例以及具有五个输入随机变量的真实案例进行的。使用两个输入随机变量，所有四种替代方案都会减少样本量，其中 QMC 和 HWE 的表现明显优于其他方案；当输入三个或更多随机变量时，HWE 变得不灵活，而 LHS 表现不佳。尽管如此，QMC 仍然是比 ASS 更好的选择，可以减少实际情况的样本量，并且在概率洪水建模中应该是首选。随附的研究代码可在线公开获取。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;本文受版权保护。保留所有权利。&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> Mahya Hajihassanpour、Georges Kesserwani、Per Pettersson、Vasilis Bellos</dc:creator><category>研究文章</category><dc:title>多个不确定输入下洪水建模中基于采样的不确定性传播方法：找出最有效的选择</dc:title><dc:identifier>10.1029/2022WR034011</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname>水资源研究</prism:publicationname><prism:doi>10.1029/2022WR034011</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR034011?af=R</prism:url><prism:section>研究文章</prism:section></item><item><link/>https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR034308?af=R<pubDate> Mon, 10 Jul 2023 09:15:31 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-07-10T09:15:31-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley：水资源研究：目录<prism:coverdate>2023 年 7 月 1 日，星期六 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate> 2023 年 7 月 1 日，星期六 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR034308</guid><title>多尺度孔隙连通性对混合湿岩石中两相流影响的成像和建模</title><description>《水资源研究》，第 59 卷，第 7 期，2023 年 7 月。</description><dc:description>摘要 孔壁的润湿特性对多孔介质中的多相流有很大影响。然而，具有复杂孔隙结构和不均匀润湿性的多孔材料中的流体流动行为仍不清楚。在这里，我们进行了非稳态准静态油驱和水驱实验，以研究两种具有可变润湿性条件的姊妹非均质砂岩（即一种天然水润湿的和一种经过化学处理的混合润湿的）中的多相流。通过基于实验室的 X 射线微型计算机断层扫描 (micro-CT) 对这一过程中的孔隙尺度流体分布进行成像。在混合湿的情况下，我们观察到孔隙充填事件，其中沿着孔体的每个位置（体积比为 13%），流体界面似乎都处于准平衡状态，这与通常与缓慢排水或渗吸相关的毛细管不稳定性形成鲜明对比。这些事件与之前在非稳态实验中观察到的缓慢位移相对应，解释了混合湿样品中广泛的位移时间尺度。我们的新数据使我们能够量化低于图像分辨率的流体饱和度，表明慢事件是由微孔性和润湿不均匀性的存在引起的。最后，我们使用最先进的多尺度孔隙网络模型研究了多相流特性对缓慢充填事件的敏感性。这表明发生此类事件的孔隙对样品总绝对渗透率的贡献高达19%，但对相对渗透率的影响可能较小。我们的研究为复杂岩石中人们知之甚少的多相流体动力学提供了新的线索，例如地下水修复和地下二氧化碳封存。</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;摘要&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;孔壁的润湿特性对通过多孔介质的多相流有很大影响。然而，具有复杂孔隙结构和不均匀润湿性的多孔材料中的流体流动行为仍不清楚。在这里，我们进行了非稳态准静态油驱和水驱实验，以研究具有可变润湿性条件的两种姊妹非均质砂岩中的多相流（即一种天然水润湿的和一种经过化学处理的混合润湿的）。通过基于实验室的 X 射线微计算机断层扫描 (micro-CT) 对这一过程中的孔隙尺度流体分布进行成像。在混合湿的情况下，我们观察到孔隙充填事件，其中沿着孔体的每个位置的流体界面似乎都处于准平衡（体积比为 13%），这与通常与缓慢排水或渗吸相关的毛细管不稳定性形成鲜明对比。这些事件与之前在非稳态实验中观察到的缓慢位移相对应，解释了混合湿样品中广泛的位移时间尺度。我们的新数据使我们能够量化低于图像分辨率的流体饱和度，表明慢事件是由微孔性和润湿不均匀性的存在引起的。最后，我们使用最先进的多尺度孔隙网络模型研究了多相流特性对缓慢充填事件的敏感性。这表明发生此类事件的孔隙对样品总绝对渗透率的贡献高达19%，但对相对渗透率的影响可能较小。我们的研究为人们对复杂岩石中知之甚少的多相流体动力学提供了新的认识，例如地下水修复和地下 CO&lt;sub>;2&lt;/sub>; 封存。&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator>王山、Arjen Mascini、Leonardo C. Ruspini、Pål-Eric Øren、Tom Bultreys</dc:creator><category>研究文章</category><dc:title>多尺度孔隙连通性对混合湿岩石中两相流影响的成像和建模</dc:title><dc:identifier>10.1029/2022WR034308</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname>水资源研究</prism:publicationname><prism:doi>10.1029/2022WR034308</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR034308?af=R</prism:url><prism:section>研究文章</prism:section><prism:volume>59</prism:volume><prism:number> 7</prism:number></item><item><link/> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2023WR034652?af=R<pubDate> Mon, 10 Jul 2023 09:15:08 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-07-10T09:15:08-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley：水资源研究：目录<prism:coverdate></prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate></prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2023WR034652</guid><title>双连续体水文地质模型输出的裂缝和基质水头模拟观测井水位：POWeR-FADS</title><description>水资源研究，已接受文章。</description><dc:description> Abstract Do observation wells in fractured porous aquifers measure water head in the fracture network, water head in the matrix, or some combination of both? This question necessarily arises when calibrating dual‐continuum hydrogeological models against on‐field data. One can assume that observation wells measure fracture water head, because matrix permeability is negligible compared to fracture permeability. Nevertheless, this reasoning is invalid for wells poorly‐connected to the fractures. Yet, the possibility of such a poor connection at given depths has never been implemented in a physics‐based manner when comparing matrix and fracture water heads simulated by dual‐continuum models to on‐field data. To fill this knowledge gap, a physically based, easy to calibrate, open‐source postprocessing tool, POWeR‐FADS (Program for Observation Well Representation in Fractured Aquifer Dual‐continuum Simulations), available at https://github.com/BJeannot1/POWeR-FADS, has been developed. It introduces as parameters well geometry and the altitude of lowest interception of the fractures by the well. From these, POWeR‐FADS nonintrusively postprocesses time series of matrix and fracture water heads at the well, as simulated by any planar, bidimensional dual‐continuum hydrogeological model, to calculate water exchanges involving the observation well and thus the evolution of water level in the well. Synthetic test cases show that POWeR‐FADS makes it possible to simulate peculiar behaviors that are similar to patterns actually observed by the authors in on‐site observation wells of a fractured porous aquifer, like “floors” in observed water levels, delayed but sharp rises at the beginning of recharge events, or inflexion points accelerating the drawdown velocity during the recession phase. This article is protected by copyright.版权所有。</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;Do observation wells in fractured porous aquifers measure water head in the fracture network, water head in the matrix, or some combination of both? This question necessarily arises when calibrating dual-continuum hydrogeological models against on-field data. One can assume that observation wells measure fracture water head, because matrix permeability is negligible compared to fracture permeability. Nevertheless, this reasoning is invalid for wells poorly-connected to the fractures. Yet, the possibility of such a poor connection at given depths has never been implemented in a physics-based manner when comparing matrix and fracture water heads simulated by dual-continuum models to on-field data. To fill this knowledge gap, a physically based, easy to calibrate, open-source postprocessing tool, POWeR-FADS (Program for Observation Well Representation in Fractured Aquifer Dual-continuum Simulations), available at &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;Link to external resource&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/BJeannot1/POWeR-FADS&quot;>;https://github.com/BJeannot1/POWeR-FADS&lt;/a>;, has been developed. It introduces as parameters well geometry and the altitude of lowest interception of the fractures by the well. From these, POWeR-FADS nonintrusively postprocesses time series of matrix and fracture water heads at the well, as simulated by any planar, bidimensional dual-continuum hydrogeological model, to calculate water exchanges involving the observation well and thus the evolution of water level in the well. Synthetic test cases show that POWeR-FADS makes it possible to simulate peculiar behaviors that are similar to patterns actually observed by the authors in on-site observation wells of a fractured porous aquifer, like “floors” in observed water levels, delayed but sharp rises at the beginning of recharge events, or inflexion points accelerating the drawdown velocity during the recession phase.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This article is protected by copyright. All rights reserved.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> B. Jeannot, L. Schaper, F. Habets</dc:creator><category> Research Article</category><dc:title> Water Level in Observation Wells Simulated from Fracture and Matrix Water Heads Outputted by Dual‐Continuum Hydrogeological Models: POWeR‐FADS</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2023WR034652</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1029/2023WR034652</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2023WR034652?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> Research Article</prism:section></item><item><link/> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2023WR034867?af=R<pubDate> Mon, 10 Jul 2023 09:15:07 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-07-10T09:15:07-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley: Water Resources Research: Table of Contents <prism:coverdate></prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate></prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2023WR034867</guid><title> Multi‐objective optimization models for the design of water distribution networks by exploring scenario‐based approaches</title><description> Water Resources Research, Accepted Article.</description><dc:description> Abstract Demand in a Water Distribution Network (WDN) is an aleatory variable, owing to the unpredictable behaviours of water users. Therefore, it is one of the main reasons for uncertainty in the design of this infrastructure. The increasing number of water demand datasets offers opportunities to improve the traditional deterministic design approaches of WDNs by combining statistical and optimization methods. Robust Optimization (RO) takes demand uncertainty into account by studying solutions that perform well under any possible demand scenario, ie, any possible realizations of this variable in the lifetime of a WDN. The right choice of scenario is therefore essential to ensure the reliability of the designed network. This paper presents a statistical methodology for generating scenarios to be used to solve a robust design optimization problem. It involves three steps: 1) descriptive analytics of historical data to derive the marginal distributions of peak hour demand in each node of the WDN, 2) generation of a very large number of snapshots by stratified sampling from the correlated marginal distributions of nodal peak demand, 3) generation of the peak demand scenarios by reducing the number of snapshots. Two heuristic techniques are proposed to reduce the number of snapshots, and for each of them, two different numbers of scenarios are derived. Two multi‐objective RO models are solved: the first model includes cost minimization and a mean‐variance Generalized Resilience and Failure index maximization objectives, and the second one additionally considers the minimization of the maximum undelivered demand, formalized using a regret function. This article is protected by copyright.版权所有。</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;Demand in a Water Distribution Network (WDN) is an aleatory variable, owing to the unpredictable behaviours of water users. Therefore, it is one of the main reasons for uncertainty in the design of this infrastructure. The increasing number of water demand datasets offers opportunities to improve the traditional deterministic design approaches of WDNs by combining statistical and optimization methods. Robust Optimization (RO) takes demand uncertainty into account by studying solutions that perform well under any possible demand scenario, ie, any possible realizations of this variable in the lifetime of a WDN. The right choice of scenario is therefore essential to ensure the reliability of the designed network. This paper presents a statistical methodology for generating scenarios to be used to solve a robust design optimization problem. It involves three steps: 1) descriptive analytics of historical data to derive the marginal distributions of peak hour demand in each node of the WDN, 2) generation of a very large number of snapshots by stratified sampling from the correlated marginal distributions of nodal peak demand, 3) generation of the peak demand scenarios by reducing the number of snapshots. Two heuristic techniques are proposed to reduce the number of snapshots, and for each of them, two different numbers of scenarios are derived. Two multi-objective RO models are solved: the first model includes cost minimization and a mean-variance Generalized Resilience and Failure index maximization objectives, and the second one additionally considers the minimization of the maximum undelivered demand, formalized using a regret function.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This article is protected by copyright. All rights reserved.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> MC Cunha, R. Magini, J. Marques</dc:creator><category> Research Article</category><dc:title> Multi‐objective optimization models for the design of water distribution networks by exploring scenario‐based approaches</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2023WR034867</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1029/2023WR034867</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2023WR034867?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> Research Article</prism:section></item><item><link/> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR032968?af=R<pubDate> Mon, 10 Jul 2023 09:15:03 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-07-10T09:15:03-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley: Water Resources Research: Table of Contents <prism:coverdate></prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate></prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR032968</guid><title> The Timing of Global Floods and its Association with Climate and Topography</title><description> Water Resources Research, Accepted Article.</description><dc:description> Abstract Until recently, the development of a global geography of floods was challenged by the fragmentation and heterogeneity of in situ data and the high costs of processing large amounts of remote sensing data. Such geography would facilitate the exploration of large‐scale drivers of flood extent and timing including wide latitudinal, climate, and topographic effects. Here we used a monthly dataset spanning 30 years (Global Surface Water) to develop a worldwide geographical characterization of slow floods (1‐degree grid), weighting the relative contribution of seasonal, interannual, and long‐term fluctuations on overall variability, and quantified precipitation‐flooding delays where seasonality dominated. We explored the dominance of different flooding timings across five main Köppen‐Geiger climates and seven topography classes derived from modeled water table depths (ie, hydro‐topography) to contribute top‐down insight about the most salient, cross‐regional flooding patterns and their likely large‐scale drivers. Our results showed that, globally, the mean extent of floods averaged 0.48% of the global land area, predominantly associated with hydro‐topography ( >; 2x more extensive in flatter landscapes). Climate drove flood timings, with predictable, seasonally‐dominated fluctuations in cold regions, interannual and mixed patterns in temperate climates, and more irregular (higher variability) and unpredictable (less seasonal) patterns in arid regions. Net gains of flooded area dominated temporal variability in 9% of the cells including boreal clusters likely affected by warming trends. We propose that this new geographical perspective of floods can aid different avenues of hydrological research in the upscaling and extrapolation of field studies and the parsimonious representation of floods in hydroclimatic models. This article is protected by copyright.版权所有。</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;Until recently, the development of a global geography of floods was challenged by the fragmentation and heterogeneity of in situ data and the high costs of processing large amounts of remote sensing data. Such geography would facilitate the exploration of large-scale drivers of flood extent and timing including wide latitudinal, climate, and topographic effects. Here we used a monthly dataset spanning 30 years (Global Surface Water) to develop a worldwide geographical characterization of slow floods (1-degree grid), weighting the relative contribution of seasonal, interannual, and long-term fluctuations on overall variability, and quantified precipitation-flooding delays where seasonality dominated. We explored the dominance of different flooding timings across five main Köppen-Geiger climates and seven topography classes derived from modeled water table depths (ie, hydro-topography) to contribute top-down insight about the most salient, cross-regional flooding patterns and their likely large-scale drivers. Our results showed that, globally, the mean extent of floods averaged 0.48% of the global land area, predominantly associated with hydro-topography ( &amp;gt; 2x more extensive in flatter landscapes). Climate drove flood timings, with predictable, seasonally-dominated fluctuations in cold regions, interannual and mixed patterns in temperate climates, and more irregular (higher variability) and unpredictable (less seasonal) patterns in arid regions. Net gains of flooded area dominated temporal variability in 9% of the cells including boreal clusters likely affected by warming trends. We propose that this new geographical perspective of floods can aid different avenues of hydrological research in the upscaling and extrapolation of field studies and the parsimonious representation of floods in hydroclimatic models.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This article is protected by copyright. All rights reserved.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> P. Torre Zaffaroni, G. Baldi, M. Texeira, CM Di Bella, EG Jobbágy</dc:creator><category> Research Article</category><dc:title> The Timing of Global Floods and its Association with Climate and Topography</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2022WR032968</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1029/2022WR032968</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR032968?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> Research Article</prism:section></item><item><link/> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033629?af=R<pubDate> Mon, 10 Jul 2023 09:14:49 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-07-10T09:14:49-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley: Water Resources Research: Table of Contents <prism:coverdate></prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate></prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR033629</guid><title> Dynamics of suspended particulate matter in an impounded river under dry and wet weather conditions</title><description> Water Resources Research, Accepted Article.</description><dc:description> Abstract The dynamics of suspended particulate matter (SPM) and SPM‐associated biological and physicochemical processes in a river vary under dry and wet weather conditions and hydraulic structures, which moves a free‐flowing river to a semi‐lacustrine environment. This study investigated the response of SPM dynamics and riverbed morphodynamics to climate and anthropogenic stressors based on in‐situ observations and biogeochemical analyses of river water and riverbed sediment. The biochemical analyses and flocculation tests demonstrate abundant biopolymers and high flocculation potential of the river water during the pre‐flood period with algal bloom. This might promote SPM deposition and high‐concentration sediment layer (HCSL) formation on the riverbed. The high fractions of clay minerals and organic carbon in the riverbed sediment indicate the deposition of organic‐rich biomineral flocs. Vertical turbidity profiles with “long tails” of high turbidity near the riverbed also confirmed SPM deposition and HCSL formation. However, the highly turbulent flow conditions during the post‐flood period disturbed the tails of high turbidity and homogenized the vertical profiles of turbidity, temperature, and dissolved oxygen. Additionally, terrestrial humic substances (HS) were discharged from the watershed during this period, increasing the deflocculation and stabilization of SPM but decreasing deposition on the riverbed, thereby reducing the fractions of clay minerals and organic carbon in the sediment. This study demonstrated the interaction mechanism of SPM dynamics and riverbed morphodynamics with hydrological and biogeochemical processes in an impounded river under dry and wet weather conditions. The findings provide insights into water resource management to deal with climate change and anthropogenic stressors. This article is protected by copyright.版权所有。</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;The dynamics of suspended particulate matter (SPM) and SPM-associated biological and physicochemical processes in a river vary under dry and wet weather conditions and hydraulic structures, which moves a free-flowing river to a semi-lacustrine environment. This study investigated the response of SPM dynamics and riverbed morphodynamics to climate and anthropogenic stressors based on in-situ observations and biogeochemical analyses of river water and riverbed sediment. The biochemical analyses and flocculation tests demonstrate abundant biopolymers and high flocculation potential of the river water during the pre-flood period with algal bloom. This might promote SPM deposition and high-concentration sediment layer (HCSL) formation on the riverbed. The high fractions of clay minerals and organic carbon in the riverbed sediment indicate the deposition of organic-rich biomineral flocs. Vertical turbidity profiles with “long tails” of high turbidity near the riverbed also confirmed SPM deposition and HCSL formation. However, the highly turbulent flow conditions during the post-flood period disturbed the tails of high turbidity and homogenized the vertical profiles of turbidity, temperature, and dissolved oxygen. Additionally, terrestrial humic substances (HS) were discharged from the watershed during this period, increasing the deflocculation and stabilization of SPM but decreasing deposition on the riverbed, thereby reducing the fractions of clay minerals and organic carbon in the sediment. This study demonstrated the interaction mechanism of SPM dynamics and riverbed morphodynamics with hydrological and biogeochemical processes in an impounded river under dry and wet weather conditions. The findings provide insights into water resource management to deal with climate change and anthropogenic stressors.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This article is protected by copyright. All rights reserved.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> TT Huynh, J. Kim, W. Kim, J. Hur, HQ Nguyen, Q. Bi, TV Bui, JJ Kim, SD Lee, YY Choi, BJ Lee</dc:creator><category> Research Article</category><dc:title> Dynamics of suspended particulate matter in an impounded river under dry and wet weather conditions</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2022WR033629</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1029/2022WR033629</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033629?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> Research Article</prism:section></item><item><link/> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2023WR034912?af=R<pubDate> Fri, 07 Jul 2023 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-07-07T12:00:00-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley: Water Resources Research: Table of Contents <prism:coverdate></prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate></prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2023WR034912</guid><title> Contribution of Fresh Submarine Groundwater Discharge to the Gulf of Alaska</title><description> Water Resources Research, Accepted Article.</description><dc:description> Abstract High latitude mountain environments are experiencing disproportionately adverse effects from climate change. The Gulf of Alaska (GoA) region is an embodiment of this change, particularly concerning a shifting hydrologic balance. Even so, the magnitude and contribution of fresh submarine groundwater discharge (fresh SGD) remains virtually unexplored within the region, though it has gained increasing attention globally due to its chemical significance and influence on coastal ecosystems. Here we provide the first regional estimates of fresh SGD to the GoA using two established water balance approaches. This is an effective way to distinguish the contribution of terrestrially derived fresh SGD, rather than the more commonly quantified total SGD which includes discharge that is driven by marine forces such as sea‐level oscillations and density gradients. We compare the approaches and assess their capabilities in computing the magnitude of fresh SGD over a large regional scale. Mean annual fresh SGD flux ranges between 26.5 to 86.8 km3 yr‐1 to the GoA, equivalent to 3.5‐11.4% of the total freshwater discharge. Contributions are highest in the Southeastern panhandle and lowest in the Cook Inlet basin, with the highest area normalized contribution occurring in the Prince William Sound. Fresh SGD exhibits high spatial and temporal variability throughout the region. Although freshwater discharge to the GoA is investigated considerably, the importance of fresh SGD has, thus far, been overlooked.</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;High latitude mountain environments are experiencing disproportionately adverse effects from climate change. The Gulf of Alaska (GoA) region is an embodiment of this change, particularly concerning a shifting hydrologic balance. Even so, the magnitude and contribution of fresh submarine groundwater discharge (fresh SGD) remains virtually unexplored within the region, though it has gained increasing attention globally due to its chemical significance and influence on coastal ecosystems. Here we provide the first regional estimates of fresh SGD to the GoA using two established water balance approaches. This is an effective way to distinguish the contribution of terrestrially derived fresh SGD, rather than the more commonly quantified total SGD which includes discharge that is driven by marine forces such as sea-level oscillations and density gradients. We compare the approaches and assess their capabilities in computing the magnitude of fresh SGD over a large regional scale. Mean annual fresh SGD flux ranges between 26.5 to 86.8 km&lt;sup>;3&lt;/sup>; yr&lt;sup>;-1&lt;/sup>; to the GoA, equivalent to 3.5-11.4% of the total freshwater discharge. Contributions are highest in the Southeastern panhandle and lowest in the Cook Inlet basin, with the highest area normalized contribution occurring in the Prince William Sound. Fresh SGD exhibits high spatial and temporal variability throughout the region. Although freshwater discharge to the GoA is investigated considerably, the importance of fresh SGD has, thus far, been overlooked.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> AA Russo, DF Boutt, LA Munk, J. Jenckes</dc:creator><category> Research Article</category><dc:title> Contribution of Fresh Submarine Groundwater Discharge to the Gulf of Alaska</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2023WR034912</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1029/2023WR034912</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2023WR034912?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> Research Article</prism:section></item><item><link/> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR034158?af=R<pubDate> Thu, 06 Jul 2023 10:04:23 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-07-06T10:04:23-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley: Water Resources Research: Table of Contents<prism:coverdate> Sat, 01 Jul 2023 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate> Sat, 01 Jul 2023 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR034158</guid><title> A Novel Semi‐Analytical (Inertial) Solution for Determining Permeability of Highly Pervious Porous Materials Using the Two‐Reservoir Laboratory Setup</title><description> Water Resources Research, Volume 59, Issue 7, July 2023.</description><dc:description> Abstract Two conventional experimental procedures for determination of the water permeability of saturated porous medium are the constant and the falling head permeability tests. The first one is more applicable on more permeable materials where the outflow from the sample is measured at variety of constant water heads, while the second one is more convenient for low permeable materials, utilizing the continuous measurements of the water head falling due to filtration through the saturated sample. However, neither of the two is useful for materials of high permeability and large cross‐sectional area. The constant head permeability test faces technical issues since a significant and continuous water discharge is required, while the falling head permeability test has limitations due to neglection of the Forchheimer&#39;s high‐velocity flow through the sample, but also the influence of inertia on the fluid mass. Here we proposed an approach for determination of the water permeability of saturated porous medium based on the agreement between the measured water level change in two connected reservoirs containing a porous sample and the new semi‐analytical expression describing that change by accounting for the mentioned theoretical deficiencies. This efficient approach has been tested on four pervious paver samples, and results showed satisfactory agreement with the constant head permeability data. It has been also confirmed the proposed semi‐analytical solution is more accurate than the falling head permeability approach in case of highly pervious materials, while for low permeable materials it reduces to the conventional approach.</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;Two conventional experimental procedures for determination of the water permeability of saturated porous medium are the constant and the falling head permeability tests. The first one is more applicable on more permeable materials where the outflow from the sample is measured at variety of constant water heads, while the second one is more convenient for low permeable materials, utilizing the continuous measurements of the water head falling due to filtration through the saturated sample. However, neither of the two is useful for materials of high permeability and large cross-sectional area. The constant head permeability test faces technical issues since a significant and continuous water discharge is required, while the falling head permeability test has limitations due to neglection of the Forchheimer&#39;s high-velocity flow through the sample, but also the influence of inertia on the fluid mass. Here we proposed an approach for determination of the water permeability of saturated porous medium based on the agreement between the measured water level change in two connected reservoirs containing a porous sample and the new semi-analytical expression describing that change by accounting for the mentioned theoretical deficiencies. This efficient approach has been tested on four pervious paver samples, and results showed satisfactory agreement with the constant head permeability data. It has been also confirmed the proposed semi-analytical solution is more accurate than the falling head permeability approach in case of highly pervious materials, while for low permeable materials it reduces to the conventional approach.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> Filip Stanić, Ognjen Govedarica, Nenad Jaćimović, Branislava Lekić, Anja Ranđelović</dc:creator><category> Research Article</category><dc:title> A Novel Semi‐Analytical (Inertial) Solution for Determining Permeability of Highly Pervious Porous Materials Using the Two‐Reservoir Laboratory Setup</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2022WR034158</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1029/2022WR034158</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR034158?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> Research Article</prism:section><prism:volume> 59</prism:volume><prism:number> 7</prism:number></item><item><link/> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2023WR034914?af=R<pubDate> Thu, 06 Jul 2023 10:01:24 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-07-06T10:01:24-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley: Water Resources Research: Table of Contents<prism:coverdate> Sat, 01 Jul 2023 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate> Sat, 01 Jul 2023 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2023WR034914</guid><title> Brazilian Water Security Threatened by Climate Change and Human Behavior</title><description> Water Resources Research, Volume 59, Issue 7, July 2023.</description><dc:description> Abstract Water scarcity is a growing concern globally, with climate change and increasing population exacerbating the issue. Here, we introduce a new framework for assessing water availability in 708 Brazilian catchments that considers the effect of CO2 concentrations on potential evapotranspiration, uses CMIP6 bias‐corrected climate change simulations, and presumes an open water balance assumption, while considering the human‐aspect by incorporating water demand projections. We note an average reduction of water security in 81% of the analyzed catchments by 2100. Among these catchments, 37% presented a reduction of future water availability, while 63% undergo a worse scenario due to an increase in human water use, which highlights the role of the human aspect in water security assessment. Our study shows important aspects for both advancing future water availability studies and for drawing a picture of the impacts of changes in climate and water use on Brazilian future water security that may be useful for water resources management practices and advancing hydrologic studies.</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;Water scarcity is a growing concern globally, with climate change and increasing population exacerbating the issue. Here, we introduce a new framework for assessing water availability in 708 Brazilian catchments that considers the effect of CO&lt;sub>;2&lt;/sub>; concentrations on potential evapotranspiration, uses CMIP6 bias-corrected climate change simulations, and presumes an open water balance assumption, while considering the human-aspect by incorporating water demand projections. We note an average reduction of water security in 81% of the analyzed catchments by 2100. Among these catchments, 37% presented a reduction of future water availability, while 63% undergo a worse scenario due to an increase in human water use, which highlights the role of the human aspect in water security assessment. Our study shows important aspects for both advancing future water availability studies and for drawing a picture of the impacts of changes in climate and water use on Brazilian future water security that may be useful for water resources management practices and advancing hydrologic studies.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> André S. Ballarin, José Gescilam Sousa Mota Uchôa, Matheus S. Santos, André Almagro, Ianca P. Miranda, Pedro Gustavo C. Silva, Greicelene J. Silva, Marcus N. Gomes Júnior, Edson Wendland, Paulo Tarso S. Oliveira</dc:creator><category> Research Article</category><dc:title> Brazilian Water Security Threatened by Climate Change and Human Behavior</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2023WR034914</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1029/2023WR034914</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2023WR034914?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> Research Article</prism:section><prism:volume> 59</prism:volume><prism:number> 7</prism:number></item><item><link/> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033003?af=R<pubDate> Thu, 06 Jul 2023 10:00:36 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-07-06T10:00:36-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley: Water Resources Research: Table of Contents<prism:coverdate> Sat, 01 Jul 2023 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate> Sat, 01 Jul 2023 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR033003</guid><title> Modeling the Morphological Responses of the Yellow River Delta to the Water‐Sediment Regulation Scheme: The Role of Impulsive River Floods and Density‐Driven Flows</title><description> Water Resources Research, Volume 59, Issue 7, July 2023.</description><dc:description> Abstract Morphological evolution of river deltas depends to a large extent on river discharges, which are usually highly unsteady due to natural hydrological cycles and anthropogenic regulations. However, it is unclear that how and to what extent the discharge fluctuations influence the delta morphology. In this study, we focus on the morphological response of the Yellow River Delta to the Water‐Sediment Regulation Schemes, which generate impulsive floods and deliver high sediment load within a short time. Tracking the fate of fluvial sediment released by 10 historical events reveals that 51.3%, 19.7%, and 17.8% of fluvial sediment are deposited in the delta front, the subaerial delta and the prodelta, respectively. Hypopycnal and hyperpycnal flows occur alternately during different phases of the regulation schemes, and the latter contribute to 32% of the deposition volume with 10% of the duration. To explore the effects of river discharge schematizations on delta evolution, numerical experiments are conducted to compare models forced by unsteady and constant discharges, with the latter being a common practice in delta morphology modeling. We show that the constant‐discharge simplification fails to capture the highly‐depositional hyperpycnal flows, leading to dramatic underestimation of river mouth depositions. In addition, we demonstrate that including the 3D flow‐sediment interactions are critical in reproducing the correct plume structures, bed surface sediment compositions and deposition patterns. Our study highlights the importance of proper river discharge schematizations and full consideration of flow‐sediment interactions in modeling deltas affected by episodic river floods and high suspended sediment concentrations.</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;Morphological evolution of river deltas depends to a large extent on river discharges, which are usually highly unsteady due to natural hydrological cycles and anthropogenic regulations. However, it is unclear that how and to what extent the discharge fluctuations influence the delta morphology. In this study, we focus on the morphological response of the Yellow River Delta to the Water-Sediment Regulation Schemes, which generate impulsive floods and deliver high sediment load within a short time. Tracking the fate of fluvial sediment released by 10 historical events reveals that 51.3%, 19.7%, and 17.8% of fluvial sediment are deposited in the delta front, the subaerial delta and the prodelta, respectively. Hypopycnal and hyperpycnal flows occur alternately during different phases of the regulation schemes, and the latter contribute to 32% of the deposition volume with 10% of the duration. To explore the effects of river discharge schematizations on delta evolution, numerical experiments are conducted to compare models forced by unsteady and constant discharges, with the latter being a common practice in delta morphology modeling. We show that the constant-discharge simplification fails to capture the highly-depositional hyperpycnal flows, leading to dramatic underestimation of river mouth depositions. In addition, we demonstrate that including the 3D flow-sediment interactions are critical in reproducing the correct plume structures, bed surface sediment compositions and deposition patterns. Our study highlights the importance of proper river discharge schematizations and full consideration of flow-sediment interactions in modeling deltas affected by episodic river floods and high suspended sediment concentrations.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> Guoxiang Wu, Kemeng Wang, Bingchen Liang, Xiao Wu, Houjie Wang, Huajun Li, Benwei Shi</dc:creator><category> Research Article</category><dc:title> Modeling the Morphological Responses of the Yellow River Delta to the Water‐Sediment Regulation Scheme: The Role of Impulsive River Floods and Density‐Driven Flows</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2022WR033003</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1029/2022WR033003</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033003?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> Research Article</prism:section><prism:volume> 59</prism:volume><prism:number> 7</prism:number></item><item><link/> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2023WR034894?af=R<pubDate> Thu, 06 Jul 2023 09:54:54 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-07-06T09:54:54-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley: Water Resources Research: Table of Contents<prism:coverdate> Sat, 01 Jul 2023 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate> Sat, 01 Jul 2023 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2023WR034894</guid><title> Automated Symbolic Upscaling: 2. Model Generation for Extended Applicability Regimes</title><description> Water Resources Research, Volume 59, Issue 7, July 2023.</description><dc:description> Abstract In this second part of the two paper series, we detail an algorithmic procedure for systematically implementing the generalized closure form strategy presented in Part 1. This strategy extends the applicability of homogenized models with respect to classical homogenization theory, as demonstrated in Part 1 where upscaled models are rigorously derived in moderately reactive physical regimes. After encoding the algorithm into Symbolica, an automated upscaling framework, we upscale two reactive mass transport problems and numerically validate the resulting nonlinear homogenized models by showing the absolute error estimates predicted by homogenization theory are satisfied. In both problems, nontrivial closure forms and closure problems are automatically formulated using the encoded strategy with no human interaction, nor prior knowledge regarding the closure required for the systems. We hope these demonstrations spark further interest in automated analytical frameworks for multiscale modeling, as such capabilities are invaluable for generating rigorous multiscale models of complex phenomena in porous media.</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;In this second part of the two paper series, we detail an algorithmic procedure for systematically implementing the generalized closure form strategy presented in Part 1. This strategy extends the applicability of homogenized models with respect to classical homogenization theory, as demonstrated in Part 1 where upscaled models are rigorously derived in moderately reactive physical regimes. After encoding the algorithm into Symbolica, an automated upscaling framework, we upscale two reactive mass transport problems and numerically validate the resulting nonlinear homogenized models by showing the absolute error estimates predicted by homogenization theory are satisfied. In both problems, nontrivial closure forms and closure problems are automatically formulated using the encoded strategy with no human interaction, nor prior knowledge regarding the closure required for the systems. We hope these demonstrations spark further interest in automated analytical frameworks for multiscale modeling, as such capabilities are invaluable for generating rigorous multiscale models of complex phenomena in porous media.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> Kyle Pietrzyk, Ilenia Battiato</dc:creator><category> Research Article</category><dc:title> Automated Symbolic Upscaling: 2. Model Generation for Extended Applicability Regimes</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2023WR034894</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1029/2023WR034894</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2023WR034894?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> Research Article</prism:section><prism:volume> 59</prism:volume><prism:number> 7</prism:number></item><item><link/> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2023WR034484?af=R<pubDate> Thu, 06 Jul 2023 09:25:32 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-07-06T09:25:32-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley: Water Resources Research: Table of Contents <prism:coverdate></prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate></prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2023WR034484</guid><title> The Music of Rivers: The Mathematics of Waves Reveals Global Structure and Drivers of Streamflow Regime</title><description> Water Resources Research, Accepted Article.</description><dc:description> Abstract River flows change on timescales ranging from minutes to millennia. These vibrations in flow are tuned by diverse factors globally, for example by dams suppressing multi‐day variability or vegetation attenuating flood peaks in some ecosystems. The relative importance of the physical, biological, and human factors influencing flow is an active area of research, as is the related question of finding a common language for describing overall flow regime. Here, we addressed both topics using a daily river discharge dataset for over 3,000 stations across the globe from 1988‐2016. We first studied similarities between common flow regime quantification methods, including traditional flow metrics, wavelets, and Fourier analysis. Across all these methods, the flow data showed low‐dimensional structure (ie, simple and consistent patterns), suggesting that fundamental mechanisms are constraining flow regime. One such pattern was that day‐to‐day variability was negatively correlated with year‐to‐year variability. Additionally, the low‐dimensional structure in river flow data correlated closely with only a small number of catchment characteristics, including catchment area, precipitation, and temperature—but notably not biome, dam surface area, or number of dams. We discuss these findings in a framework intended to be accessible to the many communities engaged in river research and management, while stressing the importance of letting structure in data guide both mechanistic inference and interdisciplinary discussion. This article is protected by copyright.版权所有。</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;River flows change on timescales ranging from minutes to millennia. These vibrations in flow are tuned by diverse factors globally, for example by dams suppressing multi-day variability or vegetation attenuating flood peaks in some ecosystems. The relative importance of the physical, biological, and human factors influencing flow is an active area of research, as is the related question of finding a common language for describing overall flow regime. Here, we addressed both topics using a daily river discharge dataset for over 3,000 stations across the globe from 1988-2016. We first studied similarities between common flow regime quantification methods, including traditional flow metrics, wavelets, and Fourier analysis. Across all these methods, the flow data showed low-dimensional structure (ie, simple and consistent patterns), suggesting that fundamental mechanisms are constraining flow regime. One such pattern was that day-to-day variability was negatively correlated with year-to-year variability. Additionally, the low-dimensional structure in river flow data correlated closely with only a small number of catchment characteristics, including catchment area, precipitation, and temperature—but notably not biome, dam surface area, or number of dams. We discuss these findings in a framework intended to be accessible to the many communities engaged in river research and management, while stressing the importance of letting structure in data guide both mechanistic inference and interdisciplinary discussion.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This article is protected by copyright. All rights reserved.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> Brian C. Brown, Aimee H. Fulerton, Darin Kopp, Flavia Tromboni, Arial J. Shogren, J. Angus Webb, Claire Ruffing, Matthew Heaton, Lenka Kuglerová, Daniel C. Allen, Lillian McGill, Jay P. Zarnetske, Matt R. Whiles, Jeremy B. Jones, Benjamin W. Abbott</dc:creator><category> Research Article</category><dc:title> The Music of Rivers: The Mathematics of Waves Reveals Global Structure and Drivers of Streamflow Regime</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2023WR034484</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1029/2023WR034484</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2023WR034484?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> Research Article</prism:section></item><item><link/> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033321?af=R<pubDate> Thu, 06 Jul 2023 09:25:28 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-07-06T09:25:28-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley: Water Resources Research: Table of Contents <prism:coverdate></prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate></prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR033321</guid><title> A method for identifying the dominant meteorological factors of atmospheric evaporative demand in mid‐long term</title><description> Water Resources Research, Accepted Article.</description><dc:description> Abstract To better understand the changes in the atmospheric evaporative demand (AED) in the context of global warming, the anomaly contribution analysis is presented to estimate mid‐long term contributions of meteorological factors to the AED. The Pearson correlation coefficient (RP) between the total contribution (ψ) of meteorological factors and the relative variation (ϕ) of the AED, and the Sen&#39;s trend slope (βS) of (ϕ, ψ) scatters are used to evaluate the applicability of the method. The smaller the values of |1‐RP| and |1‐βS|, the more applicable the method is. To validate the method, the reference crop evapotranspiration is employed as a proxy for the AED. The multi‐year contribution analysis is used as a comparison approach, which can only investigate the dominant meteorological factors of the AED in long term. Moreover, the Huaihe River basin of China is taken as a case study. Results show that (1) the values of |1‐RP| and |1‐βS| in mid‐long term are less than 0.1 in most cases when applying the anomaly contribution analysis, and the mid‐long term contribution processes of meteorological factors to the AED are clearly demonstrated; and (2) the wind speed and sunshine hours are the two most dominant factors (the total absolute contribution exceeds 60%) in long term, but they are not always the dominant factors in mid‐long term (eg wind speed in summer, and sunshine hours in winter). Therefore, the anomaly contribution analysis is a reasonable and effective method, which can help to gain insights into the changes in the AED. This article is protected by copyright.版权所有。</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;To better understand the changes in the atmospheric evaporative demand (AED) in the context of global warming, the anomaly contribution analysis is presented to estimate mid-long term contributions of meteorological factors to the AED. The Pearson correlation coefficient (&lt;i>;R&lt;/i>; &lt;sub>;P&lt;/sub>;) between the total contribution (&lt;i>;ψ&lt;/i>;) of meteorological factors and the relative variation (&lt;i>;ϕ&lt;/i>;) of the AED, and the Sen&#39;s trend slope (&lt;i>;β&lt;/i>; &lt;sub>;S&lt;/sub>;) of (&lt;i>;ϕ&lt;/i>;, &lt;i>;ψ&lt;/i>;) scatters are used to evaluate the applicability of the method. The smaller the values of |1-&lt;i>;R&lt;/i>; &lt;sub>;P&lt;/sub>;| and |1-&lt;i>;β&lt;/i>; &lt;sub>;S&lt;/sub>;|, the more applicable the method is. To validate the method, the reference crop evapotranspiration is employed as a proxy for the AED. The multi-year contribution analysis is used as a comparison approach, which can only investigate the dominant meteorological factors of the AED in long term. Moreover, the Huaihe River basin of China is taken as a case study. Results show that (1) the values of |1-&lt;i>;R&lt;/i>; &lt;sub>;P&lt;/sub>;| and &lt;i>;|&lt;/i>;1-&lt;i>;β&lt;/i>; &lt;sub>;S&lt;/sub>;| in mid-long term are less than 0.1 in most cases when applying the anomaly contribution analysis, and the mid-long term contribution processes of meteorological factors to the AED are clearly demonstrated; and (2) the wind speed and sunshine hours are the two most dominant factors (the total absolute contribution exceeds 60%) in long term, but they are not always the dominant factors in mid-long term (eg wind speed in summer, and sunshine hours in winter). Therefore, the anomaly contribution analysis is a reasonable and effective method, which can help to gain insights into the changes in the AED.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This article is protected by copyright. All rights reserved.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> Saiyan Liu, Yangyang Xie, Hongyuan Fang, Pengcheng Xu, Huihua Du</dc:creator><category> Research Article</category><dc:title> A method for identifying the dominant meteorological factors of atmospheric evaporative demand in mid‐long term</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2022WR033321</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1029/2022WR033321</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033321?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> Research Article</prism:section></item><item><link/> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR034150?af=R<pubDate> Thu, 06 Jul 2023 09:23:37 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-07-06T09:23:37-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley: Water Resources Research: Table of Contents <prism:coverdate></prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate></prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR034150</guid><title> A Physically‐based Reverse‐stage Routing Model Considering Lateral Flow for Establishing Normal Rating Curves at Ungauged Upstream River Sections</title><description> Water Resources Research, Accepted Article.</description><dc:description> Abstract Many of the world‐rivers are often ungauged or poorly gauged due to inadequate streamflow monitoring networks. Even with the limited available monitoring stations, only a few of them monitor both stage and discharge data. But when there is a need for estimation of discharges at a gauging station, where only stage data is monitored, one may employ a reverse routing technique using the stage data monitored at a nearby downstream gauging station. This study develops a novel single‐parameter reverse‐stage routing (RSR) model based on the second‐order approximate water surface gradient governing equation to estimate stage and discharge at any scantily‐gauged upstream river section using the known stage information available at the downstream section. A novel criterion is also developed for checking the applicability of the RSR model. Reverse routing experiments carried out by the RSR model using different hypothetical downstream stage hydrographs in a number of hypothetical trapezoidal and rectangular channel reaches to reproduce the benchmark upstream stage and discharge hydrographs demonstrate the good performance of the RSR model with the Nash‐Sutcliffe efficiency >;98%, absolute volume conservation error &lt;1.5%, and an absolute error in peak ≤1%. Subsequently, the RSR model was tested for three real‐river case studies in India and Italy with good reproduction performances, and along with the development of the corresponding normal rating curves at the upstream river sections. The study results reveal that the parsimonious RSR model has good potential for solving reverse routing problems with stable numerical solutions for rivers under ungauged and scantily‐gauged scenarios.</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;Many of the world-rivers are often ungauged or poorly gauged due to inadequate streamflow monitoring networks. Even with the limited available monitoring stations, only a few of them monitor both stage and discharge data. But when there is a need for estimation of discharges at a gauging station, where only stage data is monitored, one may employ a reverse routing technique using the stage data monitored at a nearby downstream gauging station. This study develops a novel single-parameter reverse-stage routing (RSR) model based on the second-order approximate water surface gradient governing equation to estimate stage and discharge at any scantily-gauged upstream river section using the known stage information available at the downstream section. A novel criterion is also developed for checking the applicability of the RSR model. Reverse routing experiments carried out by the RSR model using different hypothetical downstream stage hydrographs in a number of hypothetical trapezoidal and rectangular channel reaches to reproduce the benchmark upstream stage and discharge hydrographs demonstrate the good performance of the RSR model with the Nash-Sutcliffe efficiency &amp;gt;98%, absolute volume conservation error &amp;lt;1.5%, and an absolute error in peak ≤1%. Subsequently, the RSR model was tested for three real-river case studies in India and Italy with good reproduction performances, and along with the development of the corresponding normal rating curves at the upstream river sections. The study results reveal that the parsimonious RSR model has good potential for solving reverse routing problems with stable numerical solutions for rivers under ungauged and scantily-gauged scenarios.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> Ashutosh Pati, Bhabagrahi Sahoo, Muthiah Perumal</dc:creator><category> Research Article</category><dc:title> A Physically‐based Reverse‐stage Routing Model Considering Lateral Flow for Establishing Normal Rating Curves at Ungauged Upstream River Sections</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2022WR034150</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1029/2022WR034150</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR034150?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> Research Article</prism:section></item><item><link/> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR034099?af=R<pubDate> Wed, 05 Jul 2023 13:39:37 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-07-05T01:39:37-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley: Water Resources Research: Table of Contents<prism:coverdate> Sat, 01 Jul 2023 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate> Sat, 01 Jul 2023 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR034099</guid><title> Estimating Future Surface Water Availability Through an Integrated Climate‐Hydrology‐Management Modeling Framework at a Basin Scale Under CMIP6 Scenarios</title><description> Water Resources Research, Volume 59, Issue 7, July 2023.</description><dc:description> Abstract Climate change and increasing water demand due to population growth pose serious threats to surface water availability. The biggest challenge in addressing these threats is the gap between climate science and water management practices. Local water planning often lacks the integration of climate change information, especially with regard to its impacts on surface water storage and evaporation as well as the associated uncertainties. Using Texas as an example, state and regional water planning relies on the use of reservoir “Firm Yield” (FY)—an important metric that quantifies surface water availability. However, this existing planning methodology does not account for the impacts of climate change on future inflows and on reservoir evaporation. To bridge this knowledge gap, an integrated climate‐hydrology‐management (CHM) modeling framework was developed, which is generally applicable to river basins with geographical, hydrological, and water right settings similar to those in Texas. The framework leverages the advantages of two modeling approaches—the Distributed Hydrology Soil Vegetation Model (DHSVM) and Water Availability Modeling (WAM). Additionally, the Double Bias Correction Constructed Analogues method is utilized to downscale and incorporate Coupled Model Intercomparison Project Phase 6 GCMs. Finally, the DHSVM simulated naturalized streamflow and reservoir evaporation rate are input to WAM to simulate reservoir FY. A new term—“Ratio of Firm Yield” (RFY)—is created to compare how much FY changes under different climate scenarios. The results indicate that climate change has a significant impact on surface water availability by increasing reservoir evaporation, altering the seasonal pattern of naturalized streamflow, and reducing FY.</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;Climate change and increasing water demand due to population growth pose serious threats to surface water availability. The biggest challenge in addressing these threats is the gap between climate science and water management practices. Local water planning often lacks the integration of climate change information, especially with regard to its impacts on surface water storage and evaporation as well as the associated uncertainties. Using Texas as an example, state and regional water planning relies on the use of reservoir “Firm Yield” (FY)—an important metric that quantifies surface water availability. However, this existing planning methodology does not account for the impacts of climate change on future inflows and on reservoir evaporation. To bridge this knowledge gap, an integrated climate-hydrology-management (CHM) modeling framework was developed, which is generally applicable to river basins with geographical, hydrological, and water right settings similar to those in Texas. The framework leverages the advantages of two modeling approaches—the Distributed Hydrology Soil Vegetation Model (DHSVM) and Water Availability Modeling (WAM). Additionally, the Double Bias Correction Constructed Analogues method is utilized to downscale and incorporate Coupled Model Intercomparison Project Phase 6 GCMs. Finally, the DHSVM simulated naturalized streamflow and reservoir evaporation rate are input to WAM to simulate reservoir FY. A new term—“Ratio of Firm Yield” (RFY)—is created to compare how much FY changes under different climate scenarios. The results indicate that climate change has a significant impact on surface water availability by increasing reservoir evaporation, altering the seasonal pattern of naturalized streamflow, and reducing FY.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> Manqing Shao, Nelun Fernando, John Zhu, Gang Zhao, Shih‐Chieh Kao, Bingjie Zhao, Elizabeth Roberts, Huilin Gao</dc:creator><category> Research Article</category><dc:title> Estimating Future Surface Water Availability Through an Integrated Climate‐Hydrology‐Management Modeling Framework at a Basin Scale Under CMIP6 Scenarios</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2022WR034099</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1029/2022WR034099</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR034099?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> Research Article</prism:section><prism:volume> 59</prism:volume><prism:number> 7</prism:number></item><item><link/> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033031?af=R<pubDate> Wed, 05 Jul 2023 13:19:24 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-07-05T01:19:24-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley: Water Resources Research: Table of Contents<prism:coverdate> Sat, 01 Jul 2023 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate> Sat, 01 Jul 2023 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR033031</guid><title> Back to the Source: Consumers Response to Produce Irrigated With Different Sources of Recycled Water</title><description> Water Resources Research, Volume 59, Issue 7, July 2023.</description><dc:description> Abstract Using recycled water to irrigate agricultural products can be an effective solution to water scarcity and security. However, a better understanding of how society values different sources of recycled water provides insights into potential demand‐side barriers to adoption of these solutions. This paper implements a framed field experiment conducted in the Southwest and Mid‐Atlantic regions of the United States that evaluates consumers&#39; willingness‐to‐pay (WTP) for three sources of recycled irrigation water: “gray,” “black,” and “produced.” Our analysis indicates that people consider certain sources of recycled water more acceptable for irrigating produce than others. Recycled gray water is preferred to recycled produced water, and both are preferred to recycled black water. We also explore how people respond to scientific information about the benefits and risks of using recycled irrigation water and found no evidence to support that this information changes people&#39;s behaviors.</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;Using recycled water to irrigate agricultural products can be an effective solution to water scarcity and security. However, a better understanding of how society values different sources of recycled water provides insights into potential demand-side barriers to adoption of these solutions. This paper implements a framed field experiment conducted in the Southwest and Mid-Atlantic regions of the United States that evaluates consumers&#39; willingness-to-pay (WTP) for three sources of recycled irrigation water: “gray,” “black,” and “produced.” Our analysis indicates that people consider certain sources of recycled water more acceptable for irrigating produce than others. Recycled gray water is preferred to recycled produced water, and both are preferred to recycled black water. We also explore how people respond to scientific information about the benefits and risks of using recycled irrigation water and found no evidence to support that this information changes people&#39;s behaviors.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> Sean F. Ellis, Diya Ganguly, Maik Kecinski, Kent D. Messer</dc:creator><category> Research Article</category><dc:title> Back to the Source: Consumers Response to Produce Irrigated With Different Sources of Recycled Water</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2022WR033031</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1029/2022WR033031</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033031?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> Research Article</prism:section><prism:volume> 59</prism:volume><prism:number> 7</prism:number></item></channel></rss>