<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:prism="http://prismstandard.org/namespaces/basic/2.0/"><channel><title> Wiley：水资源研究：目录</title><link/>https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R<description>水资源研究目录。最新期和 EarlyView 期的文章列表。</description><language> en-US</language><copyright></copyright><managingeditor> wileyonlinelibrary@wiley.com（AGU 出版物）</managingeditor><pubDate> Sun, 01 Oct 2023 07:52:27 +0000</pubDate><lastbuilddate> 2023 年 10 月 1 日星期日 07:52:27 +0000</lastbuilddate><generator> Atypon®文学™</generator><docs> https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs><ttl> 10080</ttl><dc:title> Wiley：水资源研究：目录</dc:title><dc:publisher>威利</dc:publisher><prism:publicationname>水资源研究</prism:publicationname><atom:link href="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"></atom:link><image/><title> Wiley：水资源研究：目录</title><url>https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/pb-assets/journal-banners/19447973.jpg</url><link/> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R<item><link/> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2023WR034870?af=R<pubDate> Fri, 29 Sep 2023 10:22:14 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-09-29T10:22:14-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley：水资源研究：目录<prism:coverdate>2023 年 10 月 1 日，星期日 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate> 2023 年 10 月 1 日，星期日 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2023WR034870</guid><title>非线性河岸相互作用驱动源头径流的变化</title><description>《水资源研究》，第 59 卷，第 10 期，2023 年 10 月。</description><dc:description>摘要 随着美国西部干旱和野火频率的增加，我们预测水资源如何应对这些干扰的能力取决于我们对维持流域功能和水流的反馈的理解。之前对非常年源头河流的研究已经对低流量条件的驱动因素进行了排名。然而，对这些驱动因素之间的相互作用以及这些相互作用影响水流的过程的了解有限。在这里，我们使用溪流水位、土壤湿度、液流和蒸气压赤字数据来研究山区源头溪流沿线的生态水文相互作用。这些变量的相关和互相关分析表明，生态水文相互作用是（a）非线性和（b）相互关联的，这表明假设每个驱动因素的线性和独立性的分析不足以量化这些相互作用。为了解释这些问题并调查因果联系，我们使用收敛交叉映射（CCM）来表征影响非常年径流的反馈。 CCM 是一种非线性动态方法，最近才应用于水文系统。 CCM 结果表明，与当地液流和蒸气压不足相关的大气损失正在驱动土壤湿度和水流的变化（p &lt; 0.01），并且大气损失比浅层土壤湿度更直接地影响溪流水。这些结果还表明，即使在河流干涸之后，河岸过程仍继续影响河道走廊的地下流动。本研究提出了一个量化生态水文相互作用的非线性框架，该框架可以确定源头溪流如何应对干扰。</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;随着美国西部干旱和野火频率的增加，我们预测水资源如何应对这些干扰的能力取决于我们对维持流域功能和水流的反馈的理解。之前对非常年源头河流的研究已经对低流量条件的驱动因素进行了排名。然而，对这些驱动因素之间的相互作用以及这些相互作用影响水流的过程的了解有限。在这里，我们使用溪流水位、土壤湿度、液流和蒸气压赤字数据来研究山区源头溪流沿线的生态水文相互作用。这些变量的相关和互相关分析表明，生态水文相互作用是（a）非线性和（b）相互关联的，这表明假设每个驱动因素的线性和独立性的分析不足以量化这些相互作用。为了解释这些问题并调查因果联系，我们使用收敛交叉映射（CCM）来描述影响非常年水流的反馈。 CCM 是一种非线性动态方法，最近才应用于水文系统。 CCM 结果表明，与当地液流和蒸气压不足相关的大气损失正在驱动土壤湿度和水流的变化 (&lt;i>;p&lt;/i>; &lt; 0.01)，并且大气损失比浅层土壤湿度更直接地影响溪流水。这些结果还表明，即使在河流干涸之后，河岸过程仍继续影响河道走廊的地下流动。这项研究提出了一个量化生态水文相互作用的非线性框架，该框架可以确定源头溪流如何应对干扰。&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator>莎拉·K·纽科姆、莎拉·E·戈西</dc:creator><category>研究文章</category><dc:title>非线性河岸相互作用驱动源头径流的变化</dc:title><dc:identifier>10.1029/2023WR034870</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname>水资源研究</prism:publicationname><prism:doi>10.1029/2023WR034870</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2023WR034870?af=R</prism:url><prism:section>研究文章</prism:section><prism:volume>59</prism:volume><prism:number> 10</prism:number></item><item><link/> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2023WR035616?af=R<pubDate> Fri, 29 Sep 2023 10:20:45 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-09-29T10:20:45-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley：水资源研究：目录<prism:coverdate>2023 年 10 月 1 日，星期日 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate> 2023 年 10 月 1 日，星期日 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2023WR035616</guid><title>存在异质土壤时渗透池下降时间的随机分析</title><description>《水资源研究》，第 59 卷，第 10 期，2023 年 10 月。</description><dc:description>摘要 水位下降时间对于渗透池的设计和评估非常重要。本文研究了其对土壤异质性的依赖性，并给出了均值和方差的简单解析解。使用针对层状土壤的改进的 Green Ampt 模型和基于一维理查兹方程积分的模型，通过蒙特卡罗模拟在各种实际场景中对解决方案进行了测试。评估了所采用的近似值的影响，并强调了饱和导水率空间分布的主导作用。还研究了其他相关设计和自然因素的影响，包括初始水位和含水量分布。</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;摘要&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;水位下降时间对于渗透池的设计和评估非常重要。本文研究了其对土壤异质性的依赖性，并给出了均值和方差的简单解析解。使用针对层状土壤的改进的 Green Ampt 模型和基于一维理查兹方程积分的模型，通过蒙特卡洛模拟在各种实际场景中对解决方案进行测试。评估了所采用的近似值的影响，并强调了饱和导水率空间分布的主导作用。还研究了其他相关设计和自然因素的影响，包括初始水位和含水量分布。&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator>马可·费兰特、阿尔多·菲奥里</dc:creator><category>研究文章</category><dc:title>存在异质土壤时渗透池下降时间的随机分析</dc:title><dc:identifier>10.1029/2023WR035616</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname>水资源研究</prism:publicationname><prism:doi>10.1029/2023WR035616</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2023WR035616?af=R</prism:url><prism:section>研究文章</prism:section><prism:volume>59</prism:volume><prism:number> 10</prism:number></item><item><link/> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2023WR035820?af=R<pubDate> Fri, 29 Sep 2023 05:54:05 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-09-29T05:54:05-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley：水资源研究：目录<prism:coverdate></prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate></prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2023WR035820</guid><title>形态、大气和海洋驱动因素导致偏远沙岛发生多期咸水入侵</title><description>水资源研究，已接受文章。</description><dc:description>摘要 小岛屿人口过分依赖淡水地下水资源，而海洋和气候条件变化导致的盐碱化日益受到威胁。这项研究调查了多个时间尺度上岛屿地下水动态和盐化对海洋、大气和形态驱动因素的响应。为了解决这个问题，我们在 2020 年至 2022 年期间在西北大西洋的一个偏远沙岛上收集了新的地球物理和水文数据集，并与 20 世纪 70 年代的历史基线数据进行了比较。数据显示，由于数十年的侵蚀、季节性气候模式、潮汐强迫和大西洋飓风的间歇性洪水，海水入侵。长期的沙丘侵蚀导致淡水透镜体变薄且变得不对称；然而，滞后的地下水响应导致淡水透镜体与目前岛屿形态不平衡。最大垂直透镜体厚度随季节变化是恒定的，但春季当地下水位因降水和频繁的海滩洪水而升高时，沿海岸的横向过渡带会变厚并向海移动。大西洋飓风过后，由于海水泛滥，低洼海滩的地下水位和电导率显着增加，最高分别达到海拔 1.93 m 和 38 mS/cm。虽然地下水位迅速恢复，但由于冬季洪水事件之间的间隔时间短于大气补给带来的淡水，电导率（盐度）仍然较高。结果强调了多时期地下水动态以及沿海洪水、侵蚀和盐化之间的反馈的重要性。考虑盐水入侵的多种驱动因素和时间尺度的实地研究对于在环境快速变化的时代理解和管理沿海淡水资源至关重要。</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;小岛屿人口过分依赖淡水地下水资源，而海洋和气候条件变化导致的盐碱化日益威胁着这些资源。这项研究调查了多个时间尺度上岛屿地下水动态和盐化对海洋、大气和形态驱动因素的响应。为了解决这个问题，我们在 2020 年至 2022 年间在西北大西洋的一个偏远沙岛上收集了新的地球物理和水文数据集，并与 20 世纪 70 年代的历史基线数据进行比较。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;数据揭示了由于多种因素导致的咸水入侵。年代际侵蚀、季节性气候模式、潮汐强迫和大西洋飓风造成的间歇性洪水。长期的沙丘侵蚀导致淡水透镜体变薄且变得不对称；然而，滞后的地下水响应导致淡水透镜体与目前岛屿形态不平衡。最大垂直透镜体厚度随季节变化是恒定的，但春季当地下水位因降水和频繁的海滩洪水而升高时，沿海岸的横向过渡带会变厚并向海移动。大西洋飓风过后，由于海水泛滥，低洼海滩的地下水位和电导率显着增加，最高分别达到海拔 1.93 m 和 38 mS/cm。虽然地下水位迅速恢复，但由于冬季洪水事件之间的间隔时间短于大气补给带来的淡水，电导率（盐度）仍然较高。结果强调了多时期地下水动态以及沿海洪水、侵蚀和盐化之间的反馈的重要性。考虑盐水入侵的多种驱动因素和时间尺度的实地研究对于在环境快速变化的时代理解和管理沿海淡水资源至关重要。&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator>朱莉娅·A·坎特隆、克莱尔·E·罗宾逊、巴雷特·L·库里克</dc:creator><category>研究文章</category><dc:title>形态、大气和海洋驱动因素导致偏远沙岛发生多期咸水入侵</dc:title><dc:identifier>10.1029/2023WR035820</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname>水资源研究</prism:publicationname><prism:doi>10.1029/2023WR035820</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2023WR035820?af=R</prism:url><prism:section>研究文章</prism:section></item><item><link/>https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2023WR036288?af=R<pubDate> Thu, 28 Sep 2023 08:20:21 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-09-28T08:20:21-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley：水资源研究：目录<prism:coverdate></prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate></prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2023WR036288</guid><title> ChatGPT 在水文学和地球科学中的应用：机遇、前景和担忧</title><description>水资源研究，已接受文章。</description><dc:description>摘要 ChatGPT 等大型语言模型（LLM）的出现引起了人们的广泛关注，特别是在学术界和科学界。研究人员、科学家和教师对于使用 ChatGPT 进行研究和教学的优点和缺点持有不同的观点。本评论简要解释了 ChatGPT 背后的基本原理以及如何将其应用于水文学和其他地球科学领域。本文探讨了这种开放式人工智能工具在这些领域的主要应用，特别是其协助编写和编码任务的能力，并强调了与使用这种模型相关的优点和问题。此外，该研究还提出了该模型的一些其他局限性以及潜在误用的危险。最后，我们建议学术界调整其法规和政策，以利用法学硕士的潜在好处，同时减少其陷阱。 ChatGPT 将被许多科学家用来创造内容和推动科学进步。根据我们自己的经验和本研究的结论，我们建议水文学和其他地球科学界建立一个利用法学硕士的结构，并为其实施提出明确的规定。我们还概述了如何完成此结构的一些具体步骤。本文受版权保护。版权所有。</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;诸如 ChatGPT 之类的大型语言模型 (LLM) 的出现引起了人们的广泛关注，特别是在学术界和科学界。研究人员、科学家和教师对于使用 ChatGPT 进行研究和教学的优点和缺点持有不同的观点。本评论简要解释了 ChatGPT 背后的基本原理以及如何将其应用于水文学和其他地球科学领域。本文探讨了这种开放式人工智能工具在这些领域的主要应用，特别是其协助编写和编码任务的能力，并强调了与使用这种模型相关的优点和问题。此外，该研究还提出了该模型的一些其他局限性以及潜在误用的危险。最后，我们建议学术界调整其法规和政策，以利用法学硕士的潜在好处，同时减少其陷阱。 ChatGPT 将被许多科学家用来创造内容和推动科学进步。根据我们自己的经验和本研究的结论，我们建议水文学和其他地球科学界建立一个利用法学硕士的结构，并为其实施提出明确的规定。我们还概述了如何完成此结构的一些具体步骤。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;本文受版权保护。保留所有权利。&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> Ehsan Foroumandi、Hamid Moradkhani、Xavier Sanchez-Vila、Kamini Singha、Andrea Castelletti、Georgia Destouni</dc:creator><category>社论</category><dc:title>ChatGPT 在水文学和地球科学中的应用：机遇、前景和担忧</dc:title><dc:identifier>10.1029/2023WR036288</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname>水资源研究</prism:publicationname><prism:doi>10.1029/2023WR036288</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2023WR036288?af=R</prism:url><prism:section>社论</prism:section></item><item><link/>https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2023WR034849?af=R<pubDate> Thu, 28 Sep 2023 08:20:19 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-09-28T08:20:19-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley：水资源研究：目录<prism:coverdate>2023 年 10 月 1 日，星期日 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate> 2023 年 10 月 1 日，星期日 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2023WR034849</guid><title>油粘度对多孔介质中不混溶两相流水相分散的影响：X 射线断层扫描研究</title><description>《水资源研究》，第 59 卷，第 10 期，2023 年 10 月。</description><dc:description>摘要 在本研究中，研究了使用共注射方法产生的稳定两相流中的分散和混合。在大范围的流体粘度比下研究了油粘度的影响。结果表明，高度不均匀的流场是由广泛分布的不同体积的石油团簇产生的。速度分布的变化增强了示踪羽流的变形和扩散，导致较大的扩散规模和加速的扩散速率。色散系数随时间变化，并在共注射过程中表现出非菲克色散。因此，当粘度比超过 10 时，可以观察到异常混合行为。以标量耗散速率为特征的混合强度首先通过溶质表面的变形而增强。因此，扩散有助于混合，导致后期混合强度更快下降。这些结果可归因于非润湿流体变得断开，并且随着油粘度的增加，每个簇的尺寸减小。油膜的形成使孔隙空间变窄，并且即使润湿相的相对渗透率较低，油膜的润滑作用也可能有助于增强分散和混合状态。这项研究提供了在宏观和孔隙尺度上不同石油粘度的部分饱和多孔介质中的分散情况的见解，这可以进一步提高二氧化碳储存能力和安全性。</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;摘要&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;在这项研究中，研究了使用共注射方法产生的稳定两相流中的分散和混合。在大范围的流体粘度比下研究了油粘度的影响。结果表明，高度不均匀的流场是由广泛分布的不同体积的石油团簇产生的。速度分布的变化增强了示踪羽流的变形和扩散，导致较大的扩散规模和加速的扩散速率。色散系数随时间变化，并在共注射过程中表现出非菲克色散。因此，当粘度比超过 10 时，可以观察到异常混合行为。以标量耗散速率为特征的混合强度首先通过溶质表面的变形而增强。因此，扩散有助于混合，导致后期混合强度更快下降。这些结果可归因于以下事实：非润湿流体变得断开，并且随着油粘度的增加，每个簇的尺寸减小。油膜的形成使孔隙空间变窄，并且即使润湿相的相对渗透率较低，油膜的润滑作用也可能有助于增强分散和混合状态。这项研究提供了在宏观和孔隙尺度上不同石油粘度的部分饱和多孔介质中的分散性的见解，这可以进一步提高 CO&lt;sub>;2&lt;/sub>; 存储能力和安全性。&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator>李紫晶、穆罕默德·纳西尔、王伟岑、快藤一树、张春伟、末兼哲也、松下慎太郎</dc:creator><category>研究文章</category><dc:title>油粘度对多孔介质中不混溶两相流水相分散的影响：X 射线断层扫描研究</dc:title><dc:identifier>10.1029/2023WR034849</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname>水资源研究</prism:publicationname><prism:doi>10.1029/2023WR034849</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2023WR034849?af=R</prism:url><prism:section>研究文章</prism:section><prism:volume>59</prism:volume><prism:number> 10</prism:number></item><item><link/> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2023WR034473?af=R<pubDate> Thu, 28 Sep 2023 08:04:18 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-09-28T08:04:18-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley：水资源研究：目录<prism:coverdate>2023 年 10 月 1 日，星期日 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate> 2023 年 10 月 1 日，星期日 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2023WR034473</guid><title>基于蓝水短缺的水文可持续农业扩张设计方法</title><description>《水资源研究》，第 59 卷，第 10 期，2023 年 10 月。</description><dc:description>摘要 可持续发展和代际责任需要谨慎使用自然资源。水资源供应可能会限制农业，而农业是资源消耗以及商品和服务提供的关键部门。人们对其集约化和扩张的可持续性进行了研究，通常特别关注水。农业战略以当地水资源供应为基础，并对一些下游影响进行了评估。然而，尚未确定一种方法来确定和量化直接考虑下游影响的水文可持续土地利用和作物利用变化。我们提出了一个框架来设计土地利用和作物利用变化，防止当地和下游影响。我们将其应用于肯尼亚的咖啡种植园扩张，考虑到其农业、经济和社会发展潜力，该行业正在增长并计划增长，且不无与水文气候变化相关的风险。我们使用作物和土地利用特定的水文模型来模拟咖啡种植园扩张对可用合适区域的缺水影响，并利用结果迭代识别和过滤掉增加当地或下游缺水的扩张区域。事实证明，这项评估在保护水资源可用性方面是有效的，确定了 10% 的适宜和可用区域具有水文可持续性。这些扩展区域和当前使用区域的总水足迹相似，但扩展区域具有更高的降水产生的水可用性。所提出的方法以物理上稳健的方式定位和量化区域，保持所选扩展场景的灵活性。因此，该方法可用于规划水文农业发展。</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;可持续发展和代际责任需要谨慎使用自然资源。水资源供应可能会限制农业，而农业是资源消耗以及商品和服务提供的关键部门。人们对其集约化和扩张的可持续性进行了研究，通常特别关注水。农业战略以当地水资源供应为基础，并对一些下游影响进行了评估。然而，尚未确定一种方法来确定和量化直接考虑下游影响的水文可持续土地利用和作物利用变化。我们提出了一个框架来设计土地利用和作物利用变化，防止当地和下游影响。我们将其应用于肯尼亚的咖啡种植园扩张，考虑到其农业、经济和社会发展潜力，该行业正在增长并计划增长，且不无与水文气候变化相关的风险。我们使用作物和土地利用特定的水文模型来模拟咖啡种植园扩张对可用合适区域的水资源短缺影响，并利用结果迭代识别和过滤掉增加当地或下游水资源短缺的扩张区域。事实证明，这项评估在保护水资源可用性方面是有效的，确定了 10% 的适宜和可用区域具有水文可持续性。这些扩展区域和当前使用区域的总水足迹相似，但扩展区域具有更高的降水产生的可用水量。所提出的方法以物理上稳健的方式定位和量化区域，保持所选扩展场景的灵活性。因此，该方法可用于水文农业发展规划。&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator>尼古拉斯·加利、大卫·达尼洛·基亚雷利、利维娅·里卡迪、玛丽亚·克里斯蒂娜·鲁利</dc:creator><category>研究文章</category><dc:title>基于蓝水短缺的水文可持续农业扩张设计方法</dc:title><dc:identifier>10.1029/2023WR034473</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname>水资源研究</prism:publicationname><prism:doi>10.1029/2023WR034473</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2023WR034473?af=R</prism:url><prism:section>研究文章</prism:section><prism:volume>59</prism:volume><prism:number> 10</prism:number></item><item><link/> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2023WR034798?af=R<pubDate> Wed, 27 Sep 2023 18:53:37 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-09-27T06:53:37-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley：水资源研究：目录<prism:coverdate></prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate></prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2023WR034798</guid><title>海水入侵对岛屿含水层地下水供应运行成本的影响研究</title><description>水资源研究，已接受文章。</description><dc:description>摘要 管理脆弱的岛屿淡水资源需要确定抽水策略，在地下水供应的财务成本与控制与含水层抽水相关的海水入侵 (SWI) 之间进行权衡。在这项工作中，通过在地下水管理问题优化制定的背景下进行敏感性分析来研究这些权衡，其目的是在受到 SWI 控制约束的情况下，最大限度地减少与地下水抽水和海水淡化处理相关的地下水供应运营成本，通过井的地下水位下降 (Δs)、含水层中淡水体积的减少 (ΔFV) 或含水层中盐质量的增加 (ΔSM) 来量化。本研究重点关注圣萨尔瓦多岛含水层（巴哈马）的简化二维模型。抽水策略的特征是抽水系统距海岸线的距离（WL）、抽水筛深度（D）和总抽水率（Q），构成优化问题的决策变量。我们研究了泵送策略对运行成本、Δs、ΔFV 和 ΔSM 的影响。研究结果表明，增加 D 或减少 WL 会降低 Δs、ΔFV 和 ΔSM，从而保持含水层水文地质稳定性，但也会导致抽取含盐量更高的地下水，从而增加水处理要求，这对总体地下水供应成本产生重大影响。从经济角度来看，在岛屿中心附近和浅层抽取地下水似乎是最方便的策略。然而，对优化约束的分析表明，抽水系统接近岛屿中心的策略往往会导致更严重的 SWI，这凸显了需要在地下水供应成本与 SWI 控制之间进行权衡。</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;管理脆弱的岛屿淡水资源需要确定抽水策略，在地下水供应的财务成本与控制与含水层抽水相关的海水入侵 (SWI) 之间进行权衡。在这项工作中，通过在地下水管理问题优化制定的背景下进行敏感性分析来研究这些权衡，其目的是在受到 SWI 控制约束的情况下，最大限度地减少与地下水抽水和海水淡化处理相关的地下水供应运营成本，通过井上地下水位下降 (Δ&lt;i>;s&lt;/i>;)、含水层中淡水体积的减少 (Δ&lt;i>;FV&lt;/i>;) 或盐质量增加 (Δ&lt; i>;SM&lt;/i>;) 在含水层中。本研究重点关注圣萨尔瓦多岛含水层（巴哈马）的简化二维模型。抽水策略的特点是抽水系统距海岸线的距离 (&lt;i>;WL&lt;/i>;)、抽水筛深度 (&lt;i>;D&lt;/i>;) 和总抽水率 (&lt;i>;Q&lt;/i>;) i>;)，构成优化问题的决策变量。我们研究了泵送策略对运行成本 Δ&lt;i>;s&lt;/i>;、Δ&lt;i>;FV&lt;/i>; 和 Δ&lt;i>;SM&lt;/i>; 的影响。研究结果表明，增加&lt;i>;D&lt;/i>;或减少&lt;i>;WL&lt;/i>;会降低Δ&lt;i>;s&lt;/i>;、Δ&lt;i>;FV&lt;/i>;和Δ&lt;i>;SM&lt;/i >;，从而保持了含水层水文地质稳定性，但也导致抽取含盐量更高的地下水，从而增加了水处理要求，这对整体地下水供应成本产生了强烈影响。从经济角度来看，在岛屿中心附近和浅层抽取地下水似乎是最方便的策略。然而，对优化约束的分析表明，抽水系统接近岛屿中心的策略往往会导致更严重的SWI，这凸显了需要在地下水供应成本与SWI控制之间进行权衡。&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator>于伟江、Domenico Baù、Alex S. Mayer、Lauren Mancewicz、Mohammadali Geranmehr</dc:creator><category>研究文章</category><dc:title>海水入侵对岛屿含水层地下水供应运行成本的影响研究</dc:title><dc:identifier>10.1029/2023WR034798</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname>水资源研究</prism:publicationname><prism:doi>10.1029/2023WR034798</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2023WR034798?af=R</prism:url><prism:section>研究文章</prism:section></item><item><link/>https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2023WR034655?af=R<pubDate> Wed, 27 Sep 2023 18:43:30 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-09-27T06:43:30-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley：水资源研究：目录<prism:coverdate></prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate></prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2023WR034655</guid><title>全局非线性流动条件下跨多孔介质的色散标量传输的多尺度分析</title><description>水资源研究，已接受文章。</description><dc:description>摘要：我们关注在多孔介质的全局尺度上观察到的非线性流态场景，并探讨这种非线性对在具有不同程度的孔隙空间复杂性的三维多孔系统中观察到的色散标量输运的关键特征的影响。在有据可查的数字 Beadpack 和 Bentheimer 砂岩样品中，对孔隙尺度和更大尺度的流动和传输过程进行了分析。我们的模拟包括线性（达西）和非线性（福希海默）流态，并考虑佩克莱特数的广泛值区间（范围从 1×10-2 到 5×104）。分析了孔隙尺度速度和迁移标量浓度的样本概率密度函数，并将其与流动条件和孔隙空间的复杂程度相关联。与截面平均突破曲线相关的色散估计值显示了佩克莱特数的幂律缩放。标度指数取决于孔隙尺度扩散和平流的相对重要性。我们发现福希海默流态的特点是标量场的混合增强。与达西政权相比，这导致分散性增强。本文受版权保护。版权所有。</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;摘要&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;我们关注在多孔介质的全局范围内观察到的非线性流态场景，并探讨这种非线性对在三维多孔系统中观察到的色散标量输运关键特征的影响，其特征为不同程度的孔隙空间复杂性。在有据可查的数字 Beadpack 和 Bentheimer 砂岩样品中，对孔隙尺度和更大尺度的流动和传输过程进行了分析。我们的模拟包括线性 (Darcy) 和非线性 (Forchheimer) 流态，并考虑佩克莱特数的较宽范围值（范围从 1×10&lt;sup>;-2&lt;/sup>; 到 5×10&lt;sup>;4&lt;/sup） >;）。分析了孔隙尺度速度和迁移标量浓度的样本概率密度函数，并将其与流动条件和孔隙空间的复杂程度相关联。与截面平均突破曲线相关的色散估计值显示了佩克莱数的幂律缩放。标度指数取决于孔隙尺度扩散和平流的相对重要性。我们发现福希海默流态的特点是标量场的混合增强。与达西政权相比，这导致分散性增强。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;本文受版权保护。保留所有权利。&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator>哈米德·莫吉米、莫哈德塞·穆萨维·内扎德、阿尔贝托·瓜达尼尼</dc:creator><category>研究文章</category><dc:title>全局非线性流动条件下跨多孔介质的色散标量传输的多尺度分析</dc:title><dc:identifier>10.1029/2023WR034655</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname>水资源研究</prism:publicationname><prism:doi>10.1029/2023WR034655</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2023WR034655?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> Research Article</prism:section></item><item><link/> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR034228?af=R<pubDate> Wed, 27 Sep 2023 10:55:21 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-09-27T10:55:21-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley: Water Resources Research: Table of Contents<prism:coverdate> Sun, 01 Oct 2023 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate> Sun, 01 Oct 2023 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR034228</guid><title> A Novel Analytical Solution for Ponded Infiltration With Consideration of a Developing Saturated Zone</title><description> Water Resources Research, Volume 59, Issue 10, October 2023.</description><dc:description> Abstract Ponding at the soil surface exerts profound impacts on infiltration. However, the effects of ponding depth on infiltration, especially the development of a saturated zone below the soil surface, have yet to be considered in present infiltration models. A new general Green‐Ampt model solution (GAMS) was derived for a one‐dimensional vertical infiltration problem under a uniform initial moisture distribution with ponding on its surface. An expression was included in the new solution for simulating the saturated layer developed below the soil surface as long as the pressure head at the surface is sufficiently high to saturate the soil. The GAMS simulates the infiltration processes closer to the numerical solution by HYDRUS‐1D than the traditional and the recently improved Green‐Ampt model. Moreover, an inversion method to improve the estimates of soil hydraulic parameters from one‐dimensional vertical infiltration experiments that is based on the GAMS was suggested. The effect of ponding depth (hp), initial soil moisture content, soil texture, and hydraulic soil properties (saturated hydraulic conductivity Ks, water‐entry suction hd and shape coefficient n of soil water retention curve) in the saturated zone was also evaluated. The results indicate that the saturated zone length increased at a comparable rate with the unsaturated wetted zone length during infiltration. Generally, a larger saturated zone was found for soils with higher initial soil moisture contents, coarser texture, higher Ks values, greater n, and lower −hd. Our findings reveal that including the saturated zone in the infiltration model yields a better estimate of the soil hydraulic parameters. The proposed GAMS model can improve irrigation design and rainfall‐runoff simulations.</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;Ponding at the soil surface exerts profound impacts on infiltration. However, the effects of ponding depth on infiltration, especially the development of a saturated zone below the soil surface, have yet to be considered in present infiltration models. A new general Green-Ampt model solution (GAMS) was derived for a one-dimensional vertical infiltration problem under a uniform initial moisture distribution with ponding on its surface. An expression was included in the new solution for simulating the saturated layer developed below the soil surface as long as the pressure head at the surface is sufficiently high to saturate the soil. The GAMS simulates the infiltration processes closer to the numerical solution by HYDRUS-1D than the traditional and the recently improved Green-Ampt model. Moreover, an inversion method to improve the estimates of soil hydraulic parameters from one-dimensional vertical infiltration experiments that is based on the GAMS was suggested. The effect of ponding depth (&lt;i>;h&lt;/i>; &lt;sub>;p&lt;/sub>;), initial soil moisture content, soil texture, and hydraulic soil properties (saturated hydraulic conductivity &lt;i>;K&lt;/i>; &lt;sub>;s&lt;/sub>;, water-entry suction &lt;i>;h&lt;/i>; &lt;sub>;d&lt;/sub>; and shape coefficient &lt;i>;n&lt;/i>; of soil water retention curve) in the saturated zone was also evaluated. The results indicate that the saturated zone length increased at a comparable rate with the unsaturated wetted zone length during infiltration. Generally, a larger saturated zone was found for soils with higher initial soil moisture contents, coarser texture, higher &lt;i>;K&lt;/i>; &lt;sub>;s&lt;/sub>; values, greater &lt;i>;n&lt;/i>;, and lower −&lt;i>;h&lt;/i>; &lt;sub>;d&lt;/sub>;. Our findings reveal that including the saturated zone in the infiltration model yields a better estimate of the soil hydraulic parameters. The proposed GAMS model can improve irrigation design and rainfall-runoff simulations.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> DongHao Ma, SiCong Wu, ZhiPeng Liu, JiaBao Zhang</dc:creator><category> Research Article</category><dc:title> A Novel Analytical Solution for Ponded Infiltration With Consideration of a Developing Saturated Zone</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2022WR034228</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1029/2022WR034228</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR034228?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> Research Article</prism:section><prism:volume> 59</prism:volume><prism:number> 10</prism:number></item><item><link/> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/wrcr.26020?af=R<pubDate> Wed, 27 Sep 2023 08:54:34 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-09-27T08:54:34-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley: Water Resources Research: Table of Contents<prism:coverdate> Sun, 01 Oct 2023 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate> Sun, 01 Oct 2023 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1002/wrcr.26020</guid><title> Issue Information</title><description> Water Resources Research, Volume 59, Issue 10, October 2023.</description><dc:description> No abstract is available for this article.</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;p>;No abstract is available for this article.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator></dc:creator><category> Issue Information</category><dc:title> Issue Information</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1002/wrcr.26020</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1002/wrcr.26020</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/wrcr.26020?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> Issue Information</prism:section><prism:volume> 59</prism:volume><prism:number> 10</prism:number></item><item><link/> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2023WR034510?af=R<pubDate> Tue, 26 Sep 2023 16:04:14 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-09-26T04:04:14-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley: Water Resources Research: Table of Contents <prism:coverdate></prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate></prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2023WR034510</guid><title> Water charge and conservation of natural areas: An ex‐ante assessment of a policy proposal for the Mantiqueira region, Brazil</title><description> Water Resources Research, Accepted Article.</description><dc:description> Abstract Water plays a central role in several socioeconomic and environmental nexuses. Faced with various anthropogenic pressures that act as water scarcity drivers and knowing that the unavailability of water can be a limiting factor for economic development, there is an urgent need for the design and evaluation of economic instruments that help in the management of water resources. This article presents a proposal and assessment for a Pigouvian water charge instrument. The instrument suggests imposing a charge based on the amount of water consumed, targeting the agriculture, livestock, forest extraction, and aquaculture sectors. The revenue generated from this charge could be utilized to fund reforestation initiatives and support government expenditures, thereby creating both environmental and economic advantages. Based on a calibrated static computable general equilibrium economic model for the Brazilian Mantiqueira region, it was possible to estimate that a water charge policy at a rate of R$ 0.10/m3 (US$ 0.026/m3) could lead to an increase in the Brazilian GDP in the benchmark year by US$ 10.7 million. Economic benefits could also be verified at the regional level, especially in those areas where there are water‐intensive economic activities. On the environmental side, the water charge could incentivize actions capable of recovering approximately 80 km2 of natural areas. This article is protected by copyright.版权所有。</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;Water plays a central role in several socioeconomic and environmental nexuses. Faced with various anthropogenic pressures that act as water scarcity drivers and knowing that the unavailability of water can be a limiting factor for economic development, there is an urgent need for the design and evaluation of economic instruments that help in the management of water resources. This article presents a proposal and assessment for a Pigouvian water charge instrument. The instrument suggests imposing a charge based on the amount of water consumed, targeting the agriculture, livestock, forest extraction, and aquaculture sectors. The revenue generated from this charge could be utilized to fund reforestation initiatives and support government expenditures, thereby creating both environmental and economic advantages. Based on a calibrated static computable general equilibrium economic model for the Brazilian Mantiqueira region, it was possible to estimate that a water charge policy at a rate of R$ 0.10/m&lt;sup>;3&lt;/sup>; (US$ 0.026/m&lt;sup>;3&lt;/sup>;) could lead to an increase in the Brazilian GDP in the benchmark year by US$ 10.7 million. Economic benefits could also be verified at the regional level, especially in those areas where there are water-intensive economic activities. On the environmental side, the water charge could incentivize actions capable of recovering approximately 80 km&lt;sup>;2&lt;/sup>; of natural areas.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This article is protected by copyright. All rights reserved.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> Ademir Rocha, Eduardo Haddad, Alan Leal, João Corrêa</dc:creator><category> Research Article</category><dc:title> Water charge and conservation of natural areas: An ex‐ante assessment of a policy proposal for the Mantiqueira region, Brazil</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2023WR034510</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1029/2023WR034510</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2023WR034510?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> Research Article</prism:section></item><item><link/> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2023WR035408?af=R<pubDate> Tue, 26 Sep 2023 06:38:56 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-09-26T06:38:56-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley: Water Resources Research: Table of Contents <prism:coverdate></prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate></prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2023WR035408</guid><title> Predictive deep learning for high‐dimensional inverse modeling of hydraulic tomography in Gaussian and non‐Gaussian fields</title><description> Water Resources Research, Accepted Article.</description><dc:description> Abstract Inverse modeling of hydraulic tomography (HT) is computationally expensive for estimating high‐dimensional hydrogeologic parameter fields. In this work, we develop a novel method called HT‐INV‐NN, which combines dimensionality reduction techniques with a predictive deep learning (DL) model to estimate high‐dimensional Gaussian and non‐Gaussian channel fields. The HT‐INV‐NN model consists of a predictor that directly learns the inverse process from hydraulic head measurements to latent variables of random fields, and a decoder that generates high‐dimensional parameter fields from predicted latent variables. For Gaussian spatially correlated fields, the decoder utilizes principal components derived from spatial covariance, and for non‐Gaussian channel fields, a generative adversarial network (GAN) is trained using generated realizations based on a training image (TI). The predictor is a deep neural network (DNN) calibrated using the reference data obtained from HT forward simulations, which can be implemented in parallel. HT‐INV‐NN is successfully tested in multiple numerical experiments including steady‐state and transient HT for estimating Gaussian fields in 2D and 3D, as well as binary discontinuous or continuous non‐Gaussian channel fields. The training process is efficient, and the model structure demonstrates robustness for input data with perturbations. The model performance on multiple validation datasets are satisfactory when compared with other numerical and deep learning methods.</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;Inverse modeling of hydraulic tomography (HT) is computationally expensive for estimating high-dimensional hydrogeologic parameter fields. In this work, we develop a novel method called HT-INV-NN, which combines dimensionality reduction techniques with a predictive deep learning (DL) model to estimate high-dimensional Gaussian and non-Gaussian channel fields. The HT-INV-NN model consists of a predictor that directly learns the inverse process from hydraulic head measurements to latent variables of random fields, and a decoder that generates high-dimensional parameter fields from predicted latent variables. For Gaussian spatially correlated fields, the decoder utilizes principal components derived from spatial covariance, and for non-Gaussian channel fields, a generative adversarial network (GAN) is trained using generated realizations based on a training image (TI). The predictor is a deep neural network (DNN) calibrated using the reference data obtained from HT forward simulations, which can be implemented in parallel. HT-INV-NN is successfully tested in multiple numerical experiments including steady-state and transient HT for estimating Gaussian fields in 2D and 3D, as well as binary discontinuous or continuous non-Gaussian channel fields. The training process is efficient, and the model structure demonstrates robustness for input data with perturbations. The model performance on multiple validation datasets are satisfactory when compared with other numerical and deep learning methods.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> Quan Guo, Ming Liu, Jian Luo</dc:creator><category> Method</category><dc:title> Predictive deep learning for high‐dimensional inverse modeling of hydraulic tomography in Gaussian and non‐Gaussian fields</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2023WR035408</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1029/2023WR035408</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2023WR035408?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> Method</prism:section></item><item><link/> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2023WR035402?af=R<pubDate> Tue, 26 Sep 2023 02:40:59 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-09-26T02:40:59-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley: Water Resources Research: Table of Contents <prism:coverdate></prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate></prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2023WR035402</guid><title> Pore‐scale modelling of coupled CO2 flow and dissolution in 3D porous media for geological carbon storage</title><description> Water Resources Research, Accepted Article.</description><dc:description> Abstract Dissolution trapping is one of the crucial trapping mechanisms for geological carbon storage in deep saline aquifers. The injected supercritical CO2 (scCO2) flow and dissolution processes are coupled and interact with each other. Therefore, we performed direct numerical simulations in three‐dimensional micro‐CT images of sandstones using the Volume of Fluid and Continuous Species Transfer (VOF‐CST) method. We investigated the coupled scCO2 flow and dissolution processes at pore scale under different rock structures, capillary numbers and rock wettability conditions. The dynamic evolution of the scCO2/brine phase distribution and scCO2 concentration distribution occurring during the injection period were presented and analyzed. Complicated coupling mechanisms between scCO2‐brine two‐phase flow and interphase mass transfer are also revealed. Our results showed that the scCO2 dissolution was highly dependent on the local distribution of scCO2 clusters. The rock with relatively high porosity and permeability would have more capacity for scCO2 injection resulting in a faster and greater dissolution of scCO2 in brine. The effect of capillary number on the scCO2 dissolution process was related to the range of capillary number. The effective upscaled (macro‐scale) mass transfer coefficient (kA) during scCO2 dissolution was evaluated and the power‐law relationship between kA and Péclet number was obtained. Rock wettability was found to be another factor controlling the scCO2 dissolution processes by affecting the scCO2‐brine interfacial area. Our pore‐scale study provides a deep understanding of the scCO2 dissolution trapping mechanisms, which is important to enhance the prediction of sequestration risk and improve sequestration efficiency.</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;Dissolution trapping is one of the crucial trapping mechanisms for geological carbon storage in deep saline aquifers. The injected supercritical CO&lt;sub>;2&lt;/sub>; (scCO&lt;sub>;2&lt;/sub>;) flow and dissolution processes are coupled and interact with each other. Therefore, we performed direct numerical simulations in three-dimensional micro-CT images of sandstones using the Volume of Fluid and Continuous Species Transfer (VOF-CST) method. We investigated the coupled scCO&lt;sub>;2&lt;/sub>; flow and dissolution processes at pore scale under different rock structures, capillary numbers and rock wettability conditions. The dynamic evolution of the scCO&lt;sub>;2&lt;/sub>;/brine phase distribution and scCO&lt;sub>;2&lt;/sub>; concentration distribution occurring during the injection period were presented and analyzed. Complicated coupling mechanisms between scCO&lt;sub>;2&lt;/sub>;-brine two-phase flow and interphase mass transfer are also revealed. Our results showed that the scCO&lt;sub>;2&lt;/sub>; dissolution was highly dependent on the local distribution of scCO&lt;sub>;2&lt;/sub>; clusters. The rock with relatively high porosity and permeability would have more capacity for scCO&lt;sub>;2&lt;/sub>; injection resulting in a faster and greater dissolution of scCO&lt;sub>;2&lt;/sub>; in brine. The effect of capillary number on the scCO&lt;sub>;2&lt;/sub>; dissolution process was related to the range of capillary number. The effective upscaled (macro-scale) mass transfer coefficient (&lt;i>;k&lt;/i>; &lt;sub>; &lt;i>;A&lt;/i>; &lt;/sub>;) during scCO&lt;sub>;2&lt;/sub>; dissolution was evaluated and the power-law relationship between &lt;i>;k&lt;/i>; &lt;sub>; &lt;i>;A&lt;/i>; &lt;/sub>; and Péclet number was obtained. Rock wettability was found to be another factor controlling the scCO&lt;sub>;2&lt;/sub>; dissolution processes by affecting the scCO&lt;sub>;2&lt;/sub>;-brine interfacial area. Our pore-scale study provides a deep understanding of the scCO&lt;sub>;2&lt;/sub>; dissolution trapping mechanisms, which is important to enhance the prediction of sequestration risk and improve sequestration efficiency.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> Yongfei Yang, Jinlei Wang, Jianzhong Wang, Yingwen Li, Hai Sun, Lei Zhang, Junjie Zhong, Kai Zhang, Jun Yao</dc:creator><category> Research Article</category><dc:title> Pore‐scale modelling of coupled CO2 flow and dissolution in 3D porous media for geological carbon storage</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2023WR035402</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1029/2023WR035402</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2023WR035402?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> Research Article</prism:section></item><item><link/> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2023WR035088?af=R<pubDate> Tue, 26 Sep 2023 01:16:31 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-09-26T01:16:31-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley: Water Resources Research: Table of Contents <prism:coverdate></prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate></prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2023WR035088</guid><title> Intercomparison of deep learning architectures for the prediction of precipitation fields with a focus on extremes</title><description> Water Resources Research, Accepted Article.</description><dc:description> Abstract In recent years, the use of deep learning methods has rapidly increased in many research fields. Similarly, they have become a powerful tool within the climate scientific community. Deep learning methods have been successfully applied for different tasks, such as the identification of atmospheric patterns, weather extreme classification, or weather forecasting. However, due to the inherent complexity of atmospheric processes, the ability of deep learning models to simulate natural processes, particularly in the case of weather extremes, is still challenging. Therefore, a thorough evaluation of their performance and robustness in predicting precipitation fields is still needed, especially for extreme precipitation events, which can have devastating consequences in terms of infrastructure damage, economic losses, and even loss of life. In this study, we present a comprehensive evaluation of a set of deep learning architectures to simulate precipitation, including heavy precipitation events ( >; 95th percentile) and extreme events ( >; 99th percentile) over the European domain. Among the architectures analyzed here, the U‐Net network was found to be superior and outperformed the other networks in simulating precipitation events. In particular, we found that a simplified version of the original U‐Net with two encoder‐decoder levels generally achieved similar skill scores than deeper versions for predicting precipitation extremes, while significantly reducing the overall complexity and computing resources. We further assess how the model predicts through the attribution heatmaps from a Layer‐wise Relevance Propagation (LRP) explainability method.</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;In recent years, the use of deep learning methods has rapidly increased in many research fields. Similarly, they have become a powerful tool within the climate scientific community. Deep learning methods have been successfully applied for different tasks, such as the identification of atmospheric patterns, weather extreme classification, or weather forecasting. However, due to the inherent complexity of atmospheric processes, the ability of deep learning models to simulate natural processes, particularly in the case of weather extremes, is still challenging. Therefore, a thorough evaluation of their performance and robustness in predicting precipitation fields is still needed, especially for extreme precipitation events, which can have devastating consequences in terms of infrastructure damage, economic losses, and even loss of life. In this study, we present a comprehensive evaluation of a set of deep learning architectures to simulate precipitation, including heavy precipitation events ( &amp;gt; 95th percentile) and extreme events ( &amp;gt; 99th percentile) over the European domain. Among the architectures analyzed here, the U-Net network was found to be superior and outperformed the other networks in simulating precipitation events. In particular, we found that a simplified version of the original U-Net with two encoder-decoder levels generally achieved similar skill scores than deeper versions for predicting precipitation extremes, while significantly reducing the overall complexity and computing resources. We further assess how the model predicts through the attribution heatmaps from a Layer-wise Relevance Propagation (LRP) explainability method.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> Noelia Otero, Pascal Horton</dc:creator><category> Research Article</category><dc:title> Intercomparison of deep learning architectures for the prediction of precipitation fields with a focus on extremes</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2023WR035088</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1029/2023WR035088</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2023WR035088?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> Research Article</prism:section></item><item><link/> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR034401?af=R<pubDate> Mon, 25 Sep 2023 20:14:43 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-09-25T08:14:43-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley: Water Resources Research: Table of Contents <prism:coverdate></prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate></prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR034401</guid><title> A novel efficient method of estimating suspended‐to‐total sediment load fraction in natural rivers</title><description> Water Resources Research, Accepted Article.</description><dc:description> Abstract Sediment transport load monitoring is important in civil and environmental engineering fields. Monitoring the total load is difficult, especially because of the cost of the bed load transport measurement. This study proposes estimation models for the suspended‐to‐total load fraction using dimensionless hydro‐morphological variables. Two prominent variable combinations were identified using the recursive feature elimination for support vector regression (SVR): (1) width‐to‐depth ratio, dimensionless particle size, flow Reynolds number, densimetric Froude number, and falling particle Reynolds number, and (2) flow Reynolds number, Froude number, and densimetric Froude number. The explicit relations between the suspended‐to‐total load fraction and the two combinations were revealed by two modern symbolic regression methods: multi‐gene genetic programming and Operon. The five‐variable SVR model showed the best performance. Clustering analyses using a self‐organizing map and Gaussian mixture model, respectively, identified the underlying relationships between dimensionless variables. Subsequently, the one‐at‐a‐time sensitivity of the input variables of the empirical models was investigated. The suspended‐to‐total load fraction is positively related to the flow Reynolds number and is inversely related to the densimetric Froude number. The models developed in this study are practical and easy to implement in other suspended sediment monitoring methods because they only require basic measurable hydro‐morphological variables, such as velocity, depth, width, and median bed material size. This article is protected by copyright.版权所有。</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;Sediment transport load monitoring is important in civil and environmental engineering fields. Monitoring the total load is difficult, especially because of the cost of the bed load transport measurement. This study proposes estimation models for the suspended-to-total load fraction using dimensionless hydro-morphological variables. Two prominent variable combinations were identified using the recursive feature elimination for support vector regression (SVR): (1) width-to-depth ratio, dimensionless particle size, flow Reynolds number, densimetric Froude number, and falling particle Reynolds number, and (2) flow Reynolds number, Froude number, and densimetric Froude number. The explicit relations between the suspended-to-total load fraction and the two combinations were revealed by two modern symbolic regression methods: multi-gene genetic programming and Operon. The five-variable SVR model showed the best performance. Clustering analyses using a self-organizing map and Gaussian mixture model, respectively, identified the underlying relationships between dimensionless variables. Subsequently, the one-at-a-time sensitivity of the input variables of the empirical models was investigated. The suspended-to-total load fraction is positively related to the flow Reynolds number and is inversely related to the densimetric Froude number. The models developed in this study are practical and easy to implement in other suspended sediment monitoring methods because they only require basic measurable hydro-morphological variables, such as velocity, depth, width, and median bed material size.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This article is protected by copyright. All rights reserved.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> Hyoseob Noh, Yong Sung Park, Il Won Seo</dc:creator><category> Research Article</category><dc:title> A novel efficient method of estimating suspended‐to‐total sediment load fraction in natural rivers</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2022WR034401</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1029/2022WR034401</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR034401?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> Research Article</prism:section></item><item><link/> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2023WR034500?af=R<pubDate> Mon, 25 Sep 2023 07:29:06 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-09-25T07:29:06-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley: Water Resources Research: Table of Contents <prism:coverdate></prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate></prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2023WR034500</guid><title> Exploring suspended sediment dynamics using a novel indexing framework based on X‐ray diffraction spectral fingerprinting</title><description> Water Resources Research, Accepted Article.</description><dc:description> Abstract Understanding the origins and hotspots of suspended sediments is crucial for safeguarding the biotic communities and for management of water quality in river‐reservoir systems. This study is an attempt to develop a new analytical framework to deconvolve the suspended sediment sources contribution using a novel index (ie erosion susceptibility index, ESI). The ESI is computed using sediment fingerprinting information, sediment yield, and the areal coverage of the sediment sources (land use). We have used X‐ray diffraction (XRD) and Partial least square regression (PLSR) based spectral fingerprinting technique to apportion the land use classes as sources of sediments in a representative catchment of Chotanagpur Plateau (CP), India (Konar reservoir catchment). PLSR model on the XRD spectra has performed well with R2 >; 0.88 and identified agricultural areas as the major contributor of suspended sediments by delivering 28% to 43%, varying seasonally (in the period of 2018‐2019). However, based on the ESI values barren lands and human settlements were found to be the most crucial land use classes (with highest ESI value of 1.31 and 1.08 respectively) in terms of sediment generation (22% to 29% and 14% to 23% respectively) with only 14% and 12% areal coverage. The results have demonstrated that the state of critical conservation urgency of different land uses can be quantified more effectively when combining spectral tracers based knowledge with ESI.</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;Understanding the origins and hotspots of suspended sediments is crucial for safeguarding the biotic communities and for management of water quality in river-reservoir systems. This study is an attempt to develop a new analytical framework to deconvolve the suspended sediment sources contribution using a novel index (ie erosion susceptibility index, ESI). The ESI is computed using sediment fingerprinting information, sediment yield, and the areal coverage of the sediment sources (land use). We have used X-ray diffraction (XRD) and Partial least square regression (PLSR) based spectral fingerprinting technique to apportion the land use classes as sources of sediments in a representative catchment of Chotanagpur Plateau (CP), India (Konar reservoir catchment). PLSR model on the XRD spectra has performed well with R&lt;sup>;2&lt;/sup>; &amp;gt; 0.88 and identified agricultural areas as the major contributor of suspended sediments by delivering 28% to 43%, varying seasonally (in the period of 2018-2019). However, based on the ESI values barren lands and human settlements were found to be the most crucial land use classes (with highest ESI value of 1.31 and 1.08 respectively) in terms of sediment generation (22% to 29% and 14% to 23% respectively) with only 14% and 12% areal coverage. The results have demonstrated that the state of critical conservation urgency of different land uses can be quantified more effectively when combining spectral tracers based knowledge with ESI.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> Arnab Das, Renji Remesan, Ashok Kumar Gupta</dc:creator><category> Research Article</category><dc:title> Exploring suspended sediment dynamics using a novel indexing framework based on X‐ray diffraction spectral fingerprinting</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2023WR034500</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1029/2023WR034500</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2023WR034500?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> Research Article</prism:section></item><item><link/> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2023WR034639?af=R<pubDate> Mon, 25 Sep 2023 05:44:16 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-09-25T05:44:16-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley: Water Resources Research: Table of Contents <prism:coverdate></prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate></prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2023WR034639</guid><title> Influence of liquid splitting behavior at intersections on infiltration dynamics in an unsaturated fracture network</title><description> Water Resources Research, Accepted Article.</description><dc:description> Abstract Understanding the macro‐scale flow characteristics in the fractured vadose zone is of great importance for subsurface hydrological and environmental applications. Here we develop an idealized fracture network model composed of a series of linked intersections, aiming to reveal the roles of local fluid flow, storage and splitting behaviors at intersections in controlling macroscopic unsaturated flow in a fracture network. By setting different local flow rules, unsaturated flow dynamics and structure in networks are systematically investigated. Numerical simulations suggest that avalanche infiltration mode, ie, sudden release of a large amount of water from the network, emerges spontaneously, and is modulated by the local splitting behavior. In terms of water infiltration structure, we find that uneven liquid splitting at intersections inevitably leads to preferential flow in networks. The preferential paths strongly rely on the competition between gravitational and capillary forces, relating to network structure and water saturation. When flow is dominated by gravity, preferential paths extend along large‐aperture routes; conversely, when flow is dominated by capillarity, the small‐aperture paths are preferred. In terms of infiltration dynamics, we show that the power spectral density of the water saturation time series in the network follows a power law with an exponent of −2 for all simulations with different structural parameters and local flow rules, suggesting a universal self‐organized criticality behavior for unsaturated flow in fractured rocks. The improved understanding from this study may shed new light on the complex flow dynamics for unsaturated flow in fractured media. This article is protected by copyright.版权所有。</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;Understanding the macro-scale flow characteristics in the fractured vadose zone is of great importance for subsurface hydrological and environmental applications. Here we develop an idealized fracture network model composed of a series of linked intersections, aiming to reveal the roles of local fluid flow, storage and splitting behaviors at intersections in controlling macroscopic unsaturated flow in a fracture network. By setting different local flow rules, unsaturated flow dynamics and structure in networks are systematically investigated. Numerical simulations suggest that avalanche infiltration mode, ie, sudden release of a large amount of water from the network, emerges spontaneously, and is modulated by the local splitting behavior. In terms of water infiltration structure, we find that uneven liquid splitting at intersections inevitably leads to preferential flow in networks. The preferential paths strongly rely on the competition between gravitational and capillary forces, relating to network structure and water saturation. When flow is dominated by gravity, preferential paths extend along large-aperture routes; conversely, when flow is dominated by capillarity, the small-aperture paths are preferred. In terms of infiltration dynamics, we show that the power spectral density of the water saturation time series in the network follows a power law with an exponent of −2 for all simulations with different structural parameters and local flow rules, suggesting a universal self-organized criticality behavior for unsaturated flow in fractured rocks. The improved understanding from this study may shed new light on the complex flow dynamics for unsaturated flow in fractured media.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This article is protected by copyright. All rights reserved.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> Song Xue, Zhibing Yang, Zexiong Zhou, Ran Hu, Yi‐Feng Chen</dc:creator><category> Research Article</category><dc:title> Influence of liquid splitting behavior at intersections on infiltration dynamics in an unsaturated fracture network</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2023WR034639</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1029/2023WR034639</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2023WR034639?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> Research Article</prism:section></item><item><link/> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033759?af=R<pubDate> Mon, 25 Sep 2023 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-09-25T12:00:00-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley: Water Resources Research: Table of Contents <prism:coverdate></prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate></prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR033759</guid><title> Controls of variability in the Laurentian Great Lakes terrestrial water budget</title><description> Water Resources Research, Accepted Article.</description><dc:description> Abstract The land surface hydrology of the North American Great Lakes region regulates ecosystem water availability, lake levels, vegetation dynamics, and agricultural practices. In this study, we analyze the Great Lakes terrestrial water budget using the NOAH‐MP land surface model to characterize the catchment hydrological regimes and identify the dominant quantities contributing to the variability in the land surface hydrology. We show that the Great Lakes domain is not hydrologically uniform and strong spatiotemporal differences exist in the regulators of the hydrological budget at daily, monthly, and annual timescales. Sub‐seasonally, precipitation and soil moisture explain nearly all the terrestrial water budget variability in the southern basins, while the northern latitudes are snow‐dominated regimes. Seasonal assessments reveal greater differences among the basins. Precipitation, evaporation, and runoff are the dominant sources of variability at lower latitudes, while at higher latitudes, terrestrial water storage in the form of ground snowpack and soil moisture has the leading role. Differences in land cover categorizations, eg, croplands, forests, or urban zones, further induce spatial differences in the hydrological characteristics. This quantification of variability in the terrestrial water cycle embedded at different temporal scales is important to assess the impacts of changes in climate and land cover on catchment sensitivities across the diverse hydroclimate of the Great Lakes region. This article is protected by copyright.版权所有。</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;The land surface hydrology of the North American Great Lakes region regulates ecosystem water availability, lake levels, vegetation dynamics, and agricultural practices. In this study, we analyze the Great Lakes terrestrial water budget using the NOAH-MP land surface model to characterize the catchment hydrological regimes and identify the dominant quantities contributing to the variability in the land surface hydrology. We show that the Great Lakes domain is not hydrologically uniform and strong spatiotemporal differences exist in the regulators of the hydrological budget at daily, monthly, and annual timescales. Sub-seasonally, precipitation and soil moisture explain nearly all the terrestrial water budget variability in the southern basins, while the northern latitudes are snow-dominated regimes. Seasonal assessments reveal greater differences among the basins. Precipitation, evaporation, and runoff are the dominant sources of variability at lower latitudes, while at higher latitudes, terrestrial water storage in the form of ground snowpack and soil moisture has the leading role. Differences in land cover categorizations, eg, croplands, forests, or urban zones, further induce spatial differences in the hydrological characteristics. This quantification of variability in the terrestrial water cycle embedded at different temporal scales is important to assess the impacts of changes in climate and land cover on catchment sensitivities across the diverse hydroclimate of the Great Lakes region.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This article is protected by copyright. All rights reserved.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> Samar Minallah, Allison L. Steiner, Valeriy Y. Ivanov, Andrew W. Wood</dc:creator><category> Research Article</category><dc:title> Controls of variability in the Laurentian Great Lakes terrestrial water budget</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2022WR033759</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1029/2022WR033759</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033759?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> Research Article</prism:section></item><item><link/> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR034243?af=R<pubDate> Fri, 22 Sep 2023 11:08:28 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-09-22T11:08:28-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley: Water Resources Research: Table of Contents <prism:coverdate></prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate></prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR034243</guid><title> Streamflow composition and water “imbalance” in the northern Himalayas</title><description> Water Resources Research, Accepted Article.</description><dc:description> Abstract The Yarlung Zangbo River (YZR) is the largest river in the northern Himalayas, providing crucial water resources for downstream. A full understanding of the streamflow dynamics and regional water budget is critical to secure water security of the Himalayan water tower. Here we establish a comprehensive hydrological model to simulate the precipitation‐runoff‐evapotranspiration‐groundwater‐streamflow complex in the YZR basin. We decipher contributions of different water sources (eg, precipitation, meltwater, groundwater) to YZR&#39;s streamflow and estimate that groundwater sustains ∼36% of annual streamflow in the YZR, while precipitation and melt surface runoff contribute 40% and 24%, respectively. Combining modeling, observation and reanalysis data, our results reveal a water “imbalance” that ∼31% of annual precipitation and meltwater (∼333 mm yr−1 or ∼85 km3 yr−1) is unaccounted for in the YZR basin. We propose that the “excess water” discharges to deep fractured bedrock aquifers, which is promoted by widespread permeable active structures (eg, faults, fractures). This hypothesis is supported by groundwater storage estimates where inclusion of the deep groundwater bridges the discrepancy between baseflow‐derived (shallow) groundwater storage and those derived from the Gravity Recovery and Climate Experiment (GRACE) satellite data. The deep groundwater most likely flows across basins, bypasses streams, and finally discharges to downstream aquifers in the Indo‐Gangetic Plain as mountain block recharge. This study not only provides a comprehensive analysis of the streamflow composition in the YZR, but also contributes to shaping a more complete picture of the functionality of the Himalayan water tower, highlighting the importance of groundwater in regional water transfers.</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;The Yarlung Zangbo River (YZR) is the largest river in the northern Himalayas, providing crucial water resources for downstream. A full understanding of the streamflow dynamics and regional water budget is critical to secure water security of the Himalayan water tower. Here we establish a comprehensive hydrological model to simulate the precipitation-runoff-evapotranspiration-groundwater-streamflow complex in the YZR basin. We decipher contributions of different water sources (eg, precipitation, meltwater, groundwater) to YZR&#39;s streamflow and estimate that groundwater sustains ∼36% of annual streamflow in the YZR, while precipitation and melt surface runoff contribute 40% and 24%, respectively. Combining modeling, observation and reanalysis data, our results reveal a water “imbalance” that ∼31% of annual precipitation and meltwater (∼333 mm yr&lt;sup>;−1&lt;/sup>; or ∼85 km&lt;sup>;3&lt;/sup>; yr&lt;sup>;−1&lt;/sup>;) is unaccounted for in the YZR basin. We propose that the “excess water” discharges to deep fractured bedrock aquifers, which is promoted by widespread permeable active structures (eg, faults, fractures). This hypothesis is supported by groundwater storage estimates where inclusion of the deep groundwater bridges the discrepancy between baseflow-derived (shallow) groundwater storage and those derived from the Gravity Recovery and Climate Experiment (GRACE) satellite data. The deep groundwater most likely flows across basins, bypasses streams, and finally discharges to downstream aquifers in the Indo-Gangetic Plain as mountain block recharge. This study not only provides a comprehensive analysis of the streamflow composition in the YZR, but also contributes to shaping a more complete picture of the functionality of the Himalayan water tower, highlighting the importance of groundwater in regional water transfers.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> Linfeng Fan, Xingxing Kuang, Dani Or, Chunmiao Zheng</dc:creator><category> Research Article</category><dc:title> Streamflow composition and water “imbalance” in the northern Himalayas</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2022WR034243</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1029/2022WR034243</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR034243?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> Research Article</prism:section></item><item><link/> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2023WR035345?af=R<pubDate> Fri, 22 Sep 2023 04:55:17 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-09-22T04:55:17-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley: Water Resources Research: Table of Contents <prism:coverdate></prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate></prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2023WR035345</guid><title> Degradation of a foreland river after the Wenchuan Earthquake, China: A combined effect of weirs, sediment supply and sediment mining</title><description> Water Resources Research, Accepted Article.</description><dc:description> Abstract Since the 2008 Wenchuan (Ms. 8.0) Earthquake, the foreland rivers of the Longmen Mountains have suffered from significant bed degradation, among which the Shi‐ting River has experienced the largest local degradation of more than 20 m in 7 years. Potential reasons of the dramatic degradation include: (1) sediment disconnectivity due to in‐channel weirs; (2) the mobilization effect on gravel of an increased sand supply as a result of earthquake‐induced landslides; and (3) sediment extraction due to intensive mining. In this paper, we study the complex interaction among the above‐mentioned factors in the Shi‐ting River, using a one‐dimensional river morphodynamic model. Simulation results show that in‐channel weirs can reduce bedload transport and lead to bed degradation that is proportional to weir height. When coupled with additional sand supply, the weirs preferentially trap gravel and deliver sand, augmenting the downstream mobility of gravel and thus the degradation. For the Shi‐ting River, the simulated bed degradation agrees well with the observation when an annual sediment mining of 16 million tons is implemented in the simulation, along with the effects of in‐channel weirs and sand supply. The contribution of sediment mining is one order of magnitude larger than the coupling effect of weirs and sand supply. Both the simulation and observation show that the largest bed degradation occurs downstream of the Renmin Weir, due to the large spatial interval between the Renmin Weir and the next grade control structure. This article is protected by copyright.版权所有。</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;Since the 2008 Wenchuan (Ms. 8.0) Earthquake, the foreland rivers of the Longmen Mountains have suffered from significant bed degradation, among which the Shi-ting River has experienced the largest local degradation of more than 20 m in 7 years. Potential reasons of the dramatic degradation include: (1) sediment disconnectivity due to in-channel weirs; (2) the mobilization effect on gravel of an increased sand supply as a result of earthquake-induced landslides; and (3) sediment extraction due to intensive mining. In this paper, we study the complex interaction among the above-mentioned factors in the Shi-ting River, using a one-dimensional river morphodynamic model. Simulation results show that in-channel weirs can reduce bedload transport and lead to bed degradation that is proportional to weir height. When coupled with additional sand supply, the weirs preferentially trap gravel and deliver sand, augmenting the downstream mobility of gravel and thus the degradation. For the Shi-ting River, the simulated bed degradation agrees well with the observation when an annual sediment mining of 16 million tons is implemented in the simulation, along with the effects of in-channel weirs and sand supply. The contribution of sediment mining is one order of magnitude larger than the coupling effect of weirs and sand supply. Both the simulation and observation show that the largest bed degradation occurs downstream of the Renmin Weir, due to the large spatial interval between the Renmin Weir and the next grade control structure.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This article is protected by copyright. All rights reserved.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> Yongpeng Lin, Chenge An, Shan Zheng, Ruihua Nie, Gary Parker, Marwan A. Hassan, Matthew J. Czapiga, Xudong Fu</dc:creator><category> Research Article</category><dc:title> Degradation of a foreland river after the Wenchuan Earthquake, China: A combined effect of weirs, sediment supply and sediment mining</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2023WR035345</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1029/2023WR035345</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2023WR035345?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> Research Article</prism:section></item><item><link/> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR034361?af=R<pubDate> Thu, 21 Sep 2023 18:29:09 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-09-21T06:29:09-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley: Water Resources Research: Table of Contents <prism:coverdate></prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate></prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR034361</guid><title> Land cover control on the drivers of evaporation and sensible heat fluxes: An observation‐based synthesis for the Netherlands</title><description> Water Resources Research, Accepted Article.</description><dc:description> Abstract Land cover controls the land‐atmosphere exchange of water and energy through the partitioning of solar energy into latent and sensible heat. Observations over all land cover types at the regional scale are required to study these turbulent flux dynamics over a landscape. Here, we aim to study how the control of daily and midday latent and sensible heat fluxes over different land cover types is distributed along three axes: energy availability, water availability and exchange efficiency. To this end, observations from 19 eddy covariance flux tower sites in the Netherlands, covering six different land cover types located within the same climatic zone, were used in a regression analysis to explain the observed dynamics and find the principle drivers. The resulting relative position of these sites along the three axes suggests that land cover partly explains the variance of daily and midday turbulent fluxes. We found that evaporation dynamics from grassland, peatland swamp and cropland sites could mostly be explained by energy availability. Forest evaporation can mainly be explained by water availability, urban evaporation by water availability and exchange efficiency, and open water evaporation can almost entirely be explained by exchange efficiency. We found that the sensible heat flux is less sensitive to land cover type. This demonstrates that the land‐atmosphere interface plays an active role in the shedding of sensible heat. Our results contribute to a better understanding of the dynamics of evaporation over different land cover types and may help to optimise, and potentially simplify, models to predict evaporation.</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;Land cover controls the land-atmosphere exchange of water and energy through the partitioning of solar energy into latent and sensible heat. Observations over all land cover types at the regional scale are required to study these turbulent flux dynamics over a landscape. Here, we aim to study how the control of daily and midday latent and sensible heat fluxes over different land cover types is distributed along three axes: energy availability, water availability and exchange efficiency. To this end, observations from 19 eddy covariance flux tower sites in the Netherlands, covering six different land cover types located within the same climatic zone, were used in a regression analysis to explain the observed dynamics and find the principle drivers. The resulting relative position of these sites along the three axes suggests that land cover partly explains the variance of daily and midday turbulent fluxes. We found that evaporation dynamics from grassland, peatland swamp and cropland sites could mostly be explained by energy availability. Forest evaporation can mainly be explained by water availability, urban evaporation by water availability and exchange efficiency, and open water evaporation can almost entirely be explained by exchange efficiency. We found that the sensible heat flux is less sensitive to land cover type. This demonstrates that the land-atmosphere interface plays an active role in the shedding of sensible heat. Our results contribute to a better understanding of the dynamics of evaporation over different land cover types and may help to optimise, and potentially simplify, models to predict evaporation.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> Femke A. Jansen, Harro J. Jongen, Cor MJ Jacobs, Fred C. Bosveld, Alexander JV Buzacott, Bert G. Heusinkveld, Bart Kruijt, Michiel Molen, Eddy Moors, Gert‐Jan Steeneveld, Christiaan Tol, Ype Velde, Bernard Voortman, Remko Uijlenhoet, Adriaan J. Teuling</dc:creator><category> Research Article</category><dc:title> Land cover control on the drivers of evaporation and sensible heat fluxes: An observation‐based synthesis for the Netherlands</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2022WR034361</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1029/2022WR034361</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR034361?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> Research Article</prism:section></item></channel></rss>