<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:prism="http://prismstandard.org/namespaces/basic/2.0/"><channel><title> Wiley：水资源研究：目录</title><link/>https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R<description>水资源研究目录。最新期和 EarlyView 期的文章列表。</description><language> en-US</language><copyright></copyright><managingeditor> wileyonlinelibrary@wiley.com（AGU 出版物）</managingeditor><pubDate> Mon, 18 Sep 2023 07:35:59 +0000</pubDate><lastbuilddate> 2023 年 9 月 18 日星期一 07:35:59 +0000</lastbuilddate><generator> Atypon®文学™</generator><docs> https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs><ttl> 10080</ttl><dc:title> Wiley：水资源研究：目录</dc:title><dc:publisher>威利</dc:publisher><prism:publicationname>水资源研究</prism:publicationname><atom:link href="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"></atom:link><image/><title> Wiley：水资源研究：目录</title><url>https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/pb-assets/journal-banners/19447973.jpg</url><link/> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R<item><link/> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2023WR034509?af=R<pubDate> Sat, 16 Sep 2023 01:38:21 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-09-16T01:38:21-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley：水资源研究：目录<prism:coverdate></prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate></prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2023WR034509</guid><title>基于 Budyko 框架的气候变化对流域蒸发效率的影响及其对欧洲排放量的影响分析</title><description>水资源研究，已接受文章。</description><dc:description>摘要 在气候变化的背景下，围绕水资源供应的风险正在迅速加剧。分解和量化气候对排放的影响使我们能够更好地了解其对水资源的影响。我们提出了一种将气候变量年平均值变化的影响与降水年内分布的影响分开的方法。它将 Budyko 框架与陆地表面模型 (LSM) 输出相结合。 LSM 用于重现 1902 年至 2010 年间欧洲 2134 个重建流域的行为，气候输入是唯一的变化来源。我们将 Budyko 框架的单参数近似拟合到 LSM 输出。它解释了年平均降水量 (P) 和潜在蒸散量 (PET) 的演变。我们在方程中引入了一个变化的参数，代表 P 和 PET 年内分布的长期变化的影响。为了更好地评估 P 的年均值或年内分布变化的影响，我们构建了固定其中一个或另一个的合成强迫。欧洲的结果表明，磷年平均值的趋势主导了气候导致的排放趋势。第二个主要气候驱动因素是 PET，但地中海地区除外，该地区 P 的年内变化对流量的影响比 PET 的趋势更大。因此，在研究年流量变化时，需要考虑气候变量年内分布变化的影响。</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;摘要&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;在气候变化的背景下，围绕水资源供应的风险正在迅速加剧。分解和量化气候对排放的影响使我们能够更好地了解其对水资源的影响。我们提出了一种将气候变量年平均值变化的影响与降水年内分布的影响分开的方法。它将 Budyko 框架与陆地表面模型 (LSM) 输出相结合。 LSM 用于重现 1902 年至 2010 年间欧洲 2134 个重建流域的行为，气候输入是唯一的变化来源。我们将 Budyko 框架的单参数近似拟合到 LSM 输出。它解释了年平均降水量 (&lt;i>;P&lt;/i>;) 和潜在蒸散量 (&lt;i>;PET&lt;/i>;) 的演变。我们在方程中引入了一个变化的参数，代表&lt;i>;P&lt;/i>;和&lt;i>;PET&lt;/i>;的年内分布的长期变化的影响。为了更好地评估&lt;i>;P&lt;/i>;的年平均值或年内分布变化的影响，我们构建了固定其中一个或另一个的合成强迫。欧洲的结果表明，&lt;i>;P&lt;/i>;年平均值的趋势主导了气候引起的排放量的趋势。第二个主要气候驱动因素是&lt;i>;PET&lt;/i>;，但地中海地区除外，该地区&lt;i>;P&lt;/i>;的年内变化对流量的影响比&lt;i>;PET的趋势更大&lt;/i>;。因此，在考察年流量变化时，需要考虑气候变量年内分布变化的影响。&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator>朱莉·科利尼昂、扬·波尔彻、苏菲·巴斯汀、Pere Quintana-Segui</dc:creator><category>研究文章</category><dc:title>基于 Budyko 框架的气候变化对流域蒸发效率的影响及其对欧洲排放量的影响分析</dc:title><dc:identifier>10.1029/2023WR034509</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname>水资源研究</prism:publicationname><prism:doi>10.1029/2023WR034509</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2023WR034509?af=R</prism:url><prism:section>研究文章</prism:section></item><item><link/>https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2023WR035616?af=R<pubDate> Fri, 15 Sep 2023 06:49:11 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-09-15T06:49:11-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley：水资源研究：目录<prism:coverdate></prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate></prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2023WR035616</guid><title>存在异质土壤时渗透池下降时间的随机分析</title><description>水资源研究，已接受文章。</description><dc:description>摘要 水位下降时间对于渗透池的设计和评估非常重要。本文研究了其对土壤异质性的依赖性，并给出了均值和方差的简单解析解。使用针对层状土壤的改进的 Green Ampt 模型和基于一维理查兹方程积分的模型，通过蒙特卡罗模拟在各种实际场景中对解决方案进行了测试。评估了所采用的近似值的影响，并强调了饱和导水率空间分布的主导作用。还研究了其他相关设计和自然因素的影响，包括初始水位和含水量分布。</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;摘要&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;水位下降时间对于渗透池的设计和评估非常重要。本文研究了其对土壤异质性的依赖性，并给出了均值和方差的简单解析解。使用针对层状土壤的改进的 Green Ampt 模型和基于一维理查兹方程积分的模型，通过蒙特卡洛模拟在各种实际场景中对解决方案进行测试。评估了所采用的近似值的影响，并强调了饱和导水率空间分布的主导作用。还研究了其他相关设计和自然因素的影响，包括初始水位和含水量分布。&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator>马可·费兰特、阿尔多·菲奥里</dc:creator><category>研究文章</category><dc:title>存在异质土壤时渗透池下降时间的随机分析</dc:title><dc:identifier>10.1029/2023WR035616</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname>水资源研究</prism:publicationname><prism:doi>10.1029/2023WR035616</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2023WR035616?af=R</prism:url><prism:section>研究文章</prism:section></item><item><link/>https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2023WR034849?af=R<pubDate> Fri, 15 Sep 2023 03:09:49 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-09-15T03:09:49-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley：水资源研究：目录<prism:coverdate></prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate></prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2023WR034849</guid><title>油粘度对多孔介质中不混溶两相流水相分散的影响：X 射线断层扫描研究</title><description>水资源研究，已接受文章。</description><dc:description>摘要 在本研究中，研究了使用共注射方法产生的稳定两相流中的分散和混合。在大范围的流体粘度比下研究了油粘度的影响。结果表明，高度不均匀的流场是由广泛分布的不同体积的石油团簇产生的。速度分布的变化增强了示踪羽流的变形和扩散，导致较大的扩散规模和加速的扩散速率。色散系数随时间变化，并在共注射过程中表现出非菲克色散。因此，当粘度比超过 10 时，可以观察到异常混合行为。以标量耗散速率为特征的混合强度首先通过溶质表面的变形而增强。因此，扩散有助于混合，导致后期混合强度更快下降。这些结果可归因于非润湿流体变得断开，并且随着油粘度的增加，每个簇的尺寸减小。油膜的形成使孔隙空间变窄，并且即使润湿相的相对渗透率较低，油膜的润滑作用也可能有助于增强分散和混合状态。这项研究提供了在宏观和孔隙尺度上不同石油粘度的部分饱和多孔介质中的分散情况的见解，这可以进一步提高二氧化碳储存能力和安全性。本文受版权保护。版权所有。</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;摘要&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;在这项研究中，研究了使用共注射方法产生的稳定两相流中的分散和混合。在大范围的流体粘度比下研究了油粘度的影响。结果表明，高度不均匀的流场是由广泛分布的不同体积的石油团簇产生的。速度分布的变化增强了示踪羽流的变形和扩散，导致较大的扩散规模和加速的扩散速率。色散系数随时间变化，并在共注射过程中表现出非菲克色散。因此，当粘度比超过 10 时，可以观察到异常混合行为。以标量耗散速率为特征的混合强度首先通过溶质表面的变形而增强。因此，扩散有助于混合，导致后期混合强度更快下降。这些结果可归因于以下事实：非润湿流体变得断开，并且随着油粘度的增加，每个簇的尺寸减小。油膜的形成使孔隙空间变窄，并且即使润湿相的相对渗透率较低，油膜的润滑作用也可能有助于增强分散和混合状态。这项研究提供了在宏观和孔隙尺度上不同石油粘度的部分饱和多孔介质中的分散情况的见解，这可以进一步提高 CO&lt;sub>;2&lt;/sub>; 存储能力和安全性。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;本文受版权保护。保留所有权利。&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator>李紫晶、穆罕默德·纳西尔、王伟岑、快藤一树、张春伟、末兼哲也、松下慎太郎</dc:creator><category>研究文章</category><dc:title>油粘度对多孔介质中不混溶两相流水相分散的影响：X 射线断层扫描研究</dc:title><dc:identifier>10.1029/2023WR034849</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname>水资源研究</prism:publicationname><prism:doi>10.1029/2023WR034849</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2023WR034849?af=R</prism:url><prism:section>研究文章</prism:section></item><item><link/>https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2023WR035676?af=R<pubDate> Thu, 14 Sep 2023 20:42:39 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-09-14T08:42:39-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley：水资源研究：目录<prism:coverdate></prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate></prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2023WR035676</guid><title>利用深度学习集成模型的可解释人工智能和气象变量进行稳健径流预测</title><description>水资源研究，已接受文章。</description><dc:description>摘要 准确的径流预报对于及时发布洪水预警至关重要。而以往的研究主要集中在历史径流和降水变化上，而忽略了其他因素的影响。此外，大多数机器学习模型的预测过程是不透明的，导致模型预测的可解释性较低。因此，本研究开发了一个集成深度学习模型来预测三个水文站的径流。最初，采用基于时变滤波的经验模态分解（TVFEMD）将径流序列分解为多个内模函数（IMF）。随后，通过多尺度排列熵（MPE）评估每个 IMF 分量的复杂性，并根据熵值将 IMF 分为高频部分和低频部分。考虑到高频部分仍然表现出较大的波动性，采用鲁棒局部均值分解（RLMD）对高频部分进行二次分解。然后，采用Relief算法处理的气象变量和方差膨胀因子（VIF）特征作为输入，二次和初步分解的各个子序列作为双向门控循环单元（BiGRU）和极限学习机（ELM）模型的输出。引入随机森林（RF）对各个预测子模型进行非线性集成以获得最终的预测结果。所提出的模型在各种评估指标上都优于其他模型。同时，由于机器学习模型的不透明性，采用沙普利来评估每个选定的气象变量对径流长期趋势的贡献。该模型可为洪水精准预测和及时预警提供重要参考。</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;准确的径流预报对于及时发布洪水预警至关重要。而以往的研究主要集中在历史径流和降水变化上，而忽略了其他因素的影响。此外，大多数机器学习模型的预测过程是不透明的，导致模型预测的可解释性较低。因此，本研究开发了一个集成深度学习模型来预测三个水文站的径流。最初，采用基于时变滤波的经验模态分解（TVFEMD）将径流序列分解为多个内模函数（IMF）。随后，通过多尺度排列熵（MPE）评估每个 IMF 分量的复杂性，并根据熵值将 IMF 分为高频部分和低频部分。考虑到高频部分仍然表现出较大的波动性，采用鲁棒局部均值分解(RLMD)对高频部分进行二次分解。然后，采用Relief算法处理的气象变量和方差膨胀因子（VIF）特征作为输入，二次和初步分解的各个子序列作为双向门控循环单元（BiGRU）和极限学习机（ELM）模型的输出。引入随机森林（RF）对各个预测子模型进行非线性集成以获得最终的预测结果。所提出的模型在各种评估指标上都优于其他模型。同时，由于机器学习模型的不透明性，采用沙普利来评估每个选定的气象变量对径流长期趋势的贡献。该模型可为洪水精准预报和及时预警提供重要参考。&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator>吴俊豪、王兆才、董静涵、崔雪飞、陶森、陈曦</dc:creator><category>研究文章</category><dc:title>利用深度学习集成模型的可解释人工智能和气象变量进行稳健径流预测</dc:title><dc:identifier>10.1029/2023WR035676</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname>水资源研究</prism:publicationname><prism:doi>10.1029/2023WR035676</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2023WR035676?af=R</prism:url><prism:section>研究文章</prism:section></item><item><link/>https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2023WR035077?af=R<pubDate> Thu, 14 Sep 2023 11:20:03 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-09-14T11:20:03-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley：水资源研究：目录<prism:coverdate></prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate></prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2023WR035077</guid><title>大型受管制河流中的排放介导的温度管理对濒危鱼类的管理具有影响</title><description>水资源研究，已接受文章。</description><dc:description>摘要 对于大型、受监管的河流，运营商可以通过控制上游水库的流量来影响非生物条件，从而造福生态系统。了解排放的决策空间对于评估环境目标和其他目标之间的权衡是必要的。由于气候变化，水温升高越来越成为热敏感动物群的一个担忧。在加州最大的河流萨克拉门托河，鲑鱼种群的灭绝风险与高水温有关。然而，人们对水库泄洪作业对下游水温的影响程度以及对鲑鱼的潜在好处知之甚少。我们使用基于过程的水温模型来估计水库流量调节影响下游位置的河流温度加热过程的能力（流量调节温度管理）。为了限制这一分析，我们使用了最近 29 年跨度的历史强迫。结果表明，水库流量比历史记录增加最多 340 厘米，可导致下游水温下降最多 3.6℃。鲑鱼在其生命周期的大部分阶段需要低于 20°C 的水，我们发现规范的水操作可以确保春末和初秋这两个潜在管理季节的水温很少超过 20°C。这些时期恰逢鲑鱼的重要饲养和洄游时期，在此期间，在管理现状下它们经常经历过高的温度。该分析为利益相关者提供了在气候变暖的情况下管理本地动物群条件的工具，以及在其他大型监管河流中开发类似工具的框架。</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;对于大型、受监管的河流，运营商可以通过控制上游水库的流量来影响非生物条件，从而造福生态系统。了解排放的决策空间对于评估环境目标和其他目标之间的权衡是必要的。由于气候变化，水温升高日益成为热敏感动物群的一个担忧。在加州最大的河流萨克拉门托河，鲑鱼种群的灭绝风险与高水温有关。然而，人们对水库泄洪作业对下游水温的影响程度以及对鲑鱼的潜在好处知之甚少。我们使用基于过程的水温模型来估计水库流量调节影响下游位置的河流温度加热过程的能力（流量调节温度管理）。为了限制这一分析，我们使用了最近 29 年跨度的历史强迫。结果表明，水库流量较历史记录增加高达 340 厘米，可导致下游水温降低高达 3.6℃。鲑鱼在其生命周期的大部分阶段都需要低于 20°C 的水，我们发现规范的水操作可以确保春末和初秋这两个潜在管理季节的水温很少超过 20°C。这些时期恰逢鲑鱼的重要饲养和洄游时期，在此期间，在管理现状下，它们经常经历过高的温度。该分析为利益相关者提供了在气候变暖的情况下管理本地动物群条件的工具，以及在其他大型监管河流中开发类似工具的框架。&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> CJ 米歇尔、ME 丹尼尔斯、EM 丹纳</dc:creator><category>研究文章</category><dc:title>大型受管制河流中的排放介导的温度管理对濒危鱼类的管理具有影响</dc:title><dc:identifier>10.1029/2023WR035077</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname>水资源研究</prism:publicationname><prism:doi>10.1029/2023WR035077</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2023WR035077?af=R</prism:url><prism:section>研究文章</prism:section></item><item><link/>https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR034228?af=R<pubDate> Thu, 14 Sep 2023 06:10:21 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-09-14T06:10:21-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley：水资源研究：目录<prism:coverdate></prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate></prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR034228</guid><title>考虑饱和区发展的积水渗透的新型分析解决方案</title><description>水资源研究，已接受文章。</description><dc:description>摘要 土壤表面积水对入渗有着深远的影响。然而，目前的渗透模型尚未考虑积水深度对渗透的影响，特别是土壤表面以下饱和区的发展。针对表面有积水的均匀初始湿度分布下的一维垂直渗透问题，推导了一种新的通用 Green-Ampt 模型解决方案（GAMS）。新解决方案中包含一个表达式，用于模拟在土壤表面以下形成的饱和层，只要表面的压头足够高以使土壤饱和即可。与传统和最近改进的 Green-Ampt 模型相比，GAMS 模拟的渗透过程更接近 HYDRUS-1D 的数值解。此外，还提出了一种基于 GAMS 的反演方法，用于改进一维垂直渗透实验中土壤水力参数的估计。还评估了饱和区积水深度（hp）、初始土壤含水量、土壤质地和水力土壤特性（饱和导水率Ks、入水吸力hd和土壤持水曲线形状系数n）的影响。结果表明，在渗透过程中，饱和区长度以与非饱和润湿区长度相当的速率增加。一般来说，初始土壤含水量较高、质地较粗、Ks 值较高、n 较大和 ‐hd 较低的土壤会发现较大的饱和区。我们的研究结果表明，在渗透模型中包含饱和区可以更好地估计土壤水力参数。所提出的 GAMS 模型可以改进灌溉设计和降雨径流模拟。本文受版权保护。版权所有。</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;摘要&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;土壤表面积水对渗透产生深远影响。然而，目前的渗透模型尚未考虑积水深度对渗透的影响，特别是土壤表面以下饱和区的发展。针对表面有积水的均匀初始湿度分布下的一维垂直渗透问题，推导了一种新的通用 Green-Ampt 模型解（GAMS）。新解决方案中包含一个表达式，用于模拟在土壤表面以下形成的饱和层，只要表面的压头足够高以使土壤饱和即可。与传统和最近改进的 Green-Ampt 模型相比，GAMS 模拟的渗透过程更接近 HYDRUS-1D 的数值解。此外，还提出了一种基于 GAMS 的反演方法，用于改进一维垂直渗透实验中土壤水力参数的估计。积水深度 (&lt;i>;h&lt;/i>; &lt;sub>;p&lt;/sub>;)、初始土壤含水量、土壤质地和水力土壤特性（饱和导水率 &lt;i>;K&lt;/i>; &lt;sub >;s&lt;/sub>;、入水吸力&lt;i>;h&lt;/i>;&lt;sub>;d&lt;/sub>;和土壤持水曲线形状系数&lt;i>;n&lt;/i>;）也为饱和区评价。结果表明，在渗透过程中，饱和区长度以与非饱和润湿区长度相当的速率增加。一般来说，初始土壤含水量较高、质地较粗、&lt;i>;K&lt;/i>; &lt;sub>;s&lt;/sub>; 值较高、&lt;i>;n&lt;/i>; 较大且降低-&lt;i>;h&lt;/i>; &lt;sub>;d&lt;/sub>;。我们的研究结果表明，在渗透模型中包含饱和区可以更好地估计土壤水力参数。所提出的 GAMS 模型可以改进灌溉设计和降雨径流模拟。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;本文受版权保护。保留所有权利。&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator>马东浩、吴思聪、刘志鹏、张家宝</dc:creator><category>研究文章</category><dc:title>考虑饱和区发展的积水渗透的新型分析解决方案</dc:title><dc:identifier>10.1029/2022WR034228</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname>水资源研究</prism:publicationname><prism:doi>10.1029/2022WR034228</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR034228?af=R</prism:url><prism:section>研究文章</prism:section></item><item><link/>https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR034155?af=R<pubDate> Thu, 14 Sep 2023 03:24:37 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-09-14T03:24:37-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley：水资源研究：目录<prism:coverdate></prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate></prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR034155</guid><title>高地山坡地下水补贴影响低流量储排关系</title><description>水资源研究，已接受文章。</description><dc:description>摘要 针对低流量蓄排水关系的大规模跨地点科学综合可以促进关于关键区域属性之间的相互作用以及这种相互作用如何影响流域水脆弱性的可转移假设的发展。本研究利用跨地点的实证和理论分析，并根据关键区域属性之间的相互作用开发了一个相似性指数，以确定高地山坡地下水补贴对储排关系的影响，这一影响尚未得到充分研究。我们表明，高地山坡地下水补贴对低流量排放的相对程度的增加，通过深层缓慢低移动（例如基岩）存储单元发生，导致 1）低流量排放的非线性增加对存储的敏感性（β1），2）低流量存储-放电关系的凸性增加。我们的研究结果还提出了基于 Boussinesq 的水力地下水理论在低流量条件下的适用性的新假设。实证结果表明，在我们研究的部分流域中，特别是在山坡地下水补贴范围相对较小的流域中，该理论提出的非线性范围足以解释低流量储排关系的非线性。然而，在通过深层缓慢移动蓄水单元进行高地山坡地下水补贴影响较大的流域中，使用单一（非）线性代表性蓄水单元的水力地下水理论的现状可能不足以解释大的非线性和低流量存储-排放关系的凸性（或晚期衰退的长尾）。由于 β1 表明流域的低流量脆弱性，本研究的结果加深​​并概括了我们对低流量流量容易受到蓄水量变化影响的理解。</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;关于低流量储存-排放关系的大规模跨地点科学综合可以促进对关键区域属性之间的相互作用以及这种相互作用如何影响流域水脆弱性的可转移假设的发展。本研究利用跨地点的实证和理论分析，并根据关键区域属性之间的相互作用开发了一个相似性指数，以确定高地山坡地下水补贴对储存-排放关系的影响，这一影响研究很少。我们表明，高地山坡地下水补贴对低流量排放的相对程度的增加，通过深层缓慢低移动（例如基岩）存储单元发生，导致 1）低流量排放的非线性增加对存储的敏感性（&lt;i>;β&lt;/i>; &lt;sub>; &lt;i>;1&lt;/i>; &lt;/sub>;），以及2）低流量存储-放电关系的凸性增加。我们的研究结果还提出了基于 Boussinesq 的水力地下水理论在低流量条件下的适用性的新假设。实证结果表明，在我们研究的部分流域中，特别是在山坡地下水补贴范围相对较小的流域中，该理论提出的非线性范围足以解释低流量蓄排关系的非线性。然而，在通过深层缓慢移动的蓄水单元进行高地山坡地下水补贴影响较大的流域中，使用单一（非）线性代表性蓄水单元的水力地下水理论的现状可能不足以解释大的非线性以及低流量储放关系的凸性（或晚期衰退的长尾）。由于 &lt;i>;β&lt;/i>; &lt;sub>; &lt;i>;1&lt;/i>; &lt;/sub>; 揭示了流域的低流量脆弱性，本研究的结果加深​​并概括了我们对低流量流量易受影响的区域的理解。存储的变化。&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator>李宏毅，阿里·A·阿梅利</dc:creator><category>研究文章</category><dc:title>高地山坡地下水补贴影响低流量储排关系</dc:title><dc:identifier>10.1029/2022WR034155</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname>水资源研究</prism:publicationname><prism:doi>10.1029/2022WR034155</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR034155?af=R</prism:url><prism:section>研究文章</prism:section></item><item><link/>https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2023WR035266?af=R<pubDate> Thu, 14 Sep 2023 03:08:43 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-09-14T03:08:43-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley：水资源研究：目录<prism:coverdate></prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate></prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2023WR035266</guid><title>随时间变化的速度场对保守化学物质连续尺度输运的影响</title><description>水资源研究，已接受文章。</description><dc:description>摘要 由于不同的自然现象和人类活动，自然系统中的地下水输入可能在很大的时间尺度上发生变化。这些变化会产生与时间相关的速度场，这反过来可能会影响相对于恒定速度域中的迁移的化学羽流的迁移动力学。异常输送在许多地下水系统中普遍存在，并且相对于受菲克分散过程影响的化学羽流迁移尾部通常会产生更长的（非菲克）尾部，因此在这种情况下特别令人感兴趣。在此，通过实验室实验和相应的数值模拟分析了宏观一维柱和二维流动池中保守化学物质的传输。比较不同时间相关的速度场幅度条件，以研究瞬态水输入如何影响所得到的示踪剂突破曲线。采用基于随机的数值模型来解释结果并模拟超出实验室规模的条件。实验室测量表明，与恒速情况相比，不同的时间相关速度大小条件（保留了可比较的恒速系统的平均流量）产生了相似的长尾突破曲线。然后用连续时间随机游走 (CTRW) 框架对突破曲线进行量化。适当选择速度变化时的粒子跃迁时间和距离可以使 CTRW 结果与实验中获得的实验结果相匹配。对于一维和二维流场、同质和异质介质以及不同的流动场景，时间相关的速度场大小的影响可以忽略不计。本文受版权保护。版权所有。</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;摘要&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;由于不同的自然现象和人类活动，自然系统中的地下水输入可能会在很大的时间尺度上发生变化。这些变化会产生与时间相关的速度场，这反过来可能会影响相对于恒定速度域中的迁移的迁移化学羽流的动力学。 Anomalous transport, which is ubiquitous in many groundwater systems and generally yields longer (non-Fickian) tails of migrating chemical plumes relative to those subject to Fickian dispersive processes, is of particular interest in this context. Herein, transport of conservative chemical species in macroscopically 1D columns and 2D flow cells was analyzed via laboratory experiments and corresponding numerical simulations. Different time-dependent velocity field magnitude conditions were compared to study how the transient water input affects the resulting tracer breakthrough curves. A stochastic-based numerical model was employed to interpret the results and simulate conditions that extend beyond the laboratory scale. The laboratory measurements show that different time-dependent velocity magnitude conditions, which preserve the average discharge of a comparable constant-velocity system, yield similar, long-tailed breakthrough curves compared to those of the constant-velocity case. The breakthrough curves are then shown to be quantified with the continuous time random walk (CTRW) framework. Appropriate choice of particle transition times and distances at the moment of velocity change enables matching of the CTRW results to the experimental results obtained in the experiments. The negligible impact of time-dependent velocity field magnitudes is shown to be consistent for 1D and 2D flow fields, homogeneous and heterogeneous media, and different flow scenarios.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This article is protected by copyright. All rights reserved.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> Dan Elhanati, Ishai Dror, Brian Berkowitz</dc:creator><category> Research Article</category><dc:title> Impact of time‐dependent velocity fields on the continuum‐scale transport of conservative chemicals</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2023WR035266</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1029/2023WR035266</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2023WR035266?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> Research Article</prism:section></item><item><link/> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR034209?af=R<pubDate> Thu, 14 Sep 2023 01:53:09 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-09-14T01:53:09-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley: Water Resources Research: Table of Contents <prism:coverdate></prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate></prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR034209</guid><title> Estimating dynamic non‐water‐limited canopy resistance over the globe: Changes, contributors and implications</title><description> Water Resources Research, Accepted Article.</description><dc:description> Abstract Non‐water‐limited canopy resistance (rcs, also known as the bulk stomatal resistance or surface resistance) is a critical variable in estimating potential evapotranspiration (PET), which is widely used in ecohydrology related fields. However, quantifying rcs is a challenging work. Here we develop an approach for estimating rcs over the globe. Comparing results over the globe and across ten ET datasets (used as inputs), which are based on diverse mechanisms and algorithms, we find that the approach can capture canopy resistance well (mean correlation of 0.84 ± 0.04, mean relative Root Mean Squared Error of 4.4 ± 1.0%, and mean relative Mean Absolute Error of 5.8 ± 1.4%), and the estimated rcs are very close to those estimated using another method (R2 = 0.92), which is based on a quite different hypothesis that is only suitable for saturated regions. Based on these, we find that the rcs shows an overall increasing trend (0.43 ± 0.13 sm‐1 year‐1) over the globe (at 77.6 ± 3.9% of the land grid cells) during 1982‐2014, and the air temperature dominates the variabilities of rcs in regions with decreasing rcs (mean relative contribution of 57.9 ± 11.4%), while air CO2 concentration controls the changes in rcs in regions with increasing rcs (mean relative contribution of 47.3 ± 8.0%). Moreover, we also find that the traditional PET estimator explicitly overestimates the increasing trends in PET, and tends to overestimate (underestimate) the increasing (decreasing) trends in regions with increasing (decreasing) PET. These findings can improve our knowledge on the complex water‐vegetation‐environment interactions and would be helpful for developing more accurate models for quantifying the impacts of global change on water resources. This article is protected by copyright.版权所有。</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;Non-water-limited canopy resistance (r&lt;sub>;cs&lt;/sub>;, also known as the bulk stomatal resistance or surface resistance) is a critical variable in estimating potential evapotranspiration (PET), which is widely used in ecohydrology related fields. However, quantifying r&lt;sub>;cs&lt;/sub>; is a challenging work. Here we develop an approach for estimating r&lt;sub>;cs&lt;/sub>; over the globe. Comparing results over the globe and across ten ET datasets (used as inputs), which are based on diverse mechanisms and algorithms, we find that the approach can capture canopy resistance well (mean correlation of 0.84 ± 0.04, mean relative Root Mean Squared Error of 4.4 ± 1.0%, and mean relative Mean Absolute Error of 5.8 ± 1.4%), and the estimated r&lt;sub>;cs&lt;/sub>; are very close to those estimated using another method (&lt;i>;R&lt;/i>; &lt;sup>;2&lt;/sup>; = 0.92), which is based on a quite different hypothesis that is only suitable for saturated regions. Based on these, we find that the r&lt;sub>;cs&lt;/sub>; shows an overall increasing trend (0.43 ± 0.13 s m&lt;sup>;-1&lt;/sup>; year&lt;sup>;-1&lt;/sup>;) over the globe (at 77.6 ± 3.9% of the land grid cells) during 1982-2014, and the air temperature dominates the variabilities of r&lt;sub>;cs&lt;/sub>; in regions with decreasing r&lt;sub>;cs&lt;/sub>; (mean relative contribution of 57.9 ± 11.4%), while air CO&lt;sub>;2&lt;/sub>; concentration controls the changes in r&lt;sub>;cs&lt;/sub>; in regions with increasing r&lt;sub>;cs&lt;/sub>; (mean relative contribution of 47.3 ± 8.0%). Moreover, we also find that the traditional PET estimator explicitly overestimates the increasing trends in PET, and tends to overestimate (underestimate) the increasing (decreasing) trends in regions with increasing (decreasing) PET. These findings can improve our knowledge on the complex water-vegetation-environment interactions and would be helpful for developing more accurate models for quantifying the impacts of global change on water resources.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This article is protected by copyright. All rights reserved.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> Meixian Liu, Alexander Y Sun, Kairong Lin, Wei Luo, Xinjun Tu, Xiaohong Chen</dc:creator><category> Research Article</category><dc:title> Estimating dynamic non‐water‐limited canopy resistance over the globe: Changes, contributors and implications</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2022WR034209</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1029/2022WR034209</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR034209?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> Research Article</prism:section></item><item><link/> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2023WR035172?af=R<pubDate> Wed, 13 Sep 2023 12:33:56 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-09-13T12:33:56-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley: Water Resources Research: Table of Contents<prism:coverdate> Fri, 01 Sep 2023 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate> Fri, 01 Sep 2023 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2023WR035172</guid><title> The Safe Drinking Water Act at 50: A Policy Model for Grand Challenges</title><description> Water Resources Research, Volume 59, Issue 9, September 2023.</description><dc:description> Abstract Since its passage in 1974, the US Safe Drinking Water Act (SDWA) has become a pillar of water resources engineering, utility management, and public health policy. Complementing other environmental legislation from the same period, SDWA set standards for drinking water suppliers, service, and quality and has made an unmistakable positive impact on US communities for the past 50 years. While drinking water faces different specific challenges today, the general principles established by SDWA are the same. Its success may be attributed to its broad political commitment at the federal level, firm enforcement at the state level, and dutiful execution at the local (public water supplier) level—all while customers know exactly what to expect—thus creating clear accountability for safe water. Just as SDWA helped resolve last century&#39;s drinking water problems, it can serve as a policy model for addressing this century&#39;s grand challenges.</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;Since its passage in 1974, the US Safe Drinking Water Act (SDWA) has become a pillar of water resources engineering, utility management, and public health policy. Complementing other environmental legislation from the same period, SDWA set standards for drinking water suppliers, service, and quality and has made an unmistakable positive impact on US communities for the past 50 years. While drinking water faces different specific challenges today, the general principles established by SDWA are the same. Its success may be attributed to its broad political commitment at the federal level, firm enforcement at the state level, and dutiful execution at the local (public water supplier) level—all while customers know exactly what to expect—thus creating clear accountability for safe water. Just as SDWA helped resolve last century&#39;s drinking water problems, it can serve as a policy model for addressing this century&#39;s grand challenges.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> Robert B. Sowby</dc:creator><category> Commentary</category><dc:title> The Safe Drinking Water Act at 50: A Policy Model for Grand Challenges</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2023WR035172</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1029/2023WR035172</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2023WR035172?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> Commentary</prism:section><prism:volume> 59</prism:volume><prism:number> 9</prism:number></item><item><link/> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2023WR034942?af=R<pubDate> Wed, 13 Sep 2023 12:30:04 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-09-13T12:30:04-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley: Water Resources Research: Table of Contents<prism:coverdate> Fri, 01 Sep 2023 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate> Fri, 01 Sep 2023 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2023WR034942</guid><title> Reliability of Ensemble Climatological Forecasts</title><description> Water Resources Research, Volume 59, Issue 9, September 2023.</description><dc:description> Abstract Ensemble climatological forecasts play a critical part in benchmarking the predictive performance of hydroclimatic forecasts. Accounting for the skewness and censoring characteristics of hydroclimatic variables, ensemble climatological forecasts can be generated by the log, Box‐Cox and log‐sinh transformations, by the combinations of the Bernoulli distribution with the Gaussian, Gamma, log‐normal, generalized extreme value, generalized logistic and Pearson type III distributions and by the non‐parametric resampling, empirical cumulative distribution function and kernel density estimation methods. This paper is concentrated on the reliability of the 12 types of ensemble climatological forecasts. Specifically, mathematical formulations are presented and large‐sample tests are devised to verify the forecast reliability for the Multi‐Source Weighted‐Ensemble Precipitation version 2 across the globe. Climatological forecasts of monthly precipitation over 18,425 grid cells are generated for 30 years under leave‐one‐year‐out cross validation, leading to 6,633,000 (12 × 18425 × 30) sets of ensemble climatological forecasts. The results point out that the reliability of climatological forecasts considerably varies across the 12 methods, particularly in regions with high hydroclimatic variability. One observation is that climatological forecasts tend to deviate from the distributions of observations when there is inadequate flexibility to fit precipitation data. Another observation is that ensemble spreads can be overly wide when there exist overfits of sample‐specific noises in cross validation. Through the tests of global precipitation, the robustness of the log‐sinh transformation and the Bernoulli‐Gamma distribution is highlighted. Overall, the investigations can serve as a guidance on the uses of transformations, distributions and non‐parametric methods in generating climatological forecasts.</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;Ensemble climatological forecasts play a critical part in benchmarking the predictive performance of hydroclimatic forecasts. Accounting for the skewness and censoring characteristics of hydroclimatic variables, ensemble climatological forecasts can be generated by the log, Box-Cox and log-sinh transformations, by the combinations of the Bernoulli distribution with the Gaussian, Gamma, log-normal, generalized extreme value, generalized logistic and Pearson type III distributions and by the non-parametric resampling, empirical cumulative distribution function and kernel density estimation methods. This paper is concentrated on the reliability of the 12 types of ensemble climatological forecasts. Specifically, mathematical formulations are presented and large-sample tests are devised to verify the forecast reliability for the Multi-Source Weighted-Ensemble Precipitation version 2 across the globe. Climatological forecasts of monthly precipitation over 18,425 grid cells are generated for 30 years under leave-one-year-out cross validation, leading to 6,633,000 (12 × 18425 × 30) sets of ensemble climatological forecasts. The results point out that the reliability of climatological forecasts considerably varies across the 12 methods, particularly in regions with high hydroclimatic variability. One observation is that climatological forecasts tend to deviate from the distributions of observations when there is inadequate flexibility to fit precipitation data. Another observation is that ensemble spreads can be overly wide when there exist overfits of sample-specific noises in cross validation. Through the tests of global precipitation, the robustness of the log-sinh transformation and the Bernoulli-Gamma distribution is highlighted. Overall, the investigations can serve as a guidance on the uses of transformations, distributions and non-parametric methods in generating climatological forecasts.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> Zeqing Huang, Tongtiegang Zhao, Yu Tian, Xiaohong Chen, Qingyun Duan, Hao Wang</dc:creator><category>方法</category><dc:title>Reliability of Ensemble Climatological Forecasts</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2023WR034942</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1029/2023WR034942</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2023WR034942?af=R</prism:url><prism:section>方法</prism:section><prism:volume>59</prism:volume><prism:number> 9</prism:number></item><item><link/> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2023WR034461?af=R<pubDate> Wed, 13 Sep 2023 12:28:05 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-09-13T12:28:05-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley: Water Resources Research: Table of Contents<prism:coverdate> Fri, 01 Sep 2023 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate> Fri, 01 Sep 2023 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2023WR034461</guid><title> Impact of Pressure Waves on Water Imbibition and Flow in Unsaturated Porous Media</title><description> Water Resources Research, Volume 59, Issue 9, September 2023.</description><dc:description> Abstract The wetting front dynamics during water imbibition in dry porous media affect the ultimate water distribution pattern. In this study, we investigate the impact of pressure pulses that emit waves in the water phase on the water distribution and imbibition patterns in porous media. We present experimental results of water spatial distribution in sand columns following infiltration under abrupt pressured‐water pulses and compare them with those of continuous inflow. Applying pressure waves during infiltration increases pressure gradients behind the wetting front, which can overcome capillary and gravitational forces, leading to uniform imbibition. To simulate the process, we developed a pore‐network model incorporating an analytical solution of pressure wave attenuation to predict the imbibition pattern. Our results demonstrate that the amplitude of the pressure wave is associated with a sharp wetting front, resulting in higher water content compared to Darcy‐type continuous flow. The findings suggest that pressure waves have the potential to achieve high water content in unsaturated media and provide insights into the spatial extent of their impact on water distribution.</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;The wetting front dynamics during water imbibition in dry porous media affect the ultimate water distribution pattern. In this study, we investigate the impact of pressure pulses that emit waves in the water phase on the water distribution and imbibition patterns in porous media. We present experimental results of water spatial distribution in sand columns following infiltration under abrupt pressured-water pulses and compare them with those of continuous inflow. Applying pressure waves during infiltration increases pressure gradients behind the wetting front, which can overcome capillary and gravitational forces, leading to uniform imbibition. To simulate the process, we developed a pore-network model incorporating an analytical solution of pressure wave attenuation to predict the imbibition pattern. Our results demonstrate that the amplitude of the pressure wave is associated with a sharp wetting front, resulting in higher water content compared to Darcy-type continuous flow. The findings suggest that pressure waves have the potential to achieve high water content in unsaturated media and provide insights into the spatial extent of their impact on water distribution.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> Doron Kalisman, Alexander Yakirevich, Shaul Sorek, Tamir Kamai</dc:creator><category> Research Article</category><dc:title> Impact of Pressure Waves on Water Imbibition and Flow in Unsaturated Porous Media</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2023WR034461</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1029/2023WR034461</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2023WR034461?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> Research Article</prism:section><prism:volume> 59</prism:volume><prism:number> 9</prism:number></item><item><link/> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR031970?af=R<pubDate> Wed, 13 Sep 2023 12:24:21 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-09-13T12:24:21-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley: Water Resources Research: Table of Contents<prism:coverdate> Fri, 01 Sep 2023 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate> Fri, 01 Sep 2023 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR031970</guid><title> Five Centuries of Groundwater Elevations Provide Evidence of Shifting Climate Drivers and Human Influences on Water Resources in North Central Florida</title><description> Water Resources Research, Volume 59, Issue 9, September 2023.</description><dc:description> Abstract Groundwater depletion is a concern around the world with implications for food security, ecological resilience, and human conflict. Long‐term perspectives provided by tree ring‐based reconstructions can improve understanding of factors driving variability in groundwater elevations, but such reconstructions are rare to date. Here, we report a set of new 546‐year tree‐ring chronologies developed from living and remnant longleaf pine (Pinus palustris) trees that, when combined with existing bald cypress (Taxodium distichum) tree‐ring chronologies, create a set of nested reconstructions of mean annual groundwater elevation for North Central Florida that together explain 66% of the variance in instrumental measurements and span 1498–2015. Split calibration confirms the skill of the reconstructions, but coefficient of efficiency metrics and significant autocorrelation in the regression residuals indicate a weakening relationship between tree growth and groundwater elevation over recent decades. Comparison to data from nearby groundwater wells suggests extraction of groundwater is likely contributing to this weakening signal. Periodicity within the reconstruction and comparison with global sea surface temperatures (SST) highlight the role of El Niño‐Southern Oscillation (ENSO) in driving groundwater elevations, but the strength of this role varies substantially over time. Atlantic and Pacific SST modulate ENSO influences, and comparisons to multiple proxy‐based reconstructions indicate an inconsistent and weaker influence of ENSO prior to the 1800s. Our results highlight the dynamic influence of ocean‐atmospheric phenomena on groundwater resources in North Central Florida and build on instrumental records to better depict the long‐term range of groundwater elevations.</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;Groundwater depletion is a concern around the world with implications for food security, ecological resilience, and human conflict. Long-term perspectives provided by tree ring-based reconstructions can improve understanding of factors driving variability in groundwater elevations, but such reconstructions are rare to date. Here, we report a set of new 546-year tree-ring chronologies developed from living and remnant longleaf pine (&lt;i>;Pinus palustris&lt;/i>;) trees that, when combined with existing bald cypress (&lt;i>;Taxodium distichum&lt;/i>;) tree-ring chronologies, create a set of nested reconstructions of mean annual groundwater elevation for North Central Florida that together explain 66% of the variance in instrumental measurements and span 1498–2015. Split calibration confirms the skill of the reconstructions, but coefficient of efficiency metrics and significant autocorrelation in the regression residuals indicate a weakening relationship between tree growth and groundwater elevation over recent decades. Comparison to data from nearby groundwater wells suggests extraction of groundwater is likely contributing to this weakening signal. Periodicity within the reconstruction and comparison with global sea surface temperatures (SST) highlight the role of El Niño-Southern Oscillation (ENSO) in driving groundwater elevations, but the strength of this role varies substantially over time. Atlantic and Pacific SST modulate ENSO influences, and comparisons to multiple proxy-based reconstructions indicate an inconsistent and weaker influence of ENSO prior to the 1800s. Our results highlight the dynamic influence of ocean-atmospheric phenomena on groundwater resources in North Central Florida and build on instrumental records to better depict the long-term range of groundwater elevations.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> Evan R. Larson, Tom Mirti, Thomas Wilding, Chris A. Underwood</dc:creator><category> Research Article</category><dc:title> Five Centuries of Groundwater Elevations Provide Evidence of Shifting Climate Drivers and Human Influences on Water Resources in North Central Florida</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2022WR031970</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1029/2022WR031970</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR031970?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> Research Article</prism:section><prism:volume> 59</prism:volume><prism:number> 9</prism:number></item><item><link/> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR034127?af=R<pubDate> Wed, 13 Sep 2023 05:45:23 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-09-13T05:45:23-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley: Water Resources Research: Table of Contents <prism:coverdate></prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate></prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR034127</guid><title> Comparing field, probabilistic, and 2D numerical approaches to assess gravel mobility in a gravel‐bed river</title><description> Water Resources Research, Accepted Article.</description><dc:description> Abstract Sediment transport is a key process that affects the morphology and ecological habitat diversity of rivers. As part of a gravel augmentation program to mitigate sediment deficit below a dam, gravel mobility in the Ain River in Eastern France was investigated by tracking of a large amount (n = 1063) of PIT‐tagged gravels in the field, conducting a probabilistic approach based on published tracer studies, and performing two‐dimensional (2D) numerical modeling of flow and bedload transport. This comparative study highlights the strengths, weaknesses, and complementary aspects of the three approaches to the understanding of river gravel mobility. Thanks to recent technological improvements, PIT‐tagged gravels provide an increasingly reliable and accurate representation of bedload movement in the field, although it remains limited in spatio‐temporal resolution. Based on an exponential distribution, the probabilistic approach correctly reproduces the average trend in travel distances by the different classes of particles over hydrological periods, including one or several significant floods. Furthermore, the 2D numerical modeling accounts for the variability of local hydrodynamic conditions and can simulate realistic displacement distributions for the different classes of particles with high spatio‐temporal resolution. Numerical modeling is a very encouraging approach, which makes our study original because it is the first time that the estimation of mean travel distances, the application of an exponential distribution, and the comparison with a hydrodynamic model are combined. A more effective modeling strategy involves incorporating a probabilistic transport model in the 2D numerical model to reproduce the observed scatter of the individual particle trajectories. This article is protected by copyright.版权所有。</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;Sediment transport is a key process that affects the morphology and ecological habitat diversity of rivers. As part of a gravel augmentation program to mitigate sediment deficit below a dam, gravel mobility in the Ain River in Eastern France was investigated by tracking of a large amount (&lt;i>;n&lt;/i>; = 1063) of PIT-tagged gravels in the field, conducting a probabilistic approach based on published tracer studies, and performing two-dimensional (2D) numerical modeling of flow and bedload transport. This comparative study highlights the strengths, weaknesses, and complementary aspects of the three approaches to the understanding of river gravel mobility. Thanks to recent technological improvements, PIT-tagged gravels provide an increasingly reliable and accurate representation of bedload movement in the field, although it remains limited in spatio-temporal resolution. Based on an exponential distribution, the probabilistic approach correctly reproduces the average trend in travel distances by the different classes of particles over hydrological periods, including one or several significant floods. Furthermore, the 2D numerical modeling accounts for the variability of local hydrodynamic conditions and can simulate realistic displacement distributions for the different classes of particles with high spatio-temporal resolution. Numerical modeling is a very encouraging approach, which makes our study original because it is the first time that the estimation of mean travel distances, the application of an exponential distribution, and the comparison with a hydrodynamic model are combined. A more effective modeling strategy involves incorporating a probabilistic transport model in the 2D numerical model to reproduce the observed scatter of the individual particle trajectories.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This article is protected by copyright. All rights reserved.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> F. Arnaud, A. Paquier, D. Vázquez‐Tarrío, B. Camenen, J. Le Coz, K. Michel, G. Naudet, H. Pella, H. Piégay</dc:creator><category> Research Article</category><dc:title> Comparing field, probabilistic, and 2D numerical approaches to assess gravel mobility in a gravel‐bed river</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2022WR034127</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1029/2022WR034127</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR034127?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> Research Article</prism:section></item><item><link/> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2023WR034792?af=R<pubDate> Tue, 12 Sep 2023 13:19:02 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-09-12T01:19:02-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley: Water Resources Research: Table of Contents <prism:coverdate></prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate></prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2023WR034792</guid><title> Kaolinite Deposition Dynamics and Streambed Clogging During Bedform Migration under Losing and Gaining Flow Conditions</title><description> Water Resources Research, Accepted Article.</description><dc:description> Abstract Clogging of streambeds due to clay deposition influences the stream‐subsurface exchange flux and thus directly modulates hyporheic ecological and biogeochemical processes. Clogging of sandy streambeds has previously been studied under losing and gaining flows and during streambed movement, but not when these two flow conditions coincided. We conducted flume experiments to quantify the combined effect of moving bedforms and losing or gaining flows on kaolinite deposition and streambed clogging. The experiments were conducted by adding pulses of kaolinite in a flume packed with sand under a streamwater velocity of 25 cm/s. We measured the deposition rates, dynamics of hyporheic exchange flux (HEF) and vertical hydraulic conductivity (Kv), and the vertical distribution of kaolinite at the end of the experiments under two losing and two gaining flows (Darcy velocity of 10 and 20 cm/day). Kaolinite deposition led to clogging and reduction in Kv and HEF under all flow conditions. Deposition occurred faster under losing flow conditions than under gaining flow conditions. However, the changes in Kv and HEF were similar under losing and gaining flow conditions for similar kaolinite concentrations in the bed. Our results indicate that the deposition patterns of kaolinite were more influenced by bedform movement than by losing or gaining flow conditions, which is markedly different from the behavior observed under losing and gaining conditions for stationary bedforms. This implies that bedform morphodynamics control local‐scale clogging of sandy streambeds and should be accounted for when studying the hydrology of catchments at larger scales. This article is protected by copyright.版权所有。</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;Clogging of streambeds due to clay deposition influences the stream-subsurface exchange flux and thus directly modulates hyporheic ecological and biogeochemical processes. Clogging of sandy streambeds has previously been studied under losing and gaining flows and during streambed movement, but not when these two flow conditions coincided. We conducted flume experiments to quantify the combined effect of moving bedforms and losing or gaining flows on kaolinite deposition and streambed clogging. The experiments were conducted by adding pulses of kaolinite in a flume packed with sand under a streamwater velocity of 25 cm/s. We measured the deposition rates, dynamics of hyporheic exchange flux (HEF) and vertical hydraulic conductivity (&lt;i>;K&lt;/i>; &lt;sub>; &lt;i>;v&lt;/i>; &lt;/sub>;), and the vertical distribution of kaolinite at the end of the experiments under two losing and two gaining flows (Darcy velocity of 10 and 20 cm/day). Kaolinite deposition led to clogging and reduction in &lt;i>;K&lt;/i>; &lt;sub>; &lt;i>;v&lt;/i>; &lt;/sub>; and HEF under all flow conditions. Deposition occurred faster under losing flow conditions than under gaining flow conditions. However, the changes in &lt;i>;K&lt;/i>; &lt;sub>; &lt;i>;v&lt;/i>; &lt;/sub>; and HEF were similar under losing and gaining flow conditions for similar kaolinite concentrations in the bed. Our results indicate that the deposition patterns of kaolinite were more influenced by bedform movement than by losing or gaining flow conditions, which is markedly different from the behavior observed under losing and gaining conditions for stationary bedforms. This implies that bedform morphodynamics control local-scale clogging of sandy streambeds and should be accounted for when studying the hydrology of catchments at larger scales.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This article is protected by copyright. All rights reserved.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> T. Shimony, Y. Teitelbaum, E. Saavedra Cifuentes, J. Dallmann, CB Phillips, AI Packman, S. Arnon</dc:creator><category> Research Article</category><dc:title> Kaolinite Deposition Dynamics and Streambed Clogging During Bedform Migration under Losing and Gaining Flow Conditions</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2023WR034792</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1029/2023WR034792</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2023WR034792?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> Research Article</prism:section></item><item><link/> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR034321?af=R<pubDate> Tue, 12 Sep 2023 13:12:53 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-09-12T01:12:53-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley: Water Resources Research: Table of Contents <prism:coverdate></prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate></prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR034321</guid><title> Storage, transport, and fate of perfluoroalkyl acids (PFAAs) in a wastewater re‐use and groundwater recharge system</title><description> Water Resources Research, Accepted Article.</description><dc:description> Abstract Perfluoroalkyl acids (PFAAs), a group of synthetic compounds associated with adverse human health impacts, are commonly found in effluent discharged from wastewater treatment facilities. When that effluent is used for irrigation, the fate of PFAAs depends strongly on soil PFAA retention properties and effluent PFAA loading history. The relative importance of PFAA retention factors under natural field‐scale conditions remains uncertain, and the historical record of effluent PFAA concentrations is limited. Using soil cores collected from the Penn State Living Filter (irrigated with treated wastewater effluent for nearly 60 years), we evaluated PFAA mass‐balance in the irrigated soils and estimated historical effluent PFAA concentrations. Total accumulated perfluorooctanesulfonic acid (PFOS) and perfluorooctanoic acid (PFOA) masses measured in soils in 2014 were more than 450 times greater than annual mass loads applied during the 2020 effluent irrigation. Column mass‐balance models reproduced the observed PFOS and PFOA profiles, providing an estimate of historical effluent PFOS and PFOA concentrations: 70‐170 ng L‐1 and 1000‐1300 ng L‐1, respectively. Estimated concentrations were comparable to measurements in other wastewater effluents in the 1990s and 2000s, indicating that wastewater‐irrigated soils can serve as integrated records of historical PFAA loading to the environment. Mass balance calculations suggest that PFOS breakthrough to groundwater occurred 50 years after the start of wastewater irrigation, whereas simulated PFOA breakthrough occurred after only 10 years of irrigation. While wastewater irrigation of soils facilitates retention and reduces effluent PFAA loading to surface waters, resulting PFAA storage in soils potentially creates long‐term sources of PFAAs to groundwater. This article is protected by copyright.版权所有。</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;Perfluoroalkyl acids (PFAAs), a group of synthetic compounds associated with adverse human health impacts, are commonly found in effluent discharged from wastewater treatment facilities. When that effluent is used for irrigation, the fate of PFAAs depends strongly on soil PFAA retention properties and effluent PFAA loading history. The relative importance of PFAA retention factors under natural field-scale conditions remains uncertain, and the historical record of effluent PFAA concentrations is limited. Using soil cores collected from the Penn State Living Filter (irrigated with treated wastewater effluent for nearly 60 years), we evaluated PFAA mass-balance in the irrigated soils and estimated historical effluent PFAA concentrations. Total accumulated perfluorooctanesulfonic acid (PFOS) and perfluorooctanoic acid (PFOA) masses measured in soils in 2014 were more than 450 times greater than annual mass loads applied during the 2020 effluent irrigation. Column mass-balance models reproduced the observed PFOS and PFOA profiles, providing an estimate of historical effluent PFOS and PFOA concentrations: 70-170 ng L&lt;sup>;-1&lt;/sup>; and 1000-1300 ng L&lt;sup>;-1&lt;/sup>;, respectively. Estimated concentrations were comparable to measurements in other wastewater effluents in the 1990s and 2000s, indicating that wastewater-irrigated soils can serve as integrated records of historical PFAA loading to the environment. Mass balance calculations suggest that PFOS breakthrough to groundwater occurred 50 years after the start of wastewater irrigation, whereas simulated PFOA breakthrough occurred after only 10 years of irrigation. While wastewater irrigation of soils facilitates retention and reduces effluent PFAA loading to surface waters, resulting PFAA storage in soils potentially creates long-term sources of PFAAs to groundwater.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This article is protected by copyright. All rights reserved.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> Kalle L. Jahn, Demian M. Saffer, Katherine H. Freeman, Sara A. Lincoln</dc:creator><category> Research Article</category><dc:title> Storage, transport, and fate of perfluoroalkyl acids (PFAAs) in a wastewater re‐use and groundwater recharge system</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2022WR034321</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1029/2022WR034321</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR034321?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> Research Article</prism:section></item><item><link/> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2023WR034890?af=R<pubDate> Tue, 12 Sep 2023 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-09-12T12:00:00-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley: Water Resources Research: Table of Contents <prism:coverdate></prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate></prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2023WR034890</guid><title> Generalizing Reservoir Operations using a Piecewise Classification and Regression Approach</title><description> Water Resources Research, Accepted Article.</description><dc:description> Abstract Inflow anomalies at varying temporal scales, seasonally varying storage mandates, and multi‐purpose allocation requirements contribute to reservoir operational decisions. The difficulty of capturing these constraints across many basins in a generalized framework has limited the accuracy of streamflow estimates in Land Surface Models for locations downstream of reservoirs. We develop a Piece Wise Linear Regression Tree to learn generalized daily operating policies from 76 reservoirs from four major basins across the coterminous US. Reservoir characteristics, such as residence time and maximum storage, and daily state variables, such as storage and inflow, are used to group similar observations across all reservoirs. Linear regression equations are then fit between daily state variables and release for each group. We recommend two models – Model 1 (M1) that performs the best when simulating untrained records but is complex, and Model 2 (M2) that is nearly as performant as M1 but more parsimonious. The simulated release median root mean squared error is 49.7% (53.2%) of mean daily release with a median Nash‐Sutcliffe Efficiency of 0.62 (0.52) for M1 (M2). Long‐term residence time is shown to be useful in grouping similar operating reservoirs. Release from low residence time reservoirs can be mostly described using inflow‐based variables. Operations at higher residence time reservoirs are more related to previous release variables or storage variables, depending on the current inflow. The ability of the models presented to capture operational dynamics of many types of reservoirs indicates their potential to be used for untrained and limited data reservoirs.</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;Inflow anomalies at varying temporal scales, seasonally varying storage mandates, and multi-purpose allocation requirements contribute to reservoir operational decisions. The difficulty of capturing these constraints across many basins in a generalized framework has limited the accuracy of streamflow estimates in Land Surface Models for locations downstream of reservoirs. We develop a Piece Wise Linear Regression Tree to learn generalized daily operating policies from 76 reservoirs from four major basins across the coterminous US. Reservoir characteristics, such as residence time and maximum storage, and daily state variables, such as storage and inflow, are used to group similar observations across all reservoirs. Linear regression equations are then fit between daily state variables and release for each group. We recommend two models – Model 1 (M1) that performs the best when simulating untrained records but is complex, and Model 2 (M2) that is nearly as performant as M1 but more parsimonious. The simulated release median root mean squared error is 49.7% (53.2%) of mean daily release with a median Nash-Sutcliffe Efficiency of 0.62 (0.52) for M1 (M2). Long-term residence time is shown to be useful in grouping similar operating reservoirs. Release from low residence time reservoirs can be mostly described using inflow-based variables. Operations at higher residence time reservoirs are more related to previous release variables or storage variables, depending on the current inflow. The ability of the models presented to capture operational dynamics of many types of reservoirs indicates their potential to be used for untrained and limited data reservoirs.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> Lucas Ford, A. Sankarasubramanian</dc:creator><category> Research Article</category><dc:title> Generalizing Reservoir Operations using a Piecewise Classification and Regression Approach</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2023WR034890</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1029/2023WR034890</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2023WR034890?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> Research Article</prism:section></item><item><link/> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033531?af=R<pubDate> Mon, 11 Sep 2023 07:45:19 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-09-11T07:45:19-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley: Water Resources Research: Table of Contents<prism:coverdate> Fri, 01 Sep 2023 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate> Fri, 01 Sep 2023 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR033531</guid><title> Characterizing the Importance of Porosity of Large Woody Debris Accumulations at Single Bridge Piers on Localized Scour</title><description> Water Resources Research, Volume 59, Issue 9, September 2023.</description><dc:description> Abstract The accumulation of large woody debris (LWD) at bridge piers is a serious hazard to the structural integrity of bridges across watercourses worldwide. The exacerbated scour that can directly result from LWD accumulations can lead to major structural damage or even catastrophic collapse. Recent research has led to empirical equations to estimate the scour depth for given LWD accumulation size; however these are mostly based on experimental tests with prismatic and impervious solid LWD accumulations, ignoring field observations that have shown that accumulations are neither impervious nor prismatic but are porous with inverted conical shapes. In this study, we therefore investigate the effects of porous LWD accumulations having shapes commonly observed in the field on scour holes. Results reveal that LWD size and shape, and flow characteristics are the primary factors influencing the erosion of sediments at the base of bridge piers. However, the porosity of accumulations is also observed to have a considerable effect on the size and maximum depth of scour holes. In particular, porous LWD reduce the maximum scour depth by up to 50% (and on average in the range of 5%–25%) relative to the respective solid impervious accumulation. The results shown in this study also provide a practical tool for arriving at more realistic and less conservative estimates of scour depths at bridge piers when affected by LWD accumulations.</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;The accumulation of large woody debris (LWD) at bridge piers is a serious hazard to the structural integrity of bridges across watercourses worldwide. The exacerbated scour that can directly result from LWD accumulations can lead to major structural damage or even catastrophic collapse. Recent research has led to empirical equations to estimate the scour depth for given LWD accumulation size; however these are mostly based on experimental tests with prismatic and impervious solid LWD accumulations, ignoring field observations that have shown that accumulations are neither impervious nor prismatic but are porous with inverted conical shapes. In this study, we therefore investigate the effects of porous LWD accumulations having shapes commonly observed in the field on scour holes. Results reveal that LWD size and shape, and flow characteristics are the primary factors influencing the erosion of sediments at the base of bridge piers. However, the porosity of accumulations is also observed to have a considerable effect on the size and maximum depth of scour holes. In particular, porous LWD reduce the maximum scour depth by up to 50% (and on average in the range of 5%–25%) relative to the respective solid impervious accumulation. The results shown in this study also provide a practical tool for arriving at more realistic and less conservative estimates of scour depths at bridge piers when affected by LWD accumulations.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> D. Panici, P. Kripakaran</dc:creator><category> Research Article</category><dc:title> Characterizing the Importance of Porosity of Large Woody Debris Accumulations at Single Bridge Piers on Localized Scour</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2022WR033531</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1029/2022WR033531</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033531?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> Research Article</prism:section><prism:volume> 59</prism:volume><prism:number> 9</prism:number></item><item><link/> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2023WR035164?af=R<pubDate> Mon, 11 Sep 2023 07:45:15 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-09-11T07:45:15-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley: Water Resources Research: Table of Contents<prism:coverdate> Fri, 01 Sep 2023 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate> Fri, 01 Sep 2023 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2023WR035164</guid><title> SatVITS‐Flood: Satellite Vegetation Index Time Series Flood Detection Model for Hyperarid Regions</title><description> Water Resources Research, Volume 59, Issue 9, September 2023.</description><dc:description> Abstract We present the satellite vegetation index time series model for detecting historical floods in ungauged hyperarid regions (SatVITS‐Flood). SatVITS‐Flood is based on observations that floods are the primary cause of local vegetation expansion in hyperarid regions. To detect such expansion, we used two time‐series metrics: (a) trend change detection from the Breaks For Additive Season and Trend and (b) a newly developed seasonal change metric based on Temporal Fourier Analysis (TFA) and the growing‐season integral anomaly (TFA‐GSIanom). The two metrics complement each other by capturing changes in perennial plant species following extreme, rare floods and ephemeral vegetation changes following more frequent floods. Metrics were derived from the time series of the normalized difference vegetation index, the modified soil‐adjusted vegetation index, and the normalized difference water index, acquired from MODIS, Landsat, and Advanced Very High‐Resolution Radiometer. The timing of the change was compared with the date of the flood and the magnitude of change with its volume and duration. We tested SatVITS‐Flood in three regions on different continents with 40‐year‐long, systematic, reliable gauge data. Our results indicate that SatVITS‐Flood can predict flood occurrence with an accuracy of 78% and precision of 67% (Recall = 0.69 and F1 = 0.68; p &lt; 0.01), and the flood volume and duration with NSE of 0.79 (RMSE = 15.4 × 106 m3 event−1), and R2 of 0.69 (RMSE = 5.7 days), respectively. SatVITS‐Flood proved useful for detecting historical floods and may provide valuable long‐term hydrological information in poorly documented areas, which can help understand the impacts of climate change on the hydrology of hyperarid regions.</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;We present the satellite vegetation index time series model for detecting historical floods in ungauged hyperarid regions (SatVITS-Flood). SatVITS-Flood is based on observations that floods are the primary cause of local vegetation expansion in hyperarid regions. To detect such expansion, we used two time-series metrics: (a) trend change detection from the Breaks For Additive Season and Trend and (b) a newly developed seasonal change metric based on Temporal Fourier Analysis (TFA) and the growing-season integral anomaly (TFA-GSI&lt;sub>;anom&lt;/sub>;). The two metrics complement each other by capturing changes in perennial plant species following extreme, rare floods and ephemeral vegetation changes following more frequent floods. Metrics were derived from the time series of the normalized difference vegetation index, the modified soil-adjusted vegetation index, and the normalized difference water index, acquired from MODIS, Landsat, and Advanced Very High-Resolution Radiometer. The timing of the change was compared with the date of the flood and the magnitude of change with its volume and duration. We tested SatVITS-Flood in three regions on different continents with 40-year-long, systematic, reliable gauge data. Our results indicate that SatVITS-Flood can predict flood occurrence with an accuracy of 78% and precision of 67% (Recall = 0.69 and F1 = 0.68; &lt;i>;p&lt;/i>; &amp;lt; 0.01), and the flood volume and duration with NSE of 0.79 (RMSE = 15.4 × 10&lt;sup>;6&lt;/sup>; m&lt;sup>;3&lt;/sup>; event&lt;sup>;−1&lt;/sup>;), and &lt;i>;R&lt;/i>; &lt;sup>;2&lt;/sup>; of 0.69 (RMSE = 5.7 days), respectively. SatVITS-Flood proved useful for detecting historical floods and may provide valuable long-term hydrological information in poorly documented areas, which can help understand the impacts of climate change on the hydrology of hyperarid regions.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> Omer Burstein, Tamir Grodek, Yehouda Enzel, David Helman</dc:creator><category> Research Article</category><dc:title> SatVITS‐Flood: Satellite Vegetation Index Time Series Flood Detection Model for Hyperarid Regions</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2023WR035164</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1029/2023WR035164</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2023WR035164?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> Research Article</prism:section><prism:volume> 59</prism:volume><prism:number> 9</prism:number></item><item><link/> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR034004?af=R<pubDate> Mon, 11 Sep 2023 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-09-11T12:00:00-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley: Water Resources Research: Table of Contents <prism:coverdate></prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate></prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR034004</guid><title> Carbon Biogeochemistry and Export Governed by Flow in a Non‐Perennial Stream</title><description> Water Resources Research, Accepted Article.</description><dc:description> Abstract Non‐perennial headwaters experience extremes in flow conditions that likely influence carbon fate. As surface waters contract through dry periods, reconnect during storms, and re‐expand or dry again, there is a great deal of variability in carbon emissions and export. We measured discharge, dissolved oxygen (DO), carbon dioxide (CO2), and dissolved organic carbon (DOC) continuously in a persistent pool at the base of a non‐perennial, forested headwater stream in the southeastern United States to characterize how flow changes affect carbon emissions and export as the stream expands and shrinks. We also compared carbon concentrations and export during different stream flow categories before and after fall wet‐up. CO2 concentrations were high when discharge was lowest (median = 10.2 mg L‐1) and low during high flows (3.2 mg L‐1) and storms (1.1 mg L‐1). High CO2 concentrations led to high emissions on a per area basis during low flow times, but whole‐channel stream CO2 emissions were limited by the small surface area of the stream during periods of surface water disconnection. DOC concentration varied by season (range = 0.1 ‐ 16.2 mg L‐1) with large pulses during smaller summer storms. We found that CO2 and DOC concentrations differed among binned stages of stream flow. As non‐perennial streams become more prevalent across the southeastern United States due to shifts in climate, the relationships between flow and carbon movement into and out of stream networks will become increasingly critical to understanding stream carbon biogeochemistry.</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;Non-perennial headwaters experience extremes in flow conditions that likely influence carbon fate. As surface waters contract through dry periods, reconnect during storms, and re-expand or dry again, there is a great deal of variability in carbon emissions and export. We measured discharge, dissolved oxygen (DO), carbon dioxide (CO&lt;sub>;2&lt;/sub>;), and dissolved organic carbon (DOC) continuously in a persistent pool at the base of a non-perennial, forested headwater stream in the southeastern United States to characterize how flow changes affect carbon emissions and export as the stream expands and shrinks. We also compared carbon concentrations and export during different stream flow categories before and after fall wet-up. CO&lt;sub>;2&lt;/sub>; concentrations were high when discharge was lowest (median = 10.2 mg L&lt;sup>;-1&lt;/sup>;) and low during high flows (3.2 mg L&lt;sup>;-1&lt;/sup>;) and storms (1.1 mg L&lt;sup>;-1&lt;/sup>;). High CO2 concentrations led to high emissions on a per area basis during low flow times, but whole-channel stream CO&lt;sub>;2&lt;/sub>; emissions were limited by the small surface area of the stream during periods of surface water disconnection. DOC concentration varied by season (range = 0.1 - 16.2 mg L&lt;sup>;-1&lt;/sup>;) with large pulses during smaller summer storms. We found that CO&lt;sub>;2&lt;/sub>; and DOC concentrations differed among binned stages of stream flow. As non-perennial streams become more prevalent across the southeastern United States due to shifts in climate, the relationships between flow and carbon movement into and out of stream networks will become increasingly critical to understanding stream carbon biogeochemistry.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> Kristen A. Bretz, Natalie N. Murphy, Erin R. Hotchkiss</dc:creator><category> Research Article</category><dc:title> Carbon Biogeochemistry and Export Governed by Flow in a Non‐Perennial Stream</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2022WR034004</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1029/2022WR034004</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR034004?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> Research Article</prism:section></item><item><link/> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2023WR035044?af=R<pubDate> Fri, 08 Sep 2023 20:14:48 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-09-08T08:14:48-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley: Water Resources Research: Table of Contents <prism:coverdate></prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate></prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2023WR035044</guid><title> Local topography and streambed hydraulic conductivity influence riparian groundwater age and groundwater‐surface water connection</title><description> Water Resources Research, Accepted Article.</description><dc:description> Abstract The western US is experiencing increasing rain to snow ratios due to climate change, and scientists are uncertain how changing recharge patterns will affect future groundwater‐surface water connection. We examined how watershed topography and streambed hydraulic conductivity impact groundwater age and stream discharge at eight sites along a headwater stream within the Manitou Experimental Forest, CO USA. To do so, we measured: 1) continuous stream and groundwater discharge/level and specific conductivity from April to November, 2021; 2) biweekly stream and groundwater chemistry; 3) groundwater chlorofluorocarbons and tritium in spring and fall; 4) streambed hydraulic conductivity; and 5) local slope. We used the chemistry data to calculate fluorite saturation states that were used to inform end‐member mixing analysis of streamflow source. We then combined chlorofluorocarbon and tritium data to estimate the age composition of riparian groundwater. Our data suggest that future stream drying is more probable where local slope is steep and streambed hydraulic conductivity is high. In these areas, groundwater source shifted seasonally, as indicated by age increases, and we observed a high fraction of groundwater in streamflow, primarily interflow from adjacent hillslopes. In contrast, where local slope is flat and streambed hydraulic conductivity is low, streamflow is more likely to persist as groundwater age was seasonally constant and buffered by storage in alluvial sediments. Groundwater age and streamflow paired with characterization of watershed topography and subsurface characteristics enabled identification of likely controls on future stream drying patterns.</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;The western US is experiencing increasing rain to snow ratios due to climate change, and scientists are uncertain how changing recharge patterns will affect future groundwater-surface water connection. We examined how watershed topography and streambed hydraulic conductivity impact groundwater age and stream discharge at eight sites along a headwater stream within the Manitou Experimental Forest, CO USA. To do so, we measured: 1) continuous stream and groundwater discharge/level and specific conductivity from April to November, 2021; 2) biweekly stream and groundwater chemistry; 3) groundwater chlorofluorocarbons and tritium in spring and fall; 4) streambed hydraulic conductivity; and 5) local slope. We used the chemistry data to calculate fluorite saturation states that were used to inform end-member mixing analysis of streamflow source. We then combined chlorofluorocarbon and tritium data to estimate the age composition of riparian groundwater. Our data suggest that future stream drying is more probable where local slope is steep and streambed hydraulic conductivity is high. In these areas, groundwater source shifted seasonally, as indicated by age increases, and we observed a high fraction of groundwater in streamflow, primarily interflow from adjacent hillslopes. In contrast, where local slope is flat and streambed hydraulic conductivity is low, streamflow is more likely to persist as groundwater age was seasonally constant and buffered by storage in alluvial sediments. Groundwater age and streamflow paired with characterization of watershed topography and subsurface characteristics enabled identification of likely controls on future stream drying patterns.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> SR Warix, A. Navarre‐Sitchler, AH Manning, K. Singha</dc:creator><category> Research Article</category><dc:title> Local topography and streambed hydraulic conductivity influence riparian groundwater age and groundwater‐surface water connection</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2023WR035044</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1029/2023WR035044</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2023WR035044?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> Research Article</prism:section></item></channel></rss>