<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:prism="http://prismstandard.org/namespaces/basic/2.0/"><channel><title> Wiley：水资源研究：目录</title><link/>https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R<description>水资源研究目录。最新和 EarlyView 问题的文章列表。</description><language>英文</language><copyright></copyright><managingeditor>wileyonlinelibrary@wiley.com（AGU 出版物）</managingeditor><pubDate> Thu, 23 Feb 2023 08:29:08 +0000</pubDate><lastbuilddate> 2023 年 2 月 23 日星期四 08:29:08 +0000</lastbuilddate><generator> Atypon®文学™</generator><docs> https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs><ttl> 10080</ttl><dc:title> Wiley：水资源研究：目录</dc:title><dc:publisher>威利</dc:publisher><prism:publicationname>水资源研究</prism:publicationname><atom:link href="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"></atom:link><image/><title> Wiley：水资源研究：目录</title><url>https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/pb-assets/journal-banners/19447973.jpg</url><link/> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R<item><link/> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033091?af=R<pubDate> Wed, 22 Feb 2023 22:11:18 -0800</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-02-22T10:11:18-08:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley：水资源研究：目录<prism:coverdate></prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate></prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR033091</guid><title>使用机器学习通过编码器-解码器框架识别水文特征</title><description>水资源研究，接受的文章。</description><dc:description>摘要 水文特征是描述水流时间序列的定量指标。示例包括年度最大流量、基流指数和衰退形状描述符。在本文中，我们使用机器学习 (ML) 来学习编码，这些编码是水文特征的最佳 ML 等价物，并且直接从数据中导出。我们将学习到的特征与经典特征进行比较，解释它们的含义，并使用它们在其他未测量的流域中建立降雨径流模型。我们的模型具有编码器-解码器结构。编码器是一个卷积神经网络，将历史流量和气候数据映射到低维矢量编码，类似于水文特征。解码器结构包括类似于经典水文模型的存储和通量。对于每个时间步长，解码器使用当前气候数据、分水岭属性和编码来预测在商店之间分配降水的系数和商店流出系数。该模型在美国 CAMELS 流域数据集上进行端到端训练，以最大限度地减少流量误差。我们表明学习签名可以从流系列中提取新信息，因为使用学习签名作为过程通知模型的输入可以提高使用经典签名或不使用签名的基准配置的预测准确性。我们通过与经典签名的相关性来解释学习的签名，并通过使用敏感性分析来评估它们对建模商店动态的影响。学习到的特征在空间上是相关的，并且与流量动态相关，包括季节性、高低极端、基流和衰退。我们得出结论，使用水文特征的过程通知 ML 模型和其他应用程序可能会受益于用学习的特征替换专家选择的特征。本文受版权保护。版权所有。</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;摘要&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;水文特征是描述流量时间序列的定量指标。示例包括年度最大流量、基流指数和衰退形状描述符。在本文中，我们使用机器学习 (ML) 来学习编码，这些编码是水文特征的最佳 ML 等价物，并且直接从数据中导出。我们将学习到的特征与经典特征进行比较，解释它们的含义，并使用它们在其他未测量的流域中建立降雨径流模型。我们的模型具有编码器-解码器结构。编码器是一个卷积神经网络，将历史流量和气候数据映射到低维矢量编码，类似于水文特征。解码器结构包括类似于经典水文模型的存储和通量。对于每个时间步长，解码器使用当前气候数据、分水岭属性和编码来预测在商店之间分配降水的系数和商店流出系数。该模型在美国 CAMELS 流域数据集上进行了端到端训练，以最大限度地减少流量误差。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我们证明学习的签名可以从流量系列中提取新信息，因为使用学习的签名作为过程的输入-知情模型提高了使用经典签名或不使用签名的基准配置的预测准确性。我们通过与经典签名的相关性来解释学习的签名，并通过使用敏感性分析来评估它们对建模商店动态的影响。学习到的特征在空间上是相关的，并且与流量动态相关，包括季节性、高低极端、基流和衰退。我们得出结论，使用水文签名的过程通知 ML 模型和其他应用程序可能会受益于用学习的签名替换专家选择的签名。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;本文受版权保护。保留所有权利。&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator>汤姆·E·博特里尔、希拉里·K·麦克米伦</dc:creator><category>研究文章</category><dc:title>使用机器学习通过编码器-解码器框架识别水文特征</dc:title><dc:identifier>10.1029/2022WR033091</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname>水资源研究</prism:publicationname><prism:doi>10.1029/2022WR033091</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033091?af=R</prism:url><prism:section>研究文章</prism:section></item><item><link/>https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033026?af=R<pubDate> Wed, 22 Feb 2023 14:48:27 -0800</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-02-22T02:48:27-08:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley：水资源研究：目录<prism:coverdate></prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate></prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR033026</guid><title>改进未监测盆地水库运行的参数化：耦合卫星遥感、水文建模和概念运行方案的协同框架</title><description>水资源研究，接受的文章。</description><dc:description>摘要 历史和未来时期的区域水和能源安全评估需要能够准确模拟水库运行的水文模型。然而，稀缺的水库运行数据限制了当前水库表示在模拟水库行为时的准确性。此外，这些表示在不断变化的流入状态下的可靠性仍不清楚，这使得它们在长期未来规划视野中的应用值得怀疑。为此，我们提出了一个协同框架，通过结合遥感水库运行模式和模型模拟水库流入量来预测未监测水库（即没有原位流入、释放、存储数据的水库）的释放、存储和水电生产在地表水文模型中使用概念性水库运行方案。先前开发的水库运行方案扩展了基于存储异常的校准方法，以适应遥感数据相对较短的时间序列和较大的时间间隔。通过在中国雅砻江流域进行对照实验，我们表明遥感可以改进所有选定水库运行方案的未计量水库的参数估计和模拟，从而改进下游洪水和径流模拟。然而，这些方案中的大多数都表明，在不断变化的入流状态下，水库运行模拟的准确性有所下降，这可能导致对未来水资源和水电生产的评估不可靠。相比之下，我们新扩展的水库运行方案可以更适应流态变化。随着 SWOT 等卫星测高项目的不断发展，我们的研究为水库影响评估和预测提供了一个实用框架。本文受版权保护。版权所有。</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;摘要&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;评估历史和未来时期的区域水和能源安全需要能够准确模拟水库运行的水文模型。然而，稀缺的水库运行数据限制了当前水库表示在模拟水库行为时的准确性。此外，这些表示在不断变化的流入状态下的可靠性仍不清楚，这使得它们在长期未来规划视野中的应用值得怀疑。为此，我们提出了一个协同框架，通过结合遥感水库运行模式和模型模拟水库流入量来预测未监测水库（即没有现场流入、释放、存储数据的水库）的释放、存储和水电生产在地表水文模型中使用概念性水库运行方案。先前开发的水库运行方案扩展了基于存储异常的校准方法，以适应遥感数据相对较短的时间序列和较大的时间间隔。通过在中国雅砻江流域进行对照实验，我们表明遥感可以改进所有选定水库运行方案的未计量水库的参数估计和模拟，从而改进下游洪水和径流模拟。然而，这些方案中的大多数都表明，在不断变化的入流状态下，水库运行模拟的准确性有所下降，这可能导致对未来水资源和水电生产的评估不可靠。相比之下，我们新扩展的水库运行方案可以更适应流态变化。随着 SWOT 等卫星测高项目的不断发展，我们的研究为水库影响评估和预测提供了实用框架。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;本文受版权保护。保留所有权利。&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator>董宁鹏、杨明祥、魏建辉、Joël Arnault、Patrick Laux、许世勤、王浩、于中博、Harald Kunstmann</dc:creator><category>研究文章</category><dc:title>改进未监测盆地水库运行的参数化：耦合卫星遥感、水文建模和概念运行方案的协同框架</dc:title><dc:identifier>10.1029/2022WR033026</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname>水资源研究</prism:publicationname><prism:doi>10.1029/2022WR033026</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033026?af=R</prism:url><prism:section>研究文章</prism:section></item><item><link/>https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR032472?af=R<pubDate> Wed, 22 Feb 2023 09:45:48 -0800</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-02-22T09:45:48-08:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley：水资源研究：目录<prism:coverdate>2023 年 2 月 1 日，星期三 00:00:00 -0800</prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate> 2023 年 2 月 1 日，星期三 00:00:00 -0800</prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR032472</guid><title>地表处于水和能量平衡耦合的临界点</title><description>水资源研究，第 59 卷，第 2 期，2023 年 2 月。</description><dc:description>摘要 根据蒸发状态是水限制还是能量限制，地表水和能量平衡可以耦合或解耦合。随着景观在干旱期间失去土壤水分，可能会发生状态之间的转变，这意味着水-能量-碳耦合的非线性变化。经常在这两种模式之间切换的地区，即不受任何一种模式支配的地区，特别容易受到气候变率和变化的影响。为了可靠地识别这些临界点，我们根据来自遥感的全球土壤水分数据集识别干燥事件。事件识别不依赖于降水信息，并且相对于测量噪声是稳健的。然后，描绘蒸发状态转变的土壤水分阈值由顺序蒙特卡罗采样和两阶段参数化策略确定。基于全球范围内估计的土壤水分阈值，我们估计了基于观测的可用水指数，这些指数量化了土壤水分对蒸发的非线性控制。该框架使用土壤水分主动被动土壤水分反演在全球范围内进行了测试和应用。结合描述蒸发状态转换频率的新的临界点指标，我们确定了在全球范围内经常在不同蒸发状态之间切换的区域。考虑到土壤水分的单位变化，这些地区的地表水和能量的耦合方式将经历最大的变化。</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;摘要&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;地表水和能量平衡可以耦合或不耦合，这取决于蒸发状态是水限制还是能量限制。随着景观在干旱期间失去土壤水分，可能会发生制度之间的转变，这意味着水 - 能量 - 碳耦合的非线性变化。经常在这两种模式之间切换的地区，即不受任何一种模式支配的地区，特别容易受到气候变率和变化的影响。为了可靠地识别这些临界点，我们根据来自遥感的全球土壤水分数据集识别干燥事件。事件识别不依赖于降水信息，并且相对于测量噪声是稳健的。然后，描述蒸发状态转变的土壤水分阈值由顺序蒙特卡罗采样和两阶段参数化策略确定。基于全球范围内估计的土壤水分阈值，我们估计了基于观测的可用水指数，这些指数量化了土壤水分对蒸发的非线性控制。该框架使用土壤水分主动被动土壤水分反演在全球范围内进行了测试和应用。结合描述蒸发状态转换频率的新的临界点指标，我们确定了在全球范围内经常在不同蒸发状态之间切换的区域。考虑到土壤水分的单位变化，这些地区的地表水和能量的耦合方式将经历最大的变化。&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> Jianzhi Dong、Ruzbeh Akbar、Andrew F. Feldman、Daniel Short Gianotti、Dara Entekhabi</dc:creator><category>研究文章</category><dc:title>地表处于水和能量平衡耦合的临界点</dc:title><dc:identifier>10.1029/2022WR032472</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname>水资源研究</prism:publicationname><prism:doi>10.1029/2022WR032472</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR032472?af=R</prism:url><prism:section>研究文章</prism:section><prism:volume>59</prism:volume><prism:number> 2个</prism:number></item><item><link/>https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR032064?af=R<pubDate> Wed, 22 Feb 2023 09:45:48 -0800</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-02-22T09:45:48-08:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley：水资源研究：目录<prism:coverdate>2023 年 2 月 1 日，星期三 00:00:00 -0800</prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate> 2023 年 2 月 1 日，星期三 00:00:00 -0800</prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR032064</guid><title>水文模型能否受益于使用全球土壤水分、蒸发蒸腾和径流产品作为校准目标？</title><description>水资源研究，第 59 卷，第 2 期，2023 年 2 月。</description><dc:description>摘要 水文模型通常根据具有相当长且不间断记录的原位水流观测进行校准。这对于无法获得此类信息的测量不佳或未测量的盆地而言具有挑战性。即使对于测量流域，对测量流量的单目标校准也不能保证可靠的预测，因为正如其他地方所记录的那样，逆问题在数学上是病态的。因此，包含其他观测结果以及流量以外的其他水文变量的再现成为准确水文预报的关键组成部分。在本研究中，基于计量流量、全球尺度网格化土壤水分、实际蒸散量 (ET) 和径流产物的不同组合的六种单目标和多目标模型校准方案用于校准基于过程的水文模型位于劳伦森五大湖密歇根湖分水岭内的 20 个集水区。结果表明，在模型校准中将网格土壤水分添加到测量流量中可以提高大多数集水区的 ET 模拟性能，从而获得整体性能最佳的模型。使用网格化径流产品为模型提供信息的实验的每月水流模拟性能优于使用计量水流的实验，但随着流域规模的增加，这种差异得到了缓解。还提出了一种新的可视化方法，该方法可以有效地综合模拟径流、土壤水分和 ET 的模型性能。基于该方法，揭示了基流主导流域的径流模拟性能相对较弱；总体而言，这 20 个流域模型模拟的水流和 ET 优于土壤水分。</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;摘要&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;水文模型通常根据具有相当长且不间断记录的现场水流观测进行校准。这对于无法获得此类信息的测量不佳或未测量的盆地而言具有挑战性。即使对于测量流域，对测量流量的单目标校准也不能保证可靠的预测，因为正如其他地方所记录的那样，逆问题在数学上是病态的。因此，包含其他观测结果以及流量以外的其他水文变量的再现成为准确水文预报的关键组成部分。在这项研究中，基于计量流量、全球尺度网格化土壤水分、实际蒸散量 (ET) 和径流产品的不同组合的六种单目标和多目标模型校准方案用于校准基于过程的水文模型位于劳伦森五大湖密歇根湖分水岭内的 20 个集水区。结果表明，在模型校准中将网格化土壤水分添加到测量流量中可以提高大多数集水区的 ET 模拟性能，从而获得整体性能最佳的模型。使用网格化径流产品为模型提供信息的实验的每月水流模拟性能优于使用计量水流的实验，但随着流域规模的增加，这种差异得到了缓解。还提出了一种新的可视化方法，该方法可以有效地综合模拟径流、土壤水分和 ET 的模型性能。基于该方法，揭示了基流主导流域的径流模拟性能相对较弱；总体而言，20 个流域模型模拟的径流和 ET 优于土壤水分。&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> Yiwen Mei、Juliane Mai、Hong Xuan Do、Andrew Gronewold、Howard Reeves、Sandra Eberts、Richard Niswonger、R. Steven Regan、Randall J. Hunt</dc:creator><category>研究文章</category><dc:title>水文模型能否受益于使用全球土壤水分、蒸发蒸腾和径流产品作为校准目标？</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2022WR032064</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname>水资源研究</prism:publicationname><prism:doi>10.1029/2022WR032064</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR032064?af=R</prism:url><prism:section>研究文章</prism:section><prism:volume>59</prism:volume><prism:number> 2个</prism:number></item><item><link/>https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR034114?af=R<pubDate> Wed, 22 Feb 2023 07:08:34 -0800</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-02-22T07:08:34-08:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley：水资源研究：目录<prism:coverdate></prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate></prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR034114</guid><title>加拿大皮斯-阿萨巴斯卡三角洲阿萨巴斯卡河发生断裂</title><description>水资源研究，接受的文章。</description><dc:description>摘要 撕裂改变了河道并将水和沉积物输送到影响基础设施、洪泛区演化和生态系统的新渠道。突然的撕脱事件（发生数天至数周）对社会具有潜在的灾难性影响，因此比缓慢的撕脱更受关注，后者发展了数十年至数百年并且难以识别。在这里，我们使用原位测量和 37 年的 Landsat 卫星图像检查加拿大皮斯-阿萨巴斯卡河三角洲 (PAD) 的逐渐变化的河道。沿着 Embarras 河 - Mamawi 溪 (EM) 支流，阿萨巴斯卡河明显发生撕裂。从 1982 年开始，它的开放和逐渐扩大从多条观察线中显而易见：1984 年至 2021 年间，EM 和阿萨巴斯卡河之间的流量比增加了一倍多，从 9% 增加到 21%。自 1984 年以来，EM 加宽了 +53%，而阿萨巴斯卡河河道宽度保持稳定。下游的 Mamawi Creek 三角洲正以流量正常化速率增长，大约是表面积阿萨巴斯卡河三角洲的两倍。水面高程的纵向 GNSS 实地调查显示，EM 在阿萨巴斯卡河上具有 ~2 倍的坡度优势（8 × 10-5 对比 4 × 10-5），单位水流功率和河床剪应力表明增强的沉积物输送和侵蚀通过不断发展的流动路径的能力。我们的发现：1) 表明阿萨巴斯卡河正在缓慢撕裂，这可能对淹没模式、生态系统和人类对 PAD 的使用产生长期影响； 2) 展示一种观察方法，用于识别全球河流分叉处的其他缓慢撕裂。</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;摘要&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;崩解改变河道，将水和泥沙输送到新的渠道，影响基础设施、漫滩演化和生态系统。突然的撕脱事件（发生数天至数周）对社会具有潜在的灾难性影响，因此比缓慢的撕脱更受关注，后者发展了数十年至数百年并且难以识别。在这里，我们使用现场测量和 37 年的 Landsat 卫星图像检查加拿大皮斯-阿萨巴斯卡河三角洲 (PAD) 的逐渐变化的河道。沿 Embarras 河 - Mamawi Creek (EM) 支流，阿萨巴斯卡河明显发生撕裂。从 1982 年开始，它的开放和逐渐扩大从多条观察线中显而易见：1984 年至 2021 年间，EM 和阿萨巴斯卡河之间的流量比增加了一倍多，从 9% 增加到 21%。自 1984 年以来，EM 加宽了 +53%，而阿萨巴斯卡河河道宽度保持稳定。下游的 Mamawi Creek 三角洲正以流量归一化速率增长，其表面积大约是阿萨巴斯卡河三角洲表面积的两倍。水面高程的纵向 GNSS 实地调查显示，EM 在阿萨巴斯卡河上具有 ∼2 倍的坡度优势（8 × 10&lt;sup>;-5&lt;/sup>; 对比 4 × 10&lt;sup>;-5&lt;/sup>;），单位水流功率和河床剪切应力表明，通过不断演变的水流路径增强了泥沙输送和侵蚀能力。我们的发现：1) 表明阿萨巴斯卡河正在缓慢撕裂，这可能对洪水模式、生态系统和人类对 PAD 的使用产生长期影响； 2) 展示一种观察方法，用于识别全球河流分叉处的其他缓慢撕裂。&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator>王博、劳伦斯·C·史密斯、科林·格里森、伊桑·D·基兹瓦特、杰西卡·V·费恩、梅里特·E·哈兰、西奥多·兰霍斯特、冯冬梅、艾米丽·艾丹、塞巴斯蒂安·穆尼奥斯、朱丽安·戴维斯、塔姆林·M·帕维尔斯基、丹尼尔·L·彼得斯</dc:creator><category>研究文章</category><dc:title>加拿大皮斯-阿萨巴斯卡三角洲阿萨巴斯卡河发生断裂</dc:title><dc:identifier>10.1029/2022WR034114</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname>水资源研究</prism:publicationname><prism:doi>10.1029/2022WR034114</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR034114?af=R</prism:url><prism:section>研究文章</prism:section></item><item><link/>https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033276?af=R<pubDate> Wed, 22 Feb 2023 06:56:30 -0800</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-02-22T06:56:30-08:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley：水资源研究：目录<prism:coverdate></prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate></prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR033276</guid><title>大孔隙对沼泽土壤咸水蒸发的影响</title><description>水资源研究，接受的文章。</description><dc:description>摘要 蟹穴等大孔隙是盐沼沉积物的普遍特征，被认为是影响盐沼孔隙水流动的重要因素。在这项研究中，我们基于实验室实验和数值模拟研究了大孔隙对盐水蒸发和孔隙水盐度的影响。有和没有人造大孔的土柱用粘壤土填充，并在底部设置不同的水头。结果表明，孔隙水盐度的增加显着降低了蒸发速率。与没有大孔隙的均质土壤相比，由大孔隙引起的优先流补给了大孔隙周围的土壤并保持了更高的蒸发率。由于大孔隙诱导侧流，大孔隙周围浅层土壤的孔隙水盐度降低，而远离大孔隙区域的孔隙水盐度增加。这些影响在水头较高的土层上更为显着。敏感性分析表明，随着初始孔隙水盐度较高，大孔隙对粘壤土和粉砂壤土土壤蒸发率的影响更为显着。这些结果揭示了大孔隙对土壤蒸发过程和土壤条件的影响，也揭示了盐沼中相关的生物地球化学过程。本文受版权保护。版权所有。</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;摘要&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;蟹穴等大孔隙是盐沼沉积物的普遍特征，被认为是影响盐沼孔隙水流动的重要因素。在这项研究中，我们基于实验室实验和数值模拟研究了大孔隙对盐水蒸发和孔隙水盐度的影响。有和没有人造大孔的土柱用粘壤土填充，并在底部设置不同的水头。结果表明，孔隙水盐度的增加显着降低了蒸发率。与没有大孔隙的均质土壤相比，由大孔隙引起的优先流补给了大孔隙周围的土壤并保持了更高的蒸发率。由于大孔诱导侧流，大孔周围浅层土壤的孔隙水盐度降低，而远离大孔的区域孔隙水盐度增加。这些影响在水头较高的土层上更为显着。敏感性分析表明，初始孔隙水矿化度越高，粘壤土和粉砂壤土大孔隙对土壤蒸发速率的影响越显着。这些结果揭示了大孔隙对土壤蒸发过程和土壤条件的影响，也揭示了盐沼中相关的生物地球化学过程。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;本文受版权保护。保留所有权利。&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator>徐兴华，裴鑫，周廷章，于夏阳</dc:creator><category>研究文章</category><dc:title>大孔隙对沼泽土壤咸水蒸发的影响</dc:title><dc:identifier>10.1029/2022WR033276</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname>水资源研究</prism:publicationname><prism:doi>10.1029/2022WR033276</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033276?af=R</prism:url><prism:section>研究文章</prism:section></item><item><link/>https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2021WR031896?af=R<pubDate> Wed, 22 Feb 2023 05:13:45 -0800</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-02-22T05:13:45-08:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley：水资源研究：目录<prism:coverdate></prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate></prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2021WR031896</guid><title>使用具有各向异性孔隙率的浅水方程快速模拟移动床上的植被流和泥沙输送</title><description>水资源研究，接受的文章。</description><dc:description>摘要 开发了一种基于各向异性孔隙率方法的二维浅水模型，用于通过刚性植被预测水流、泥沙输运和河床形态变化。通过添加额外的植被阻力和引入孔隙率参数来考虑植被阻力和空间占用的影响。通过为体积占用定义基于单元的孔隙率和为通量交换定义基于边缘的孔隙率，可以很好地捕获优先流的各向异性特性。基于有限体积法，该模型使用混合 LTS/GMaTS 方法显式求解，并使用 Open MP 技术并行化。该模型的数值网格收敛性和定量精度已针对固定或移动床上刚性挺水植被的各种配置的一系列水槽实验进行了测试。结果表明，使用具有各向异性孔隙率的浅水方程，恒定的阻力系数可以导致与那些复杂的经验关系具有可比精度的数值解。此外，对茎尺度湍流效应的适当量化显着改进了受植被影响的沉积物输运的建模。本文受版权保护。版权所有。</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;摘要&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;开发了一种基于各向异性孔隙率方法的二维浅水模型，用于预测刚性植被的水流、泥沙输运和河床形态变化。通过添加额外的植被阻力和引入孔隙率参数来考虑植被阻力和空间占用的影响。通过为体积占用定义基于单元的孔隙率和为通量交换定义基于边缘的孔隙率，可以很好地捕获优先流的各向异性特性。基于有限体积法，该模型使用混合 LTS/GMaTS 方法显式求解，并使用 Open MP 技术并行化。该模型的数值网格收敛性和定量精度已针对固定或移动床上刚性挺水植被的各种配置的一系列水槽实验进行了测试。结果表明，使用具有各向异性孔隙率的浅水方程，恒定的阻力系数可以导致与那些复杂的经验关系具有可比精度的数值解。此外，对茎尺度湍流效应的适当量化为受植被影响的泥沙输运建模带来了显着改进。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;本文受版权保护。保留所有权利。&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator>李伟、刘炳润、胡鹏</dc:creator><category>研究文章</category><dc:title>使用具有各向异性孔隙率的浅水方程快速模拟移动床上的植被流和泥沙输送</dc:title><dc:identifier>10.1029/2021WR031896</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname>水资源研究</prism:publicationname><prism:doi>10.1029/2021WR031896</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2021WR031896?af=R</prism:url><prism:section>研究文章</prism:section></item><item><link/>https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR034062?af=R<pubDate> Tue, 21 Feb 2023 22:49:20 -0800</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-02-21T10:49:20-08:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley：水资源研究：目录<prism:coverdate></prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate></prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR034062</guid><title>河流代谢、生态系统效率及其对气候变化响应的网络规模建模框架</title><description>水资源研究，接受的文章。</description><dc:description>摘要 气候变化和预测的更温暖的温度和更极端的水文状况可能会影响淡水生态系统及其能量途径。为了理解流动水中碳循环的复杂时空相互作用，生态系统代谢（总初级生产 GPP 和生态系统呼吸，ER）必须在整个河流网络的规模上得到解决。在这里，我们提出了一个元生态系统框架，将光照和温度状况与河段尺度生态系统模型相结合，并整合了网络结构、集水区土地覆盖和水文状况。该模型模拟了溶解和颗粒有机碳、自养生物量以及生态系统代谢的分布功能，并相当好地再现了在奥地利 Ybbs 河网 12 个河段观察到的代谢机制。结果表明，年度网络规模代谢是异养的，但在春季有明显的自养高峰。本土能源贡献了总ER的43%。我们进一步研究了改变的热和水文状况对新陈代谢和生态系统效率的影响。我们预测平均流水温度增加 2.5 °C 可以使 ER 和 GPP 分别提高 31% (24% – 57%) 和 28% (5% – 57%)。更闪亮的水文状况的影响更复杂，取决于自养生物量密度。 The analysis shows the complex interactions between environmental conditions and biota in shaping stream metabolism, and highlights the existing knowledge gaps for reliable predictions of the effects of climate change in these ecosystems.</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;Climate change and the predicted warmer temperatures and more extreme hydrological regimes could affect freshwater ecosystems and their energy pathways. To appreciate the complex spatial and temporal interactions of carbon cycling in flowing waters, ecosystem metabolism (gross primary production, GPP, and ecosystem respiration, ER) must be resolved at the scale of an entire river network. Here, we propose a meta-ecosystem framework that couples light and temperature regimes with a reach-scale ecosystem model, and integrates network structure, catchment land cover and the hydrologic regime. The model simulates the distributed functioning of dissolved and particulate organic carbon, autotrophic biomass, and thus ecosystem metabolism, and reproduces fairly well the metabolic regimes observed in 12 reaches of the Ybbs river network, Austria. Results show that the annual network–scale metabolism was heterotrophic, yet with a clear peak of autotrophy in spring. Autochthonous energy sources contributed 43% of the total ER. We further investigated the effect of altered thermal and hydrologic regimes on metabolism and ecosystem efficiency. We predicted that an increase of 2.5 °C in average streamwater temperature could boost ER and GPP by 31% (24% – 57%) and 28% (5% – 57%), respectively. The effect of flashier hydrologic regimes is more complex and depends on autotrophic biomass density. The analysis shows the complex interactions between environmental conditions and biota in shaping stream metabolism, and highlights the existing knowledge gaps for reliable predictions of the effects of climate change in these ecosystems.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> Pier Luigi Segatto, Tom J. Battin, Enrico Bertuzzo</dc:creator><category> Research Article</category><dc:title> A Network‐Scale Modeling Framework for Stream Metabolism, Ecosystem Efficiency and Their Response to Climate Change</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2022WR034062</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1029/2022WR034062</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR034062?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> Research Article</prism:section></item><item><link/> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033198?af=R<pubDate> Tue, 21 Feb 2023 22:25:52 -0800</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-02-21T10:25:52-08:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley: Water Resources Research: Table of Contents <prism:coverdate></prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate></prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR033198</guid><title> Calibration‐free Priestley‐Taylor Method for Reference Evapotranspiration Estimation</title><description> Water Resources Research, Accepted Article.</description><dc:description> Abstract The Priestley‐Taylor (PT) method is widely used in hydrologic and crop models to calculate the atmospheric demand for water or reference evapotranspiration (ETo). However, the default value of the PT coefficient ( cannot assure reliability under different climatic regions due to the inadequate consideration of the aerodynamic components. In addition, the spatial and temporal evolution of PTa at global scales and how meteorological parameters affect its change have not been elucidated to date. Here, we derived an analytical expression of PTa following the Penman‐Monteith method, ie, , where SA and represent the available energy and wind speed impacts on ETo, respectively. The daily Princeton Global Forcing dataset (0.25° × 0.25°, 1948‐2016) was used to validate PTa. The calibration‐free PTa improved the simulation of aerodynamic components and, consequently, the accuracy of ETo estimation. The gridded global monthly PTa dataset is fully open‐source and can be incorporated into hydrologic and crop models. We also demonstrated that PTa under equilibrium or quasi‐equilibrium evaporation conditions (1.26 ± 0.04) was very close to the default value. T he simplified PTa, with relative humidity as the only input, still performed better than the original method. Results indicated that the radiative component was the driving factor of the global ETo changes from 1948 to 2016. The impacts of available energy and wind speed on global ETo variations tend to intensify in a warming climate. Our findings have important implications for understanding the roles of radiative and aerodynamic components in the global ETo changes. This article is protected by copyright.版权所有。</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;The Priestley-Taylor (PT) method is widely used in hydrologic and crop models to calculate the atmospheric demand for water or reference evapotranspiration (ET&lt;sub>;o&lt;/sub>;). However, the default value of the PT coefficient ( cannot assure reliability under different climatic regions due to the inadequate consideration of the aerodynamic components. In addition, the spatial and temporal evolution of PT&lt;sub>;a&lt;/sub>; at global scales and how meteorological parameters affect its change have not been elucidated to date. Here, we derived an analytical expression of PT&lt;sub>;a&lt;/sub>; following the Penman-Monteith method, ie, , where &lt;i>;S&lt;/i>; &lt;sub>; &lt;i>;A&lt;/i>; &lt;/sub>; and represent the available energy and wind speed impacts on ET&lt;sub>;o&lt;/sub>;, respectively. The daily Princeton Global Forcing dataset (0.25° × 0.25°, 1948-2016) was used to validate PT&lt;sub>;a&lt;/sub>;. The calibration-free PT&lt;sub>;a&lt;/sub>; improved the simulation of aerodynamic components and, consequently, the accuracy of ET&lt;sub>;o&lt;/sub>; estimation. The gridded global monthly PT&lt;sub>;a&lt;/sub>; dataset is fully open-source and can be incorporated into hydrologic and crop models. We also demonstrated that PT&lt;sub>;a&lt;/sub>; under equilibrium or quasi-equilibrium evaporation conditions (1.26 ± 0.04) was very close to the default value. The simplified PT&lt;sub>;a&lt;/sub>;, with relative humidity as the only input, still performed better than the original method. Results indicated that the radiative component was the driving factor of the global ET&lt;sub>;o&lt;/sub>; changes from 1948 to 2016. The impacts of available energy and wind speed on global ET&lt;sub>;o&lt;/sub>; variations tend to intensify in a warming climate. Our findings have important implications for understanding the roles of radiative and aerodynamic components in the global ET&lt;sub>;o&lt;/sub>; changes.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This article is protected by copyright. All rights reserved.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> Qiong Su, Vijay P. Singh</dc:creator><category> Research Article</category><dc:title> Calibration‐free Priestley‐Taylor Method for Reference Evapotranspiration Estimation</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2022WR033198</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1029/2022WR033198</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033198?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> Research Article</prism:section></item><item><link/> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR034381?af=R<pubDate> Tue, 21 Feb 2023 12:32:51 -0800</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-02-21T12:32:51-08:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley: Water Resources Research: Table of Contents <prism:coverdate></prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate></prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR034381</guid><title> A comprehensive evaluation of GRACE‐like terrestrial water storage (TWS) reconstruction products at an interannual scale during 1981‐2019</title><description> Water Resources Research, Accepted Article.</description><dc:description> Abstract Given the success of the Gravity Recovery and Climate Experiment (GRACE) mission in mapping terrestrial water storage (TWS) since 2002, recent reconstructions of long‐term TWS rely on the use of statistical machine learning to apply GRACE‐derived information to past decades. Evaluating the interannual accuracy during nonobservational periods is a key challenge. This study develops a comprehensive framework to discuss the interannual accuracy of three different TWS reconstructions during 1981‐2019, including (1) global‐scale accuracy assessment using GRACE and satellite laser ranging (SLR) data; (2) regional‐scale accuracy testing across various underlying surfaces (ie, rivers, lakes, and glaciers); and (3) investigation of relevant evidence from other Earth subsystems (ie, historic climate events, sea level budget, and polar motion). Among the three reconstructions, the one that additionally corrects glacial TWS changes (REC2) detects a breaking point in the 1990s and further closes the interannual sea level budget with an absolute difference reduction to 5.13 mm; the reconstruction that is forced by local meteorological conditions (REC1), accounting for 54% of the GRACE‐derived signal energy, underestimates glacial TWS variability but outperforms the other reconstructions in reproducing lake levels, basin‐scale water balances, and climate events at the interannual scale, while the others consider 95‐99% of the GRACE‐derived signal energy. The relatively high accuracy of REC1 (and REC2) in reflecting interannual changes in nonglacial (and glacial) regions is further confirmed by explaining the χ2‐ (and χ1‐) component polar motion. Ten to 20% of the interannual polar motion remains unexplained, indicating room for improvement in interannual TWS reconstruction. This article is protected by copyright.版权所有。</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;Given the success of the Gravity Recovery and Climate Experiment (GRACE) mission in mapping terrestrial water storage (TWS) since 2002, recent reconstructions of long-term TWS rely on the use of statistical machine learning to apply GRACE-derived information to past decades. Evaluating the interannual accuracy during nonobservational periods is a key challenge. This study develops a comprehensive framework to discuss the interannual accuracy of three different TWS reconstructions during 1981-2019, including (1) global-scale accuracy assessment using GRACE and satellite laser ranging (SLR) data; (2) regional-scale accuracy testing across various underlying surfaces (ie, rivers, lakes, and glaciers); and (3) investigation of relevant evidence from other Earth subsystems (ie, historic climate events, sea level budget, and polar motion). Among the three reconstructions, the one that additionally corrects glacial TWS changes (REC2) detects a breaking point in the 1990s and further closes the interannual sea level budget with an absolute difference reduction to 5.13 mm; the reconstruction that is forced by local meteorological conditions (REC1), accounting for 54% of the GRACE-derived signal energy, underestimates glacial TWS variability but outperforms the other reconstructions in reproducing lake levels, basin-scale water balances, and climate events at the interannual scale, while the others consider 95-99% of the GRACE-derived signal energy. The relatively high accuracy of REC1 (and REC2) in reflecting interannual changes in nonglacial (and glacial) regions is further confirmed by explaining the &lt;i>;χ&lt;/i>; &lt;sub>;2&lt;/sub>;- (and &lt;i>;χ&lt;/i>; &lt;sub>;1&lt;/sub>;-) component polar motion. Ten to 20% of the interannual polar motion remains unexplained, indicating room for improvement in interannual TWS reconstruction.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This article is protected by copyright. All rights reserved.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> Shanshan Deng, Yuxin Liu, Wenxi Zhang</dc:creator><category> Research Article</category><dc:title> A comprehensive evaluation of GRACE‐like terrestrial water storage (TWS) reconstruction products at an interannual scale during 1981‐2019</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2022WR034381</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1029/2022WR034381</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR034381?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> Research Article</prism:section></item><item><link/> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR032171?af=R<pubDate> Tue, 21 Feb 2023 10:32:23 -0800</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-02-21T10:32:23-08:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley: Water Resources Research: Table of Contents <prism:coverdate></prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate></prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR032171</guid><title> Constraining mountain streamflow constituents by integrating citizen scientist acquired geochemical samples and Sentinel‐1 SAR wet snow time‐series for the Shimshal catchment in the Karakoram Mountains of Pakistan</title><description> Water Resources Research, Accepted Article.</description><dc:description> Abstract Upper Indus Basin streamflow originates largely from glacier and snow melt in the upstream Himalaya, Karakoram, and Hindu Kush mountain ranges and is extremely vulnerable because of its projected climate changes, dense populations, and hydropolitical tensions. Accurate knowledge of streamflow constituents is required for resilient water resources management; this is precluded by a paucity of measurement as well as climatological and topographic complexity. Here we integrate citizen scientist acquired geochemical samples, collected from October 2018 through September 2019 in the Shimshal watershed of the Karakoram Mountains of Pakistan, with Sentinel‐1 (S1) synthetic aperture radar (SAR)‐derived wet snow maps, to better understand streamflow constituents for the high altitude and heavily glaciated catchment. We use Bayesian end‐member mixture analyses to separate river flows into baseflow and meltwater constituents, using fixed and time‐variant melt end‐member values. We compare river hydrograph separation results with S1 wet snow time series maps for the same timeframe. We then utilize S1 imagery to inform end‐member mixture analysis to separate meltwaters into snow and glacier melt. For the Shimshal catchment, we find that about 85% of annual river flows are derived from snow and glacier melt; 45% of annual flows are derived from snow melt and 40% glacier melt. Engaged and committed citizen scientists enabled geochemical sample collection and analysis on a significant temporal and spatial scale. In the future, co‐produced knowledge that both implements local expertise and that is also planned and utilized by diverse stakeholders may increase climatological awareness and resilience in the Upper Indus Basin.</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;Upper Indus Basin streamflow originates largely from glacier and snow melt in the upstream Himalaya, Karakoram, and Hindu Kush mountain ranges and is extremely vulnerable because of its projected climate changes, dense populations, and hydropolitical tensions. Accurate knowledge of streamflow constituents is required for resilient water resources management; this is precluded by a paucity of measurement as well as climatological and topographic complexity.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Here we integrate citizen scientist acquired geochemical samples, collected from October 2018 through September 2019 in the Shimshal watershed of the Karakoram Mountains of Pakistan, with Sentinel-1 (S1) synthetic aperture radar (SAR)-derived wet snow maps, to better understand streamflow constituents for the high altitude and heavily glaciated catchment. We use Bayesian end-member mixture analyses to separate river flows into baseflow and meltwater constituents, using fixed and time-variant melt end-member values.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;We compare river hydrograph separation results with S1 wet snow time series maps for the same timeframe. We then utilize S1 imagery to inform end-member mixture analysis to separate meltwaters into snow and glacier melt. For the Shimshal catchment, we find that about 85% of annual river flows are derived from snow and glacier melt; 45% of annual flows are derived from snow melt and 40% glacier melt.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Engaged and committed citizen scientists enabled geochemical sample collection and analysis on a significant temporal and spatial scale. In the future, co-produced knowledge that both implements local expertise and that is also planned and utilized by diverse stakeholders may increase climatological awareness and resilience in the Upper Indus Basin.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> Jewell Lund, Richard R Forster, Yusuf Jameel, Summer B Rupper, Elias J Deeb, Ghulam Hussain Dars, Azhar Zaheer, Masood Ali, Abdul Ghafoor, Garee Khan, Muhammad Arfan, Glen E Liston, Javed Akhter Qureshi, Gregory Carling, Steven J Burian</dc:creator><category> Research Article</category><dc:title> Constraining mountain streamflow constituents by integrating citizen scientist acquired geochemical samples and Sentinel‐1 SAR wet snow time‐series for the Shimshal catchment in the Karakoram Mountains of Pakistan</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2022WR032171</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1029/2022WR032171</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR032171?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> Research Article</prism:section></item><item><link/> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033703?af=R<pubDate> Tue, 21 Feb 2023 07:29:18 -0800</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-02-21T07:29:18-08:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley: Water Resources Research: Table of Contents <prism:coverdate></prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate></prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR033703</guid><title> A Robust Strategy to Account for Data Sampling Variability in the Development of Hydrological Models</title><description> Water Resources Research, Accepted Article.</description><dc:description> Abstract It is typical to use a single portion of the available data to calibrate hydrological models, and the remainder for model evaluation. To minimize model‐bias, this partitioning must be performed so as to ensure distributional representativeness and mutual consistency. However, failure to account for data sampling variability (DSV) in the underlying Data Generating Process can weaken the model&#39;s generalization performance. While “K‐fold cross‐validation” can mitigate this problem, it is computationally inefficient since the calibration/evaluation operations must be repeated numerous times. This paper develops a general strategy for stochastic evolutionary parameter optimization (SEPO) that explicitly accounts for DSV when calibrating a model using any population‐based evolutionary optimization algorithm (EOA), such as Shuffled Complex Evolution (SCE). Inspired in part by the machine‐learning strategy of stochastic gradient descent (SGD), we use various representative random sub‐samples to drive the EOA towards the distribution of the model parameters. Unlike in SGD, derivative information is not required and hence SEPO can be applied to any hydrological model where such information is not readily available. To demonstrate the effectiveness of the proposed strategy, we implement it within the well‐known SCE, to calibrate the GR4J conceptual rainfall‐runoff model to 163 hydro‐climatically diverse catchments. Using only a single optimization run, our Stochastic SCE method converges to population‐based estimates of model parameter distributions (and corresponding simulation uncertainties), without compromising model performance during either calibration or evaluation. Further, it effectively reduces the need to perform independent evaluation tests of model performance under conditions that are represented by the available data. This article is protected by copyright.版权所有。</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;It is typical to use a &lt;i>; &lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration:underline&quot;>;single&lt;/span>; &lt;/i>; portion of the available data to calibrate hydrological models, and the remainder for model evaluation. To minimize model-bias, this partitioning must be performed so as to ensure distributional representativeness and mutual consistency. However, failure to account for &lt;i>;data sampling variability&lt;/i>; (DSV) in the underlying &lt;i>;Data Generating Process&lt;/i>; can weaken the model&#39;s generalization performance. While “&lt;i>;K-fold cross-validation&lt;/i>;” can mitigate this problem, it is computationally inefficient since the calibration/evaluation operations must be repeated numerous times. This paper develops a general strategy for &lt;i>;stochastic evolutionary parameter optimization&lt;/i>; (SEPO) that explicitly accounts for DSV when calibrating a model using &lt;i>;any&lt;/i>; population-based &lt;i>;evolutionary optimization algorithm&lt;/i>; (EOA), such as &lt;i>;Shuffled Complex Evolution&lt;/i>; (SCE). Inspired in part by the machine-learning strategy of &lt;i>;stochastic gradient descent&lt;/i>; (SGD), we use various representative random sub-samples to drive the EOA towards the distribution of the model parameters. Unlike in SGD, derivative information is not required and hence SEPO can be applied to any hydrological model where such information is not readily available. To demonstrate the effectiveness of the proposed strategy, we implement it within the well-known SCE, to calibrate the GR4J conceptual rainfall-runoff model to 163 hydro-climatically diverse catchments. Using only a single optimization run, our &lt;i>;Stochastic SCE&lt;/i>; method converges to population-based estimates of model parameter distributions (and corresponding simulation uncertainties), without compromising model performance during either calibration or evaluation. Further, it effectively reduces the need to perform independent evaluation tests of model performance under conditions that are represented by the available data.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This article is protected by copyright. All rights reserved.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> Feifei Zheng, Junyi Chen, Yiyi Ma, Qiuwen Chen, Holger R. Maier, Hoshin Gupta</dc:creator><category> Research Article</category><dc:title> A Robust Strategy to Account for Data Sampling Variability in the Development of Hydrological Models</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2022WR033703</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1029/2022WR033703</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033703?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> Research Article</prism:section></item><item><link/> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR032736?af=R<pubDate> Tue, 21 Feb 2023 06:39:03 -0800</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-02-21T06:39:03-08:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley: Water Resources Research: Table of Contents <prism:coverdate></prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate></prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR032736</guid><title> Breaking the window of detection: Using multi‐scale solute tracer studies to assess mass recovery at the detection limit</title><description> Water Resources Research, Accepted Article.</description><dc:description> Abstract Stream solute tracers are commonly injected to assess transport and transformation in study reaches, but results are biased toward the shortest and fastest storage locations. While this bias has been understood for decades, the impact of an experimental constraint on our understanding has yet to be considered. Here, we ask how different our understanding of reach‐ and segment‐scale transport would be if our empirical limits were extended. We demonstrate a novel approach to manipulate experimental conditions and observe mass that is stored at timescales beyond the traditional reach‐scale window of detection. We are able to explain the fate of an average of 26% of solute tracer mass that would have been considered as &#39;lost&#39; in a traditional study design across our 14 replicates, extending our detection limits to characterize flowpaths that would have been previously unmeasured. We demonstrate how this formerly lost mass leads to predicting lower magnitudes of gross gains and losses in individual reaches, and ultimately show that the network turnover we infer from solute tracers represents an upper limit on actual, expected behavior. Finally, we review the evolution of tracer studies and their interpretation including this approach and provide a proposed future direction to extend empirical studies to not‐before‐seen timescales This article is protected by copyright.版权所有。</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;Stream solute tracers are commonly injected to assess transport and transformation in study reaches, but results are biased toward the shortest and fastest storage locations. While this bias has been understood for decades, the impact of an experimental constraint on our understanding has yet to be considered. Here, we ask how different our understanding of reach- and segment-scale transport would be if our empirical limits were extended. We demonstrate a novel approach to manipulate experimental conditions and observe mass that is stored at timescales beyond the traditional reach-scale window of detection. We are able to explain the fate of an average of 26% of solute tracer mass that would have been considered as &#39;lost&#39; in a traditional study design across our 14 replicates, extending our detection limits to characterize flowpaths that would have been previously unmeasured. We demonstrate how this formerly lost mass leads to predicting lower magnitudes of gross gains and losses in individual reaches, and ultimately show that the network turnover we infer from solute tracers represents an upper limit on actual, expected behavior. Finally, we review the evolution of tracer studies and their interpretation including this approach and provide a proposed future direction to extend empirical studies to not-before-seen timescales&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This article is protected by copyright. All rights reserved.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> Adam S. Ward, Steven M. Wondzell, Michael N. Gooseff, Tim Covino, Skuyler Herzog, Brian McGlynn, Robert A. Payn</dc:creator><category> Research Article</category><dc:title> Breaking the window of detection: Using multi‐scale solute tracer studies to assess mass recovery at the detection limit</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2022WR032736</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1029/2022WR032736</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR032736?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> Research Article</prism:section></item><item><link/> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033033?af=R<pubDate> Tue, 21 Feb 2023 06:29:11 -0800</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-02-21T06:29:11-08:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley: Water Resources Research: Table of Contents <prism:coverdate></prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate></prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR033033</guid><title> Upscaling Tracer‐aided Ecohydrological Modeling to Larger Catchments: Implications for Process Representation and Heterogeneity in Landscape Organization</title><description> Water Resources Research, Accepted Article.</description><dc:description> Abstract Stable isotopes of water are ideal tracers to integrate into process‐based models, advancing ecohydrological understanding. Current tracer‐aided ecohydrological modeling is mostly conducted in relatively small‐scale catchments, due to limited tracer data availability and often highly damped stream isotope signals in larger catchments (>;100 km2). Recent model developments have prioritized better spatial representation, offering new potential for advancing upscaling in tracer‐aided modeling. Here we adapted the fully distributed EcH2O‐iso model to the Selke catchment (456 km2, Germany), incorporating monthly sampled isotopes from seven sites between 2012‐2017. Parameter sensitivity analysis indicated that the information content of isotope data was generally complementary to discharge and more sensitive to runoff partitioning, soil water and energy dynamics. Multi‐criteria calibrations revealed that inclusion of isotopes could significantly improve discharge performance during validations and isotope simulations, resulting in more reasonable estimates of stream water age seasonality. However, capturing isotopic signals of highly non‐linear near‐surface processes remained challenging for the upscaled model, but still allowed for plausible simulation of water ages reflecting non‐stationarity in transport and mixing. The detailed modeling also helped unravel spatio‐temporally varying patterns of water storage‐flux‐age interactions and their interplay under severe drought conditions. Embracing the upscaling challenges, this study demonstrated that even coarsely sampled isotope data can be of value in aiding ecohydrological modeling and consequent process representation in larger catchments. The derived innovative insights into ecohydrological functioning at scales commensurate with management decision making, are of particular importance for guiding science‐based measures for tackling environmental changes. This article is protected by copyright.版权所有。</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;Stable isotopes of water are ideal tracers to integrate into process-based models, advancing ecohydrological understanding. Current tracer-aided ecohydrological modeling is mostly conducted in relatively small-scale catchments, due to limited tracer data availability and often highly damped stream isotope signals in larger catchments (&amp;gt;100 km&lt;sup>;2&lt;/sup>;). Recent model developments have prioritized better spatial representation, offering new potential for advancing upscaling in tracer-aided modeling. Here we adapted the fully distributed EcH&lt;sub>;2&lt;/sub>;O-iso model to the Selke catchment (456 km&lt;sup>;2&lt;/sup>;, Germany), incorporating monthly sampled isotopes from seven sites between 2012-2017. Parameter sensitivity analysis indicated that the information content of isotope data was generally complementary to discharge and more sensitive to runoff partitioning, soil water and energy dynamics. Multi-criteria calibrations revealed that inclusion of isotopes could significantly improve discharge performance during validations and isotope simulations, resulting in more reasonable estimates of stream water age seasonality. However, capturing isotopic signals of highly non-linear near-surface processes remained challenging for the upscaled model, but still allowed for plausible simulation of water ages reflecting non-stationarity in transport and mixing. The detailed modeling also helped unravel spatio-temporally varying patterns of water storage-flux-age interactions and their interplay under severe drought conditions. Embracing the upscaling challenges, this study demonstrated that even coarsely sampled isotope data can be of value in aiding ecohydrological modeling and consequent process representation in larger catchments. The derived innovative insights into ecohydrological functioning at scales commensurate with management decision making, are of particular importance for guiding science-based measures for tackling environmental changes.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This article is protected by copyright. All rights reserved.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> Xiaoqiang Yang, Doerthe Tetzlaff, Christin Müller, Kay Knöller, Dietrich Borchardt, Chris Soulsby</dc:creator><category> Research Article</category><dc:title> Upscaling Tracer‐aided Ecohydrological Modeling to Larger Catchments: Implications for Process Representation and Heterogeneity in Landscape Organization</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2022WR033033</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1029/2022WR033033</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033033?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> Research Article</prism:section></item><item><link/> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2021WR031451?af=R<pubDate> Tue, 21 Feb 2023 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-02-21T12:00:00-08:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley: Water Resources Research: Table of Contents<prism:coverdate> Wed, 01 Feb 2023 00:00:00 -0800</prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate> Wed, 01 Feb 2023 00:00:00 -0800</prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2021WR031451</guid><title> Anisotropy and Heterogeneity Induced by Shale in Aquifer lithology—Influence of Aquifer Shale on the Leaky Model With Tidal Response Analysis</title><description> Water Resources Research, Volume 59, Issue 2, February 2023.</description><dc:description> Abstract Tidal and barometric water‐level responses in wells have been widely used to calculate the hydraulic properties of aquifer systems. The effect of anisotropy induced by shale content on such responses has not received significant attention. In this study, we examine how the presence of shale (anisotropy, extremely low porosity/permeability; approximately 10−4 to 10−3 mD), which occurs as interlayers in aquifers, affects the tidal responses of the leaky model. Our findings show that the number of wells with shale in the screened section of the study aquifer is limited. Here, we focus on the study of the limited number of wells in the North China Platform to ensure a similar geological background for each well. Calculations indicate that wells, even with a small amount of shale (≥∼5%) in the observation aquifer, may exhibit strong anisotropy and heterogeneity, deviating from the theoretical analytical solutions obtained using isotropic and homogeneous assumption models. Generally, the higher the shale content in aquifer lithology, the greater the phase shifts deviated. Thus, theoretical ideal models with isotropic and homogeneous assumptions may only obtain a rough estimation for wells with shale in aquifer lithology, suggesting that we avoid setting observation aquifers onto shale layers.</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;Tidal and barometric water-level responses in wells have been widely used to calculate the hydraulic properties of aquifer systems. The effect of anisotropy induced by shale content on such responses has not received significant attention. In this study, we examine how the presence of shale (anisotropy, extremely low porosity/permeability; approximately 10&lt;sup>;−4&lt;/sup>; to 10&lt;sup>;−3&lt;/sup>; mD), which occurs as interlayers in aquifers, affects the tidal responses of the leaky model. Our findings show that the number of wells with shale in the screened section of the study aquifer is limited. Here, we focus on the study of the limited number of wells in the North China Platform to ensure a similar geological background for each well. Calculations indicate that wells, even with a small amount of shale (≥∼5%) in the observation aquifer, may exhibit strong anisotropy and heterogeneity, deviating from the theoretical analytical solutions obtained using isotropic and homogeneous assumption models. Generally, the higher the shale content in aquifer lithology, the greater the phase shifts deviated. Thus, theoretical ideal models with isotropic and homogeneous assumptions may only obtain a rough estimation for wells with shale in aquifer lithology, suggesting that we avoid setting observation aquifers onto shale layers.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> Yan Zhang, Li‐Yun Fu, Aiyu Zhu, Lianfeng Zhao, Shengwen Qi, Tianming Huang, Yuchuan Ma, Wang Zhang</dc:creator><category> Commentary</category><dc:title> Anisotropy and Heterogeneity Induced by Shale in Aquifer lithology—Influence of Aquifer Shale on the Leaky Model With Tidal Response Analysis</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2021WR031451</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1029/2021WR031451</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2021WR031451?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> Commentary</prism:section><prism:volume> 59</prism:volume><prism:number> 2个</prism:number></item><item><link/>https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033168?af=R<pubDate> Tue, 21 Feb 2023 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-02-21T12:00:00-08:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley: Water Resources Research: Table of Contents<prism:coverdate> Wed, 01 Feb 2023 00:00:00 -0800</prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate> Wed, 01 Feb 2023 00:00:00 -0800</prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR033168</guid><title> Physics‐Informed Neural Networks of the Saint‐Venant Equations for Downscaling a Large‐Scale River Model</title><description> Water Resources Research, Volume 59, Issue 2, February 2023.</description><dc:description> Abstract Large‐scale river models are being refined over coastal regions to improve the scientific understanding of coastal processes, hazards and responses to climate change. However, coarse mesh resolutions and approximations in physical representations of tidal rivers limit the performance of such models at resolving the complex flow dynamics especially near the river‐ocean interface, resulting in inaccurate simulations of flood inundation. In this research, we propose a machine learning (ML) framework based on the state‐of‐the‐art physics‐informed neural network (PINN) to simulate the downscaled flow at the subgrid scale. First, we demonstrate that PINN is able to assimilate observations of various types and solve the one‐dimensional (1‐D) Saint‐Venant equations (SVE) directly. We perform the flow simulations over a floodplain and along an open channel in several synthetic case studies. The PINN performance is evaluated against analytical solutions and numerical models. Our results indicate that the PINN solutions of water depth have satisfactory accuracy with limited observations assimilated. In the case of flood wave propagation induced by storm surge and tide, a new neural network architecture is proposed based on Fourier feature embeddings that seamlessly encodes the periodic tidal boundary condition in the PINN&#39;s formulation. Furthermore, we show that the PINN‐based downscaling can produce more reasonable subgrid solutions of the along‐channel water depth by assimilating observational data. The PINN solution outperforms the simple linear interpolation in resolving the topography and dynamic flow regimes at the subgrid scale. This study provides a promising path toward improving emulation capabilities in large‐scale models to characterize fine‐scale coastal processes.</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;Large-scale river models are being refined over coastal regions to improve the scientific understanding of coastal processes, hazards and responses to climate change. However, coarse mesh resolutions and approximations in physical representations of tidal rivers limit the performance of such models at resolving the complex flow dynamics especially near the river-ocean interface, resulting in inaccurate simulations of flood inundation. In this research, we propose a machine learning (ML) framework based on the state-of-the-art physics-informed neural network (PINN) to simulate the downscaled flow at the subgrid scale. First, we demonstrate that PINN is able to assimilate observations of various types and solve the one-dimensional (1-D) Saint-Venant equations (SVE) directly. We perform the flow simulations over a floodplain and along an open channel in several synthetic case studies. The PINN performance is evaluated against analytical solutions and numerical models. Our results indicate that the PINN solutions of water depth have satisfactory accuracy with limited observations assimilated. In the case of flood wave propagation induced by storm surge and tide, a new neural network architecture is proposed based on Fourier feature embeddings that seamlessly encodes the periodic tidal boundary condition in the PINN&#39;s formulation. Furthermore, we show that the PINN-based downscaling can produce more reasonable subgrid solutions of the along-channel water depth by assimilating observational data. The PINN solution outperforms the simple linear interpolation in resolving the topography and dynamic flow regimes at the subgrid scale. This study provides a promising path toward improving emulation capabilities in large-scale models to characterize fine-scale coastal processes.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> Dongyu Feng, Zeli Tan, QiZhi He</dc:creator><category> Research Article</category><dc:title> Physics‐Informed Neural Networks of the Saint‐Venant Equations for Downscaling a Large‐Scale River Model</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2022WR033168</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1029/2022WR033168</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033168?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> Research Article</prism:section><prism:volume> 59</prism:volume><prism:number> 2个</prism:number></item><item><link/>https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033779?af=R<pubDate> Tue, 21 Feb 2023 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-02-21T12:00:00-08:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley: Water Resources Research: Table of Contents<prism:coverdate> Wed, 01 Feb 2023 00:00:00 -0800</prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate> Wed, 01 Feb 2023 00:00:00 -0800</prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR033779</guid><title> Quantifying Coupling Effects Between Soil Matric Potential and Osmotic Potential</title><description> Water Resources Research, Volume 59, Issue 2, February 2023.</description><dc:description> Abstract Soil matric potential and osmotic potential are widely accepted as two independent components of total soil water potential. However, laboratory observations repeatedly demonstrated that matric potential can vary with salt concentration, implying a potential coupling between matric potential and osmotic potential. To date, it remains elusive whether matric potential and osmotic potential are independent or not and why so, and a theoretical theory for quantifying the coupling between them is still missing. Herein, a theoretical model is developed to quantitatively explain this problem via a lens provided by a recent concept of soil sorptive potential (SSP). The proposed model substantiates that matric potential and osmotic potential are not independent. The increasing salt concentration can notably depress two variables underpinning SSP, namely relative permittivity and electrical double layer thickness, leading to non‐negligible decreasing (more negative) of matric potential in the high suction range, and increasing (less negative) of it in the low suction range. In turn, the soil‐water interactions redistribute ions in soil water, raising osmotic potential especially for clay with high cation exchange capacity. The proposed model shows excellent performance in capturing experimental data, validating its accuracy. A parametric study implies that the neglection of coupling effects can lead to a significant underestimation of soil hydraulic conductivity in the film flow regime.</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;Soil matric potential and osmotic potential are widely accepted as two independent components of total soil water potential. However, laboratory observations repeatedly demonstrated that matric potential can vary with salt concentration, implying a potential coupling between matric potential and osmotic potential. To date, it remains elusive whether matric potential and osmotic potential are independent or not and why so, and a theoretical theory for quantifying the coupling between them is still missing. Herein, a theoretical model is developed to quantitatively explain this problem via a lens provided by a recent concept of soil sorptive potential (SSP). The proposed model substantiates that matric potential and osmotic potential are not independent. The increasing salt concentration can notably depress two variables underpinning SSP, namely relative permittivity and electrical double layer thickness, leading to non-negligible decreasing (more negative) of matric potential in the high suction range, and increasing (less negative) of it in the low suction range. In turn, the soil-water interactions redistribute ions in soil water, raising osmotic potential especially for clay with high cation exchange capacity. The proposed model shows excellent performance in capturing experimental data, validating its accuracy. A parametric study implies that the neglection of coupling effects can lead to a significant underestimation of soil hydraulic conductivity in the film flow regime.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> Shaojie Hu, Chao Zhang, Ning Lu</dc:creator><category> Research Article</category><dc:title> Quantifying Coupling Effects Between Soil Matric Potential and Osmotic Potential</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2022WR033779</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1029/2022WR033779</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033779?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> Research Article</prism:section><prism:volume> 59</prism:volume><prism:number> 2个</prism:number></item><item><link/>https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR032091?af=R<pubDate> Tue, 21 Feb 2023 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-02-21T12:00:00-08:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley: Water Resources Research: Table of Contents<prism:coverdate> Wed, 01 Feb 2023 00:00:00 -0800</prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate> Wed, 01 Feb 2023 00:00:00 -0800</prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR032091</guid><title> A New Approach for Assessing Groundwater Recharge by Combining GRACE and Baseflow With Case Studies in Karst Areas of Southwest China</title><description> Water Resources Research, Volume 59, Issue 2, February 2023.</description><dc:description> Abstract A new approach combining groundwater storage change (GWSC) derived from Gravity Recovery and Climate Experiment (GRACE) satellite data and baseflow was proposed to estimate groundwater recharge at large spatial scales but a short (monthly) time scale. This method was applied in two typical karst basins of southwest China, the Wujiang River basin (WRB, ∼87,900 km2, ∼70% karstification) and Xijiang River Basin (XRB, ∼360,000 km2, ∼44% karstification). The 2006–2012 monthly baseflow was first separated from in situ streamflow through multivariate regression analysis. Groundwater recharge was estimated using separated baseflow and GWSC estimated from GRACE data and observation‐based groundwater‐level data. The comparison between GRACE‐ and observation‐based recharge in the larger XRB shows better consistency, while that in the smaller WRB shows larger discrepancies. Considering the associated uncertainty (60–93 mm/yr), the 2006–2012 mean recharge in two basins, ranging 199–225 mm/yr (17%–19% of precipitation) is comparable to bulletin‐reported estimates (∼145 mm/yr). Both the degree of karstification and aquifer water table depth influence recharge and discharge processes in karst areas of southwest China. The more karstic WRB exhibits more rapid infiltration (due to more developed permeable epikarst zone) and higher discharge capability (due to more developed underground drainage systems), particularly during dry periods (2009, 2011, and winter). Baseflow exhibits a shorter time lag to recharge and GWSC in the XRB than WRB owing to more quick flow, lower storage with more rapid infiltration, and shorter mean groundwater residence time. Observation‐based monthly recharge reflects different rainfall‐infiltration‐runoff processes under different rainfall intensities, particularly in the WRB.</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;A new approach combining groundwater storage change (GWSC) derived from Gravity Recovery and Climate Experiment (GRACE) satellite data and baseflow was proposed to estimate groundwater recharge at large spatial scales but a short (monthly) time scale. This method was applied in two typical karst basins of southwest China, the Wujiang River basin (WRB, ∼87,900 km&lt;sup>;2&lt;/sup>;, ∼70% karstification) and Xijiang River Basin (XRB, ∼360,000 km&lt;sup>;2&lt;/sup>;, ∼44% karstification). The 2006–2012 monthly baseflow was first separated from in situ streamflow through multivariate regression analysis. Groundwater recharge was estimated using separated baseflow and GWSC estimated from GRACE data and observation-based groundwater-level data. The comparison between GRACE- and observation-based recharge in the larger XRB shows better consistency, while that in the smaller WRB shows larger discrepancies. Considering the associated uncertainty (60–93 mm/yr), the 2006–2012 mean recharge in two basins, ranging 199–225 mm/yr (17%–19% of precipitation) is comparable to bulletin-reported estimates (∼145 mm/yr). Both the degree of karstification and aquifer water table depth influence recharge and discharge processes in karst areas of southwest China. The more karstic WRB exhibits more rapid infiltration (due to more developed permeable epikarst zone) and higher discharge capability (due to more developed underground drainage systems), particularly during dry periods (2009, 2011, and winter). Baseflow exhibits a shorter time lag to recharge and GWSC in the XRB than WRB owing to more quick flow, lower storage with more rapid infiltration, and shorter mean groundwater residence time. Observation-based monthly recharge reflects different rainfall-infiltration-runoff processes under different rainfall intensities, particularly in the WRB.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> Zhiyong Huang, Pat J.‐F. Yeh, Jiu Jimmy Jiao, Xin Luo, Yun Pan, Yuannan Long, Chong Zhang, Longqun Zheng</dc:creator><category> Research Article</category><dc:title> A New Approach for Assessing Groundwater Recharge by Combining GRACE and Baseflow With Case Studies in Karst Areas of Southwest China</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2022WR032091</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1029/2022WR032091</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR032091?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> Research Article</prism:section><prism:volume> 59</prism:volume><prism:number> 2个</prism:number></item><item><link/>https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033910?af=R<pubDate> Tue, 21 Feb 2023 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-02-21T12:00:00-08:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley: Water Resources Research: Table of Contents<prism:coverdate> Wed, 01 Feb 2023 00:00:00 -0800</prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate> Wed, 01 Feb 2023 00:00:00 -0800</prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR033910</guid><title> Impact of Matrix Diffusion on Heat Transport Through Heterogeneous Fractured Aquifers</title><description> Water Resources Research, Volume 59, Issue 2, February 2023.</description><dc:description> Abstract Heat transport in fractured aquifers is determined by the combined effects of flow velocity heterogeneity in the fracture system, and diffusive exchange between the fluid in the fractures and the rock matrix, which can be assumed as impervious. We analyze the impacts of this diffusive exchange on the response to heat transport, as opposite to the pure advective displacement, which governs solute transport. We focus on the post‐peak behavior where we observe pre‐asymptotic regimes with slopes that differ from the signature of matrix diffusion, which exhibits a decay rate of −3/2. This deviation is driven by the variability of both velocity field and fracture aperture field. We derive theoretical models that predict these pre‐asymptotic tails under three extreme cases that can be related with specific network structures, that is, networks dominated by large or small fractures, networks with highly or poorly channelized flow. These theoretical predictions are compared with results from numerical simulations in different sets of three‐dimensional discrete fracture networks. We determine that the combined observation of solute and heat transport responses allows classifying the network in terms of connectivity structure, and partially characterizing the fracture aperture variability in terms of upscaled parameters.</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;Heat transport in fractured aquifers is determined by the combined effects of flow velocity heterogeneity in the fracture system, and diffusive exchange between the fluid in the fractures and the rock matrix, which can be assumed as impervious. We analyze the impacts of this diffusive exchange on the response to heat transport, as opposite to the pure advective displacement, which governs solute transport. We focus on the post-peak behavior where we observe pre-asymptotic regimes with slopes that differ from the signature of matrix diffusion, which exhibits a decay rate of −3/2. This deviation is driven by the variability of both velocity field and fracture aperture field. We derive theoretical models that predict these pre-asymptotic tails under three extreme cases that can be related with specific network structures, that is, networks dominated by large or small fractures, networks with highly or poorly channelized flow. These theoretical predictions are compared with results from numerical simulations in different sets of three-dimensional discrete fracture networks. We determine that the combined observation of solute and heat transport responses allows classifying the network in terms of connectivity structure, and partially characterizing the fracture aperture variability in terms of upscaled parameters.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> Silvia Simone, Olivier Bour, Philippe Davy</dc:creator><category> Research Article</category><dc:title> Impact of Matrix Diffusion on Heat Transport Through Heterogeneous Fractured Aquifers</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2022WR033910</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1029/2022WR033910</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033910?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> Research Article</prism:section><prism:volume> 59</prism:volume><prism:number> 2个</prism:number></item><item><link/>https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033318?af=R<pubDate> Tue, 21 Feb 2023 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-02-21T12:00:00-08:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley: Water Resources Research: Table of Contents<prism:coverdate> Wed, 01 Feb 2023 00:00:00 -0800</prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate> Wed, 01 Feb 2023 00:00:00 -0800</prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR033318</guid><title> A Novel Physics‐Aware Machine Learning‐Based Dynamic Error Correction Model for Improving Streamflow Forecast Accuracy</title><description> Water Resources Research, Volume 59, Issue 2, February 2023.</description><dc:description> Abstract Occurrences of extreme events, especially floods, have become more frequent and severe in the recent past due to the global impacts of climate change. In this context, possibilities for generating a near‐accurate streamflow forecast at higher lead times, which could be utilized for developing a reliable flood warning system to minimize the effects of extreme events, are highly important. This paper aims to investigate the potential of a novel hybrid modeling framework that couples the random forest algorithm, particle filter, and the HBV model for improving the overall accuracy of forecasts at higher lead times through the dynamic error correction schematic. The new framework simulates an ensemble of streamflow for estimating uncertainty associated with the predictions and is applied across two snow‐fed Himalayan rivers: the Beas River in India and the Sunkoshi River in Nepal. Several statistical indices along with graphical performance indicators were used for assessing the accuracy of the model performance and associated uncertainty. The modeling framework achieved the Nash Sutcliffe Efficiency of 0.94 and 0.98 in calibration and 0.95 and 0.99 in validation for the Beas and Sunkoshi river basin respectively for a 7‐day ahead forecast. Thus, the proposed framework can be considered as a promising tool having reasonably good performance in forecasting streamflow at a higher lead time.</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;Occurrences of extreme events, especially floods, have become more frequent and severe in the recent past due to the global impacts of climate change. In this context, possibilities for generating a near-accurate streamflow forecast at higher lead times, which could be utilized for developing a reliable flood warning system to minimize the effects of extreme events, are highly important. This paper aims to investigate the potential of a novel hybrid modeling framework that couples the random forest algorithm, particle filter, and the HBV model for improving the overall accuracy of forecasts at higher lead times through the dynamic error correction schematic. The new framework simulates an ensemble of streamflow for estimating uncertainty associated with the predictions and is applied across two snow-fed Himalayan rivers: the Beas River in India and the Sunkoshi River in Nepal. Several statistical indices along with graphical performance indicators were used for assessing the accuracy of the model performance and associated uncertainty. The modeling framework achieved the Nash Sutcliffe Efficiency of 0.94 and 0.98 in calibration and 0.95 and 0.99 in validation for the Beas and Sunkoshi river basin respectively for a 7-day ahead forecast. Thus, the proposed framework can be considered as a promising tool having reasonably good performance in forecasting streamflow at a higher lead time.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> Abhinanda Roy, KS Kasiviswanathan, Sandhya Patidar, Adebayo J. Adeloye, Bankaru‐Swamy Soundharajan, Chandra Shekhar P. Ojha</dc:creator><category> Research Article</category><dc:title> A Novel Physics‐Aware Machine Learning‐Based Dynamic Error Correction Model for Improving Streamflow Forecast Accuracy</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2022WR033318</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1029/2022WR033318</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033318?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> Research Article</prism:section><prism:volume> 59</prism:volume><prism:number> 2个</prism:number></item><item><link/>https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR032415?af=R<pubDate> Mon, 20 Feb 2023 18:08:36 -0800</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-02-20T06:08:36-08:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley: Water Resources Research: Table of Contents <prism:coverdate></prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate></prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR032415</guid><title> Grain for Green project may not threaten ecosystem sustainability by degrading water availability in humid karst landscapes</title><description> Water Resources Research, Accepted Article.</description><dc:description> Abstract Grain for Green project could result in high evapotranspiration (ET), exacerbate water shortage, and intensify conflicts in water demand between ecosystems and humans in many water‐limited areas. However, it is still unclear how vegetation restoration would influence ET in humid karst regions where abundant precipitation but quick leakage. Particularly, it is challenging that existing ET measurement methods are not applicable simultaneously for various ecosystems in such highly heterogeneous and fragmented landscapes. To solve this issue, this study, for the first time, develops a new ET measurement system, by integrating multi‐techniques, to quantify ET for multiple vegetation restoration types and identify their controlling factors in a humid karst region for three consecutive years. The results show that (1) for different succession stages during natural restoration, the ET of secondary forest (680 ± 7 mm yr‐1) >; shrub (564 ± 16 mm yr‐1) >; grass (546 ± 12 mm yr‐1) >; cropland (513 ± 8 mm yr‐1) (P &lt; 0.05); (2) ET of all ecosystems are far less than that of precipitation (1059 ± 63 mm yr‐1) but closer to potential ET (849 ± 11 mm yr‐1), and soil moisture has been maintained at >; 0.20 cm3cm‐3 in the growing season; (3) solar radiation and vapor pressure deficit are the two predominant factors on the ET (P &lt;0.01), while there is no significant relationship between ET and soil moisture (P >;0.05). The results suggest that vegetation restoration returned from cropland in humid karst regions increased ET but may not induce water scarcity for vegetation sustainability, at least under normal climatic conditions. This article is protected by copyright.版权所有。</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;Grain for Green project could result in high evapotranspiration (ET), exacerbate water shortage, and intensify conflicts in water demand between ecosystems and humans in many water-limited areas. However, it is still unclear how vegetation restoration would influence ET in humid karst regions where abundant precipitation but quick leakage. Particularly, it is challenging that existing ET measurement methods are not applicable simultaneously for various ecosystems in such highly heterogeneous and fragmented landscapes. To solve this issue, this study, for the first time, develops a new ET measurement system, by integrating multi-techniques, to quantify ET for multiple vegetation restoration types and identify their controlling factors in a humid karst region for three consecutive years. The results show that (1) for different succession stages during natural restoration, the ET of secondary forest (680 ± 7 mm yr&lt;sup>;-1&lt;/sup>;) &amp;gt; shrub (564 ± 16 mm yr&lt;sup>;-1&lt;/sup>;) &amp;gt; grass (546 ± 12 mm yr&lt;sup>;-1&lt;/sup>;) &amp;gt; cropland (513 ± 8 mm yr&lt;sup>;-1&lt;/sup>;) (P &amp;lt; 0.05); (2) ET of all ecosystems are far less than that of precipitation (1059 ± 63 mm yr&lt;sup>;-1&lt;/sup>;) but closer to potential ET (849 ± 11 mm yr&lt;sup>;-1&lt;/sup>;), and soil moisture has been maintained at &amp;gt; 0.20 cm&lt;sup>;3&lt;/sup>;cm&lt;sup>;-3&lt;/sup>; in the growing season; (3) solar radiation and vapor pressure deficit are the two predominant factors on the ET (&lt;i>;P&lt;/i>; &amp;lt;0.01), while there is no significant relationship between ET and soil moisture (&lt;i>;P&lt;/i>; &amp;gt;0.05). The results suggest that vegetation restoration returned from cropland in humid karst regions increased ET but may not induce water scarcity for vegetation sustainability, at least under normal climatic conditions.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This article is protected by copyright. All rights reserved.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> Ruzhou Yi, Xianli Xu, Yaohua Zhang, Zongda Ye, Kelin Wang</dc:creator><category> Research Article</category><dc:title> Grain for Green project may not threaten ecosystem sustainability by degrading water availability in humid karst landscapes</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2022WR032415</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1029/2022WR032415</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR032415?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> Research Article</prism:section></item></channel></rss>