<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:prism="http://prismstandard.org/namespaces/basic/2.0/"><channel><title> Wiley：水资源研究：目录</title><link/>https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R<description>水资源研究目录。最新和 EarlyView 问题的文章列表。</description><language>英文</language><copyright></copyright><managingeditor>wileyonlinelibrary@wiley.com（AGU 出版物）</managingeditor><pubDate> Wed, 12 Apr 2023 07:32:41 +0000</pubDate><lastbuilddate> 2023 年 4 月 12 日星期三 07:32:41 +0000</lastbuilddate><generator> Atypon®文学™</generator><docs> https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs><ttl> 10080</ttl><dc:title> Wiley：水资源研究：目录</dc:title><dc:publisher>威利</dc:publisher><prism:publicationname>水资源研究</prism:publicationname><atom:link href="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"></atom:link><image/><title> Wiley：水资源研究：目录</title><url>https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/pb-assets/journal-banners/19447973.jpg</url><link/> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R<item><link/> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033342?af=R<pubDate> Tue, 11 Apr 2023 13:07:46 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-04-11T01:07:46-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley：水资源研究：目录<prism:coverdate>2023 年 4 月 1 日星期六 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate> 2023 年 4 月 1 日星期六 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR033342</guid><title>是否可以通过同化高分辨率卫星土壤水分产品来量化灌溉用水？</title><description>水资源研究，第 59 卷，第 4 期，2023 年 4 月。</description><dc:description>摘要 灌溉是水循环中最大的人为干预，可以调节极端气候，但灌溉用水 (IWU) 在大多数地区仍然鲜为人知。微波遥感提供了一种通过监测灌溉引起的土壤水分变化来量化 IWU 的实用方法。然而，高分辨率卫星土壤水分数据通常很少见（例如，6-12 天），因此可能会错过灌溉事件。本研究通过使用粒子批量平滑器 (PBS) 的基于物理的陆地表面模型 (LSM) 同化高分辨率 (1 km) SMAP-Sentinel 1 遥感土壤水分来评估量化 IWU 的能力。设计了一套综合实验来评估不同的误差源。综合实验的结果表明，已知灌溉时间的无偏模拟可以产生准确的灌溉估计，相对于观察到的 IWU，平均年偏差为 0.45%，平均 R2 为 0.97。未知的灌溉时间会显着降低模型性能，导致平均年偏差增加到 23%，平均 R2 降低到 0.36。除了低观察频率（>;12 天）的实验外，在合成观察中添加随机噪声不会显着降低模型性能。在现实世界的实验中，当 IWU 的时间已知时，PBS 数据同化方法将观察到的 IWU 低估了 18.6%。与非灌溉像素相比，IWU 估计值在灌溉像素上始终显着更高，表明数据同化巧妙地将灌溉信号传递给 LSM。</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;摘要&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;灌溉是水循环中最大的人为干预，可以调节极端气候，但灌溉用水 (IWU) 在大多数地区仍然鲜为人知。微波遥感提供了一种通过监测灌溉引起的土壤水分变化来量化 IWU 的实用方法。然而，高分辨率卫星土壤水分数据通常很少（例如，6-12 天），因此可能会错过灌溉事件。本研究通过使用粒子批量平滑器 (PBS) 同化高分辨率 (1 km) SMAP-Sentinel 1 遥感土壤水分和基于物理的陆地表面模型 (LSM) 来评估量化 IWU 的能力。设计了一套综合实验来评估不同的误差源。综合实验的结果表明，已知灌溉时间的无偏模拟可以产生准确的灌溉估计，平均年偏差为 0.45%，平均 &lt;i>;R&lt;/i>; &lt;sup>;2&lt;/sup>; 为 0.97，相对观察 IWU。未知的灌溉时间会显着降低模型性能，导致平均年偏差增加到 23%，平均 &lt;i>;R&lt;/i>; &lt;sup>;2&lt;/sup>; 降低到 0.36。除了低观察频率（>;12 天）的实验外，向合成观察添加随机噪声不会显着降低模型性能。在现实世界的实验中，当 IWU 的时间已知时，PBS 数据同化方法将观察到的 IWU 低估了 18.6%。与非灌溉像素相比，灌溉像素的 IWU 估计值始终显着更高，表明数据同化巧妙地将灌溉信号传递给 LSM。&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> Ehsan Jalilvand、Ronnie Abolafia-Rosenzweig、Masoud Tajrishy、Sujay V. Kumar、Mohammad Reza Mohammadi、Narendra N. Das</dc:creator><category>研究文章</category><dc:title>是否可以通过同化高分辨率卫星土壤水分产品来量化灌溉用水？</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2022WR033342</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname>水资源研究</prism:publicationname><prism:doi>10.1029/2022WR033342</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033342?af=R</prism:url><prism:section>研究文章</prism:section><prism:volume>59</prism:volume><prism:number> 4个</prism:number></item><item><link/>https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033912?af=R<pubDate> Tue, 11 Apr 2023 12:34:12 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-04-11T12:34:12-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley：水资源研究：目录<prism:coverdate>2023 年 4 月 1 日星期六 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate> 2023 年 4 月 1 日星期六 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR033912</guid><title>配对空气和溪流温度分析 (PASTA) 以评估地下水对溪流的影响</title><description>水资源研究，第 59 卷，第 4 期，2023 年 4 月。</description><dc:description>摘要 地下水对于维持溪流基流和热稳定性至关重要；然而，地下水对水流的影响很难在广泛的空间尺度上进行评估。基流分离等技术需要水流记录，并且不能直接表明地下水入流是否可能来自更具动态的浅水流道。我们提出了一个网络工具应用程序 PASTA（配对空气和流温度分析；https://cuahsi.shinyapps.io/pasta/），它利用增加的公共流温度数据可用性和大规模、网格化的气候观测来提供新的和高效的关于地下水对河流的相对影响的见解。 PASTA 分析成对的空气和溪流水温信号，以评估溪流热敏感性和相对地下水影响的时空模式，包括关于主要源地下水深度（浅或深（即，大约 >;6 m 深度））的推断。该工具链接到公开可用的流温度数据集，并接受用户上传的数据集。由于不经常监测当地气温，当无法获得直接测量数据时，PASTA 会从全面的 Daymet 产品中提取每日气温数据，从而允许重新利用现有的气流温度数据。选择或上传数据后，该工具 (a) 按年份（水或日历）拟合每日流量和气温的正弦曲线，以指示地下水影响特征，以及 (b) 对流量与气温进行线性回归以指示流量热敏感性.结果以 ASCII 文件格式导出，创建了一种高效且易于使用的分析工具，用于采用新开发的从河流范围到景观尺度的热跟踪分析。</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;摘要&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;地下水对于维持溪流基流和热稳定性至关重要；然而，地下水对水流的影响很难在广泛的空间尺度上进行评估。基流分离等技术需要水流记录，并且不能直接表明地下水入流是否可能来自更具动态的浅水流道。我们展示了一个网络工具应用程序 &lt;i>;PASTA&lt;/i>;（成对空气和水流温度分析；&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;Link to external resource&quot; href=&quot;https://cuahsi.shinyapps.io/ pasta/&quot;>;https://cuahsi.shinyapps.io/pasta/&lt;/a>;）利用增加的公共河流温度数据可用性和大规模网格化气候观测来提供有关地下水对河流的相对影响的新的有效见解. &lt;i>;PASTA&lt;/i>; 分析成对的空气和溪流水温信号，以评估溪流热敏感性和相对地下水影响的时空模式，包括关于主要水源地下水深度（浅或深（即，大约 >;6 m 深度）的推断)).该工具链接到公开可用的流温度数据集，并接受用户上传的数据集。由于不经常监测当地气温，当无法获得直接测量数据时，PASTA 会从全面的 Daymet 产品中提取每日气温数据，从而允许重新利用现有的气流温度数据。选择或上传数据后，该工具 (a) 按年份（水或日历）拟合每日流量和气温的正弦曲线，以指示地下水影响特征，以及 (b) 对流量与气温进行线性回归以指示流量热敏感性.结果以 ASCII 文件格式导出，创建了一种高效且易于使用的分析工具，用于采用从河流范围到景观尺度的新开发的热跟踪分析。&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> Danielle K. Hare、Susanne A. Benz、Barret L. Kurylyk、Zachary C. Johnson、Neil C. Terry、Ashley M. Helton</dc:creator><category>方法</category><dc:title>配对空气和溪流温度分析 (PASTA) 以评估地下水对溪流的影响</dc:title><dc:identifier>10.1029/2022WR033912</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname>水资源研究</prism:publicationname><prism:doi>10.1029/2022WR033912</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033912?af=R</prism:url><prism:section>方法</prism:section><prism:volume>59</prism:volume><prism:number> 4个</prism:number></item><item><link/>https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033677?af=R<pubDate> Mon, 10 Apr 2023 11:56:08 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-04-10T11:56:08-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley：水资源研究：目录<prism:coverdate></prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate></prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR033677</guid><title>使用温度数据追踪可变饱和区的土壤水通量</title><description>水资源研究，接受的文章。</description><dc:description>摘要 水、汽和固相的共存以及热导率随含水量变化而发生的时空变化对用于计算可变饱和区水通量的伴热方法提出了挑战。在这项研究中，开发了一种采用有限差分数值格式以及有限记忆 Broyden-Fletcher-Goldfarb-Shanno 有界 (L-BFGS-B) 参数优化算法的新方法，以反溯追踪可变的垂直土壤水通量使用温度深度时间序列数据的饱和区。新开发的方法没有使用水力参数，仅使用相邻深度的温度时间序列数据作为边界条件。通过使用 L-BFGS-B 算法拟合目标深度的温度时间序列，优化给定位置的土壤水、蒸汽通量和热导率的时空变化。此外，该方法通过在具有饱和和自由排水底部边界的两根柱子中进行的不同饱和条件下的实验室实验以及具有相对稳定流动条件的五组不同流速进行验证。使用所提出的方法计算的土壤水通量与观测数据一致，从而验证了该方法在相对稳定流速应用中的可靠性。此外，将新方法应用于现场，使用测得的温度数据估算随时间变化的土壤水通量。计算得到的不同深度土壤水通量变化趋势与野外水文条件和观测结果一致。因此，本研究提供了一种计算效率高且易于实施的新型工具，可以使用温度测量来确定土壤水通量。</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;摘要&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;水、汽和固相的共存以及热导率随含水量变化的时空变化对用于计算水通量的伴热方法提出了挑战可变饱和区。在这项研究中，开发了一种采用有限差分数值方案以及有限记忆 Broyden–Fletcher–Goldfarb–Shanno 有界 (L-BFGS-B) 参数优化算法的新方法，以反溯追踪垂直土壤水通量使用温度深度时间序列数据的饱和区。新开发的方法没有使用水力参数，仅使用相邻深度的温度时间序列数据作为边界条件。通过使用 L-BFGS-B 算法拟合目标深度的温度时间序列，优化给定位置的土壤水、蒸汽通量和热导率的时空变化。此外，该方法通过在具有饱和和自由排水底部边界的两根柱子中进行的不同饱和条件下的实验室实验以及具有相对稳定流动条件的五组不同流速进行验证。使用所提出的方法计算的土壤水通量与观测数据一致，从而验证了该方法在相对稳定流速应用中的可靠性。此外，将新方法应用于现场，使用测得的温度数据估算随时间变化的土壤水通量。计算得到的不同深度土壤水通量变化趋势与野外水文条件和观测结果一致。因此，本研究提供了一种计算效率高且易于实施的新型工具，可通过温度测量来确定土壤水通量。&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> Meng Su, Rui Ma, 王云泉, Ziyong Sun, Maosheng Yin, Mengyan Ge</dc:creator><category>研究文章</category><dc:title>使用温度数据追踪可变饱和区的土壤水通量</dc:title><dc:identifier>10.1029/2022WR033677</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname>水资源研究</prism:publicationname><prism:doi>10.1029/2022WR033677</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033677?af=R</prism:url><prism:section>研究文章</prism:section></item><item><link/>https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033714?af=R<pubDate> Mon, 10 Apr 2023 11:54:27 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-04-10T11:54:27-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley：水资源研究：目录<prism:coverdate></prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate></prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR033714</guid><title>洪泛区连接渠道作为三角洲河网水文连通性的关键路径</title><description>水资源研究，接受的文章。</description><dc:description>摘要 河流分叉对于将水、沉积物和养分分配到三角洲河网的下游支流至关重要。然而，分叉的下游分支可以通过穿过三角洲漫滩的连接通道连接起来。作为下游控制的洪泛区连接通道可以影响河流分叉处的水分配，从而影响河网的水文连通性。然而，它的影响在很大程度上仍然难以捉摸。在这项研究中，我们探讨了连接下游支流的连接渠道如何影响上游分叉处的水分配和两个支流的水分配。调查是通过使用 Delft3D 的理想化数值模拟进行的，然后使用图论分析了对河网水文连通性的级联效应。结果表明，连接通道可以减轻上游分叉处的不对称水分配。然而，这是以在下游出口引起更多不均匀流动为代价的。流量调整是由于两个分支中空间水面坡度的改变与通过连接通道从一个通道到另一个通道的流量交换相关联。对水文连通性的进一步分析表明，连接渠道通常可以通过增强两个分支之间的流量交换来降低渠道网络对水文变化的脆弱性，尤其是入流变化。我们的结果表明，连接渠道是水文连通性的关键路径，这对三角洲河网及其漫滩的管理具有重要意义。</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;摘要&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;河流分叉对于将水、沉积物和养分分配到三角洲河网的下游支流至关重要。然而，分叉的下游分支可以通过穿过三角洲漫滩的连接通道连接起来。作为下游控制的洪泛区连接通道可以影响河流分叉处的水分配，从而影响河网的水文连通性。然而，它的影响在很大程度上仍然难以捉摸。在这项研究中，我们探讨了连接下游支流的连接渠道如何影响上游分叉处的水分配和两个支流的水分配。调查是通过使用 Delft3D 的理想化数值模拟进行的，然后使用图论分析了对河网水文连通性的级联效应。结果表明，连接通道可以减轻上游分叉处的不对称水分配。然而，这是以在下游出口引起更多不均匀流动为代价的。流量调整是由于两个分支中空间水面坡度的改变与通过连接通道从一个通道到另一个通道的流量交换相关联。对水文连通性的进一步分析表明，连接渠道通常可以通过增强两个分支之间的流量交换来降低渠道网络对水文变化的脆弱性，尤其是入流变化。我们的结果表明，连接渠道是水文连通性的关键路径，这对三角洲河网及其漫滩的管理具有重要意义。&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> Weilun Gao, Zheng Bing Wang, Maarten G. Kleinhans, Chiyuan Miao, Baoshan Cui, 邵东东</dc:creator><category>研究文章</category><dc:title>洪泛区连接渠道作为三角洲河网水文连通性的关键路径</dc:title><dc:identifier>10.1029/2022WR033714</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname>水资源研究</prism:publicationname><prism:doi>10.1029/2022WR033714</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033714?af=R</prism:url><prism:section>研究文章</prism:section></item><item><link/>https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033655?af=R<pubDate> Mon, 10 Apr 2023 11:54:15 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-04-10T11:54:15-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley：水资源研究：目录<prism:coverdate></prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate></prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR033655</guid><title>季节性水文预报的地球观测和现场数据同化评价</title><description>水资源研究，接受的文章。</description><dc:description>摘要 地球观测是对水文学现场测量的宝贵补充，因为它们可以在无法进行直接测量或测量成本过高的地方提供信息。最近的进展使得能够将不同物理变量的数据集同化到水文模型中，以更好地估计状态和通量。与气象强迫一起，同化数据对预报施加控制；因此，重要的是分配来自强迫和同化数据的贡献。质量评估有时是在伪现实中进行的，忽略了观察和模型的局限性。在这里，我们介绍了一个诊断框架，该框架考虑了观察以评估技能来源并推断同化和强迫数据的季节性重要性。我们使用来自缩小的全球环流模型的强迫数据集测试该框架，并吸收四个地球观测和两个现场数据集来初始化预测。我们使用 HYPE 模型调查了 2001-2015 年瑞典融雪主导流域的水文响应和季节预测。由于不同的同化数据和气象强迫，该框架允许评估季节性技能的提高。对于所研究的流域，所有地球观测和现场数据集都为最终预测添加了信息。数据同化影响预报技能的提前期也因数据集和季节而异，例如，同化雪水当量影响冬季超过 20 周的预报。最后，在所研究的以雪为主的流域中，同化数据集对于径流预报技能通常比气象强迫更重要。本文受版权保护。版权所有。</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;摘要&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;地球观测是对水文学现场测量的宝贵补充，因为它们可以在无法进行直接测量或测量成本过高的地方提供信息。最近的进展使得能够将不同物理变量的数据集同化到水文模型中，以更好地估计状态和通量。与气象强迫一起，同化数据对预报施加控制；因此，重要的是分配来自强迫和同化数据的贡献。质量评估有时是在伪现实中进行的，忽略了观察和模型的局限性。在这里，我们介绍了一个诊断框架，该框架考虑了观察以评估技能来源并推断同化和强迫数据的季节性重要性。我们使用来自缩小的全球环流模型的强迫数据集测试该框架，并吸收四个地球观测和两个现场数据集来初始化预测。我们使用 HYPE 模型调查了 2001-2015 年瑞典融雪流域的水文响应和季节预测。由于不同的同化数据和气象强迫，该框架允许评估季节性技能的提高。对于所研究的流域，所有地球观测和现场数据集都为最终预测添加了信息。数据同化影响预报技能的提前期也因数据集和季节而异，例如，同化雪水当量影响冬季超过 20 周的预报。最后，在所研究的以雪为主的流域中，同化数据集对于径流预报技能通常比气象强迫更重要。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;本文受版权保护。保留所有权利。&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> Jude L. Musuuza、Louise Crochemore、Ilias G. Pechlivanidis</dc:creator><category>研究文章</category><dc:title>季节性水文预报的地球观测和现场数据同化评价</dc:title><dc:identifier>10.1029/2022WR033655</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname>水资源研究</prism:publicationname><prism:doi>10.1029/2022WR033655</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033655?af=R</prism:url><prism:section>研究文章</prism:section></item><item><link/>https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033646?af=R<pubDate> Mon, 10 Apr 2023 11:53:59 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-04-10T11:53:59-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley：水资源研究：目录<prism:coverdate></prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate></prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR033646</guid><title>不同空间尺度水行星边界概念的定量应用综述</title><description>水资源研究，接受的文章。</description><dc:description>摘要 水行星边界 (PB) 量化了人类用水的安全操作空间，并被理解为根据预防原则设置在距选定阈值（或危险水平）安全距离处的控制变量。水PB对指导可持续发展具有重要意义，各种水PB多尺度定量评价已经开展。为了增进我们的理解并指导未来的应用，我们对自该概念引入以来发表的所有研究进行了全面审查。我们在文献中确定了总共 288 篇相关论文，并对 28 篇论文进行了系统回顾和荟萃分析，提供了不同空间尺度的 488 条数据记录。分析主要涉及相关量化指标（QIs）、量化方法、水PB与不同尺度用水现状的比较，以及相关问题的识别。最后，我们提出了未来重要研究的十个展望。这篇综述表明，作为早期研究领域的理论水 PB 框架已经逐渐发展，尽管可用的方法很少，而且不完善。为了解决以往研究的局限性，我们提出了两个改进框架来指导未来的研究：在一致的科学框架内进一步改进传统流行的量化多尺度水 PB 的方法和改进的量化不同尺度水 PB 的框架以获得更适合不同研究目的和研究领域的结果。基于这次审查，我们指出了一些很少受到关注的重要问题，包括安全距离的量化和多尺度水 PB 之间的联系。本文受版权保护。版权所有。</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;摘要&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;水星球边界 (PB) 量化了人类用水的安全操作空间，并被理解为与选定阈值（或危险水平）基于安全距离设置的控制变量本着预防原则。水PB对指导可持续发展具有重要意义，各种水PB多尺度定量评价已经开展。为了增进我们的理解并指导未来的应用，我们对自该概念引入以来发表的所有研究进行了全面审查。我们在文献中确定了总共 288 篇相关论文，并对 28 篇论文进行了系统回顾和荟萃分析，提供了不同空间尺度的 488 条数据记录。分析主要涉及相关量化指标（QIs）、量化方法、水PB与不同尺度用水现状的比较，以及相关问题的识别。最后，我们提出了未来重要研究的十个展望。这篇综述表明，作为一个早期研究领域的理论水-PB 框架已经逐渐发展，尽管可用的方法很少，而且还不完善。为了解决以往研究的局限性，我们提出了两个改进框架来指导未来的研究：在一致的科学框架内进一步改进传统流行的量化多尺度水 PB 的方法和改进的量化不同尺度水 PB 的框架以获得更适合不同研究目的和研究领域的结果。基于这篇综述，我们指出了一些鲜为人知的重要问题，包括安全距离的量化和多尺度水 PB 之间的联系。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;本文受版权保护。保留所有权利。&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator>韩思琪、冷国勇、于林飞</dc:creator><category>评论文章</category><dc:title>不同空间尺度水行星边界概念的定量应用综述</dc:title><dc:identifier>10.1029/2022WR033646</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname>水资源研究</prism:publicationname><prism:doi>10.1029/2022WR033646</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033646?af=R</prism:url><prism:section>评论文章</prism:section></item><item><link/>https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR032499?af=R<pubDate> Mon, 10 Apr 2023 06:46:39 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-04-10T06:46:39-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley：水资源研究：目录<prism:coverdate>2023 年 4 月 1 日星期六 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate> 2023 年 4 月 1 日星期六 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR032499</guid><title>新兴植被中的近床流结构和床剪应力</title><description>水资源研究，第 59 卷，第 4 期，2023 年 4 月。</description><dc:description>摘要 水流底部边界层 (BBL) 的结构影响一系列生物物理过程，包括沉积物运输、潜流交换和生物膜形成。虽然已经对裸露沉积物床上方的 BBL 结构进行了深入研究，但对水生植被中复杂的近床流动结构知之甚少。在这项研究中，我们使用高分辨率实验室测量和数值大涡模拟来研究在各种流动条件和密度下交错有序的涌现植被中的近床平均和湍流特性。植被要素尺度上的关键近床流特征具有很强的空间变异性。确定了提供最接近空间平均值的单点流量特性的测量位置。空间平均 BBL 厚度受植被密度的强烈影响。植被密度的这种影响是通过其对近床湍流动能 (TKE) 的直接控制而产生的，而后者又与 BBL 厚度呈负相关，无论是在给定流量中还是在此处研究的流量条件范围内。开发了一个基于近床 TKE 的模型来预测 BBL 厚度，并最终预测床层剪应力。模型预测与实验和数值结果非常吻合。这些发现为近床流动变量之间的物理联系提供了新的见解，因此有助于理解植被流动中存在的一些复杂的生物物理过程。</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;摘要&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;水流中底部边界层 (BBL) 的结构影响一系列生物物理过程，包括沉积物运输、潜流交换和生物膜形成。虽然 BBL 在裸露沉积物床上方的结构已得到充分研究，但对水生植被中复杂的近床流动结构知之甚少。在这项研究中，我们使用高分辨率实验室测量和数值大涡模拟来研究在各种流动条件和密度下交错有序的涌现植被中的近床平均和湍流特性。植被要素尺度上的关键近床流特征具有很强的空间变异性。确定了提供最接近空间平均值的单点流量特性的测量位置。空间平均 BBL 厚度受植被密度的强烈影响。植被密度的这种影响是通过其对近床湍流动能 (TKE) 的直接控制而产生的，而后者又与 BBL 厚度呈负相关，无论是在给定流量中还是在此处研究的流量条件范围内。开发了一个基于近床 TKE 的模型来预测 BBL 厚度，并最终预测床层剪应力。模型预测与实验和数值结果非常吻合。这些发现为近床流动变量之间的物理联系提供了新的见解，因此有助于理解植被流动中存在的一些复杂的生物物理过程。&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> M. Conde-Frias、M. Ghisalberti、RJ Lowe、M. Abdolahpour、V. Etminan</dc:creator><category>研究文章</category><dc:title>新兴植被中的近床流结构和床剪应力</dc:title><dc:identifier>10.1029/2022WR032499</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname>水资源研究</prism:publicationname><prism:doi>10.1029/2022WR032499</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR032499?af=R</prism:url><prism:section>研究文章</prism:section><prism:volume>59</prism:volume><prism:number> 4个</prism:number></item><item><link/>https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR034188?af=R<pubDate> Mon, 10 Apr 2023 06:37:45 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-04-10T06:37:45-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley：水资源研究：目录<prism:coverdate>2023 年 4 月 1 日星期六 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate> 2023 年 4 月 1 日星期六 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR034188</guid><title>使用 Burg 熵谱分析和多分辨率方法对美国大陆进行长周期干旱预报</title><description>水资源研究，第 59 卷，第 4 期，2023 年 4 月。</description><dc:description>摘要 气候变化中，极端干旱事件频发，社会经济环境损失加剧。 To be prepared for upcoming droughts, proactive drought management planning based on drought forecasting is being highlighted. This study, therefore, developed a long‐term drought forecasting model using Burg entropy spectral analysis with the maximal overlap discrete wavelet transform across the continental United States (CONUS). The model forecasted monthly self‐calibrated Palmer Drought Severity Index (scPDSI) up to median lead times of 12 months with root mean square error less than 0.8 and the modified Nash‐Sutcliffe efficiency coefficient greater than 0.6 across CONUS. The lead‐time with an acceptable accuracy was affected by how the model parameterized low‐frequency structure of scPDSI that was significantly correlated to sea surface temperature climate mode. The correlation between low‐frequency signals and Niño‐3.4 tended to be weaker for the regions located at higher elevations. Thus, higher variability in spectral structures of low‐frequency signals at higher elevation‐regions led to shorter memory/persistency of time series that shortened the forecast lead time. Besides, higher variability in precipitation linked to the variability of scPDIS also shortened the forecast lead time. To appraise the applicability of the suggested forecast model to drought management planning, drought characteristics (ie, severity, duration, and area) were obtained by the three‐dimensional drought clustering algorithm for the forecasted and observed scPDSI. Then, risk was analyzed for drought characteristics using the vine copula. Risk analysis for drought characteristics forecasted up to a 12‐month lead time showed the potential for applicability of the model to drought mitigation plans.</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;Amid climate change, extreme droughts have occurred more frequently, accompanied by increasing socio-economic-environmental losses. To be prepared for upcoming droughts, proactive drought management planning based on drought forecasting is being highlighted. This study, therefore, developed a long-term drought forecasting model using Burg entropy spectral analysis with the maximal overlap discrete wavelet transform across the continental United States (CONUS). The model forecasted monthly self-calibrated Palmer Drought Severity Index (scPDSI) up to median lead times of 12 months with root mean square error less than 0.8 and the modified Nash-Sutcliffe efficiency coefficient greater than 0.6 across CONUS. The lead-time with an acceptable accuracy was affected by how the model parameterized low-frequency structure of scPDSI that was significantly correlated to sea surface temperature climate mode. The correlation between low-frequency signals and Niño-3.4 tended to be weaker for the regions located at higher elevations. Thus, higher variability in spectral structures of low-frequency signals at higher elevation-regions led to shorter memory/persistency of time series that shortened the forecast lead time. Besides, higher variability in precipitation linked to the variability of scPDIS also shortened the forecast lead time. To appraise the applicability of the suggested forecast model to drought management planning, drought characteristics (ie, severity, duration, and area) were obtained by the three-dimensional drought clustering algorithm for the forecasted and observed scPDSI. Then, risk was analyzed for drought characteristics using the vine copula. Risk analysis for drought characteristics forecasted up to a 12-month lead time showed the potential for applicability of the model to drought mitigation plans.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> Jeongwoo Han, Vijay P. Singh</dc:creator><category> Research Article</category><dc:title> Long‐Lead Drought Forecasting Across the Continental United States Using Burg Entropy Spectral Analysis With a Multiresolution Approach</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2022WR034188</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1029/2022WR034188</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR034188?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> Research Article</prism:section><prism:volume> 59</prism:volume><prism:number> 4个</prism:number></item><item><link/>https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033133?af=R<pubDate> Mon, 10 Apr 2023 06:37:29 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-04-10T06:37:29-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley: Water Resources Research: Table of Contents<prism:coverdate> Sat, 01 Apr 2023 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate> Sat, 01 Apr 2023 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR033133</guid><title> On the Spatial Scale Dependence of Long‐Term Persistence in Global Annual Precipitation Data and the Hurst Phenomenon</title><description> Water Resources Research, Volume 59, Issue 4, April 2023.</description><dc:description> Abstract Precipitation deficits are the main physical drivers of droughts across the globe, and their level of persistence can be characterized by the Hurst coefficient H (0.5 &lt; H &lt; 1), with high H indicating strong long‐term persistence (LTP). Previous analyses of point and gridded annual global precipitation datasets have concluded that LTP in precipitation is weak (H ∼ 0.6) which is inconsistent with higher values of H for large river basins, for example, the Nile. Based on an analysis of gridded annual precipitation data for eight selected regions distributed across the globe, an important new finding is that H increases with the spatial scale of averaging, with mean H values at the grid and regional scale of 0.66 and 0.83, respectively. The discovery of enhanced LTP at the regional scale of averaging of precipitation has important implications for characterizing the severity of regional droughts, as well as LTP in the annual flows of large rivers and recharge to major aquifers. Teleconnections with known modes of low frequency variability in the global climate system are demonstrated using correlation analysis and stepwise regression. Despite having several constituent regions exhibiting LTP, the Northern Hemisphere surprisingly has no LTP; this is shown to result from different modes of low frequency climatic variability canceling each other out. LTP for the Southern Hemisphere is moderate, and weak for Global average precipitation. LTP in Blue Nile basin scale precipitation is shown to explain the Hurst Phenomenon in naturalized annual flows for the River Nile, more than 70 years after its discovery by Hurst.</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;Precipitation deficits are the main physical drivers of droughts across the globe, and their level of persistence can be characterized by the Hurst coefficient &lt;i>;H&lt;/i>; (0.5 &amp;lt; &lt;i>;H&lt;/i>; &amp;lt; 1), with high &lt;i>;H&lt;/i>; indicating strong long-term persistence (LTP). Previous analyses of point and gridded annual global precipitation datasets have concluded that LTP in precipitation is weak (&lt;i>;H&lt;/i>; ∼ 0.6) which is inconsistent with higher values of &lt;i>;H&lt;/i>; for large river basins, for example, the Nile. Based on an analysis of gridded annual precipitation data for eight selected regions distributed across the globe, an important new finding is that &lt;i>;H&lt;/i>; increases with the spatial scale of averaging, with mean &lt;i>;H&lt;/i>; values at the grid and regional scale of 0.66 and 0.83, respectively. The discovery of enhanced LTP at the regional scale of averaging of precipitation has important implications for characterizing the severity of regional droughts, as well as LTP in the annual flows of large rivers and recharge to major aquifers. Teleconnections with known modes of low frequency variability in the global climate system are demonstrated using correlation analysis and stepwise regression. Despite having several constituent regions exhibiting LTP, the Northern Hemisphere surprisingly has no LTP; this is shown to result from different modes of low frequency climatic variability canceling each other out. LTP for the Southern Hemisphere is moderate, and weak for Global average precipitation. LTP in Blue Nile basin scale precipitation is shown to explain the Hurst Phenomenon in naturalized annual flows for the River Nile, more than 70 years after its discovery by Hurst.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> Enda O&#39;Connell, Greg O&#39;Donnell, Demetris Koutsoyiannis</dc:creator><category> Research Article</category><dc:title> On the Spatial Scale Dependence of Long‐Term Persistence in Global Annual Precipitation Data and the Hurst Phenomenon</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2022WR033133</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1029/2022WR033133</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033133?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> Research Article</prism:section><prism:volume> 59</prism:volume><prism:number> 4个</prism:number></item><item><link/>https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR034092?af=R<pubDate> Mon, 10 Apr 2023 06:35:29 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-04-10T06:35:29-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley: Water Resources Research: Table of Contents<prism:coverdate> Sat, 01 Apr 2023 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate> Sat, 01 Apr 2023 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR034092</guid><title> Streamflow Prediction in Poorly Gauged Watersheds in the United States Through Data‐Driven Sparse Sensing</title><description> Water Resources Research, Volume 59, Issue 4, April 2023.</description><dc:description> Abstract Many rivers and streams are ungauged or poorly gauged and predicting streamflow in such watersheds is challenging. Although streamflow signals result from processes with different frequencies, they can be “sparse” or have a “lower‐dimensional” representation in a transformed feature space. In such cases, if this appropriate feature space can be identified from streamflow data in gauged watersheds by dimensionality reduction, streamflow in poorly gauged watersheds can be predicted with a few measurements taken. This study utilized this framework, named data‐driven sparse sensing (DSS), to predict daily‐scale streamflow in 543 watersheds across the contiguous United States. A tailored library of features was extracted from streamflow training data in watersheds within the same climatic region, and this feature space was used to reconstruct streamflow in poorly gauged watersheds and identify the optimal timings for measurement. Among different regions, streamflow in snowmelt‐dominated and baseflow‐dominated watersheds (eg, Rocky Mountains) was more effectively predicted with fewer streamflow measurements taken. The prediction efficiency in some rainfall‐dominated regions, for example, New England and the Pacific coast, increased significantly with an increasing number of measurements. The spatial variability of prediction efficiency can be attributed to the process‐driven mechanisms and the dimensionality of watershed dynamics. Storage‐dominated systems are lower‐dimensional and more predictable than rainfall‐dominated systems. Measurements taken during periods with large streamflow magnitudes and/or variances are more informative and lead to better predictions. This study demonstrates that DSS can be an especially useful technique to integrate ground‐based measurements with remotely sensed data for streamflow prediction, sensor placement, and watershed classification.</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;Many rivers and streams are ungauged or poorly gauged and predicting streamflow in such watersheds is challenging. Although streamflow signals result from processes with different frequencies, they can be “sparse” or have a “lower-dimensional” representation in a transformed feature space. In such cases, if this appropriate feature space can be identified from streamflow data in gauged watersheds by dimensionality reduction, streamflow in poorly gauged watersheds can be predicted with a few measurements taken. This study utilized this framework, named data-driven sparse sensing (DSS), to predict daily-scale streamflow in 543 watersheds across the contiguous United States. A tailored library of features was extracted from streamflow training data in watersheds within the same climatic region, and this feature space was used to reconstruct streamflow in poorly gauged watersheds and identify the optimal timings for measurement. Among different regions, streamflow in snowmelt-dominated and baseflow-dominated watersheds (eg, Rocky Mountains) was more effectively predicted with fewer streamflow measurements taken. The prediction efficiency in some rainfall-dominated regions, for example, New England and the Pacific coast, increased significantly with an increasing number of measurements. The spatial variability of prediction efficiency can be attributed to the process-driven mechanisms and the dimensionality of watershed dynamics. Storage-dominated systems are lower-dimensional and more predictable than rainfall-dominated systems. Measurements taken during periods with large streamflow magnitudes and/or variances are more informative and lead to better predictions. This study demonstrates that DSS can be an especially useful technique to integrate ground-based measurements with remotely sensed data for streamflow prediction, sensor placement, and watershed classification.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> Kun Zhang, Mitul Luhar, Manuela I. Brunner, Anthony J. Parolari</dc:creator><category> Research Article</category><dc:title> Streamflow Prediction in Poorly Gauged Watersheds in the United States Through Data‐Driven Sparse Sensing</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2022WR034092</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1029/2022WR034092</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR034092?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> Research Article</prism:section><prism:volume> 59</prism:volume><prism:number> 4个</prism:number></item><item><link/>https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR032336?af=R<pubDate> Fri, 07 Apr 2023 06:17:09 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-04-07T06:17:09-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley: Water Resources Research: Table of Contents<prism:coverdate> Sat, 01 Apr 2023 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate> Sat, 01 Apr 2023 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR032336</guid><title> The Benefits of Using State‐Of‐The‐Art Digital Soil Properties Maps to Improve the Modeling of Soil Moisture in Land Surface Models</title><description> Water Resources Research, Volume 59, Issue 4, April 2023.</description><dc:description> Abstract This study assesses the added value of using emerging maps of soil properties to improve surface soil moisture simulations using the HydroBlocks land surface model with different soil hydraulic parameterization schemes. Simulations were run at an hourly 30‐m resolution between 2012 and 2019 and evaluated against US Climate Reference Network measurements. The results show that state‐of‐the‐art soil properties maps (POLARIS and SoilGrids250m V2.0) improve the accuracy of simulated surface soil moisture when compared to the STATSGO‐derived CONUS‐SOIL map. Contemporary pedotransfer functions (multi‐linear regression and Artificial Neural Networks‐based) also improve model performance in comparison to the lookup table‐derived soil parameterization schemes. The addition of vertical heterogeneity to the soil properties further improves the mean Kling‐Gupta efficiency by 0.04 and lowers the mean Root mean square error by 0.003 over the CONUS. This study demonstrates that land surface modeling can be improved by using state‐of‐the‐art maps of soil properties, accounting for the vertical heterogeneity of soils, and advancing the use of contemporary pedotransfer functions.</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;This study assesses the added value of using emerging maps of soil properties to improve surface soil moisture simulations using the HydroBlocks land surface model with different soil hydraulic parameterization schemes. Simulations were run at an hourly 30-m resolution between 2012 and 2019 and evaluated against US Climate Reference Network measurements. The results show that state-of-the-art soil properties maps (POLARIS and SoilGrids250m V2.0) improve the accuracy of simulated surface soil moisture when compared to the STATSGO-derived CONUS-SOIL map. Contemporary pedotransfer functions (multi-linear regression and Artificial Neural Networks-based) also improve model performance in comparison to the lookup table-derived soil parameterization schemes. The addition of vertical heterogeneity to the soil properties further improves the mean Kling-Gupta efficiency by 0.04 and lowers the mean Root mean square error by 0.003 over the CONUS. This study demonstrates that land surface modeling can be improved by using state-of-the-art maps of soil properties, accounting for the vertical heterogeneity of soils, and advancing the use of contemporary pedotransfer functions.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> Chengcheng Xu, Laura Torres‐Rojas, Noemi Vergopolan, Nathaniel W. Chaney</dc:creator><category> Research Article</category><dc:title> The Benefits of Using State‐Of‐The‐Art Digital Soil Properties Maps to Improve the Modeling of Soil Moisture in Land Surface Models</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2022WR032336</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1029/2022WR032336</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR032336?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> Research Article</prism:section><prism:volume> 59</prism:volume><prism:number> 4个</prism:number></item><item><link/>https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033618?af=R<pubDate> Fri, 07 Apr 2023 06:14:54 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-04-07T06:14:54-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley: Water Resources Research: Table of Contents<prism:coverdate> Sat, 01 Apr 2023 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate> Sat, 01 Apr 2023 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR033618</guid><title> Response of Two Glaciers in Different Climate Settings of the Tibetan Plateau to Climate Change Through Year 2100 Using a Hybrid Modeling Approach</title><description> Water Resources Research, Volume 59, Issue 4, April 2023.</description><dc:description> Abstract Glaciers in High Mountain Asia (HMA) have been continuously retreating over the past four decades under global warming, affecting water availability for humans and ecosystems. However, the potential differences in mass loss and glacier runoff between maritime and continental glaciers of HMA are poorly understood. To understand the response of both types of glaciers to climate change, this study developed a hybrid modeling approach suited to data‐sparse regions, and applied the proposed approach to the Parlung No. 94 Glacier (a maritime glacier) and the Dongkemadi Glacier (a continental glacier) to project glacier change under climate change. Results show that the maritime glacier has a higher balance amplitude and more negative net balance than the continental glacier. Forced by model outputs from the sixth phase of the Coupled Model Intercomparison Project, both glaciers are projected to melt almost entirely by year 2100 under the highest emission scenario (SSP585). The projected year by which the continental glacier&#39;s volume (area) is expected to halve, relative to year 2018, is about 5–11 (14) years later than that of the maritime glacier due to lower glacier retreat rates. Glacier runoff projections indicate that the peak glacier runoff occurs later and is larger for higher emission scenarios and for the continental glacier than the maritime glacier. The peak water year for the Dongkemadi Glacier is projected to occur about 24–35 years later than for the Parlung No. 94 Glacier, for which it is expected to occur by the mid‐21st‐century.</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;Glaciers in High Mountain Asia (HMA) have been continuously retreating over the past four decades under global warming, affecting water availability for humans and ecosystems. However, the potential differences in mass loss and glacier runoff between maritime and continental glaciers of HMA are poorly understood. To understand the response of both types of glaciers to climate change, this study developed a hybrid modeling approach suited to data-sparse regions, and applied the proposed approach to the Parlung No. 94 Glacier (a maritime glacier) and the Dongkemadi Glacier (a continental glacier) to project glacier change under climate change. Results show that the maritime glacier has a higher balance amplitude and more negative net balance than the continental glacier. Forced by model outputs from the sixth phase of the Coupled Model Intercomparison Project, both glaciers are projected to melt almost entirely by year 2100 under the highest emission scenario (SSP585). The projected year by which the continental glacier&#39;s volume (area) is expected to halve, relative to year 2018, is about 5–11 (14) years later than that of the maritime glacier due to lower glacier retreat rates. Glacier runoff projections indicate that the peak glacier runoff occurs later and is larger for higher emission scenarios and for the continental glacier than the maritime glacier. The peak water year for the Dongkemadi Glacier is projected to occur about 24–35 years later than for the Parlung No. 94 Glacier, for which it is expected to occur by the mid-21st-century.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> Pengfei Han, Di Long, Fanyu Zhao, Louise J. Slater</dc:creator><category> Research Article</category><dc:title> Response of Two Glaciers in Different Climate Settings of the Tibetan Plateau to Climate Change Through Year 2100 Using a Hybrid Modeling Approach</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2022WR033618</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1029/2022WR033618</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033618?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> Research Article</prism:section><prism:volume> 59</prism:volume><prism:number> 4个</prism:number></item><item><link/>https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR032834?af=R<pubDate> Fri, 07 Apr 2023 06:10:57 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-04-07T06:10:57-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley: Water Resources Research: Table of Contents<prism:coverdate> Sat, 01 Apr 2023 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate> Sat, 01 Apr 2023 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR032834</guid><title> Probabilistic Sensitivity Analysis With Dependent Variables: Covariance‐Based Decomposition of Hydrologic Models</title><description> Water Resources Research, Volume 59, Issue 4, April 2023.</description><dc:description> Abstract Variance‐based analysis has emerged as method of choice for quantifying the sensitivity of the output, y, of a scalar‐valued square‐integrable function, f ∈ L2(), to its d ≥ 1 input variables, x = {x1, …, xd}, with support . The prototype of this approach, Sobol&#39;s method is a generalization of the analysis of variance (ANOVA) to d >; 2 independent input variables and decomposes y, as sum of elementary functions of zeroth‐, first‐, second‐, up to dth‐order. This independence assumption is mathematically convenient but may not be borne out of the causal or correlational relationships between the x&#39;s. This paper is concerned with variance‐based sensitivity analysis (SA) for correlated input variables, for example, multivariate dependencies in a posterior parameter distribution. We use high‐dimensional model representation (HDMR) of Li et al. (2010, https://doi.org/10.1021/jp9096919), Li and Rabitz (2012, https://doi.org/10.1007/s10910-011-9898-0) and replace Sobol&#39;s elementary functions with so‐called component functions with unknown expansion coefficients to disentangle the structural, correlative and total contribution of input factors. We contrast the default HDMR methodology with cubic B‐splines and sequential coefficient estimation against its successor, HDMRext of Li and Rabitz (2012, https://doi.org/10.1007/s10910-011-9898-0), which uses polynomial component functions with an extended orthonormalized basis. Benchmark experiments confirm that HDMR and HDMRext parse out the structural and correlative contributions of input factors to the model output and infer an optimal experimental design with parameter correlation. Our last study applies HDMRext to probabilistic SA of a watershed model. The multivariate posterior parameter distribution supports model emulation and yields sensitivity indices that pertain to measured discharge data.</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;Variance-based analysis has emerged as method of choice for quantifying the sensitivity of the output, &lt;i>;y&lt;/i>;, of a scalar-valued square-integrable function, &lt;i>;f&lt;/i>; ∈ &lt;i>;L&lt;/i>; &lt;sup>;2&lt;/sup>;(), to its &lt;i>;d&lt;/i>; ≥ 1 input variables, &lt;b>;x&lt;/b>; = {&lt;i>;x&lt;/i>; &lt;sub>;1&lt;/sub>;, …, &lt;i>;x&lt;/i>; &lt;sub>; &lt;i>;d&lt;/i>; &lt;/sub>;}, with support . The prototype of this approach, Sobol&#39;s method is a generalization of the analysis of variance (ANOVA) to &lt;i>;d&lt;/i>; &amp;gt; 2 independent input variables and decomposes &lt;i>;y&lt;/i>;, as sum of elementary functions of zeroth-, first-, second-, up to &lt;i>;d&lt;/i>;th-order. This independence assumption is mathematically convenient but may not be borne out of the causal or correlational relationships between the &lt;i>;x&lt;/i>;&#39;s. This paper is concerned with variance-based sensitivity analysis (SA) for correlated input variables, for example, multivariate dependencies in a posterior parameter distribution. We use high-dimensional model representation (HDMR) of Li et al. (2010, &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;Link to external resource&quot; href=&quot;https://doi.org/10.1021/jp9096919&quot;>;https://doi.org/10.1021/jp9096919&lt;/a>;), Li and Rabitz (2012, &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;Link to external resource&quot; href=&quot;https://doi.org/10.1007/s10910-011-9898-0&quot;>;https://doi.org/10.1007/s10910-011-9898-0&lt;/a>;) and replace Sobol&#39;s elementary functions with so-called component functions with unknown expansion coefficients to disentangle the structural, correlative and total contribution of input factors. We contrast the default HDMR methodology with cubic B-splines and sequential coefficient estimation against its successor, HDMR&lt;sub>;ext&lt;/sub>; of Li and Rabitz (2012, &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;Link to external resource&quot; href=&quot;https://doi.org/10.1007/s10910-011-9898-0&quot;>;https://doi.org/10.1007/s10910-011-9898-0&lt;/a>;), which uses polynomial component functions with an extended orthonormalized basis. Benchmark experiments confirm that HDMR and HDMR&lt;sub>;ext&lt;/sub>; parse out the structural and correlative contributions of input factors to the model output and infer an optimal experimental design with parameter correlation. Our last study applies HDMR&lt;sub>;ext&lt;/sub>; to probabilistic SA of a watershed model. The multivariate posterior parameter distribution supports model emulation and yields sensitivity indices that pertain to measured discharge data.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> Yifu Gao, Abdullah Sahin, Jasper A. Vrugt</dc:creator><category> Research Article</category><dc:title> Probabilistic Sensitivity Analysis With Dependent Variables: Covariance‐Based Decomposition of Hydrologic Models</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2022WR032834</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1029/2022WR032834</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR032834?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> Research Article</prism:section><prism:volume> 59</prism:volume><prism:number> 4个</prism:number></item><item><link/>https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR034211?af=R<pubDate> Thu, 06 Apr 2023 06:34:20 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-04-06T06:34:20-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley: Water Resources Research: Table of Contents<prism:coverdate> Sat, 01 Apr 2023 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate> Sat, 01 Apr 2023 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR034211</guid><title> New Insights Into Freezing Behavior of Saturated and Air‐Entrained Porous Media via a Micromechanics‐Based Thermo‐Hydro‐Mechanical Model</title><description> Water Resources Research, Volume 59, Issue 4, April 2023.</description><dc:description> Abstract A micromechanics‐based thermo‐hydro‐mechanical model for capturing the freezing behavior of porous media is devised, where a microstructure‐dependent constitutive relation, thermo‐hydro‐mechanical conditions, and the origin of freezing deformation are comprehensively considered. A micromechanical upscaling approach is proposed to improve the physical understanding of the freezing behavior of porous media. Comparisons against experimental and theoretical results suggest that the present model is a reliable means to predict the freezing deformation of saturated and air‐entrained porous media. The results show that the freezing deformation induced by the hydraulic pressure strongly depends on the boundary and air‐entrained conditions, and the undercooling phenomenon can be captured well. Moreover, the magnitude of surface energy (0–8 MPa) is in the ascending order of saturated undrained, drained, and air‐entrained conditions. The proposed model sheds light on the quantitative effects of freezing rate, liquid water transfer, and pore shape on the freezing deformation of porous media, which can provide insights into the freezing resistance mechanism of porous media.</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;A micromechanics-based thermo-hydro-mechanical model for capturing the freezing behavior of porous media is devised, where a microstructure-dependent constitutive relation, thermo-hydro-mechanical conditions, and the origin of freezing deformation are comprehensively considered. A micromechanical upscaling approach is proposed to improve the physical understanding of the freezing behavior of porous media. Comparisons against experimental and theoretical results suggest that the present model is a reliable means to predict the freezing deformation of saturated and air-entrained porous media. The results show that the freezing deformation induced by the hydraulic pressure strongly depends on the boundary and air-entrained conditions, and the undercooling phenomenon can be captured well. Moreover, the magnitude of surface energy (0–8 MPa) is in the ascending order of saturated undrained, drained, and air-entrained conditions. The proposed model sheds light on the quantitative effects of freezing rate, liquid water transfer, and pore shape on the freezing deformation of porous media, which can provide insights into the freezing resistance mechanism of porous media.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> Weiqi Guo, Fengjuan Wang, Yang Wu, Jinyang Jiang, Wenxiang Xu</dc:creator><category> Research Article</category><dc:title> New Insights Into Freezing Behavior of Saturated and Air‐Entrained Porous Media via a Micromechanics‐Based Thermo‐Hydro‐Mechanical Model</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2022WR034211</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1029/2022WR034211</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR034211?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> Research Article</prism:section><prism:volume> 59</prism:volume><prism:number> 4个</prism:number></item><item><link/>https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR032559?af=R<pubDate> Thu, 06 Apr 2023 06:28:13 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-04-06T06:28:13-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley: Water Resources Research: Table of Contents<prism:coverdate> Sat, 01 Apr 2023 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate> Sat, 01 Apr 2023 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR032559</guid><title> An Economic Model of Spatial and Temporal Water Trade in the Australian Southern Murray‐Darling Basin</title><description> Water Resources Research, Volume 59, Issue 4, April 2023.</description><dc:description> Abstract Within the Australian southern Murray‐Darling Basin (sMDB) water markets have become a key institutional response to water scarcity and environmental problems. These markets facilitate trading of water among many users and across multiple connected regions. Increasingly, these markets also support intertemporal transfers via the carryover of user water allocations within public water storages. While trading can improve the spatial allocation of water, carryover can improve the temporal allocation by ensuring storage reserves reflect prevailing user preferences. This paper presents an economic model of water markets and irrigated agriculture in the sMDB. A reduced‐form statistical model of water demand is estimated using historical irrigation and water market data. This statistical model is placed within an economic partial‐equilibrium framework accounting for both interregional trade and interyear carryover. The model is solved numerically for a dynamic market equilibrium given assumptions over future stochastic water supplies. Out‐of‐sample tests show the model can realistically simulate water market prices and irrigation activity across the basin. The model is applied to estimate the economic benefits of interregional water trading and interyear carryover. Results show around a third of the economic benefits of water markets in the region can be attributed to interyear carryover.</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;Within the Australian southern Murray-Darling Basin (sMDB) water markets have become a key institutional response to water scarcity and environmental problems. These markets facilitate trading of water among many users and across multiple connected regions. Increasingly, these markets also support intertemporal transfers via the carryover of user water allocations within public water storages. While trading can improve the spatial allocation of water, carryover can improve the temporal allocation by ensuring storage reserves reflect prevailing user preferences. This paper presents an economic model of water markets and irrigated agriculture in the sMDB. A reduced-form statistical model of water demand is estimated using historical irrigation and water market data. This statistical model is placed within an economic partial-equilibrium framework accounting for both interregional trade and interyear carryover. The model is solved numerically for a dynamic market equilibrium given assumptions over future stochastic water supplies. Out-of-sample tests show the model can realistically simulate water market prices and irrigation activity across the basin. The model is applied to estimate the economic benefits of interregional water trading and interyear carryover. Results show around a third of the economic benefits of water markets in the region can be attributed to interyear carryover.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> Neal Hughes, Mihir Gupta, Linden Whittle, Tim Westwood</dc:creator><category> Research Article</category><dc:title> An Economic Model of Spatial and Temporal Water Trade in the Australian Southern Murray‐Darling Basin</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2022WR032559</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1029/2022WR032559</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR032559?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> Research Article</prism:section><prism:volume> 59</prism:volume><prism:number> 4个</prism:number></item><item><link/>https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2021WR031614?af=R<pubDate> Thu, 06 Apr 2023 06:25:15 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-04-06T06:25:15-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley: Water Resources Research: Table of Contents<prism:coverdate> Sat, 01 Apr 2023 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate> Sat, 01 Apr 2023 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2021WR031614</guid><title> A Framework for Estimating Global River Discharge From the Surface Water and Ocean Topography Satellite Mission</title><description> Water Resources Research, Volume 59, Issue 4, April 2023.</description><dc:description> Abstract The Surface Water and Ocean Topography (SWOT) mission will vastly expand measurements of global rivers, providing critical new data sets for both gaged and ungaged basins. SWOT discharge products (available approximately 1 year after launch) will provide discharge for all river that reaches wider than 100 m. In this paper, we describe how SWOT discharge produced and archived by the US and French space agencies will be computed from measurements of river water surface elevation, width, and slope and ancillary data, along with expected discharge accuracy. We present for the first time a complete estimate of the SWOT discharge uncertainty budget, with separate terms for random (standard error) and systematic (bias) uncertainty components in river discharge time series. We expect that discharge uncertainty will be less than 30% for two‐thirds of global reaches and will be dominated by bias. Separate river discharge estimates will combine both SWOT and in situ data; these “gage‐constrained” discharge estimates can be expected to have lower systematic uncertainty. Temporal variations in river discharge time series will be dominated by random error and are expected to be estimated within 15% for nearly all reaches, allowing accurate inference of event flow dynamics globally, including in ungaged basins. We believe this level of accuracy lays the groundwork for SWOT to enable breakthroughs in global hydrologic science.</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;The Surface Water and Ocean Topography (SWOT) mission will vastly expand measurements of global rivers, providing critical new data sets for both gaged and ungaged basins. SWOT discharge products (available approximately 1 year after launch) will provide discharge for all river that reaches wider than 100 m. In this paper, we describe how SWOT discharge produced and archived by the US and French space agencies will be computed from measurements of river water surface elevation, width, and slope and ancillary data, along with expected discharge accuracy. We present for the first time a complete estimate of the SWOT discharge uncertainty budget, with separate terms for random (standard error) and systematic (bias) uncertainty components in river discharge time series. We expect that discharge uncertainty will be less than 30% for two-thirds of global reaches and will be dominated by bias. Separate river discharge estimates will combine both SWOT and in situ data; these “gage-constrained” discharge estimates can be expected to have lower systematic uncertainty. Temporal variations in river discharge time series will be dominated by random error and are expected to be estimated within 15% for nearly all reaches, allowing accurate inference of event flow dynamics globally, including in ungaged basins. We believe this level of accuracy lays the groundwork for SWOT to enable breakthroughs in global hydrologic science.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> Michael Durand, Colin J. Gleason, Tamlin M. Pavelsky, Renato Prata de Moraes Frasson, Michael Turmon, Cédric H. David, Elizabeth H. Altenau, Nikki Tebaldi, Kevin Larnier, Jerome Monnier, Pierre Olivier Malaterre, Hind Oubanas, George H. Allen, Brian Astifan, Craig Brinkerhoff, Paul D. Bates, David Bjerklie, Stephen Coss, Robert Dudley, Luciana Fenoglio, Pierre‐André Garambois, Augusto Getirana, Peirong Lin, Steven A. Margulis, Pascal Matte, J. Toby Minear, Aggrey Muhebwa, Ming Pan, Daniel Peters, Ryan Riggs, Md Safat Sikder, Travis Simmons, Cassie Stuurman, Jay Taneja, Angelica Tarpanelli, Kerstin Schulze, Mohammad J. Tourian, Jida Wang</dc:creator><category> Research Article</category><dc:title> A Framework for Estimating Global River Discharge From the Surface Water and Ocean Topography Satellite Mission</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2021WR031614</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1029/2021WR031614</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2021WR031614?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> Research Article</prism:section><prism:volume> 59</prism:volume><prism:number> 4个</prism:number></item><item><link/>https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033742?af=R<pubDate> Thu, 06 Apr 2023 06:21:30 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-04-06T06:21:30-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley: Water Resources Research: Table of Contents <prism:coverdate></prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate></prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR033742</guid><title> Layered Green &amp; Ampt Infiltration with Redistribution</title><description> Water Resources Research, Accepted Article.</description><dc:description> Abstract Numerical solution of the one‐dimensional Richards equation (RE) accurately partitions precipitation into infiltration and runoff in capillary dominated soils. However, its application sometimes requires significant computational effort and presents reliability challenges. The Green &amp; Ampt (G&amp;A) approach represents a conservative and efficient method to calculate one‐dimensional infiltration but is limited to deep, well drained, uniform, non‐layered soils for a single rainfall event. The original G&amp;A model and subsequent advancements represent wetting fronts as discrete objects, rather than discretizing the model domain in space, yielding a computationally simpler model than the RE. This paper describes an extension of the G&amp;A method into layered soils on a continuous basis that we call Layered Green &amp; Ampt with Redistribution (LGAR). Assumptions employed in the derivation include: uniform soil hydraulic properties within layers, single‐valued capillary head at the interface between soil layers, and no influence of groundwater table on soil moisture. Wetting fronts advance due to the combined effects of gravity and wetting front capillary drive in a layered soil profile. Results of multi‐month continuous LGAR simulations of infiltration using forcing and soil hydraulic data from USDA SCAN sites are compared against infiltration calculated using the HYDRUS‐1D RE solver using standard metrics. The assumptions employed in deriving the LGAR method limit is application to situations where cumulative potential evapotranspiration is greater than cumulative precipitation, typical of arid or semi‐arid conditions. LGAR is a mass‐conservative, computationally efficient, reliable and reasonably accurate method for simulating infiltration over extended time periods compared to the numerical solution of the RE in layered soils in arid and semi‐arid regions.</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;Numerical solution of the one-dimensional Richards equation (RE) accurately partitions precipitation into infiltration and runoff in capillary dominated soils. However, its application sometimes requires significant computational effort and presents reliability challenges. The Green &amp; Ampt (G&amp;A) approach represents a conservative and efficient method to calculate one-dimensional infiltration but is limited to deep, well drained, uniform, non-layered soils for a single rainfall event. The original G&amp;A model and subsequent advancements represent wetting fronts as discrete objects, rather than discretizing the model domain in space, yielding a computationally simpler model than the RE. This paper describes an extension of the G&amp;A method into layered soils on a continuous basis that we call Layered Green &amp; Ampt with Redistribution (LGAR). Assumptions employed in the derivation include: uniform soil hydraulic properties within layers, single-valued capillary head at the interface between soil layers, and no influence of groundwater table on soil moisture. Wetting fronts advance due to the combined effects of gravity and wetting front capillary drive in a layered soil profile. Results of multi-month continuous LGAR simulations of infiltration using forcing and soil hydraulic data from USDA SCAN sites are compared against infiltration calculated using the HYDRUS-1D RE solver using standard metrics. The assumptions employed in deriving the LGAR method limit is application to situations where cumulative potential evapotranspiration is greater than cumulative precipitation, typical of arid or semi-arid conditions. LGAR is a mass-conservative, computationally efficient, reliable and reasonably accurate method for simulating infiltration over extended time periods compared to the numerical solution of the RE in layered soils in arid and semi-arid regions.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> Peter La Follette, Fred L. Ogden, Ahmad Jan</dc:creator><category> Research Article</category><dc:title> Layered Green &amp; Ampt Infiltration with Redistribution</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2022WR033742</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1029/2022WR033742</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033742?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> Research Article</prism:section></item><item><link/> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033584?af=R<pubDate> Thu, 06 Apr 2023 06:20:45 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-04-06T06:20:45-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley: Water Resources Research: Table of Contents <prism:coverdate></prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate></prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR033584</guid><title> A portable device for on‐site measurement of sediment concentration through volume‐mass replacement</title><description> Water Resources Research, Accepted Article.</description><dc:description> Abstract To enable on‐site and near‐real‐time sediment concentration measurements, a novel type of portable device with a constant volume sampling bottle was developed in this study. The device consisted of a sampling bottle, a measuring assembly, and a platform for auxiliary data management. Five representative soils and eight sediment concentrations were used to validate the device accuracy and application. Moreover, a novel concept of sediment effective density (SED) was proposed. Under SED, a linear regression was fit between the measured and actual sediment concentrations. The results revealed that the slopes of the fitting line were close to 1, and the R2 values were greater than 0.999 for five soils. Moreover, for total samples, the root mean square error (RMSE) and Nash–Sutcliffe efficiency coefficient (NSE) values were 5.59 g/L and 0.9996, respectively. Additionally, an average SED of 2.51 g/cm3 was calculated in this study. With an average soil SED of 2.51 g/cm3 and an average soil solid density of 2.65 g/cm3, the RMSE and NSE were 11.85 and 18.50 g/L and 0.9981 and 0.9954, respectively. This result demonstrated that the designed device accurately measured sediment concentration under various conditions. Furthermore, relative to the traditional oven‐drying method, the device could measure sediment concentration near‐real‐time and with high accuracy, which could be useful for researchers with excellent potential. It was recommended to measure the SED in a laboratory or runoff plot because the sediment sources could be identified and obtained. In a field or river, it was recommended to use 2.51 g/cm3 as the sediment effective density, which was more accurate than 2.65 g/cm3. This article is protected by copyright.版权所有。</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;To enable on-site and near-real-time sediment concentration measurements, a novel type of portable device with a constant volume sampling bottle was developed in this study. The device consisted of a sampling bottle, a measuring assembly, and a platform for auxiliary data management. Five representative soils and eight sediment concentrations were used to validate the device accuracy and application. Moreover, a novel concept of sediment effective density (SED) was proposed. Under SED, a linear regression was fit between the measured and actual sediment concentrations. The results revealed that the slopes of the fitting line were close to 1, and the R&lt;sup>;2&lt;/sup>; values were greater than 0.999 for five soils. Moreover, for total samples, the root mean square error (RMSE) and Nash–Sutcliffe efficiency coefficient (NSE) values were 5.59 g/L and 0.9996, respectively. Additionally, an average SED of 2.51 g/cm&lt;sup>;3&lt;/sup>; was calculated in this study. With an average soil SED of 2.51 g/cm&lt;sup>;3&lt;/sup>; and an average soil solid density of 2.65 g/cm&lt;sup>;3&lt;/sup>;, the RMSE and NSE were 11.85 and 18.50 g/L and 0.9981 and 0.9954, respectively. This result demonstrated that the designed device accurately measured sediment concentration under various conditions. Furthermore, relative to the traditional oven-drying method, the device could measure sediment concentration near-real-time and with high accuracy, which could be useful for researchers with excellent potential. It was recommended to measure the SED in a laboratory or runoff plot because the sediment sources could be identified and obtained. In a field or river, it was recommended to use 2.51 g/cm&lt;sup>;3&lt;/sup>; as the sediment effective density, which was more accurate than 2.65 g/cm&lt;sup>;3&lt;/sup>;.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This article is protected by copyright. All rights reserved.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> Qiuxing Yue, Xiaoyun Zhan, Minghang Guo, Jun Zhao, Baoyuan Liu</dc:creator><category> Method</category><dc:title> A portable device for on‐site measurement of sediment concentration through volume‐mass replacement</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2022WR033584</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1029/2022WR033584</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033584?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> Method</prism:section></item><item><link/> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR034305?af=R<pubDate> Thu, 06 Apr 2023 06:20:33 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-04-06T06:20:33-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley: Water Resources Research: Table of Contents <prism:coverdate></prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate></prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR034305</guid><title> Spatiotemporal variability of current and future sub‐daily rainfall in Japan using state‐of‐the‐art high‐quality datasets</title><description> Water Resources Research, Accepted Article.</description><dc:description> Abstract Using potentially best available rainfall datasets for the entire country of Japan (spatial scales of 1‐km and 20‐km), we analyze the 1‐24 hour and city‐scale (1‐400 km2) extreme rainfalls for both current (2006‐2020) and future periods (2081‐2109) at 1.5 K global warming scenario, complementing previous work that focuses on either coarse spatial and temporal scales or other warming scenarios (eg, RCP and 2 K warming scenarios). A peak‐over‐threshold (POT)‐based approach is applied to compute areal reduction factor (ARF) for subsequently establishing intensity‐duration‐area‐frequency (IDAF) curves. Our results reveal that ARF values generally decrease with increasing area size and increase with longer duration and are affected by multiple underlying physical phenomena. Moreover, we find a greater increase in the rainfall intensities for shorter durations and higher return periods, ranging from 9.4% (1‐hour) to 6.2% (24‐hour), averaged for all return periods and 8.3% (25‐year) to 7.3% (2‐year), averaged for all rainfall durations. Spatially, extreme rainfall intensities are projected to increase by 8.9% in northern Japan (albeit with a less intense rainfall intensity in the current period), which is greater than the rest of the country (6.8%), underscoring the need to focus more on infrastructure designs in northern Japan. The projected IDAF curves further display an increase in the frequency of extreme events at city‐scale, eg, 25‐year extreme rainfall events in 2006‐2020 would likely be 5‐10‐year events in 2081‐2109. Our results with the state‐of‐art data and implementable approach can be utilized for policymaking to reduce the warming‐induced risks in Japan and beyond. This article is protected by copyright.版权所有。</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;Using potentially best available rainfall datasets for the entire country of Japan (spatial scales of 1-km and 20-km), we analyze the 1-24 hour and city-scale (1-400 km&lt;sup>;2&lt;/sup>;) extreme rainfalls for both current (2006-2020) and future periods (2081-2109) at 1.5 K global warming scenario, complementing previous work that focuses on either coarse spatial and temporal scales or other warming scenarios (eg, RCP and 2 K warming scenarios). A peak-over-threshold (POT)-based approach is applied to compute areal reduction factor (ARF) for subsequently establishing intensity-duration-area-frequency (IDAF) curves. Our results reveal that ARF values generally decrease with increasing area size and increase with longer duration and are affected by multiple underlying physical phenomena. Moreover, we find a greater increase in the rainfall intensities for shorter durations and higher return periods, ranging from 9.4% (1-hour) to 6.2% (24-hour), averaged for all return periods and 8.3% (25-year) to 7.3% (2-year), averaged for all rainfall durations. Spatially, extreme rainfall intensities are projected to increase by 8.9% in northern Japan (albeit with a less intense rainfall intensity in the current period), which is greater than the rest of the country (6.8%), underscoring the need to focus more on infrastructure designs in northern Japan. The projected IDAF curves further display an increase in the frequency of extreme events at city-scale, eg, 25-year extreme rainfall events in 2006-2020 would likely be 5-10-year events in 2081-2109. Our results with the state-of-art data and implementable approach can be utilized for policymaking to reduce the warming-induced risks in Japan and beyond.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This article is protected by copyright. All rights reserved.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> Wenpeng Zhao, Abhishek, Bijoychandra S. Takhellambam, Jiantao Zhang, Yakun Zhao, Tsuyoshi Kinouchi</dc:creator><category> Research Article</category><dc:title> Spatiotemporal variability of current and future sub‐daily rainfall in Japan using state‐of‐the‐art high‐quality datasets</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2022WR034305</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1029/2022WR034305</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR034305?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> Research Article</prism:section></item><item><link/> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR032578?af=R<pubDate> Thu, 06 Apr 2023 06:19:44 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-04-06T06:19:44-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley: Water Resources Research: Table of Contents <prism:coverdate></prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate></prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR032578</guid><title> Subsurface Porewater Flow Accelerates Talik Development under the Alaska Highway, Yukon: A Prelude to Road Collapse and Final Permafrost Thaw?</title><description> Water Resources Research, Accepted Article.</description><dc:description> Abstract The presence of taliks (perennially unfrozen zones in permafrost areas) adversely affects the thermal stability of infrastructure in cold regions, including roads. The role of heat advection on talik development and feedback on permafrost degradation has not been quantified methodically in this context. We incorporate a surface energy balance model into a coupled groundwater flow and energy transport numerical model (SUTRA‐ice). The model, calibrated with long‐term observations (1997‐2018 on the Alaska Highway), is used to investigate and quantify the role of heat advection on talik initiation and development under a road embankment. Over the 25‐year simulation period, the new model is driven by reconstructed meteorological data and has a good agreement with near surface soil temperatures. The model successfully reproduces the increasing depth to the permafrost table (mean absolute error &lt; 0.2 m), and talik development. The results demonstrate that heat advection provides an additional energy source that expedites the rate of permafrost thaw and roughly doubles the rate of permafrost table deepening, compared to purely conductive thawing. Talik initially formed and grew over time under the combined effect of water flow, snow insulation, road construction and climate warming. Talik formation creates a new thermal state under the road embankment, resulting in acceleration of underlying permafrost degradation, due to the positive feedback of heat accumulation created by trapped unfrozen water. In a changing climate, mobile water flow will play a more important role in permafrost thaw and talik development under road embankments, and is likely to significantly increase maintenance costs and reduce the long‐term stability of the infrastructure.</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;The presence of taliks (perennially unfrozen zones in permafrost areas) adversely affects the thermal stability of infrastructure in cold regions, including roads. The role of heat advection on talik development and feedback on permafrost degradation has not been quantified methodically in this context. We incorporate a surface energy balance model into a coupled groundwater flow and energy transport numerical model (SUTRA-ice). The model, calibrated with long-term observations (1997-2018 on the Alaska Highway), is used to investigate and quantify the role of heat advection on talik initiation and development under a road embankment. Over the 25-year simulation period, the new model is driven by reconstructed meteorological data and has a good agreement with near surface soil temperatures. The model successfully reproduces the increasing depth to the permafrost table (mean absolute error &amp;lt; 0.2 m), and talik development. The results demonstrate that heat advection provides an additional energy source that expedites the rate of permafrost thaw and roughly doubles the rate of permafrost table deepening, compared to purely conductive thawing. Talik initially formed and grew over time under the combined effect of water flow, snow insulation, road construction and climate warming. Talik formation creates a new thermal state under the road embankment, resulting in acceleration of underlying permafrost degradation, due to the positive feedback of heat accumulation created by trapped unfrozen water. In a changing climate, mobile water flow will play a more important role in permafrost thaw and talik development under road embankments, and is likely to significantly increase maintenance costs and reduce the long-term stability of the infrastructure.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> Lin Chen, Daniel Fortier, Jeffrey M. McKenzie, Clifford I. Voss, Pierrick Lamontagne‐Hallé</dc:creator><category> Research Article</category><dc:title> Subsurface Porewater Flow Accelerates Talik Development under the Alaska Highway, Yukon: A Prelude to Road Collapse and Final Permafrost Thaw?</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2022WR032578</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1029/2022WR032578</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR032578?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> Research Article</prism:section></item><item><link/> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033367?af=R<pubDate> Wed, 05 Apr 2023 12:54:43 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-04-05T12:54:43-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley: Water Resources Research: Table of Contents<prism:coverdate> Sat, 01 Apr 2023 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate> Sat, 01 Apr 2023 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR033367</guid><title> Earthquakes and Heavy Rainfall Influence on Aquifer Properties: A New Coupled Earth and Barometric Tidal Response Model in a Confined Bi‐Layer Aquifer</title><description> Water Resources Research, Volume 59, Issue 4, April 2023.</description><dc:description> Abstract Among the impacts of earthquakes on aquifers, permeability change is one of the most challenging to quantify, since techniques to measure permeability evolution are scarce. The study of tidal response of boreholes is one of the most promising, yet complex to use in practice. We used 14 years of piezometric level measurements and two concurrent source signals, earth tidal strain and barometric pressure, for which we separated the respective contribution in a state‐of‐the‐art tidal analysis. We developed a new general analytical hydrogeological model, based on geological observations of a confined bi‐layer aquifer. It is able to match combined observations of earth and barometric tide phase lags which could not be explained by existing models. We demonstrate that its relative complexity can be overcome thanks to the results of tidal analysis, yielding a simpler model adapted to the Fond Lahaye site of the Martinique Island. The resulting evolution of diffusivity and loading efficiency, was validated independently with several pumping tests occurring all along the studied period. The transient diffusivity increases and decreases indicate which earthquakes impacted the aquifer, enabling to establish an empirical magnitude‐distance relationship criterion. This criterion confirms the suspected dependence on dynamic stresses, which decrease as the square of the hypocentral distance. Additionally, we investigate two other factors of diffusivity changes: heavy rainfall events and aquifer withdrawals, which demonstrates the sensitivity of volcanic aquifers properties to environmental and anthropogenic influence.</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;Among the impacts of earthquakes on aquifers, permeability change is one of the most challenging to quantify, since techniques to measure permeability evolution are scarce. The study of tidal response of boreholes is one of the most promising, yet complex to use in practice. We used 14 years of piezometric level measurements and two concurrent source signals, earth tidal strain and barometric pressure, for which we separated the respective contribution in a state-of-the-art tidal analysis. We developed a new general analytical hydrogeological model, based on geological observations of a confined bi-layer aquifer. It is able to match combined observations of earth and barometric tide phase lags which could not be explained by existing models. We demonstrate that its relative complexity can be overcome thanks to the results of tidal analysis, yielding a simpler model adapted to the Fond Lahaye site of the Martinique Island. The resulting evolution of diffusivity and loading efficiency, was validated independently with several pumping tests occurring all along the studied period. The transient diffusivity increases and decreases indicate which earthquakes impacted the aquifer, enabling to establish an empirical magnitude-distance relationship criterion. This criterion confirms the suspected dependence on dynamic stresses, which decrease as the square of the hypocentral distance. Additionally, we investigate two other factors of diffusivity changes: heavy rainfall events and aquifer withdrawals, which demonstrates the sensitivity of volcanic aquifers properties to environmental and anthropogenic influence.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> A. Thomas, J. Fortin, B. Vittecoq, S. Violette</dc:creator><category> Research Article</category><dc:title> Earthquakes and Heavy Rainfall Influence on Aquifer Properties: A New Coupled Earth and Barometric Tidal Response Model in a Confined Bi‐Layer Aquifer</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2022WR033367</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1029/2022WR033367</prism:doi><prism:url> https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033367?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> Research Article</prism:section><prism:volume> 59</prism:volume><prism:number> 4个</prism:number></item></channel></rss>