<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:prism="http://prismstandard.org/namespaces/basic/2.0/"><channel><title> Wiley：水资源研究：目录</title><link/>https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R<description>水资源研究目录。最新期和 EarlyView 期的文章列表。</description><language> en-US</language><copyright></copyright><managingeditor> wileyonlinelibrary@wiley.com（Wiley 在线图书馆）</managingeditor><pubDate> Wed, 06 Sep 2023 10:56:42 +0000</pubDate><lastbuilddate> 2023 年 9 月 6 日星期三 10:56:42 +0000</lastbuilddate><generator> Atypon®文学™</generator><docs> https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs><ttl> 10080</ttl><dc:title> Wiley：水资源研究：目录</dc:title><dc:publisher>威利</dc:publisher><prism:publicationname>水资源研究</prism:publicationname><atom:link href="https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"></atom:link><image/><title> Wiley：水资源研究：目录</title><url>https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/pb-assets/journal-banners/19447973.jpg</url><link/> https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R<item><link/> https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033782?af=R<pubDate> Tue, 05 Sep 2023 18:54:35 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-09-05T06:54:35-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley：水资源研究：目录<prism:coverdate></prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate></prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR033782</guid><title>茂密的水生植被对农业源头河流季节性磷酸盐和颗粒输送的重要性</title><description>水资源研究，已接受文章。</description><dc:description>摘要 农业源头溪流和沟渠通常拥有茂密的水生植被，这些植被随季节生长和腐烂，并对养分从农田向较大河流的输送施加物理和生物控制。本研究通过恒定速率注入新型示踪剂混合物 [保守盐（Cl 为 NaCl）、溶解磷 (KH2PO4)，研究了莫米河流域（美国俄亥俄州）农业排水沟中磷 (P) 迁移的变化。 ），以及春季、夏季和秋季的荧光细颗粒。我们使用传统的瞬态存储建模框架来量化溶质和颗粒的传输行为，该框架由通过一阶交换率常数连接的移动和固定存储区域组成。春季的瞬时储存量最大，此时植被较厚，造成更多的积水和水流停滞，而秋季则随着植被变薄而减少。秋季可溶性磷的吸收长度比春季长 8.7 倍，这可能是由于气温较低和植被稀疏导致生物吸收率下降和固定区储存所致。从秋季到春季，颗粒物捕获长度也减少了 4.3 倍。随着伊利湖和世界各地农业景观下游水体的富营养化日益严重，了解跨流域（包括小型农业溪流）的养分输送是有益的。这项研究强调了水生植被在小型农业溪流中所发挥的物理和生物作用，它们通过创建季节性变化的固定区域来减缓养分的流动，为生物膜提供表面积，并捕获结合养分的颗粒。</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;农业源头溪流和沟渠通常拥有茂密的水生植被，这些植被随季节生长和腐烂，并对养分从农田到较大河流的运输施加物理和生物控制。本研究通过恒定速率注入新型示踪剂混合物 [保守盐（Cl 为 NaCl）、溶解磷 (KH &lt;sub>;2&lt;/sub>;PO&lt;sub>;4&lt;/sub>;），以及春季、夏季和秋季的荧光细颗粒]。我们使用传统的瞬态存储建模框架来量化溶质和颗粒的传输行为，该框架由通过一阶交换率常数连接的移动和固定存储区域组成。春季的瞬时储存量最大，此时植被较厚，造成更多的积水和水流停滞，而秋季则随着植被变薄而减少。秋季可溶性磷的吸收长度比春季长 8.7 倍，这可能是由于气温较低和植被稀疏导致生物吸收率下降和固定区储存所致。从秋季到春季，颗粒物捕获长度也减少了 4.3 倍。随着伊利湖和世界各地农业景观下游水体的富营养化日益严重，了解跨流域（包括小型农业溪流）的养分输送是有益的。这项研究强调了水生植被在小型农业溪流中发挥的物理和生物作用，它们通过创建季节性变化的固定区域来减缓养分的流动，为生物膜提供表面积，并捕获结合养分的颗粒。&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator>汉娜·R·菲尔德、奥黛丽·H·索耶、苏珊·A·韦尔奇、瑞安·K·贝内菲尔、德文·M·马蒂、詹姆斯·M·胡德、伊森·D·帕夫洛夫斯基、戴安娜·L·卡万、丽贝卡·M·克莱林、扎克里·I·约翰逊、布列塔尼·R·汉拉汉、凯文·W·金</dc:creator><category>研究文章</category><dc:title>茂密的水生植被对农业源头河流季节性磷酸盐和颗粒输送的重要性</dc:title><dc:identifier>10.1029/2022WR033782</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname>水资源研究</prism:publicationname><prism:doi>10.1029/2022WR033782</prism:doi><prism:url> https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033782?af=R</prism:url><prism:section>研究文章</prism:section></item><item><link/>https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR034297?af=R<pubDate> Tue, 05 Sep 2023 08:20:11 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-09-05T08:20:11-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley：水资源研究：目录<prism:coverdate>2023 年 9 月 1 日星期五 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate> 2023 年 9 月 1 日星期五 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR034297</guid><title>水平含水层的非线性衰退模型</title><description>《水资源研究》，第 59 卷，第 9 期，2023 年 9 月。</description><dc:description>摘要 衰退分析是确定河岸含水层水力特征的有力工具。该方法的基础依赖于非线性 Boussinesq 方程的两个解析解：一个适用于半无限含水层中的均匀地下水位剖面，而另一个适用于有限含水层中的假设初始剖面。两种解决方案都假设相邻河流的水深可以忽略不计。在目前的工作中，使用行波近似导出一维 Boussinesq 方程的非线性解。该解更好地代表了现场条件，因为它涉及与非零水位的河流相邻的有限含水层中的均匀地下水位剖面。它可以导出地下水位下降、流量和相关排水量的简单代数表达式。还获得了将流量与流出量相关的近似值，用于含水层水力参数估计的实际实施。所提出的参数估计方法与衰退分析的标准方法的比较表明，本方法是优越的，因为它避免了与经典方法相关的陷阱，特别是当使用具有固有观测误差的日流量值时。衰退模型在实际案例中的应用证明了其在估计流域规模导水率和可排水孔隙度方面的有效性。</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;摘要&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;衰退分析是确定河岸含水层水力特征的有力工具。该方法的基础依赖于非线性 Boussinesq 方程的两个解析解：一个适用于半无限含水层中的均匀地下水位剖面，而另一个适用于有限含水层中的假设初始剖面。两种解决方案都假设相邻河流的水深可以忽略不计。在目前的工作中，使用行波近似导出一维 Boussinesq 方程的非线性解。该解更好地代表了现场条件，因为它涉及与非零水位的溪流相邻的有限含水层中的均匀地下水位剖面。它可以导出地下水位下降、流量和相关排水量的简单代数表达式。还获得了将流量与流出量相关的近似值，用于含水层水力参数估计的实际实施。所提出的参数估计方法与衰退分析的标准方法的比较表明，本方法是优越的，因为它避免了与经典方法相关的陷阱，特别是当使用具有固有观测误差的日流量值时。衰退模型在实际案例中的应用证明了其在流域尺度导水率和可排水孔隙度估算中的有效性。&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator>哈岜沙</dc:creator><category>研究文章</category><dc:title>水平含水层的非线性衰退模型</dc:title><dc:identifier>10.1029/2022WR034297</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname>水资源研究</prism:publicationname><prism:doi>10.1029/2022WR034297</prism:doi><prism:url> https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR034297?af=R</prism:url><prism:section>研究文章</prism:section><prism:volume>59</prism:volume><prism:number> 9</prism:number></item><item><link/> https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033671?af=R<pubDate> Tue, 05 Sep 2023 08:15:37 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-09-05T08:15:37-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley：水资源研究：目录<prism:coverdate>2023 年 9 月 1 日星期五 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate> 2023 年 9 月 1 日星期五 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR033671</guid><title>推进公平、稳健、适应性强、合作稳定的区域供水管理和基础设施投资路径</title><description>《水资源研究》，第 59 卷，第 9 期，2023 年 9 月。</description><dc:description>摘要 区域化方法（地理上邻近的公用事业公司合作管理干旱风险并共同投资新基础设施）越来越成为利用规模经济满足不断增长的需求和应对金融风险的必要策略。然而，区域化也给供水规划带来了新的挑战。成功的区域化政策必须公平地平衡多个合作伙伴的利益，同时处理区域参与者之间的权力关系。在长期基础设施规划背景下，不断发展的系统状态动态加剧了这一挑战，而基础设施投资可能从根本上重塑系统状态动态。这项工作介绍了公平、稳健、自适应和稳定的深度不确定路径 (DU PathwaysERAS)，这是一个用于开发区域供水管理和基础设施投资路径的探索性建模框架。 DU PathwaysERAS 为利益相关者提供了一个综合框架，以评估合作伙伴之间政策结果的公平性，并探索合作基础设施政策中的区域权力关系。为了捕捉基础设施路径随时间演变的动态，DU PathwaysERAS 采用了新工具来衡量路径政策的适应能力并评估随时间演变的脆弱性。我们展示了六家公用事业供水伙伴关系的框架，寻求在北卡罗来纳州研究三角区开发合作基础设施投资途径。我们的结果表明，常用的稳健性框架可能会对区域伙伴关系产生巨大且意想不到的不利后果。结果进一步表明，区域和个体脆弱性是高度相互依存的，并强调需要通过精心设计的合作协议来限制交易对手风险。除了研究三角之外，这些结果广泛适用于全球合作供水基础设施投资和管理。</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;区域化方法（地理上邻近的公用事业公司合作管理干旱风险并共同投资新基础设施）越来越成为利用规模经济满足不断增长的需求和应对金融风险的必要战略。然而，区域化也给供水规划带来了新的挑战。成功的区域化政策必须公平地平衡多个合作伙伴的利益，同时处理区域参与者之间的权力关系。在长期基础设施规划背景下，不断发展的系统状态动态加剧了这一挑战，而基础设施投资可能从根本上重塑系统状态动态。这项工作介绍了公平、稳健、适应性和稳定的深度不确定路径（DU Pathways&lt;sub>; &lt;i>;ERAS&lt;/i>; &lt;/sub>;），这是一个用于开发区域供水管理和基础设施投资路径的探索性建模框架。 DU Pathways&lt;sub>; &lt;i>;ERAS&lt;/i>; &lt;/sub>; 为利益相关者提供了一个综合框架，以评估合作伙伴之间政策成果的公平性，并探索合作基础设施政策中的区域权力关系。为了捕捉基础设施路径随时间演变的动态，DU Pathways&lt;sub>; &lt;i>;ERAS&lt;/i>; &lt;/sub>; 采用了新工具来衡量路径政策的适应能力并评估随时间演变的脆弱性。我们展示了六家公用事业供水伙伴关系的框架，寻求在北卡罗来纳州研究三角区开发合作基础设施投资途径。我们的结果表明，常用的稳健性框架可能会对区域伙伴关系产生巨大且意想不到的不利后果。结果进一步表明，区域和个体脆弱性是高度相互依存的，并强调需要通过精心设计的合作协议来限制交易对手风险。除了研究三角之外，这些结果广泛适用于全球合作供水基础设施投资和管理。&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator>大卫·F·戈尔德、帕特里克·M·里德、大卫·E·戈尔利克、格雷戈里·W·查拉克利斯</dc:creator><category>研究文章</category><dc:title>推进公平、稳健、适应性强、合作稳定的区域供水管理和基础设施投资路径</dc:title><dc:identifier>10.1029/2022WR033671</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname>水资源研究</prism:publicationname><prism:doi>10.1029/2022WR033671</prism:doi><prism:url> https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033671?af=R</prism:url><prism:section>研究文章</prism:section><prism:volume>59</prism:volume><prism:number> 9</prism:number></item><item><link/> https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR034023?af=R<pubDate> Tue, 05 Sep 2023 08:11:57 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-09-05T08:11:57-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley：水资源研究：目录<prism:coverdate>2023 年 9 月 1 日星期五 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate> 2023 年 9 月 1 日星期五 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR034023</guid><title>土壤张力对同位素分馏、传输的影响以及根部吸水来源的解释</title><description>《水资源研究》，第 59 卷，第 9 期，2023 年 9 月。</description><dc:description>摘要 HYDRUS-1D 中的新同位素模块可用于推断根系吸水量 (RWU) 的来源，这是农业和森林水资源管理的合适动态指标。然而，有证据表明，土壤内液态水和水蒸气之间的平衡分馏不仅受到土壤温度的影响，还受到土壤张力的影响。土壤张力如何影响同位素输运模型和 RWU 起源的解释仍然未知。在本研究中，我们评估了 Langeoog 岛现场数据集模型性能的三种分馏情景：(a) 无分馏 (Non_Frac)，(b) 标准 Craig‐Gordon 方程描述的平衡分馏的土壤温度控制（ (c) CG_Frac 加上平衡分馏的土壤张力控制 (CGT_Frac)。模型模拟表明，与 CG_Frac 相比，CGT_Frac 导致表层土壤水同位素成分更加贫化。使用水平衡（WB）计算和贝叶斯混合模型（SIAR）估计RWU的垂直原点。前者直接使用水流输出，后者使用 RWU 和土壤水的模拟同位素组成（使用不同的分馏场景）作为输入。两种方法都提供了不同土层对 RWU 贡献随时间和深度的相似变化趋势。 CGT_Frac 情景解释的所有土层的贡献始终介于 Non_Frac 和 CG_Frac 之间。 RWU 的时间起源是从粒子跟踪（PT，为单个降水事件释放一个假设粒子并根据粒子之间的水平衡跟踪其运动）和虚拟示踪实验（VTE，为单个降水事件分配已知的同位素组成）推导出来的并根据累积同位素通量跟踪其运动）。两种方法都揭示了排水和根区 (RZ) 传播时间随时间的相似变化趋势。解释的排水和 RZ 走时时间通常排列为 Non_Frac >; CGT_Frac >; CG_Frac。总体而言，标准 CG 方程中考虑的因素主导着同位素分馏、传输和 RWU 起源的解释。基于同位素输运的方法（SIAR、VTE）比基于水流的方法（WB、PT）对计算的要求更高。</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;摘要&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;HYDRUS-1D 中的新同位素模块可用于推断根系吸水量 (RWU) 的来源，这是农业和森林水资源管理的合适动态指标。然而，有证据表明，土壤内液态水和水蒸气之间的平衡分馏不仅受到土壤温度的影响，还受到土壤张力的影响。土壤张力如何影响同位素输运模型和 RWU 起源的解释仍然未知。在本研究中，我们评估了 Langeoog 岛现场数据集模型性能的三种分馏情景：(a) 无分馏 (Non_Frac)，(b) 标准 Craig-Gordon 方程描述的平衡分馏的土壤温度控制 ( (c) CG_Frac 加上平衡分馏的土壤张力控制 (CGT_Frac)。模型模拟表明，与 CG_Frac 相比，CGT_Frac 导致表层土壤水同位素成分更加贫化。使用水平衡（WB）计算和贝叶斯混合模型（SIAR）估计RWU的垂直原点。前者直接使用水流输出，后者使用 RWU 和土壤水的模拟同位素组成（使用不同的分馏场景）作为输入。两种方法都提供了不同土层对 RWU 贡献随时间和深度的相似变化趋势。 CGT_Frac 情景解释的所有土层的贡献始终介于 Non_Frac 和 CG_Frac 之间。 RWU 的时间起源是从粒子跟踪（PT，为单个降水事件释放一个假设粒子并根据粒子之间的水平衡跟踪其运动）和虚拟示踪实验（VTE，为单个降水事件分配已知的同位素组成）推导出来的并根据累积同位素通量跟踪其运动）。两种方法都揭示了排水和根区 (RZ) 传播时间随时间的相似变化趋势。解释的排水和RZ行程时间通常被排序为Non_Frac>;1。 CGT_Frac>; CG_Frac。总体而言，标准 CG 方程中考虑的因素主导着同位素分馏、传输和 RWU 起源的解释。基于同位素输运的方法（SIAR、VTE）比基于水流的方法（WB、PT）对计算的要求更高。&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator>周天天、Jiří Šimůnek、Paolo Nasta、Giuseppe Brunetti、Marcel Gaj、Christoph Neukum、Vincent Post</dc:creator><category>研究文章</category><dc:title>土壤张力对同位素分馏、传输的影响以及根部吸水来源的解释</dc:title><dc:identifier>10.1029/2022WR034023</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname>水资源研究</prism:publicationname><prism:doi>10.1029/2022WR034023</prism:doi><prism:url> https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR034023?af=R</prism:url><prism:section>研究文章</prism:section><prism:volume>59</prism:volume><prism:number> 9</prism:number></item><item><link/> https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2023WR034958?af=R<pubDate> Mon, 04 Sep 2023 20:36:35 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-09-04T08:36:35-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley：水资源研究：目录<prism:coverdate></prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate></prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2023WR034958</guid><title>粗糙裂缝中剪切稀化流体对牛顿流体的位移模式</title><description>水资源研究，已接受文章。</description><dc:description>摘要 裂缝介质中涉及非牛顿流体的两相流在许多自然过程和地下工程应用中至关重要，例如岩石灌浆、地下水修复和提高采收率。然而，非牛顿流变学如何影响位移动力学仍然是一个悬而未决的问题。在这里，我们进行了一次排水实验，其中剪切稀化黄原胶溶液取代了透明粗糙裂缝中的硅油，以获得广泛的剪切稀化特性（由聚合物浓度控制）和流速。我们首先评估剪切稀化特性对驱替效率的影响。基于对观察到的流体形态的定性和定量分析，我们提出了所获得的位移模式的实验相图。我们描述了一种新颖的驱替模式，其中流体-流体界面从稳定（活塞流）变为不稳定（指状流），因为裂缝孔径（在横向上平均）沿平均流动方向变化。我们证明，这种混合位移模式的存在可以通过剪切稀化行为和孔径空间变异性耦合引起的局部粘度异质性来解释。最后，我们提出了一个理论模型来阐明流态转变背后的机制。该模型预测的界面稳定性准则与实验测量结果吻合良好，并强调了流体流变学与孔径变异性在粗糙裂缝中的不混相位移中的潜在重要作用。这些发现为具有非牛顿效应的不混溶两相流的动力学提供了新的见解，并对上述工程应用具有潜在的影响。本文受版权保护。版权所有。</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;裂缝介质中涉及非牛顿流体的两相流在许多自然过程和地下工程应用中至关重要，例如岩石灌浆、地下水修复和提高石油采收率。然而，非牛顿流变学如何影响位移动力学仍然是一个悬而未决的问题。在这里，我们进行了一次排水实验，其中剪切稀化黄原胶溶液取代了透明粗糙裂缝中的硅油，以获得广泛的剪切稀化特性（由聚合物浓度控制）和流速。我们首先评估剪切稀化特性对驱替效率的影响。基于对观察到的流体形态的定性和定量分析，我们提出了所获得的位移模式的实验相图。我们描述了一种新颖的驱替模式，其中流体-流体界面从稳定（活塞流）变为不稳定（指状流），因为裂缝孔径（在横向上平均）沿平均流动方向变化。我们证明，这种混合位移模式的存在可以通过剪切稀化行为和孔径空间变异性耦合引起的局部粘度异质性来解释。最后，我们提出了一个理论模型来阐明流态转变背后的机制。该模型预测的界面稳定性准则与实验测量结果吻合良好，并强调了流体流变学与孔径变异性在粗糙裂缝中的不混相位移中的潜在重要作用。这些发现为具有非牛顿效应的不混溶两相流的动力学提供了新的见解，并对上述工程应用具有潜在的影响。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;本文受版权保护。保留所有权利。&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator>张乐、杨志兵、Yves Méheust、Insa Neuweiler、胡然、陈一峰</dc:creator><category>研究文章</category><dc:title>粗糙裂缝中剪切稀化流体对牛顿流体的位移模式</dc:title><dc:identifier>10.1029/2023WR034958</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname>水资源研究</prism:publicationname><prism:doi>10.1029/2023WR034958</prism:doi><prism:url> https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2023WR034958?af=R</prism:url><prism:section>研究文章</prism:section></item><item><link/>https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2023WR034800?af=R<pubDate> Mon, 04 Sep 2023 01:38:25 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-09-04T01:38:25-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley：水资源研究：目录<prism:coverdate></prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate></prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2023WR034800</guid><title>基于成核理论的冻土过冷特性研究</title><description>水资源研究，已接受文章。</description><dc:description>摘要 土壤-水系统中冻结的澄清对于评估冻结带和液态水流的形成至关重要。人们在冻结过程中发现了土壤孔隙溶液的过冷现象，但其机制仍知之甚少。在这项研究中，我们提出了基于经典成核理论（CNT）的土壤-水系统的自由能函数。结合电解质溶液中的初始冻结温度模型和Pitzer活度系数模型，得到了盐渍土-水体系临界成核问题的解析解。然后，对不同含盐量的盐渍土进行冻融实验，对解析解进行验证。导出的边界成核率是过冷临界条件的定量解。研究结果表明理论结果与实验结果吻合良好。对于无盐土壤-水系统，临界最大过冷半径为7.15 nm。我们比较了八种经典的冰水界面张力模型，“Reinhardt &amp; Doye”和“DeMott &amp; Rogers”模型在使用新的自由能理论框架预测土壤-水体系的结晶成核速率时表现出了优异的性能。检测到边界成核率与土壤水势之间呈正相关。根据影响因素，土-水系统边界成核率可分为盐性控制区（R>;100μm）、盐孔混合控制区（100μm>;R>;100nm）和孔径控制区3个区域。区（R&lt;100nm）。</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;摘要&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;澄清土壤-水系统中的冻结对于评估冻结带和液态水流的形成至关重要。人们在冻结过程中发现了土壤孔隙溶液的过冷现象，但其机制仍知之甚少。在这项研究中，我们提出了基于经典成核理论（CNT）的土壤-水系统的自由能函数。结合电解质溶液中的初始冻结温度模型和Pitzer活度系数模型，得到了盐渍土-水体系临界成核问题的解析解。然后，对不同含盐量的盐渍土进行冻融实验，对解析解进行验证。导出的边界成核率是过冷临界条件的定量解。研究结果表明理论结果与实验结果吻合良好。对于无盐土壤-水系统，临界最大过冷半径为7.15 nm。我们比较了八个经典的冰水界面张力模型，“Reinhardt &amp; Doye”和“DeMott &amp; Rogers”模型在使用新的自由能理论框架预测土-水体系的结晶成核速率时表现出了优异的性能。检测到边界成核率与土壤水势之间呈正相关。根据影响因素，土-水系统边界成核率可分为盐性控制区（R>;100μm）、盐孔混合控制区（100μm>;R>;100nm）和孔径控制区3个区域区（R&lt;100nm）。&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator>王冲、李坤宇、林志坤、杨志杰、蔡红红、赖远明、李双阳</dc:creator><category>研究文章</category><dc:title>基于成核理论的冻土过冷特性研究</dc:title><dc:identifier>10.1029/2023WR034800</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname>水资源研究</prism:publicationname><prism:doi>10.1029/2023WR034800</prism:doi><prism:url> https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2023WR034800?af=R</prism:url><prism:section>研究文章</prism:section></item><item><link/>https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033531?af=R<pubDate> Sat, 02 Sep 2023 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-09-02T12:00:00-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley：水资源研究：目录<prism:coverdate></prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate></prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR033531</guid><title>表征单桥墩处大型木质碎屑堆积物孔隙度对局部冲刷的重要性</title><description>水资源研究，已接受文章。</description><dc:description>摘要 桥墩处大型木质碎片（LWD）的堆积对全球跨水道桥梁的结构完整性造成严重危害。随钻测井积累直接导致的加剧冲刷可能导致重大结构损坏，甚至灾难性倒塌。最近的研究得出了经验方程来估计给定随钻测井堆积尺寸的冲刷深度；然而，这些大多基于棱柱状和不渗透固体随钻测井堆积物的实验测试，忽略了现场观察，这些观察表明堆积物既不是不渗透的也不是棱柱状的，而是具有倒圆锥形的多孔性。因此，在本研究中，我们研究了具有现场常见形状的多孔随钻测井堆积物对冲孔的影响。结果表明，随钻测井尺寸、形状和水流特征是影响桥墩底部沉积物侵蚀的主要因素。然而，也观察到堆积物的孔隙度对冲孔的尺寸和最大深度有相当大的影响。特别是，相对于相应的固体不渗透堆积物，多孔随钻测井可将最大冲刷深度减少高达 50%（平均在 5-25% 范围内）。本研究显示的结果还提供了一种实用工具，可以在受随钻测井累积影响时对桥墩冲刷深度进行更实际、更保守的估计。本文受版权保护。版权所有。</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;摘要&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;桥墩处大型木质碎片 (LWD) 的堆积对全球跨水道桥梁的结构完整性构成严重危害。随钻测井积累直接导致的加剧冲刷可能导致重大结构损坏，甚至灾难性倒塌。最近的研究得出了经验方程来估计给定随钻测井堆积尺寸的冲刷深度；然而，这些大多基于棱柱状和不渗透固体随钻测井堆积物的实验测试，忽略了现场观察，这些观察表明堆积物既不是不渗透的也不是棱柱状的，而是具有倒圆锥形的多孔性。因此，在本研究中，我们研究了具有现场常见形状的多孔随钻测井堆积物对冲孔的影响。结果表明，随钻测井尺寸、形状和水流特征是影响桥墩底部沉积物侵蚀的主要因素。然而，也观察到堆积物的孔隙度对冲孔的尺寸和最大深度有相当大的影响。特别是，相对于相应的固体不渗透堆积物，多孔随钻测井可将最大冲刷深度减少高达 50%（平均在 5-25% 范围内）。本研究中显示的结果还提供了一个实用工具，用于在受 LWD 累积影响时对桥墩冲刷深度进行更现实、更保守的估计。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;本文受版权保护。保留所有权利。&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> D.帕尼奇、P.克里帕卡兰</dc:creator><category>研究文章</category><dc:title>Characterising the importance of porosity of large woody debris accumulations at single bridge piers on localised scour</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2022WR033531</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1029/2022WR033531</prism:doi><prism:url> https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033531?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> Research Article</prism:section></item><item><link/> https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2023WR034506?af=R<pubDate> Fri, 01 Sep 2023 20:41:15 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-09-01T08:41:15-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley: Water Resources Research: Table of Contents <prism:coverdate></prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate></prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2023WR034506</guid><title> Soil moisture estimation by assimilating in‐situ and SMAP surface soil moisture using unscented weighted ensemble Kalman filter</title><description> Water Resources Research, Accepted Article.</description><dc:description> Abstract Highly accurate soil moisture information is necessary to understand land surface processes. However, observational techniques do not produce adequately accurate spatial‐temporal continuous regional soil moisture data. The data assimilation method can be used to improve the soil moisture estimations by merging multi‐source observed data, but its performance is affected by error covariance and the quality of assimilated data. We designed eight numerical experiments to analyze how to improve the filter performance through soil moisture assimilation using the unscented weighted ensemble Kalman filter (UWEnKF) and 1‐D Richards equation at Maqu and Erlinghu (ELH) observational sites in the source region of Yellow River (SRYR), China. The experimental results show that the filter performance improves as the quality of assimilated data increases in the soil moisture assimilation experiment when assimilating in‐situ surface soil moisture (SSM) observations, SMAP SSM data and downscaled SMAP SSM data. In other aspects, filter performance is readily affected by model and observation error covariances in soil moisture assimilation. If the SMAP SSM data are taken to be perfect (ie, small bias), UWEnKF performs differently between different sites because of the underestimation or overestimation of SMAP SSM and model simulations compared to the in‐situ observations. Additionally, different soil moisture assimilation results can be obtained with different initial values at the beginning of the assimilation period. Overall, filter performance can be improved primarily by improving the quality of assimilated data (eg, downscaling the remote sensing data), and by creating a reasonable and effective method for determining error covariance. This article is protected by copyright.版权所有。</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;Highly accurate soil moisture information is necessary to understand land surface processes. However, observational techniques do not produce adequately accurate spatial-temporal continuous regional soil moisture data. The data assimilation method can be used to improve the soil moisture estimations by merging multi-source observed data, but its performance is affected by error covariance and the quality of assimilated data. We designed eight numerical experiments to analyze how to improve the filter performance through soil moisture assimilation using the unscented weighted ensemble Kalman filter (UWEnKF) and 1-D Richards equation at Maqu and Erlinghu (ELH) observational sites in the source region of Yellow River (SRYR), China. The experimental results show that the filter performance improves as the quality of assimilated data increases in the soil moisture assimilation experiment when assimilating in-situ surface soil moisture (SSM) observations, SMAP SSM data and downscaled SMAP SSM data. In other aspects, filter performance is readily affected by model and observation error covariances in soil moisture assimilation. If the SMAP SSM data are taken to be perfect (ie, small bias), UWEnKF performs differently between different sites because of the underestimation or overestimation of SMAP SSM and model simulations compared to the in-situ observations. Additionally, different soil moisture assimilation results can be obtained with different initial values at the beginning of the assimilation period. Overall, filter performance can be improved primarily by improving the quality of assimilated data (eg, downscaling the remote sensing data), and by creating a reasonable and effective method for determining error covariance.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This article is protected by copyright. All rights reserved.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> Xiaolei Fu, Yuchen Zhang, Qi Zhong, Haishen Lü, Yongjian Ding, Zhaoguo Li, Zhongbo Yu, Xiaolei Jiang</dc:creator><category> Research Article</category><dc:title> Soil moisture estimation by assimilating in‐situ and SMAP surface soil moisture using unscented weighted ensemble Kalman filter</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2023WR034506</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1029/2023WR034506</prism:doi><prism:url> https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2023WR034506?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> Research Article</prism:section></item><item><link/> https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR034339?af=R<pubDate> Fri, 01 Sep 2023 15:48:38 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-09-01T03:48:38-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley: Water Resources Research: Table of Contents <prism:coverdate></prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate></prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR034339</guid><title> Fracture network characterization in reservoirs by joint inversion of microseismicity and thermal breakthrough data: Method development and verification</title><description> Water Resources Research, Accepted Article.</description><dc:description> Abstract The spatial configuration of fractures often regulates flow and transport in the subsurface. However, the characterization of fracture networks is a challenging task, especially in deep reservoirs, because here only a limited number of boreholes is available to perform downhole logs and cross‐well hydraulic and tracer tests. In this study, we develop a joint inversion procedure to infer fracture number, geometry, and aperture based on Bayesian principles, utilizing microseismic (MS) events and thermal breakthrough data; both are typically available in enhanced geothermal systems and unconventional gas/oil reservoirs. A basic discrete fracture geometry, including orientations, lengths and positions of fractures, is generated from an MS events cloud by minimizing the distance between fractures and MS events. This geometric configuration, together with the aperture, is then further adjusted, based on the reversible jump Markov chain Monte Carlo algorithm, to minimize the misfit between observed and calculated thermal breakthrough curves by iterative forward flow and heat transport modeling. The inversion model is applied to two synthetic test cases. Following the sensitivity analysis of temperatures to fracture parameters, and the robustness analysis on the model performance under supportive data featuring good and poor quality, it is confirmed that the probabilistic joint inversion procedure approximates the fracture geometry and aperture well, and errors in predicting temperatures based on realizations of fracture networks are well below 5%. The methodology provides a new way to characterize fracture networks in the subsurface, without restrictions on predetermined fracture sizes or the number of fractures.</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;The spatial configuration of fractures often regulates flow and transport in the subsurface. However, the characterization of fracture networks is a challenging task, especially in deep reservoirs, because here only a limited number of boreholes is available to perform downhole logs and cross-well hydraulic and tracer tests. In this study, we develop a joint inversion procedure to infer fracture number, geometry, and aperture based on Bayesian principles, utilizing microseismic (MS) events and thermal breakthrough data; both are typically available in enhanced geothermal systems and unconventional gas/oil reservoirs. A basic discrete fracture geometry, including orientations, lengths and positions of fractures, is generated from an MS events cloud by minimizing the distance between fractures and MS events. This geometric configuration, together with the aperture, is then further adjusted, based on the reversible jump Markov chain Monte Carlo algorithm, to minimize the misfit between observed and calculated thermal breakthrough curves by iterative forward flow and heat transport modeling. The inversion model is applied to two synthetic test cases. Following the sensitivity analysis of temperatures to fracture parameters, and the robustness analysis on the model performance under supportive data featuring good and poor quality, it is confirmed that the probabilistic joint inversion procedure approximates the fracture geometry and aperture well, and errors in predicting temperatures based on realizations of fracture networks are well below 5%. The methodology provides a new way to characterize fracture networks in the subsurface, without restrictions on predetermined fracture sizes or the number of fractures.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> Zhenjiao Jiang, Lisa Maria Ringel, Peter Bayer, Tianfu Xu</dc:creator><category> Research Article</category><dc:title> Fracture network characterization in reservoirs by joint inversion of microseismicity and thermal breakthrough data: Method development and verification</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2022WR034339</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1029/2022WR034339</prism:doi><prism:url> https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR034339?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> Research Article</prism:section></item><item><link/> https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2023WR034725?af=R<pubDate> Fri, 01 Sep 2023 08:33:57 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-09-01T08:33:57-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley: Water Resources Research: Table of Contents<prism:coverdate> Fri, 01 Sep 2023 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate> Fri, 01 Sep 2023 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2023WR034725</guid><title> One‐Parameter Analytical Derivation in Modified Budyko Framework for Unsteady‐State Streamflow Elasticity in Humid Catchments</title><description> Water Resources Research, Volume 59, Issue 9, September 2023.</description><dc:description> Abstract The changes in climate and catchment properties have altered the hydrological processes significantly at different spatiotemporal scales around the world. In particular for finer time scales, changes in water storage, which has been commonly neglected for long‐term temporal scales, may play an important role on hydrological processes. Nevertheless, few studies addressed this question in modifying the Budyko framework, with most of them remaining a steady‐state assumption on catchment characteristics. Here, we derive new analytical formulas of unsteady‐state streamflow elasticity in a modified Budyko framework, incorporating both storage change and one specific parameter for catchment properties. We study 78 humid catchments in the USA with simulation data of daily hydrological processes from a probability‐distribution‐based hydrological model (the modified HyMOD). As indicated by results, the annual storage change ratio is linearly correlated with the annual aridity index, and this relationship can be used to estimate elasticity coefficients with our formulas. The estimated elasticity coefficients perform well in simulating the annual streamflow with the power‐law model. For different catchments, variability of the unsteady‐state elasticity is higher than that of the steady‐state elasticity. Unsteady‐state streamflow coefficients show significant linear correlation with catchment properties, such as the average slope, average elevation, and catchment area. This study provides a new analytical approach to investigate the interannual stability of catchments with varying climate and catchment properties.</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;The changes in climate and catchment properties have altered the hydrological processes significantly at different spatiotemporal scales around the world. In particular for finer time scales, changes in water storage, which has been commonly neglected for long-term temporal scales, may play an important role on hydrological processes. Nevertheless, few studies addressed this question in modifying the Budyko framework, with most of them remaining a steady-state assumption on catchment characteristics. Here, we derive new analytical formulas of unsteady-state streamflow elasticity in a modified Budyko framework, incorporating both storage change and one specific parameter for catchment properties. We study 78 humid catchments in the USA with simulation data of daily hydrological processes from a probability-distribution-based hydrological model (the modified HyMOD). As indicated by results, the annual storage change ratio is linearly correlated with the annual aridity index, and this relationship can be used to estimate elasticity coefficients with our formulas. The estimated elasticity coefficients perform well in simulating the annual streamflow with the power-law model. For different catchments, variability of the unsteady-state elasticity is higher than that of the steady-state elasticity. Unsteady-state streamflow coefficients show significant linear correlation with catchment properties, such as the average slope, average elevation, and catchment area. This study provides a new analytical approach to investigate the interannual stability of catchments with varying climate and catchment properties.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> Peng‐Fei Han, Arumugam Sankarasubramanian, Xu‐Sheng Wang, Li Wan, Lili Yao</dc:creator><category> Research Article</category><dc:title> One‐Parameter Analytical Derivation in Modified Budyko Framework for Unsteady‐State Streamflow Elasticity in Humid Catchments</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2023WR034725</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1029/2023WR034725</prism:doi><prism:url> https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2023WR034725?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> Research Article</prism:section><prism:volume> 59</prism:volume><prism:number> 9</prism:number></item><item><link/> https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR032831?af=R<pubDate> Fri, 01 Sep 2023 08:26:00 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-09-01T08:26:00-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley: Water Resources Research: Table of Contents<prism:coverdate> Fri, 01 Sep 2023 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate> Fri, 01 Sep 2023 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR032831</guid><title> Defining Renewable Groundwater Use and Its Relevance to Sustainable Groundwater Management</title><description> Water Resources Research, Volume 59, Issue 9, September 2023.</description><dc:description> Abstract Groundwater systems are commonly defined as renewable or non‐renewable based on natural fluxes of recharge or on estimates of aquifer storage and groundwater residence time. However, we show here that the principle of capture (ie, how recharge and discharge change due to pumping) challenges simple definitions so that a groundwater system cannot be renewable or non‐renewable in and of itself, but only with reference to how the groundwater is being used. We develop and propose more hydraulically informed definitions for flux‐renewable and storage‐renewable groundwater use, and a combined definition that encompasses both the flux‐based and storage‐based perspectives such that: renewable groundwater use allows for dynamically stable re‐equilibrium of groundwater levels and quality on human timescales. Further, we show how a matrix of combinations of (a) the ratio of pumping rate to the maximum rate of capture along with (b) the response or recovery timescales implicit in this definition, leads to a useful four‐quadrant framework for characterizing groundwater use, illustrated using case studies from aquifers around the world. Renewable groundwater use may inform pathways to groundwater sustainability, which encompasses a broader set of dimensions (eg, socio‐political, economic, ecological and cultural) beyond the scope of groundwater science. We propose that separating physically robust definitions of renewable groundwater use from the inherently value‐based language of sustainability, can help bring much needed clarity to wider discussions about sustainable groundwater management strategies, and the role of groundwater science and scientists in such endeavors.</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;Groundwater systems are commonly defined as renewable or non-renewable based on natural fluxes of recharge or on estimates of aquifer storage and groundwater residence time. However, we show here that the principle of capture (ie, how recharge and discharge change due to pumping) challenges simple definitions so that a groundwater system cannot be renewable or non-renewable in and of itself, but only with reference to how the groundwater is being used. We develop and propose more hydraulically informed definitions for flux-renewable and storage-renewable groundwater use, and a combined definition that encompasses both the flux-based and storage-based perspectives such that: &lt;i>;renewable groundwater use allows for dynamically stable re-equilibrium of groundwater levels and quality on human timescales&lt;/i>;. Further, we show how a matrix of combinations of (a) the ratio of pumping rate to the maximum rate of capture along with (b) the response or recovery timescales implicit in this definition, leads to a useful four-quadrant framework for characterizing groundwater use, illustrated using case studies from aquifers around the world. Renewable groundwater use may inform pathways to groundwater sustainability, which encompasses a broader set of dimensions (eg, socio-political, economic, ecological and cultural) beyond the scope of groundwater science. We propose that separating physically robust definitions of renewable groundwater use from the inherently value-based language of sustainability, can help bring much needed clarity to wider discussions about sustainable groundwater management strategies, and the role of groundwater science and scientists in such endeavors.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> MO Cuthbert, T. Gleeson, MFP Bierkens, G. Ferguson, RG Taylor</dc:creator><category> Commentary</category><dc:title> Defining Renewable Groundwater Use and Its Relevance to Sustainable Groundwater Management</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2022WR032831</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1029/2022WR032831</prism:doi><prism:url> https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR032831?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> Commentary</prism:section><prism:volume> 59</prism:volume><prism:number> 9</prism:number></item><item><link/> https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2023WR034715?af=R<pubDate> Fri, 01 Sep 2023 08:22:32 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-09-01T08:22:32-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley: Water Resources Research: Table of Contents<prism:coverdate> Fri, 01 Sep 2023 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate> Fri, 01 Sep 2023 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2023WR034715</guid><title> Thermal Dispersion in a Fracture‐Matrix System With Application to Geothermal Energy Extraction</title><description> Water Resources Research, Volume 59, Issue 9, September 2023.</description><dc:description> Abstract We studied thermal dispersion in a fracture walled by a porous and permeable rock matrix, where the fluid flow and heat transport are coupled across the interface between these media. The reduced order model of the advective‐dispersive heat transport in the fracture‐matrix system is resulted from the Reynolds decomposition. The model allows the calculations of the upscaled dispersion and advection terms. A simple scaling relation is developed to estimate heat extraction from geothermal fracture‐matrix systems. It was shown that the extracted heat is inversely proportional to the height of the matrix squared. Our finding also revealed that the dimensionless extracted heat is weakly dependent on fracture Peclet number and matrix Darcy number and is threefold the matrix dimensionless thermal diffusion time. In the analysis presented, we assumed a homogenous system. The heterogeneity caused by a variation in fracture and rock matrix properties (such as porosity, permeability, thickness, and aperture) adds more complexity. Including these complexities in the determination of the thermal dispersion with the coupled fracture‐matrix approach needs further investigation. However, the developed model, along with the findings of this study, provides valuable insight into the physics of thermal energy extraction from fractured geothermal reservoirs and can be used for testing the underlying hypotheses in real‐field applications.</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;We studied thermal dispersion in a fracture walled by a porous and permeable rock matrix, where the fluid flow and heat transport are coupled across the interface between these media. The reduced order model of the advective-dispersive heat transport in the fracture-matrix system is resulted from the Reynolds decomposition. The model allows the calculations of the upscaled dispersion and advection terms. A simple scaling relation is developed to estimate heat extraction from geothermal fracture-matrix systems. It was shown that the extracted heat is inversely proportional to the height of the matrix squared. Our finding also revealed that the dimensionless extracted heat is weakly dependent on fracture Peclet number and matrix Darcy number and is threefold the matrix dimensionless thermal diffusion time. In the analysis presented, we assumed a homogenous system. The heterogeneity caused by a variation in fracture and rock matrix properties (such as porosity, permeability, thickness, and aperture) adds more complexity. Including these complexities in the determination of the thermal dispersion with the coupled fracture-matrix approach needs further investigation. However, the developed model, along with the findings of this study, provides valuable insight into the physics of thermal energy extraction from fractured geothermal reservoirs and can be used for testing the underlying hypotheses in real-field applications.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> Morteza Dejam, Hassan Hassanzadeh</dc:creator><category> Research Article</category><dc:title> Thermal Dispersion in a Fracture‐Matrix System With Application to Geothermal Energy Extraction</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2023WR034715</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1029/2023WR034715</prism:doi><prism:url> https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2023WR034715?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> Research Article</prism:section><prism:volume> 59</prism:volume><prism:number> 9</prism:number></item><item><link/> https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2023WR035123?af=R<pubDate> Fri, 01 Sep 2023 08:22:27 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-09-01T08:22:27-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley: Water Resources Research: Table of Contents <prism:coverdate></prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate></prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2023WR035123</guid><title> The importance of heat storage for estimating lake evaporation on different timescales: Insights from a large shallow subtropical lake</title><description> Water Resources Research, Accepted Article.</description><dc:description> Abstract The change in heat storage (Gc) is an essential component of a lake&#39;s energy balance, and its importance for lake evaporation (Ew) has been widely recognized. However, the effect of Gc on Ew exhibits diversity across time dimensions. The controls on Gc and the effects of Gc on Ew estimates at different time scales remain largely unexplored. To address these gaps, we identified the primary controls on Gc at an eddy covariance site in a large shallow lake (Lake Taihu) and quantified the role of Gc in estimating Ew on three (hourly, daily, and monthly) timescales based on two energy balance‐based Ew models. Our results indicate that the diurnal variation of Gc is dominated by net radiation and peaks around noon, while the seasonal variation of Gc is mainly controlled by air temperature and peaks in spring. In contrast, the daily variation of Gc is subjective to a confluence of factors—net radiation, wind speed, and relative humidity—displaying more stochasticity than that on the other two timescales. We also found that the importance of Gc for Ew estimates decreases as the time scale extends. Compared to the two models disregarding Gc, considering the effect of Gc enhances the average Kling‐Gupta efficiency (KGE) values of the two models by 1.33, 0.42, and 0.08 on the three timescales, respectively. Overall, this study highlights the importance of time scales in evaluating the effect of Gc on Ew estimates.</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;The change in heat storage (G&lt;sub>;c&lt;/sub>;) is an essential component of a lake&#39;s energy balance, and its importance for lake evaporation (E&lt;sub>;w&lt;/sub>;) has been widely recognized. However, the effect of G&lt;sub>;c&lt;/sub>; on E&lt;sub>;w&lt;/sub>; exhibits diversity across time dimensions. The controls on G&lt;sub>;c&lt;/sub>; and the effects of G&lt;sub>;c&lt;/sub>; on E&lt;sub>;w&lt;/sub>; estimates at different time scales remain largely unexplored. To address these gaps, we identified the primary controls on G&lt;sub>;c&lt;/sub>; at an eddy covariance site in a large shallow lake (Lake Taihu) and quantified the role of G&lt;sub>;c&lt;/sub>; in estimating E&lt;sub>;w&lt;/sub>; on three (hourly, daily, and monthly) timescales based on two energy balance-based E&lt;sub>;w&lt;/sub>; models. Our results indicate that the diurnal variation of G&lt;sub>;c&lt;/sub>; is dominated by net radiation and peaks around noon, while the seasonal variation of G&lt;sub>;c&lt;/sub>; is mainly controlled by air temperature and peaks in spring. In contrast, the daily variation of G&lt;sub>;c&lt;/sub>; is subjective to a confluence of factors—net radiation, wind speed, and relative humidity—displaying more stochasticity than that on the other two timescales. We also found that the importance of G&lt;sub>;c&lt;/sub>; for E&lt;sub>;w&lt;/sub>; estimates decreases as the time scale extends. Compared to the two models disregarding G&lt;sub>;c&lt;/sub>;, considering the effect of G&lt;sub>;c&lt;/sub>; enhances the average Kling-Gupta efficiency (KGE) values of the two models by 1.33, 0.42, and 0.08 on the three timescales, respectively. Overall, this study highlights the importance of time scales in evaluating the effect of G&lt;sub>;c&lt;/sub>; on E&lt;sub>;w&lt;/sub>; estimates.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> Peng Bai, Yongsheng Wang</dc:creator><category> Research Article</category><dc:title> The importance of heat storage for estimating lake evaporation on different timescales: Insights from a large shallow subtropical lake</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2023WR035123</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1029/2023WR035123</prism:doi><prism:url> https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2023WR035123?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> Research Article</prism:section></item><item><link/> https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2023WR035026?af=R<pubDate> Thu, 31 Aug 2023 11:00:48 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-08-31T11:00:48-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley: Water Resources Research: Table of Contents<prism:coverdate> Fri, 01 Sep 2023 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate> Fri, 01 Sep 2023 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2023WR035026</guid><title> Estuarine Hypoxia—Identifying High Risk Catchments Now and Under Future Climate Scenarios</title><description> Water Resources Research, Volume 59, Issue 9, September 2023.</description><dc:description> Abstract Hypoxic blackwater events occur worldwide, affecting inland and coastal waters. These events have been exacerbated by man‐made floodplain drainage, leading to large‐scale fish kills and ecological degradation. This paper presents a new method to identify estuarine catchment areas that are most likely to generate hypoxic conditions. The method uses established risk factors, including vegetation type, inundation extent and duration, ground‐truthed in eastern Australia. A catchment is at higher risk of hypoxic blackwater generation if (a) it is located where floodwaters are high and/or drainage is impeded, (b) the site topography includes an extensive, low‐lying floodplain; and/or (c) the land‐use and environmental characteristics have a high deoxygenation potential. Consequent impacts to an estuary are determined by the floodplain connectivity with the estuary, and the discharge characteristics of the catchment drainage system. Where multiple, proximate catchments have similar drainage conditions, compounding plumes of hypoxic blackwater can overwhelm the assimilation capacity of the estuary. Climate change may significantly increase the volume and frequency of blackwater events in estuarine environments as a result of reduced drainage due to sea level rise, higher temperatures, and more intense and sporadic rainfall events. It is recommended that management measures be introduced to mitigate the effects of climate change and avoid further widespread hypoxic blackwater events.</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;Hypoxic blackwater events occur worldwide, affecting inland and coastal waters. These events have been exacerbated by man-made floodplain drainage, leading to large-scale fish kills and ecological degradation. This paper presents a new method to identify estuarine catchment areas that are most likely to generate hypoxic conditions. The method uses established risk factors, including vegetation type, inundation extent and duration, ground-truthed in eastern Australia. A catchment is at higher risk of hypoxic blackwater generation if (a) it is located where floodwaters are high and/or drainage is impeded, (b) the site topography includes an extensive, low-lying floodplain; and/or (c) the land-use and environmental characteristics have a high deoxygenation potential. Consequent impacts to an estuary are determined by the floodplain connectivity with the estuary, and the discharge characteristics of the catchment drainage system. Where multiple, proximate catchments have similar drainage conditions, compounding plumes of hypoxic blackwater can overwhelm the assimilation capacity of the estuary. Climate change may significantly increase the volume and frequency of blackwater events in estuarine environments as a result of reduced drainage due to sea level rise, higher temperatures, and more intense and sporadic rainfall events. It is recommended that management measures be introduced to mitigate the effects of climate change and avoid further widespread hypoxic blackwater events.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> K. Waddington, A. Harrison, D. Rayner, T. Tucker, W. Glamore</dc:creator><category> Research Article</category><dc:title> Estuarine Hypoxia—Identifying High Risk Catchments Now and Under Future Climate Scenarios</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2023WR035026</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1029/2023WR035026</prism:doi><prism:url> https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2023WR035026?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> Research Article</prism:section><prism:volume> 59</prism:volume><prism:number> 9</prism:number></item><item><link/> https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033719?af=R<pubDate> Thu, 31 Aug 2023 11:00:37 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-08-31T11:00:37-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley: Water Resources Research: Table of Contents<prism:coverdate> Fri, 01 Sep 2023 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate> Fri, 01 Sep 2023 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR033719</guid><title> Improving CINRAD Radar QPE Through GPM‐DPR Reflectivity Bias Correction</title><description> Water Resources Research, Volume 59, Issue 9, September 2023.</description><dc:description> Abstract Reflectivity bias of ground‐based weather radar (GR) is a common error source that can lead to biases in quantitative precipitation estimation (QPE). In this study, the Dual‐frequency Precipitation Radar onboard the Global Precipitation Measurement Mission Core Observatory (GPM‐DPR) is used to correct GR reflectivity bias. The reflectivity bias correction comprehensively considers variations in GR‐DPR reflectivity difference associated with radar frequency difference, data matching approach, precipitation type, GR orographic beam blockage, attenuation, and sample size. The criteria to perform a robust GR‐DPR comparison are presented. Disdrometer validation, based on eight typical rain events from April to August 2019, demonstrates that GPM‐DPR can effectively reduce GR reflectivity bias to ±1 dB. For the period from June to August 2021, the reflectivity correction method is applied to 17 operational GRs. The multiradar QPE shows a significant increase in correlation coefficient (from 0.62 to 0.71), and decreases in relative mean bias (from −0.28 to −0.19) and root mean square error (from 3.96 to 3.54 mm) compared to rain gauges. These results confirm that GPM‐DPR can effectively correct the reflectivity biases of a GR network and improve multiradar QPE accuracy and consistency.</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;Reflectivity bias of ground-based weather radar (GR) is a common error source that can lead to biases in quantitative precipitation estimation (QPE). In this study, the Dual-frequency Precipitation Radar onboard the Global Precipitation Measurement Mission Core Observatory (GPM-DPR) is used to correct GR reflectivity bias. The reflectivity bias correction comprehensively considers variations in GR-DPR reflectivity difference associated with radar frequency difference, data matching approach, precipitation type, GR orographic beam blockage, attenuation, and sample size. The criteria to perform a robust GR-DPR comparison are presented. Disdrometer validation, based on eight typical rain events from April to August 2019, demonstrates that GPM-DPR can effectively reduce GR reflectivity bias to ±1 dB. For the period from June to August 2021, the reflectivity correction method is applied to 17 operational GRs. The multiradar QPE shows a significant increase in correlation coefficient (from 0.62 to 0.71), and decreases in relative mean bias (from −0.28 to −0.19) and root mean square error (from 3.96 to 3.54 mm) compared to rain gauges. These results confirm that GPM-DPR can effectively correct the reflectivity biases of a GR network and improve multiradar QPE accuracy and consistency.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> Ziwei Zhu, Youcun Qi, Donghuan Li</dc:creator><category> Research Article</category><dc:title> Improving CINRAD Radar QPE Through GPM‐DPR Reflectivity Bias Correction</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2022WR033719</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1029/2022WR033719</prism:doi><prism:url> https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033719?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> Research Article</prism:section><prism:volume> 59</prism:volume><prism:number> 9</prism:number></item><item><link/> https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2023WR035191?af=R<pubDate> Thu, 31 Aug 2023 10:54:54 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-08-31T10:54:54-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley: Water Resources Research: Table of Contents<prism:coverdate> Fri, 01 Sep 2023 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate> Fri, 01 Sep 2023 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2023WR035191</guid><title> Hydraulic Tomography Estimates Improved by Zonal Information From the Clustering of Geophysical Survey Data</title><description> Water Resources Research, Volume 59, Issue 9, September 2023.</description><dc:description> Abstract Hydraulic tomography (HT) has been demonstrated as a robust approach to characterize subsurface heterogeneity through the inverse modeling of multiple pumping data. However, smooth or even erroneous tomograms can result when insufficient observations are involved in the inversion. In this study, the feasibility of integrating geophysical survey data into HT analysis is investigated. First, k‐means clustering is utilized to extract zonal information from borehole geophysical logs, and a new type of spatial constraints containing geological knowledge is proposed to obtain improved hydrostratigraphic boundaries along boreholes. Next, zonation models are constructed by applying clustering‐based zone geometry and populating zonal estimates of hydraulic conductivity (K) from analyzing pumping data. Afterwards, zonation models are treated as the initial guess of spatial variability in the geostatistical inversion of HT analysis. Additionally, local K measurements can be utilized to further improve HT estimates. Comparative cases of HT analyses are designed for a numerical sandbox experiment to highlight the HT performance integrated with geophysical surveys, in which the geostatistical inversion is initialized with: (a) a homogeneous K field; (b) zonation models built by the clustering of disparate geophysical surveys with/without spatial constraints; and (c) zonation improved by incorporating local K measurements. Based on ln K field comparisons and validation through predictions of drawdowns and tracer plume migration from independent tests not used in the calibration effort, we find that integration of geophysical surveys into HT analysis by clustering with spatial constraints is demonstrated as an effective approach, and local K measurements can further improve HT estimates.</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;Hydraulic tomography (HT) has been demonstrated as a robust approach to characterize subsurface heterogeneity through the inverse modeling of multiple pumping data. However, smooth or even erroneous tomograms can result when insufficient observations are involved in the inversion. In this study, the feasibility of integrating geophysical survey data into HT analysis is investigated. First, &lt;i>;k&lt;/i>;-means clustering is utilized to extract zonal information from borehole geophysical logs, and a new type of spatial constraints containing geological knowledge is proposed to obtain improved hydrostratigraphic boundaries along boreholes. Next, zonation models are constructed by applying clustering-based zone geometry and populating zonal estimates of hydraulic conductivity (&lt;i>;K&lt;/i>;) from analyzing pumping data. Afterwards, zonation models are treated as the initial guess of spatial variability in the geostatistical inversion of HT analysis. Additionally, local &lt;i>;K&lt;/i>; measurements can be utilized to further improve HT estimates. Comparative cases of HT analyses are designed for a numerical sandbox experiment to highlight the HT performance integrated with geophysical surveys, in which the geostatistical inversion is initialized with: (a) a homogeneous &lt;i>;K&lt;/i>; field; (b) zonation models built by the clustering of disparate geophysical surveys with/without spatial constraints; and (c) zonation improved by incorporating local &lt;i>;K&lt;/i>; measurements. Based on ln &lt;i>;K&lt;/i>; field comparisons and validation through predictions of drawdowns and tracer plume migration from independent tests not used in the calibration effort, we find that integration of geophysical surveys into HT analysis by clustering with spatial constraints is demonstrated as an effective approach, and local &lt;i>;K&lt;/i>; measurements can further improve HT estimates.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> Chenxi Wang, Walter A. Illman</dc:creator><category> Research Article</category><dc:title> Hydraulic Tomography Estimates Improved by Zonal Information From the Clustering of Geophysical Survey Data</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2023WR035191</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1029/2023WR035191</prism:doi><prism:url> https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2023WR035191?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> Research Article</prism:section><prism:volume> 59</prism:volume><prism:number> 9</prism:number></item><item><link/> https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2023WR034544?af=R<pubDate> Thu, 31 Aug 2023 10:54:32 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-08-31T10:54:32-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley: Water Resources Research: Table of Contents<prism:coverdate> Fri, 01 Sep 2023 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate> Fri, 01 Sep 2023 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2023WR034544</guid><title> Making the Best Use of GRACE, GRACE‐FO and SMAP Data Through a Constrained Bayesian Data‐Model Integration</title><description> Water Resources Research, Volume 59, Issue 9, September 2023.</description><dc:description> Abstract The Gravity Recovery and Climate Experiment (GRACE, 2003–2017) and its Follow‐On mission GRACE‐FO (2018‐now) provide global estimates of the vertically integrated Terrestrial Water Storage Changes (TWSC). Since 2015, the Soil Moisture Active Passive (SMAP) radiometer observes global L‐band brightness temperatures, which are sensitive to near‐surface soil moisture. In this study, we introduce our newly developed Constrained Bayesian (ConBay) optimization approach to merge the TWSC of GRACE/GRACE‐FO along with SMAP soil moisture data into the ∼10 km resolution W3RA water balance model. ConBay is formulated based on two hierarchical multivariate state‐space models to (I) separate land hydrology compartments from GRACE/GRACE‐FO TWSC, and (II) constrain the estimation of surface soil water storage based on the SMAP data. The numerical implementation is demonstrated over the High Plain (HP) aquifer in the United States between 2015 and 2021. The implementation of ConBay is compared with an unconstrained Bayesian formulation, and our validations are performed against in‐situ USGS groundwater level observations and the European Space Agency (ESA)&#39;s Climate Change Initiative (CCI) soil moisture data. Our results indicate that the single GRACE/GRACE‐FO assimilation improves particularly the groundwater compartment. Adding SMAP data to the ConBay approach controls the updates assigned to the surface storage compartments. For example, correlation coefficients between the ESA CCI and the ConBay‐derived surface soil water storage (0.8) that are considerably higher than those derived from the unconstrained experiment (−0.3) in the North HP. The percentage of updates introduced to the W3RA groundwater storage is also decreased from 64% to 57%.</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;The Gravity Recovery and Climate Experiment (GRACE, 2003–2017) and its Follow-On mission GRACE-FO (2018-now) provide global estimates of the vertically integrated Terrestrial Water Storage Changes (TWSC). Since 2015, the Soil Moisture Active Passive (SMAP) radiometer observes global L-band brightness temperatures, which are sensitive to near-surface soil moisture. In this study, we introduce our newly developed Constrained Bayesian (ConBay) optimization approach to merge the TWSC of GRACE/GRACE-FO along with SMAP soil moisture data into the ∼10 km resolution W3RA water balance model. ConBay is formulated based on two hierarchical multivariate state-space models to (I) separate land hydrology compartments from GRACE/GRACE-FO TWSC, and (II) constrain the estimation of surface soil water storage based on the SMAP data. The numerical implementation is demonstrated over the High Plain (HP) aquifer in the United States between 2015 and 2021. The implementation of ConBay is compared with an unconstrained Bayesian formulation, and our validations are performed against in-situ USGS groundwater level observations and the European Space Agency (ESA)&#39;s Climate Change Initiative (CCI) soil moisture data. Our results indicate that the single GRACE/GRACE-FO assimilation improves particularly the groundwater compartment. Adding SMAP data to the ConBay approach controls the updates assigned to the surface storage compartments. For example, correlation coefficients between the ESA CCI and the ConBay-derived surface soil water storage (0.8) that are considerably higher than those derived from the unconstrained experiment (−0.3) in the North HP. The percentage of updates introduced to the W3RA groundwater storage is also decreased from 64% to 57%.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> Nooshin Mehrnegar, Maike Schumacher, Thomas Jagdhuber, Ehsan Forootan</dc:creator><category> Research Article</category><dc:title> Making the Best Use of GRACE, GRACE‐FO and SMAP Data Through a Constrained Bayesian Data‐Model Integration</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2023WR034544</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1029/2023WR034544</prism:doi><prism:url> https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2023WR034544?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> Research Article</prism:section><prism:volume> 59</prism:volume><prism:number> 9</prism:number></item><item><link/> https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033588?af=R<pubDate> Thu, 31 Aug 2023 10:48:52 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-08-31T10:48:52-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley: Water Resources Research: Table of Contents<prism:coverdate> Fri, 01 Sep 2023 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate> Fri, 01 Sep 2023 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR033588</guid><title> Large‐Scale Groundwater Monitoring in Brazil Assisted With Satellite‐Based Artificial Intelligence Techniques</title><description> Water Resources Research, Volume 59, Issue 9, September 2023.</description><dc:description> Abstract Here, we develop and test an artificial intelligence (AI)‐based approach to monitor major Brazilian aquifers. The approach combines Gravity Recovery and Climate Experiment (GRACE) data and ground‐based hydrogeological measurements from Brazil&#39;s Integrated Groundwater Monitoring Network at hundreds of wells distributed in 12 aquifers across the country. We tested model ensembles based on three AI approaches: Extreme Gradient Boost, Light Gradient Boosting Model and CatBoost, followed by a Linear Regression step. The approach is further boosted with wavelet and seasonal decomposition processes applied to GRACE data. To determine the AI‐based model&#39;s sensitivity to data availability, we propose four experiments combining hydrogeological measurements from different aquifers. Groundwater storage (GWS) estimates from the Global Land Data Assimilation System (GLDAS) are used as benchmark. A sensitivity analysis shows that the LR‐based model ensemble is the best suited and to reproduce GWS change in all studied Brazilian aquifers. Results show that the proposed approach outperforms GLDAS in all experiments, with an root mean square error (RMSE) value of 2.68 cm for the experiment that covers all monitored wells in Brazil. GLDAS resulted in RMSE = 6.76 cm. Using our AI model outputs, we quantified the GWS change of two major aquifers, Urucuia and Bauru‐Caiuá, over the past two decades: −31 and −6 km3, respectively. Water loss is driven by a prolonged drought across most of the country and intensification of groundwater pumping for irrigation. This study demonstrates that combining satellite data and AI can be a cost‐effective alternative to monitor poorly equipped aquifers at the continental scale, with possible global replicability.</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;Here, we develop and test an artificial intelligence (AI)-based approach to monitor major Brazilian aquifers. The approach combines Gravity Recovery and Climate Experiment (GRACE) data and ground-based hydrogeological measurements from Brazil&#39;s Integrated Groundwater Monitoring Network at hundreds of wells distributed in 12 aquifers across the country. We tested model ensembles based on three AI approaches: Extreme Gradient Boost, Light Gradient Boosting Model and CatBoost, followed by a Linear Regression step. The approach is further boosted with wavelet and seasonal decomposition processes applied to GRACE data. To determine the AI-based model&#39;s sensitivity to data availability, we propose four experiments combining hydrogeological measurements from different aquifers. Groundwater storage (GWS) estimates from the Global Land Data Assimilation System (GLDAS) are used as benchmark. A sensitivity analysis shows that the LR-based model ensemble is the best suited and to reproduce GWS change in all studied Brazilian aquifers. Results show that the proposed approach outperforms GLDAS in all experiments, with an root mean square error (RMSE) value of 2.68 cm for the experiment that covers all monitored wells in Brazil. GLDAS resulted in RMSE = 6.76 cm. Using our AI model outputs, we quantified the GWS change of two major aquifers, Urucuia and Bauru-Caiuá, over the past two decades: −31 and −6 km&lt;sup>;3&lt;/sup>;, respectively. Water loss is driven by a prolonged drought across most of the country and intensification of groundwater pumping for irrigation. This study demonstrates that combining satellite data and AI can be a cost-effective alternative to monitor poorly equipped aquifers at the continental scale, with possible global replicability.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> Clyvihk Renna Camacho, Augusto Getirana, Otto Corrêa Rotunno Filho, Maria Antonieta A. Mourão</dc:creator><category> Research Article</category><dc:title> Large‐Scale Groundwater Monitoring in Brazil Assisted With Satellite‐Based Artificial Intelligence Techniques</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2022WR033588</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1029/2022WR033588</prism:doi><prism:url> https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033588?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> Research Article</prism:section><prism:volume> 59</prism:volume><prism:number> 9</prism:number></item><item><link/> https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR034224?af=R<pubDate> Thu, 31 Aug 2023 10:48:41 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-08-31T10:48:41-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley: Water Resources Research: Table of Contents<prism:coverdate> Fri, 01 Sep 2023 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate> Fri, 01 Sep 2023 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR034224</guid><title> Biogeochemical Processes Are Altered by Non‐Conservative Mixing at Stream Confluences</title><description> Water Resources Research, Volume 59, Issue 9, September 2023.</description><dc:description> Abstract Stream confluences are ubiquitous interfaces in freshwater networks and serve as junctions of previously independent landscapes. However, few studies have investigated how confluences influence the transport, mixing, and fate of organic matter (OM) and inorganic nutrients at the scale of river networks. To understand how network biogeochemical fluxes may be altered by confluences, we conducted two sampling campaigns at five confluences in summer and fall 2021 spanning the extent of a mixed land use stream network. We sampled the confluence mainstem and tributary reaches as well as throughout the mixing zone downstream. We predicted that biologically reactive solutes would mix non‐conservatively downstream of confluences and that alterations to downstream biogeochemistry would be driven by differences in chemistry and size of the tributary and upstream reaches. In our study, confluences were geomorphically distinct (eg, wider, deeper, unique erosional, and depositional features) downstream compared to reaches upstream of the confluence. Dissolved OM and nutrients mixed non‐conservatively downstream of the five confluences. Biogeochemical patterns downstream of confluences were only partially explained by contributing reach chemistry and drainage area. We found that the relationship between geomorphic variability, water residence time, and microbial respiration differed between reaches upstream and downstream of confluences. The lack of explanatory power from network‐scale drivers suggests that non‐conservative mixing downstream of confluences may be driven by biogeochemical processes within the confluence mixing zone. The unique geomorphology, non‐conservative biogeochemistry, and ubiquity of confluences highlights a need to account for the distinct functional role of confluences in water resource management in freshwater networks.</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;Stream confluences are ubiquitous interfaces in freshwater networks and serve as junctions of previously independent landscapes. However, few studies have investigated how confluences influence the transport, mixing, and fate of organic matter (OM) and inorganic nutrients at the scale of river networks. To understand how network biogeochemical fluxes may be altered by confluences, we conducted two sampling campaigns at five confluences in summer and fall 2021 spanning the extent of a mixed land use stream network. We sampled the confluence mainstem and tributary reaches as well as throughout the mixing zone downstream. We predicted that biologically reactive solutes would mix non-conservatively downstream of confluences and that alterations to downstream biogeochemistry would be driven by differences in chemistry and size of the tributary and upstream reaches. In our study, confluences were geomorphically distinct (eg, wider, deeper, unique erosional, and depositional features) downstream compared to reaches upstream of the confluence. Dissolved OM and nutrients mixed non-conservatively downstream of the five confluences. Biogeochemical patterns downstream of confluences were only partially explained by contributing reach chemistry and drainage area. We found that the relationship between geomorphic variability, water residence time, and microbial respiration differed between reaches upstream and downstream of confluences. The lack of explanatory power from network-scale drivers suggests that non-conservative mixing downstream of confluences may be driven by biogeochemical processes within the confluence mixing zone. The unique geomorphology, non-conservative biogeochemistry, and ubiquity of confluences highlights a need to account for the distinct functional role of confluences in water resource management in freshwater networks.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> Stephen Plont, Durelle T. Scott, Erin R. Hotchkiss</dc:creator><category> Research Article</category><dc:title> Biogeochemical Processes Are Altered by Non‐Conservative Mixing at Stream Confluences</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2022WR034224</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1029/2022WR034224</prism:doi><prism:url> https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR034224?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> Research Article</prism:section><prism:volume> 59</prism:volume><prism:number> 9</prism:number></item><item><link/> https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2023WR034461?af=R<pubDate> Thu, 31 Aug 2023 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-08-31T12:00:00-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley: Water Resources Research: Table of Contents <prism:coverdate></prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate></prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2023WR034461</guid><title> Impact of pressure waves on water imbibition and flow in unsaturated porous media</title><description> Water Resources Research, Accepted Article.</description><dc:description> Abstract The wetting front dynamics during water imbibition in dry porous media affect the ultimate water distribution pattern. In this study, we investigate the impact of pressure pulses that emit waves in the water phase on the water distribution and imbibition patterns in porous media. We present experimental results of water spatial distribution in sand columns following infiltration under abrupt pressured‐water pulses and compare them with those of continuous inflow. Applying pressure waves during infiltration increases pressure gradients behind the wetting front, which can overcome capillary and gravitational forces, leading to uniform imbibition. To simulate the process, we developed a pore network model incorporating an analytical solution of pressure wave attenuation to predict the imbibition pattern. Our results demonstrate that the amplitude of the pressure wave is associated with a sharp wetting front, resulting in higher water content compared to Darcy‐type continuous flow. The findings suggest that pressure waves have the potential to achieve high water content in unsaturated media and provide insights into the spatial extent of their impact on water distribution. This article is protected by copyright.版权所有。</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;The wetting front dynamics during water imbibition in dry porous media affect the ultimate water distribution pattern. In this study, we investigate the impact of pressure pulses that emit waves in the water phase on the water distribution and imbibition patterns in porous media. We present experimental results of water spatial distribution in sand columns following infiltration under abrupt pressured-water pulses and compare them with those of continuous inflow. Applying pressure waves during infiltration increases pressure gradients behind the wetting front, which can overcome capillary and gravitational forces, leading to uniform imbibition. To simulate the process, we developed a pore network model incorporating an analytical solution of pressure wave attenuation to predict the imbibition pattern. Our results demonstrate that the amplitude of the pressure wave is associated with a sharp wetting front, resulting in higher water content compared to Darcy-type continuous flow. The findings suggest that pressure waves have the potential to achieve high water content in unsaturated media and provide insights into the spatial extent of their impact on water distribution.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This article is protected by copyright. All rights reserved.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> Doron Kalisman, Alexander Yakirevich, Shaul Sorek, Tamir Kamai</dc:creator><category> Research Article</category><dc:title> Impact of pressure waves on water imbibition and flow in unsaturated porous media</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2023WR034461</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1029/2023WR034461</prism:doi><prism:url> https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2023WR034461?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> Research Article</prism:section></item><item><link/> https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033363?af=R<pubDate> Wed, 30 Aug 2023 07:54:26 -0700</pubDate><dc:date> 2023-08-30T07:54:26-07:00</dc:date><source url="https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/19447973?af=R"/> Wiley: Water Resources Research: Table of Contents<prism:coverdate> Fri, 01 Sep 2023 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdate><prism:coverdisplaydate> Fri, 01 Sep 2023 00:00:00 -0700</prism:coverdisplaydate><guid ispermalink="false"> 10.1029/2022WR033363</guid><title> Predicting Hydrological Change in an Alpine Glacierized Basin and Its Sensitivity to Landscape Evolution and Meteorological Forcings</title><description> Water Resources Research, Volume 59, Issue 9, September 2023.</description><dc:description> Abstract Shifting precipitation patterns, a warming climate, changing snow dynamics and retreating glaciers are occurring simultaneously in glacierized mountain headwaters. To predict future hydrological behavior in an exemplar glacierized basin, a spatially distributed, physically based cold regions process hydrological model including on and off‐glacier process representations was applied to the Peyto Glacier Research Basin in the Canadian Rockies. The model was forced with bias‐corrected outputs from a high‐resolution Weather and Research Forecasting (WRF‐PGW) atmospheric simulation for 2000–2015, and under pseudo‐global warming for 2085–2100 under a business‐as‐usual climate change scenario. The simulations show that the end‐of‐century increase in precipitation nearly compensates for the decreased ice melt associated with almost complete deglaciation, resulting in a decrease in annual streamflow of 7%. However, the timing of streamflow advances drastically, with peak flow shifting from July to June, and August streamflow dropping by 68%. To examine the sensitivity of future hydrology to possible future drainage basin biophysical attributes, the end‐of‐century simulations were run under a range of initial conditions and parameters and showed the highest sensitivity to initial ice volume and surface water storage capacity. This comprehensive examination suggests that hydrological compensation between declining icemelt and increasing rainfall and snowmelt runoff as well as between deglaciation and increasing basin depressional storage capacity play important roles in determining future streamflow in a rapidly deglaciating high‐mountain environment. Conversely, afforestation and soil development had relatively smaller impacts on future hydrology.</dc:description><content:encoded> &lt;h2>;Abstract&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;Shifting precipitation patterns, a warming climate, changing snow dynamics and retreating glaciers are occurring simultaneously in glacierized mountain headwaters. To predict future hydrological behavior in an exemplar glacierized basin, a spatially distributed, physically based cold regions process hydrological model including on and off-glacier process representations was applied to the Peyto Glacier Research Basin in the Canadian Rockies. The model was forced with bias-corrected outputs from a high-resolution Weather and Research Forecasting (WRF-PGW) atmospheric simulation for 2000–2015, and under pseudo-global warming for 2085–2100 under a business-as-usual climate change scenario. The simulations show that the end-of-century increase in precipitation nearly compensates for the decreased ice melt associated with almost complete deglaciation, resulting in a decrease in annual streamflow of 7%. However, the timing of streamflow advances drastically, with peak flow shifting from July to June, and August streamflow dropping by 68%. To examine the sensitivity of future hydrology to possible future drainage basin biophysical attributes, the end-of-century simulations were run under a range of initial conditions and parameters and showed the highest sensitivity to initial ice volume and surface water storage capacity. This comprehensive examination suggests that hydrological compensation between declining icemelt and increasing rainfall and snowmelt runoff as well as between deglaciation and increasing basin depressional storage capacity play important roles in determining future streamflow in a rapidly deglaciating high-mountain environment. Conversely, afforestation and soil development had relatively smaller impacts on future hydrology.&lt;/p>;</content:encoded><dc:creator> Caroline Aubry‐Wake, John W. Pomeroy</dc:creator><category> Research Article</category><dc:title> Predicting Hydrological Change in an Alpine Glacierized Basin and Its Sensitivity to Landscape Evolution and Meteorological Forcings</dc:title><dc:identifier> 10.1029/2022WR033363</dc:identifier><prism:publicationname> Water Resources Research</prism:publicationname><prism:doi> 10.1029/2022WR033363</prism:doi><prism:url> https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2022WR033363?af=R</prism:url><prism:section> Research Article</prism:section><prism:volume> 59</prism:volume><prism:number> 9</prism:number></item></channel></rss>